Welcome to my channel.
Orchids after flowers fade.
This is a button that has not yet bloomed and has a very high chance of developing into a kiekie.
Cinnamon.
Sprinkle on the cut.
Leave in a cool place and do not water for 1 week to let the cut heal naturally.
Take 1 ginger root.
Rinse with water.
1 green or ripe banana.
5-10 eggshells.
Effective Microorganisms (EM) 2 spoon.
Sugar 2 spoons.
Warm water 2 Liters.
Leave in a cool place for 1 week.
1 WEEK LATER.
Take 20ml.
Add 2 liters of water.
Clean the leaves.
Water this liquid fertilizer once a week.
Cotton clips soaked in liquid fertilizer.
Change the cotton once a week.
And continue to fertilize with liquid fertilizer once a week.
1 MONTH LATER.
Continue fertilizing the roots with liquid fertilizer once a week.
And spray liquid fertilizer for small orchids once a week.
After the next 2 months.
Grow small orchids in pots.