Hello friends.
In my hand is a wilted orchid branch.
And in this video I will share so that you can propagate from any orchid branch.
We cut off the spots that have bloomed.
Just keep these 3 paragraphs can still sprout.
Applying candle solution on the cut will help protect the orchid from rot.
Peel off the protective film of the sleeping sprout.
Use 1 sprig of chopped fresh ginger.
500 ml of boiled water.
wait 1 day.
Soak orchids in ginger water for 30 minutes.
Soak moss in ginger water for 30 minutes.
I use recycled plastic boxes to make miniature greenhouses to help propagate orchids faster.
There's a vent here.
Put the orchid in a miniature greenhouse and spray it with moisture once a week.
Place in a bright place and avoid direct sunlight.
21 DAYS AFTER.
Continue misting to keep moisture and keep in a light place, avoid direct sunlight.
AFTER 1O NEXT DAY.
AFTER 2 NEXT WEEKS.
Plant in pots to let the orchid adapt and grow in the outside environment.
If you find it interesting, please subscribe to the channel, like, share to let more people know.
My videos have subtitles in different languages. Please select the appropriate language to understand the video content clearly.
Remember to plant the root higher than the pot so that the orchid does not have root rot.
That's all I want to share with you in this video.
Now goodbye and see you in the next videos.