Welcome to my Happiness Garden channel
Cattleya is an orchid with bright colors and an attractive scent, so it is loved by many people around the world.
In this video, I share how to make them reproduce quickly.
This is a pot of Cattleya orchids.
Includes 6 barren pseudobulbs.
First you need to cut off all damaged roots.
I then inserted these bars to stabilize the orchid so it wouldn't shake.
Then use scissors to separate each pseudobulb.
This helps the orchid grow many new pseudobulbs.
Then leave it in a cool place for 1 week without watering to let the wound heal itself.
a week later
Take 5 spoons of rice.
Add 2 liters of warm water.
Then add 1 teaspoon of turmeric powder.
Soak rice and turmeric starch for 30 minutes.
30 Minutes later.
Then you use this rice water mixed with turmeric powder to water the orchid roots.
Rice water contains some basic nutrients such as nitrogen, potassium, and phosphorus,
like a natural fertilizer to provide nutrients to plants.
You can soak the orchid pot for 20 minutes.
Next, use this water to thoroughly wipe both sides of the orchid leaves.
Turmeric starch contains antioxidants and has antibacterial effects.
Helps eliminate fungi, bacteria, and insects that harm orchids
Apply 2-3 times per month with the above 2 methods.
2 weeks later.
The sprouts begin to sprout.
I continue to fertilize the orchids with fertilizer from rice water and turmeric starch.
Fertilize 2-3 times/month with this type of fertilizer. On weekdays you just need to water to keep it moist.
2 Months later.
The sprouts have grown healthily.
There are 6 sprouts in total.
Normally, if you do not apply the method I just shared, the orchid will only grow 1-2 sprouts.
Now I plant orchids in larger pots so they can grow stronger.
Continue applying this fertilizer.
One year later.
I have a giant pot of orchids.
Thank you for watching the video. If you find the video meaningful, please like and share so more people know.
Good luck. See you in the next video.