Welcome to my channel.
To help you have many options when caring for orchids at home with organic fertilizer.
Helps orchids grow and bloom with many, long-lasting flowers.
In this video, I continue to share new methods.
When eating oranges, don't rush to throw away the peel.
Right now I will share this tip for making organic fertilizer from orange peels.
First, please subscribe to my channel so you don't miss any tips on my channel.
And share so more people know this good tip.
I cut the peel of an orange and put it in a jar.
Add 2 liters of warm water.
Then add 1 spoon of sugar and 1 spoon of yeast.
Punch holes in the lid, close the lid and leave in a cool place for 1 month.
1 MONTH LATER.
I already have GE orange peel fertilizer.
I took 4 tablespoons of GE orange peel.
mix 2 liters of water.
FIRST METHOD.
Use a GE orange peel to thoroughly wipe the top and bottom of the leaf.
Orange peels contain essential oils that after incubation will help repel insects very effectively
Helps leaves photosynthesize and create chlorophyll better.
Do this 1-2 times a month to protect orchids and keep the leaves green.
SECOND METHOD.
Applying this fertilizer to the roots 1-2 times per month helps provide organic substances such as:
humic acid, fulvic acid and enhance water retention in orchid growing media.
Orange peel also contains many important minerals such as potassium, magnesium, calcium and trace elements.
GE fertilizer helps orchids grow strongly and increase flower production.
GE fertilizer helps improve the ability of plants to absorb nutrients,
helping orchids make better use of available nutrients in the environment.
RESULT.
The flower color is more vibrant than usual.
Orchids bloom many flowers on the same tree but do not fall.
Flowers bloom continuously from season to season all year round.
The flowers stay on the branches for a long time before fading.
Thank you for watching the video. Good luck and see you in the next videos.