welcome to my channel.
In this video, I share tips on recycling organic waste to make great fertilizer for orchids.
We will not have to spend money on fertilizer and the orchids will still grow healthily.
Orchids grow many flowers.
Flowers bloom continuously from one wave to another.
To make this fertilizer I will recycle fish bones into fertilizer.
Tumble dry on low heat for 10 minutes.
pulverize.
Take 1 spoon of fish bone powder.
2 liters of hot water.
Wait for the water to cool.
rice 5 spoons.
2 liters of water.
Wait 1 hour.
1 Hour later.
Filter out residue.
FIRST METHOD.
Fertilize the orchid pot with fish bones and rice water.
Fish bones are a rich source of natural phosphorus.
Phosphorus is one of three important nutritional elements for orchid growth.
It helps create many important cell types, such as energy cells and nutrient transport cells.
Calcium in fish bones helps create strong orchid cell structures,
especially in forming and maintaining the structure of leaves and flowers.
Soaking this fertilizer for about 10-20 minutes and then lifting the orchid pot out will be better.
Do this 1-2 times a month to supplement nutrients for orchids.
SECOND METHOD.
Spray this fertilizer on the entire orchid.
Rice is rich in potassium, Potassium helps balance water in plants,
Increases plants' ability to tolerate water shortages and improves plants' ability to respond to environmental stresses.
Rice also provides some minerals and organic substances such as amino acids, which can be helpful for orchid growth.
RESULT.
After 2 months, the roots grow very healthy, helping the orchid absorb the most nutrients.
Many buds develop.
New sprouts are very strong and grow quickly.
bloom many flowers.
The flower color is more vibrant than usual.
The flowers stay on the branches for a long time before fading.
If you find this video meaningful, please share it so more people know about this video.
Thank you for watching the video. Good luck and see you in the next videos.