Welcome to my channel.
To help you have many choices when caring for orchids at home with organic fertilizer.
Helps multiply new plants.
The flowers bloom profusely and hang on the branches for a long time before fading.
In this video, I continue to share new methods.
Subscribe to the video so you don't miss any tips on my channel.
To make this fertilizer I use 1 tablespoon of rice.
Then soak in 300ml of water for 30 minutes.
puree
Filter out residue
Add 3 liters of water.
Take 3 more spoons of GE ginger solution.
FIRST METHOD
Now take this liquid fertilizer mixture and water it on the orchid roots.
Fertilizer from GE rice and ginger helps supplement nutrients and amino acids that are beneficial for orchid growth.
Especially helps stimulate extremely fast germination
Rice helps grow beneficial microorganisms to protect orchid roots from rot.
Do this once a month to supplement nutrition and increase the orchid's resistance.
SECOND METHOD
Spray this fertilizer on the entire orchid.
This method is similar to using foliar fertilizer.
Minerals in GE rice and ginger help stimulate rooting and shoot growth very well.
Do this once a month to supplement nutrition and increase the orchid's resistance..
THIRD METHOD
Clean the leaf surface with this liquid fertilizer.
This is an aphid species that harms orchids. This method kills insects very well.
The leaf surface will always be clean and the stomata will be clear.
Orchids will photosynthesize better.
RESULT.
AFTER 1 MONTH.
Roots grow very strongly.
AFTER THE NEXT 2 MONTHS.
Many buds develop.
AFTER THE NEXT 3 MONTHS.
bloom many flowers.
The flower color is more vibrant than usual.
The flowers stay on the branches for a long time before fading.
Thank you for watching the video. Good luck and see you in the next videos.