Welcome to my channel.
To help you have many choices when caring for orchids at home with organic fertilizer.
In this video, I continue to share new methods.
Subscribe to the video so you don't miss any tips on my channel.
First, to make this type of fertilizer you need cinnamon powder.
Take 1 teaspoon of cinnamon powder and soak it in 1 liter of boiled water.
Then brew until the water cools.
Next, when I eat mushrooms, I will recycle mushroom scraps to make fertilizer for orchids.
I used about 20 grams of mushrooms.
Add 500ml of water and puree.
Filter out residue.
After the water cools, filter to remove cinnamon residue.
Mix cinnamon water and mushroom water together.
Add water to get 2 liters of liquid fertilizer.
Method 1: Wipe the top and bottom of the leaves.
This method helps eliminate fungal diseases and insects hiding on the leaves.
And helps leaves photosynthesize sunlight to synthesize nutrients to feed plants better.
Do it 1-2 times per month.
Method 2: spray foliar fertilizer.
This is like you are using foliar fertilizer for orchids.
Spray all leaves, stems and roots of orchids.
Spray thoroughly on the back of the leaves because this is where fungi and insects often hide, causing harm to orchids.
Do it 1-2 times per month.
Method 3: Fertilize the roots.
Mushrooms help create a good soil environment with an organic soil particle structure,
Helps retain water and provides comfort for orchid root systems.
This fertilizer increases the ability to stimulate the plant's immune system,
Cinnamon essential oil helps repel insects from your garden without using chemicals.
Cinnamon powder has a pleasant aroma,
helping to create a comfortable environment for the plant and a pleasant feeling for the grower.
Do it 1-2 times per month.
Result.
Plant roots are protected and supplemented with nutrients so they grow very healthily.
will help orchids absorb the most nutrients.
After 2 months of spraying, the orchid has developed many flower buds.
Each plant grows from 3-6 flower stems.
Because they are provided with enough nutrition, the flowers bloom more brilliantly.
Many flowers bloom on the same branch.
Thank you for watching the video. Good luck and see you in the next videos.