Hello everyone, today I share a simple and easy way to care for orchids at home
Helps plants grow quickly and always have lots of flower buds
The flowers will stay on the branches longer.
so that orchids grow quickly and are healthy and lush
and blooms beautifully all year round
Once every 10 days, water the plant.
This method will help orchids grow very quickly and healthy.
Soak the potted plant in water for 20 minutes.
then take it out.
I used 1 okra, which contains a lot of nutrients.
Helps orchids grow very quickly.
It positively affects the growth of leaves, branches and flowers.
Helps plants take root quickly and flower abundantly
Add 200ml of water and wait 30 minutes before using.
When orchids are purchased or have been grown for a long time without flowers.
You should repot the plant.
Remove all old planting material.
Then cut off all damaged roots.
The roots are damaged to the point that the leaves wilt.
After soaking for 30 minutes, okra gel will form.
Please use this water.
Cleans the leaves, helping to remove dirt.
and helps plants grow better when replanted.
Then add the onion peel water.
Then filter out the residue.
Mix with 2 liters of water.
Then soak the entire root in okra gel solution for about 30 minutes.
This helps new roots grow faster..
Then water this water at the base of the tree.
You should apply this method every 2 weeks
Use this water to spray on the leaves.
Helps prevent mealybugs, thrips, and spiders from sticking to orchid leaves.
Okra gel has adhesion and antibacterial and antiseptic properties.
Helps plants to be protected and healthier.
The tree will continuously develop new roots very quickly.
Roots help absorb nutrients fastest and best
Helps weak plants quickly recover and grow strongly again.
Now take it out and plant it in a pot.
I use pine bark as a substrate that has been sterilized to treat fungal diseases
I have created a lot of subtitles, you can view and choose the appropriate language.
After planting, water just enough to keep it moist.
Don't forget to like, share, subscribe to the channel and ring the bell so you don't miss any tips!.
Goodbye and see you again. Good luck!!!