welcome to my channel.
If you want orchids to bloom a lot.
Orchids always grow healthily.
So let's explore organic fertilizers with me in this video.
For safe composting today I used coffee grounds.
Take 50 grams of coffee grounds.
Next is fresh milk.
Take about 20ml of milk.
Next, we need fungal spores and Trichoderma - Bacillus bacteria. SP.
Take 1 spoon.
Add a little warm water.
Mix well and leave in a cool place for 3 days.
After 3 days.
Take 2 liters of water.
After 3 days, cells from fungi and bacteria Trichoderma and Bacillus. The product developed must be white in color.
Take 1 spoon about 20 grams.
Filter out residue.
First method.
I apply this fertilizer to the roots every 2 weeks.
Coffee grounds and milk contain many important nutrients such as nitrogen, potassium, phosphorus, calcium, and magnesium.
When used as fertilizer, it helps promote their growth and flowering.
Beneficial fungi and bacteria from trichoderma and Bacillus. SP after biomass will help protect roots from rot better.
Coffee grounds also have the ability to hold water, helping to maintain the necessary humidity for orchids.
Second method.
Clean the top and bottom of the leaves with this water.
Helps kill fungi, insects, and harmful bacteria very effectively.
If you apply this method 1-2 times a month, the leaves will always be green and disease-free.
Third method.
You can also spray this fertilizer on the entire orchid plant.
Like foliar fertilization for orchids.
Coffee grounds often have a slightly acidic pH, reducing the alkalinity of the soil.
This is beneficial for orchids because many orchids prefer soil environments with a slightly acidic pH.
Do not spray on flowers because wet flowers easily fall off.
Reault.
After 1 month the roots grew very strongly.
This helps the plant roots absorb the most nutrients through the roots.
Flower buds also develop faster.
Many flower stems grow on the same orchid.
Flowers bloom with more vibrant colors.
Flowers bloom for a long time.
Hope the video will help you a lot.
If you find it interesting, please share and like so more people know about this video.
Thank you for watching the video. Good luck and see you in the next videos.