Welcome to my channel.
These are orchids after the flowers have withered.
Once the flower stalk has bloomed, it will no longer be able to produce buds.
But at the tip of this withered flower branch, many flower buds can still continue to grow.
To help the orchid continue to bloom, I use 20 grams of beetroot.
I added about 20 grams of aloe vera leaves.
Puree in 400ml of water.
Filter out residue.
Pour the juice from beets and aloe vera leaves into cotton balls.
Clip on a withered flower branch.
Beets and aloe vera are rich sources of potassium, an important mineral that promotes plant health.
Natural potassium helps orchids develop buds and flowers very effectively.
I mixed the remaining beet juice and aloe vera with water to make 2 liters of liquid fertilizer.
Then water the orchid roots with this water once a week.
The presence of phosphorus in this fertilizer helps orchids grow strongly and have good flowering ability.
Then I use this water to clean the top and bottom of the leaves.
When the cotton is dry, spray moisturizer regularly.
and water the roots.
Change the cotton once a week.
1 MONTH LATER.
The tips of the withered flower branches have sprouted many new flower buds.
With this simple method, wilted orchids will grow many new healthy flower buds.
2 MONTH LATER.
This is the orchid I have applied in the newly shared way.
The wilted orchid has grown many beautiful flowers.
If you find the video meaningful, please support me by liking, sharing and subscribing to my channel
Good luck and see you in the next videos.