Hello everyone, to easily care for orchids to always grow healthily.
There are more flower buds and flowers stay on the branches longer.
Today I share a very easy way to keep orchids growing healthily.
When eating bananas, don't throw away the peel.
Because banana peels contain many nutrients, especially organic potassium.
Very good for the growth of buds, flowers and has anti-drought effects.
I cut the banana peel thinly and put it in a jar.
Next I took a piece of bread.
Bread contains phosphorus, which plays an important role in plant growth, especially stimulating root growth.
Adding 1 teaspoon of yeast helps decompose organic matter faster and prevents it from rotting.
And adding a spoonful of sugar helps nourish the growth of beneficial microorganisms.
Add 500ml warm water.
Then leave in a cool place for 3 weeks.
3 Weeks later.
Take 2 liters of water.
After 3 weeks of composting we have this wonderful fertilizer.
Take 50ml.
then mix into water.
Method 1: Fertilize the roots.
Water each orchid pot with this water 5-10 spoons per week.
This fertilizer provides potassium, an important mineral that improves plant health and vitality.
This type of fertilizer also helps retain water and enhances the plant's ability to absorb water.
Beneficial fungi Mycorrhiza will grow to help the plant more easily absorb nutrients from the orchid growing medium.
Method 2.
Use this water to spray on the leaves.
Helps supplement nutrients through leaves very effectively.
Helps orchid leaves become strong and healthy.
and sprayed on aerial roots to help aerial roots grow and easily absorb nutrients in the air.
You should do it early in the morning and by noon the leaves will dry very quickly.
Do this once a week to keep the orchid healthy.
Method 3:
Now I wash the leaves with this water.
Beneficial microorganisms will help kill mold and insects very effectively.
Do this every 2 weeks to protect your orchids.
Result
After fertilizing, orchids will always be green and healthy.
Potassium in banana peels and bread helps flower buds grow strongly.
When the flowers bloom, they will stay on the branches for a long time.
Flowers can last on branches for up to 6 months before fading.
Hopefully the video will help you a lot in taking better care of orchids at home.
Thank you for watching the video. Good luck and see you in the next videos!