Welcome to my channel.
To help you have many options in making your own organic fertilizer to care for orchids at home.
In this video, I continue to share the extremely effective method of making organic fertilizer to care for orchids at home.
If you are interested, Subscribe to the channel so you don't miss any tips on my channel.
First, to make this fertilizer, I use oats.
Soak 1 tablespoon of oats in warm water for 1 hour.
After 1 hour, puree the oats.
Filter out residue.
Next, take a spoonful of yogurt and mix it with water from the oatmeal.
Then add water to get 2 liters of liquid fertilizer.
METHOD 1.
Wipe the top and bottom of the leaves with this liquid fertilizer.
This method helps eliminate fungi and insects that harm orchids.
Also adds nutrition through leaves to orchids.
This method helps leaves photosynthesize and synthesize chlorophyll better.
Helps keep green leaves and healthy plants.
METHOD 2.
Spray this liquid fertilizer on the entire orchid plant 1-2 times a month.
Helps supplement nutrients through leaves and roots for orchids.
Oats are a source of many nutrients such as vitamins, minerals
and fiber that are very good for the growth of orchids.
METHOD 3.
Apply this liquid fertilizer to orchid roots 1-2 times a month.
Yogurt contains lactic acid which helps control soil pH,
Create good growing conditions for orchids to grow.
Yogurt provides calcium, phosphorus and other minerals that are very good for orchid growth.
This method helps provide nutrients directly through the roots so the orchid grows fastest.
RESULT.
After 2 months of fertilization, the orchid has developed many new roots.
This helps orchids absorb the most nutrients.
When provided with enough nutrition, the flowers will bloom more brilliantly.
The flowers stay on the branches for a long time before fading.
Many flowers grow on the same branch without falling off.
Hopefully the video will help you a lot in taking better care of orchids at home.
If you find it interesting, please click like and share so more people know this tip.
Thank you for watching the video. Good luck and see you in the next videos!