Welcome to my channel.
In this video, I share how to fertilize to help flower branches continue to revive and bloom after the flowers wither.
Please subscribe to the channel so you don't miss any orchid growing tips on my channel.
These are the branches after the flowers have faded.
I cut off all the dry branches.
Then sprinkle cinnamon powder on the cut to help the wound heal quickly.
Then leave it for 1 day without watering to let the cut heal completely.
Take 1 aloe vera leaf and cut it into thin slices.
Then I applied aloe vera gel to the spent flower stems.
This helps the flower branches recover very quickly.
I do it once a week.
and I continue to apply aloe vera gel to the leaves once a week.
This helps eliminate pathogens and wilted orchids recover very quickly.
I put sliced ​​aloe vera leaves in a jar and add 2 liters of boiled water.
Add 1 spoon of rice.
Then add 3 crushed egg shells.
Wait for the water to cool before you can use it.
After cooling, filter to remove residue.
Water this once a week.
Helps supplement nutrition and orchids recover very quickly.
Soak the orchid pot in this water for 20 minutes then take it out.
Spray this water once a week.
Helps supplement nutrients through the leaves so the leaves recover very quickly.
At the same time, it effectively destroys disease-causing fungi and bacteria.
After 20 minutes lift it out.
After 1 month.
From withered branches, many new flower buds have grown.
This method helps the sprouts grow very quickly.
After only 1 month, many buds have grown.
Continue watering this and spray this water once a week.
after the next 1 month.
Orchids bloom many beautiful flowers.
Even though the flower branches have withered, the newly bloomed flowers have very bright colors.
The flowers are very healthy and sturdy so they will hang on the branches for a long time before fading.
With this simple method we can care for orchids at home and bloom all year round.
If you find the video interesting, don't forget to like and share so more people know.
Thank you for watching the video. Good luck and see you in the next videos!.