Hello friends.
Nice to meet you on my channel.
You see here a withered orchid.
Maybe it's because you didn't water it.
or due to direct sunlight shining on the orchid.
If you want orchids to be nourished and grow quickly.
Please watch this video carefully.
Now I will share this amazing trick with you.
You need 1 aloe vera leaf.
This aloe vera gel is great for reviving orchids.
Now apply aloe vera gel on the top and bottom of the leaf.
Aloe vera gel has a very good moisturizing effect.
In addition, aloe vera also contains vitamins A, B, and C
and minerals such as nitrogen, phosphorus and potassium.
Do this every 5 days and leave the orchid pot in a cool place for 3 weeks.
Next, take 1 liter of warm water and put it in the bottle.
Then take 1 spoon of rice and soak it in this water for about 30 minutes.
Let the nutrients in the rice completely dissolve into the water.
Chop the remaining aloe vera leaves into small pieces.
Then puree with 300ml of water.
Filter out residue half past four Add 2 liters of water at room temperature.
After soaking for 30 minutes, filter this rice water.
Mix rice water with aloe vera juice.
So I ended up with about 3 liters of this wonderful liquid manure solution.
Cover the pot with moss to retain moisture better.
Now you use this solution to water the orchid every 5 days.
Soak the orchid pot in this water for 2 hours.
After soaking for 2 hours, remember to lift the orchid pot and place it in a cool place to let the orchid recover.
2 WEEKS LATER.
Fertilize after 2 weeks for fresher orchid leaves.
New roots develop very well.
Many new roots are growing.
New roots will help transport water and nutrients from the roots to the stem.
If the leaves are provided with enough water and nutrients from the roots,
The leaves will gradually become lush again.
1 MONTH LATER.
You see the leaves are very fresh.
and the orchid grows a new leaf.
after the next 2 months
The orchid has grown two branches (two buds).
But the leaves at the base have turned yellow so I will cut off these yellow leaves.
Instinctively, when an orchid buds, if the plant lacks nutrients,
the base leaves will turn yellow and fall off to provide nutrients for the buds to develop.
Now I need to supplement the orchid's nutrition by taking 3 spoons of rice.
Then soak in 2 liters of water at room temperature
and wait 30 minutes for the nutrients to completely dissolve in water before using.
30 Minutes Later
Add 3 tablespoons of milk
Rice water and milk are excellent sources of nutrients for orchids to grow
Now you water the orchid with this solution once a week to help the orchid recover quickly.
After the next 1 month.
After 3-4 times of applying liquid fertilizer from milk and rice water, the orchid had many roots.
When the roots grow, they will absorb enough water and nutrients
and the leaves will turn green again very quickly.
After the next 1 month.
The orchid grew more leaves and the withered leaves were completely recovered.
Roots grow very healthily.
The leaves have completely recovered so they are very sturdy and green.
Many buds develop.
The flowers have bright colors and hang on the branches for a long time before fading.
Hope the video will help you a lot.
Thank you for watching the video. Wish you luck and see you in the next videos.