Welcome to my channel.
To help you have many options when caring for orchids at home with organic fertilizer.
Helps develop new shoots. Flowers bloom profusely and last long.
In this video, I continue to share new methods.
First you need 2 liters of water.
Then take 1 spoon of yeast and mix it with water.
Then continue to mix 1 spoon of yogurt.
Then leave in a cool place for 1 week to ferment.
1 WEEK LATER.
Take 200ml.
then mixed with water to obtain 2 analyte analyses.
Method 1
Clean the top and bottom of the leaves with this solution.
The leaf surface will always be clean and the stomata will be clear.
Orchids will photosynthesize better.
If applied regularly, you will not encounter this problem.
Leaves will always be green.
Method 2
Spray this fertilizer on the entire orchid.
Minerals contained in ginger and fermented rice water will help stimulate rooting and shoot growth very well.
Do this once a month to supplement nutrition and increase the orchid's resistance.
METHOD 3
Now take this liquid fertilizer mixture and water it on the orchid roots.
Applying yogurt after fermentation helps supplement nutrients
amino acids are beneficial for the growth of orchids.
Especially helps stimulate germination and rooting extremely quickly.
ONE MONTH LATER.
Roots begin to sprout.
AFTER 2 MONTHS.
The roots grow very healthily, helping the orchid absorb the most nutrients.
AFTER THE NEXT 2 MONTHS.
Many buds develop.
New shoots are very strong and grow quickly.
AFTER THE NEXT 3 MONTHS.
bloom many flowers.
The flower color is more vibrant than usual.
The flowers stay on the branches for a long time before fading.
If you find this video meaningful, please share it so more people know about this video.
And don't forget to subscribe to the channel so you don't miss any tips on my channel.
Thank you for watching the video. Good luck and see you in the next videos.