Welcome to my channel.
To help you have many options when caring for orchids at home with organic fertilizer.
Aims to protect the environment but still help orchids grow strongly.
In this video, I continue to share new methods.
Subscribe to videos so you don't miss any Tips on my channel.
To make this compost I recycle chicken bones into fertilizer.
First, wash the chicken bones several times with water
Chicken bones are rich in potassium and calcium.
These are all very benign substances and have very good effects for the growth and development of orchids.
Using chicken bones as fertilizer will help you take care of orchids more effectively.
Wash the chicken bones and dry them crispy at low temperature.
After the chicken bones are dry and crispy, they will be ground into powder.
Take 1 tablespoon of chicken bone powder and put it in a jar.
Then soak with 2 liters of water.
Wait a day before using.
The remainder is stored for use in the next batch.
A DAY LATER.
Filter out residue.
FIRST METHOD.
Water this fertilizer solution on the orchid roots.
Chicken bones contain many minerals and organic substances that help provide nutrition for orchids.
It contains nitrogen, potassium and phosphorus which are important for orchid growth.
Potassium helps flower development and resists drought very well.
Phosphorus helps roots grow quickly. Nitrogen will help develop orchid stems and leaves.
NEXT METHOD
Spray this fertilizer on the entire orchid.
Spray the top and bottom of the leaves thoroughly
Spray seedlings to help them grow faster.
Spraying the roots will stimulate many branches.
RESULT
After 1-2 months of applying this fertilizer, many roots and branches grow.
Potassium in chicken bones helps prevent flower buds from wilting.
The flowers bloom more brightly than usual.
The flowers stay on the branches for a long time before fading.
Thank you for watching the video. Good luck
goodbye and see you again in the next videos.