Welcome to my channel.
This orchid has yellow leaf disease.
The cause is due to insects sucking tree sap and then being infected with fungi and bacteria through insect bites.
This disease leaves the leaves still succulent but falls off very quickly.
Only one healthy leaf remains. The rest are infected.
I cut here to check for disease inside the stem.
All infected leaves need to be removed.
Black spots are where the disease resides so they need to be removed.
then take 5 spoons of cement.
Mix 5 liters of water.
Then wait for the sediment to settle.
10 Minutes later.
Take only the clear water at the top.
Clean orchid branches with cement water.
Soak the orchid pot in cement water for 10 minutes
Soak the moss in cement water for 10 minutes.
Soak 10 eggshells in 2 liters of boiled water.
Wait for the water to cool.
In the meantime, I recycle plastic bottles into orchid nursery equipment.
Take 3 more Vitamin B1 tablets and mix them into eggshell water.
Soak the orchid branches in this water for 20 minutes.
20 minutes later.
Sprinkle cement powder on the cut.
Place the orchid branch in.
Pour some water into the plate.
Place in a cool place, avoid direct sunlight.
After 1 week, spray water every 5 days.
Water from eggshells and B1.
Pour some water into the bowl.
Leave in a cool place, after 1 week spray water every 5 days.
1 MONTH LATER.
Roots grow very strongly.
Now plant it in a pot so it can grow outside
Under the orchid tree, two more small orchids have grown.
Hope the video will help you a lot.
If you find the video meaningful, please share, like and subscribe to my support channel.
Thank you for watching the video. Good luck and see you in the next videos.