Welcome to my channel.
For orchids to grow well, the roots must be strong.
Because the roots are healthy, they can absorb more nutrients to feed the plant.
When Lan absorbs enough nutrients, the flower will bloom.
To do that, in this video I share a very easy fertilizer.
To make this fertilizer I will recycle potato peels as fertilizer.
Potato peels contain many important nutrients such as potassium, fosfor and many other minerals.
Recycled fertilizer from them helps provide these nutrients to plants, helping them grow strongly.
I used the peel of 1 potato.
and soak in 2 liters of boiled water.
Then incubate for a day so that the nutrients are completely dissolved in the water.
Next I used 3 cloves of garlic.
Garlic contains natural antibacterial compounds such as allicin,
Helps prevent the growth of bacteria and mold in soil and on orchids.
After cutting into small pieces, put them in a jar and soak with 2 liters of water.
Then leave for 1 day for the nutrients to completely dissolve in the water.
1 DAY LATER.
Filter out residue.
FIRST METHOD.
Apply this liquid fertilizer to the orchid roots.
Potato peels and garlic contain many important nutrients such as potassium,
fosfor and many other minerals.
Their recycled fertilizer helps provide these nutrients to orchids, helping them grow strongly.
Do this every 2-3 weeks to supplement nutrients and increase disease resistance for orchids.
SECOND METHOD.
Spray this fertilizer on the top and bottom of the leaves and roots of the orchid.
Garlic is known for its resistance to diseases and pests.
Using recycled fertilizer from garlic helps plants prevent and fight harmful diseases and pests.
Using recycled fertilizer from potato peels and garlic helps reduce the need to use chemicals for orchids,
because they provide essential nutrients for plants. This helps reduce negative impacts on the environment.
3. RESULT
After 2-3 times of fertilizing this way, the orchid will have many branched roots.
This helps the orchid easily absorb most nutrients through the roots.
By providing nutrients and improving soil structure, potato
and garlic fertilizers help increase the yield and quality of orchids.
Garlic and potatoes are rich in potassium, so they help orchids bloom more.
Hope it will help you a lot.
If you find it interesting, don't forget to like, share and subscribe to help the channel reach 1,000,000 subscribers soon.
Thank you for watching the video. Good luck and see you in the next videos!