Welcome to my Happiness Garden channel.
If you grow many orchids, it is inevitable that the orchids will rot due to bacteria or fungi.
My orchid has leaf rot and stem rot.
When we encounter an orchid like this, we need to cut off all rotten leaves, roots, and stems.
If you haven't subscribed to the channel yet, please click the subscribe button to support me
and not miss any orchid growing tips! It's great to have company!
In addition to the English dub, we've now created dubs in French, German, Italian, Spanish, Portuguese,
Japanese, Hindi, and Indonesian to help you hear and understand the content. Videos are easier.
Please comment to me which country you are watching the video from!
It's great that we can chat together from all over the world!
To restore this orchid, I use 2 okra pods.
Soak in 1/2 US gallon of water (about 2 liters).
Wait 30 minutes for the gel and nutrients from the okra to dissolve into the water.
Next take 1 teaspoon of cinnamon powder.
Soak in 1/2 US gallon of boiling water (about 2 liters) for 30 minutes.
AFTER 30 MINUTES.
Filter out residue.
Wipe the orchid with cinnamon water. This helps eliminate fungal diseases and harmful insects.
Then incubate the roots with cinnamon water for about 20 minutes to help disinfect
and stimulate roots to grow and germinate.
Soak the moss in cinnamon water for 20 minutes. Helps eliminate fungi and bacteria in moss.
Soak orchid stems in okra gel for 20 minutes.
Water okra gel into old orchid roots.
This helps stimulate better germination and rooting.
Adding moss helps retain moisture better.
Spray moisturizer with water once a week
Place in a cool, well-lit place.
I reused a plastic container and cut a drainage hole in the bottom.
Place the orchid branch in then spray it with water to keep it moist once a week.
Place in a cool, well-lit place.
6 weeks later.
You can see that the orchid has taken root and is very healthy.
With this simple method, you can easily restore an orchid without roots.
Because the roots are strong, I planted them in pots to help the plants grow quickly.
The old root below has also revived new orchid sprouts.
Hope the video will help you a lot.
Wishing you success and happiness in life. Goodbye and see you again in the next videos.