Welcome to my channel.
In this video, I share a new type of organic fertilizer for orchids.
It seems like every house has one but few people know about it
Very convenient and very good for the growth of orchids.
When the flower stalks wither, you need to cut them all off.
and cut off damaged branches and leaves.
If the position of the orchid pot is not suitable, the orchid will not bloom.
Place them in a sunny spot.
Without sunlight, flowers will not bloom.
But if the sun is too harsh, the orchid will easily go into shock and die.
This is chrysanthemum tea.
It is not only good for human health but also very good for the growth of orchids.
Use 1 bag of chrysanthemum tea (or 5 bags of used chrysanthemum tea grounds).
Soak in boiled water for 3 minutes.
Take 1 teaspoon of honey.
Take 1 liter of water.
Then mix chamomile tea and honey into the water.
So you have a special fertilizer.
FIRST METHOD.
Wipe the top and bottom of the leaves with honey chamomile tea.
Honey has antiseptic properties that help kill fungi and insects very effectively.
Honey and chrysanthemums contain many nutrients that are very good and safe for orchids to grow.
SECOND METHOD
Apply this liquid fertilizer to the orchid roots 1-2 times a month.
This type of fertilizer helps orchids increase resistance to pests.
because it provides essential nutrients such as nitrogen, phosphorus, potassium, sugar, vitamins...
This type of fertilizer also creates conditions for beneficial microorganisms to grow, helping to protect orchids very well.
THIRD METHOD.
You can also spray this fertilizer on the entire orchid.
Helps supplement nutrients through leaves very effectively.
This method is also performed 1-2 times/month.
RESULT
After 2-3 times of applying this fertilizer, you will see good green orchids.
Many roots and branches grow.
Flowers bloom brightly and stay fresh for a long time.
The whole garden blooms but does not cause the orchid to lose its strength.
Flowers bloom for a long time before fading.
Thank you for watching the video. Good luck and see you in the next videos.