Welcome to my channel.
This is a wilted orchid.
If you also love orchids, please join me in reviving it.
First, subscribe to the channel so you don't miss any videos.
First take an aloe vera leaf.
Aloe vera gel is very good in restoring wilted and stunted orchids.
Apply this aloe vera gel on the top and bottom of the leaves every 5 days.
Aloe vera gel contains many vitamins, minerals, and amino acids
and enzymes stimulate the growth, development and flowering of orchids.
Next I use rice, because it contains a lot of B vitamins, especially vitamin B1 and minerals that are very good for orchid growth.
Roast 100 grams of rice until crispy.
Wait for the rice to cool completely.
Once cooled, grind into powder.
Take 1 spoon of roasted rice flour mixed with 2 liters of water.
Then water the orchid roots with this rice water every 5 days.
Rice water prevents shock, helps orchids adapt to new environments faster,
Especially when newly planted trees, or orchids are stunted or withered in the environment.
Soaking the orchid pot in rice flour water for about 30 minutes will stimulate the roots to develop better.
Spray mist every day to moisturize with water.
2 WEEKS LATER.
The leaves become stiffer and the roots grow more branches.
A developed root system will help the orchid absorb nutrients and water, helping the plant recover quickly
Continue watering rice flour every 5 days.
and continue to apply aloe vera gel to the top and bottom of the leaves every 5 days.
After the next 3 months.
The leaves are very strong and healthy.
I continue to water with rice flour water.
and continue to apply aloe vera gel to this orchid every 5 days.
After the next 3 months.
The orchid has completely recovered.
The leaves are sturdy and have 2 more flower stems.
Hope the video will help you a lot.
If you find it interesting, please click like and share so more people know.
Thank you for watching the video. Good luck and see you in the next videos.