Welcome to my channel.
In this video, I share how to make fertilizer to help flower branches continue to revive and bloom after they wither.
Subscribe to the channel so you don't miss any orchid growing tips on my channel.
These are the branches after the flowers have faded.
I cut off all the dead flowers and dry branches.
When eating bananas, don't throw away the banana peel.
I take 1-2 banana peels and cut them into thin slices.
Or you can also use 1-2 dried banana peels.
Then take 2-3 eggshells and crumble them.
Then take 2 liters of water and boil it.
Add 3 spoons of rice to this boiling water.
Then add eggshells and banana peels to soak together.
Incubate until the water cools.
2 HOURS LATER.
Filter the residue after the water cools.
Add 2 liters of water.
Now I use this water to water orchid roots.
This will help stimulate root and flower growth.
Do it once a week.
Soak in this water for about 30 minutes at a time so that the roots can absorb many substances.
Now I spray the orchids with this water once a week.
Helps supplement nutrients through leaves and increase resistance.
This should be done early in the morning, so that by noon the leaves will dry naturally and are less likely to rot.
And spray these branches once a week to help stimulate bud production.
After soaking for 30 minutes, take it out.
1 Month Later.
From withered branches, many new flower buds have grown.
I continue to water this once a week.
And spray the leaves with this water once a week.
AFTER NEXT 1 MONTH.
Orchids bloom many beautiful flowers.
With this simple method we can care for orchids at home and bloom all year round.
If you find the video interesting, don't forget to like and share so more people know.
Thank you for watching the video. Good luck and see you in the next videos!.