Welcome to my channel.
When orchids have enough nutrients and a good soil environment
The plant will grow strongly and flower more.
helps create the best conditions for flowers to grow,
At the same time, it helps orchids bloom more beautifully,
Both the roots and flowers are unimaginably large.
The first method I will share with you is how to make fertilizer from activated carbon.
It is made from naturally dried firewood.
I use about 20 grams of activated carbon like this.
Then puree with 2 liters of water.
Filter to get clear water.
Add water to make 5 liters of solution.
FIRST METHOD.
I use this water to wash the leaves.
The orchid will be protected from fungi and insects.
The calcium content in activated carbon helps make leaves strong.
Do this regularly every 2 weeks and you will see healthy orchids
SECOND METHOD.
You can also use this water to spray the entire orchid plant.
Helps kill fungi and insects on leaves very well.
and it also provides some nutrients through the leaves.
THIRD METHOD.
Now use this water to water the orchid roots.
Do this periodically every 2 weeks for normal orchids.
Helps prevent diseases and improve pH in growing media.
Activated carbon also contains high levels of calcium and natural minerals that are very good for orchids.
Helps stimulate rooting.
Soaking in this water for about 30 minutes is better.
RESULT.
The roots are very strong.
If the planting medium has good drainage, the orchid will never have root rot.
After about 1-2 months, depending on the orchid variety, many branch roots will grow.
Helps orchids absorb nutrients best.
The flowers will be brighter and stronger.
Many flower buds grow on the same tree.
The leaves are very strong and sturdy.
Surely you will be surprised with this type of fertilizer.
Now I continue to share how to make the second type of fertilizer.
To help you have many choices when caring for orchids at home with organic fertilizer.
Subscribe to the video so you don't miss any tips on my channel.
To make this fertilizer you need ash.
Take 1 teaspoon of ash and soak it in 1 liter of warm water for 2 hours.
Next, take 2 liters of water and put it in the jar.
and take 15ml of milk.
Then mix the milk into the water.
FIRST METHOD.
Clean the leaf surface with this water
The leaf surface will always be clean and the stomata will be clear.
Orchids will photosynthesize better.
SECOND METHOD.
Filter to get clear water.
Mix the two together.
Now you take this liquid fertilizer mixture and apply it to the orchid roots..
Milk-based fertilizer provides natural calcium which is very good for orchids.
Ash contains nitrogen in compound form.
In addition, ash also contains many other chemical elements that are very good for orchids such as:
potassium, magnesium, iron, calcium, phosphorus, boron, sulfur...
Using ash can replace phosphate and potassium fertilizers.
Do this 1-2 times/month to supplement nutrition and increase the orchid's resistance.
THIRD METHOD
Spray this fertilizer on the entire orchid.
This method is similar to using foliar fertilizer.
The potassium in ash is very rich, which will help orchids resist drought and develop flowers very well.
Do this 1-2 times/month to supplement nutrition and increase the orchid's resistance.
RESULT.
After 1 month of fertilization, the orchid has developed many branch roots.
This helps the orchid absorb the most nutrients to feed the plant.
This type of fertilizer also stimulates the growth and development of sprouts very well.
The nutrition of this synthetic fertilizer helps leaves stay green.
Potassium in ash helps orchids develop many flower buds.
The flowers bloom more brightly than usual.
The flowers stay on the branches for a long time, it can take up to 6 months to fade.
Thank you for watching the video. Good luck and see you in the next videos.