Welcome everyone to my Happiness Garden channel!
You see this is an orchid rotten by the bacteria that causes orchid rot.
With orchid branches like this, people often throw them away.
But don't throw it away, let me guide you to revive it quickly.
First, cut off all the rotten areas.
Next, take 1 teaspoon of cloves.
And add 1 clove of garlic.
Add 300ml of water.
Then puree.
Filter out residue.
Add 2 liters of water.
Wipe orchid branches with this garlic and clove solution.
This helps eliminate harmful fungi and stimulates growth.
Then soak the stem in this solution for 30 minutes.
While waiting, I used this solution to water other orchids..
This helps prevent harmful fungi and stimulates growth for orchids.
Helps orchids increase resistance and grow healthily.
30 MINUTES LATER.
Blot dry.
Use cinnamon powder to sprinkle on the cut.
Helps cuts heal quickly and protects orchids from rotting.
Next I used cotton to make rope.
Then wrap this string around the orchid stem.
Then I put the orchid branches in a glass jar.
then pour water into the bottle.
Water will penetrate the cotton fibers to help the orchid stem always have moderate moisture.
Then cover the top with a clear plastic bottle like a miniature greenhouse.
and place it in a cool, well-lit place to wait for the orchid to revive.
ONE MONTH LATER.
The orchid has grown many roots.
With this simple method, you can easily revive weak orchids.
Cotton fibers always absorb water to create appropriate humidity, so orchids develop roots very quickly.
Now I plant it in a pot so the orchid can grow in an outside environment.
Below I use a medium made of terracotta beads and aquaponic plastic beads to help with good drainage.
Spread a layer of dry moss on top to keep it moist.
Then you water it to keep it moist and leave it in a cool place with enough light for the orchid to grow.
Thank you for watching the video. Good luck and see you in the next videos.