Welcome to my channel.
Today I picked up a rotten orchid that someone threw away.
The roots have mostly rotted, so all damaged roots need to be removed.
Only one root remains that has not rotted.
Then rinse with water.
Turmeric starch 1 spoon.
Add 2 liters of water.
Vitamin B1 one tablet.
Soak for 10 minutes
Soak the moss for 30 minutes.
Soak pine bark for 30 minutes.
10 MINUTES LATER.
Dry the cut.
Apply toothpaste to the cut.
Wait for the toothpaste to dry.
Recycle plastic boxes into orchid nursery tools.
Styrofoam.
30 MINUTES LATER.
Place the orchid branch in the nursery pot.
Pour water into the orchid pot.
The water level only reached the base of the pine bark.
Then spray vitamin B1 water once every 7 days (Recipe at the end of the video).
Place in a cool, well-lit place.
3 WEEKS LATER.
The dry orchid branch has sprouted and taken root.
Take 1 vitamin B1 tablet and mix it with 300ml of water.
Then spray vitamin B1 on the orchid every 7 days.
2 MONTHS LATER.
The orchid branch has grown strong and strong.
Roots grow very healthily.
From now on, I add fertilizer to the small orchids to help them grow quickly.
and does not require shielding like a greenhouse, allowing orchids to grow in the outside environment.
Thank you for watching the video. Good luck and see you in the next videos..