Welcome to my channel.
This video is a useful source of information for beginners growing orchids
or having difficulty getting the orchid to bloom.
The curriculum provides the basics of how to care for orchids, including:
Light, temperature, humidity and fertilizer help orchids bloom year-round.
If you are interested in taking care of orchids, watch the video to learn more knowledge and skills.
1. Light
Orchids need enough light to grow.
Make sure they get enough sunlight or good artificial light.
You can place the orchid pot on the windowsill or under a specialized sun filter for orchids.
If left in direct sunlight, orchids can easily die.
2. Water and humidity.
Water appropriately.
Orchids usually need steady humidity, but don't keep the soil wet all the time.
Every month you water and soak the orchid pot in water once.
This helps retain moisture and wash away excess humus and fertilizer in the orchid growing medium.
On weekdays, when you see the substrate is dry, spray mist to keep the orchid pot moist.
3. Orchid planting materials.
Use the appropriate type of orchid growing medium,
Usually the material contains organic matter and has good drainage ability.
I often use pine bark or pumice as the growing medium for orchids.
When planting orchids, do not bury the stems deeply under the orchid growing medium.
4. Wind is very important.
Orchids need wind, but if the wind is strong, the orchid roots will shake, causing the orchid to wilt.
5. Which fertilizer is good for orchids?
There are many types of fertilizer, but in this video I share a common type of fertilizer
Rice 5 spoons.
Soak rice in water for 30 minutes.
30 MINUTES LATER
Filter residue.
Add water to get 5 liters of liquid fertilizer solution.
Method 1: Fertilize through orchid roots.
Water orchids with rice water 1-2 times/month
Rice water contains minerals and trace elements that are beneficial to plants,
Helps provide necessary nutrition.
Rice water helps orchids develop a stronger immune system,
Helps fight diseases and pests.
Method 2: Fertilize through leaves.
You can also spray rice water on the orchid 2-3 times a month.
This method is similar to using foliar fertilizer.
Rice water helps stimulate the flowering process and flower more regularly.
RESULT.
Orchids always grow well and are green.
and free from insects and fungal diseases.
Healthy orchids will develop many buds on the same plant.
The flowers hang on the branches for a long time before falling.
and bloom continuously from season to season.
Hope the video will help you a lot.
If you find the video meaningful, please like, share and subscribe to my support channel.
Good luck and see you in the next video.