Welcome to my channel.
In this video, I continue to share how to care for orchids at home to keep them healthy and blooming.
Next, I share a new way to make organic fertilizer so you have more choices.
Subscribe to the channel so you don't miss any orchid care tips on my channel.
This orchid has disease on its leaves.
And if you don't know how to take care of it, it will be stunted and not bloom.
We remove yellow leaves and dry branches and dry roots.
When eating tangerines, don't throw away the peel.
because tangerine peel contains many essential substances for orchids.
And garlic also has many essential substances to care for orchids.
I took 1 clove of garlic and 1 tangerine peel.
Add 1 liter of water.
then puree.
then filter out the residue.
Mix 1 liter of water.
Step 1
Wash the leaves with this water once a month.
Tangerine peel and garlic contain essential oils that have natural antibacterial and anti-pest properties.
Using tangerine peel and garlic will help reduce the risk of disease for orchids.
If you apply this method regularly, the orchid will not be harmed by pests and diseases,
so the leaves will always be green and healthy.
Step 2
Water the orchid roots with this water once a week
Tangerine peel and garlic contain minerals and nutrients that are very good for orchid growth.
Tangerine peel also provides trace elements and other nutrients for orchids.
Garlic contains nitrogen, an important nutrient that promotes leaf growth.
Garlic also provides potassium, an important nutrient that helps roots and orchids resist the effects of stress.
Soak in this water for 10 minutes then take out the orchid pot.
Step 3
Now spray this water on the leaves once a week.
Nitrogen in garlic plays an important role in the synthesis of protein
and chlorophyll, helping orchids maintain their green color.
This water helps protect orchids from plant health problems.
Result.
After applying this fertilizer for 3 months, the orchids grew healthily.
Roots, stems, and leaves all develop well.
After 5 months the orchid will bloom.
The flower colors are vibrant and stay on the branches for a long time before fading.
Hope the video helps you a lot.
If you find it interesting, please share it so more people know this trick.
Thank you for watching the video. Good luck and see you in the next videos.