Hello everyone, to easily care for orchids to always grow healthily.
There are many flower buds, the flowers stay on the branches longer.
Today I share a very easy way to make orchids always grow healthily.
lush green and flowers will bloom all year round.
Water it once a week.
and leave for 10 minutes.
to help the roots turn green.
then take it out.
I use a small teaspoon of cinnamon powder mixed into 1 liter of boiled water.
Cinnamon powder is very good, helping orchids grow very quickly.
Wait for this water to cool.
After the water cools, will filter this water.
And I use 1 tablespoon of flour, which contains a lot of nutrients.
Add 1 liter of water.
The nutrients in wheat flour also help plants grow very quickly.
and mix with cinnamon water.
will create a great organic nutrient for orchids.
And water immediately at the base of the tree.
You should fertilize orchids every 2 weeks.
Use this water to spray on the leaves.
Helps prevent insects such as thrips and mealybugs.
You should do it early in the morning and by noon the leaves will dry very quickly.
Leave it like that for 20 minutes.
Wheat always contains many organic nutrients.
Helps orchids grow healthily.
This type of water also helps a lot for weak, underdeveloped plants.
If the orchid has been planted for many years and still hasn't bloomed, repot it.
Cut off damaged roots.
use this water wipe the leaves.
Helps leaves recover from fungus.
Cinnamon powder has antibacterial and antiseptic properties and wheat contains a lot of minerals.
and essential vitamins, helping plants recover very quickly.
Adding this amount of water helps new roots grow quickly.
Soak in this water for 20 minutes.
Then take it out.
Place the plant in a bright place.
Helps plants photosynthesize, create chlorophyll, keep leaves green and roots strong.
and the flowers will bloom more beautifully.
Hope it will always help you a lot.
Don't forget to like, share, subscribe to the channel and ring the bell for easy viewing.
Thank you for watching the video. Good luck and see you in the next videos.
.