Welcome to my channel.
To help you have many options when caring for orchids at home with organic fertilizer.
Helps roots grow and bloom with many, long-lasting flowers..
In this video, I continue to share new methods.
First, please help me by subscribing to the channel, liking and sharing so more people know.
To make this organic fertilizer, I first used corn.
This germination will be better.
Using about 10 grams is enough.
Then soak in 1 liter of hot water and wait to cool.
AFTER 3 HOURS.
After cooling, puree and filter to remove residue.
Add 4 liters of water.
Next I used about 50ml of GE ginger.
Method 1: Apply to the roots.
GE fertilizer from ginger and corn water helps supplement nutrients
and amino acids that are beneficial for orchid growth.
Especially helps stimulate roots and flower buds very well.
Corn is a rich source of natural Nitrogen.
Nitrogen helps orchids develop strong leaves and produce good young plants.
Soaking the orchid for 30 minutes and then lifting the orchid pot will be very good.
Method 2: spray on leaves and roots.
Spraying on the top and bottom of leaves helps supplement nutrients through the leaves.
Spraying on the roots will help stimulate root growth and the amino acids in GE ginger also protect the roots from rot.
Method 3: You can water the soil for flowers planted on the ground.
This fertilizer is also very good for flower plants grown in soil such as chrysanthemums, roses, sunflowers...
RUSULT.
After 1 month of applying this fertilizer, the orchid has grown many new roots.
This helps orchids absorb the most nutrients.
The flower color is more vibrant than usual.
bloom many flowers.
The flowers stay on the branches for a long time before fading.
My chrysanthemums and sunflowers also bloomed profusely.
The flower colors are also more vibrant than usual.
Thank you for watching the video. Good luck and see you in the next videos.