welcome to my channel.
Caring for orchids with organic fertilizer is always my choice.
because it is very good and reduces environmental pollution from chemical fertilizers.
If you want the same then subscribe to my channel so you don't miss any tips!
In this video, I will show you how to make organic fertilizer from tofu residue.
I mixed 100 grams of tofu residue in 2 liters of warm water.
Next add 3 spoons of sugar.
And you add 3 tablespoons of microorganisms used to compost livestock manure.
Now I recycle plastic bottles to make this fertilizer.
Use cotton to cover this hole so insects don't get into the bottle.
Then apply the tape and be careful not to completely seal it.
This will prevent the jar from exploding when the solution ferments.
Pour into bottle.
Note to leave space like this.
Then store in a cool place for 1 month
1 MONTH LATER
After incubation for 1 month, take 3 spoons of this liquid fertilizer solution.
Then mix with 5 liters of water.
FIRST METHOD.
Wipe the top and bottom of the leaves with this solution.
This method helps kill harmful insects and fungi on leaves very effectively.
The leaf surface will always be clean.
Regularly performing this method will help keep the leaves clean and the orchid will photosynthesize better.
The leaves will be strong and healthy.
SECOND METHOD
Now take this liquid fertilizer mixture and water it on the orchid roots.
Fertilizer from fermented tofu residue helps supplement nutrients and amino acids that are beneficial for orchid growth.
Especially helps stimulate germination and rooting extremely quickly.
The beneficial microorganisms in this fertilizer will effectively protect orchid roots from rotting.
THIRD METHOD.
Spray this fertilizer on the entire orchid.
This method is similar to using foliar fertilizer.
The nutrients and amino acids in this fertilizer stimulate orchids to develop comprehensively from roots,
stems, leaves and flowers very effectively.
Do all 3 of these methods once a month to supplement nutrition and increase the orchid's resistance.
RESULT.
After a month of fertilizing, the orchid has developed many branch roots.
Many buds develop.
The flower color is more vibrant than usual.
Thank you for watching the video. Good luck and see you in the next videos.