Welcome to my channel.
Today I share a solution to help orchids that have not yet bloomed.
Can bloom many times a year
Subscribe to the channel so you don't miss any orchid care tips on my channel.
When the last flower fades, the flower stem is still fresh.
I cut off all the wilted flowers.
This stimulates them to grow new flowers.
Buds will continue to grow in this location.
First I took 1 tablespoon of dry yeast.
Mix with 1 liter of warm water.
Then I took a piece of bread and soaked it in yeast.
This helps beneficial microorganisms grow faster.
Cover and leave overnight.
After 1 night.
Filter out residue.
Add water to make 5 liters of solution.
First method.
Apply this liquid fertilizer to the roots 1-2 times a month.
The growth of beneficial microorganisms will invade harmful fungi in the orchid pot.
This helps protect orchid roots from rotting.
At the same time, the nutrients contained in this fertilizer are also very good for the growth of flowers and leaves.
Because this type of fertilizer contains a lot of natural potassium and nitrogen.
Orchids are very easy to absorb and grow.
Second method.
You can also use this fertilizer to spray the entire orchid plant.
This method is similar to foliar fertilization for orchids.
Beneficial microorganisms also grow and protect orchids from fungal diseases.
Do not spray on flowers.
Because when wet, flowers will easily fall off.
Result.
After using this fertilizer for 2 months, the leaves become stronger than usual.
From the flower branches that have bloomed, suddenly more flower buds appear at the tips of the branches.
This helps orchids bloom again and again many times a year.
And so my garden always has orchids blooming all year round.
If you find the video interesting, please like and share so more people know this orchid care tip.
Thank you for watching the video. Good luck and see you in the next videos.