Welcome to my channel.
To help orchids grow quickly in this video, I share how to help sick orchids recover quickly
and shoot many baby orchids at the same time.
Helps orchids shoot many plants at the same time in the same pot.
and blooms a lot of flowers.
An orchid has rot disease.
The cause of the disease is fungi and bacteria that cause leaf rot.
If rot is not treated promptly, it will spread and cause the orchid to die.
I need to check the roots.
Then cut off all damaged roots.
Then rinse with water.
Take 2 liters of water.
Add 5 vitamin B1 tablets.
Vitamin B1 helps stimulate rooting and germination very quickly.
Take 1 aloe vera leaf and cut it into thin slices.
Soak aloe vera in Vitamin B1 water.
and wait 10 minutes for the nutrients to completely dissolve in the water.
Then filter this water.
Soak the orchid branches in this water for 20 minutes.
Helps stimulate the growth of roots and sprouts very quickly.
Using a pine bark growing medium helps maintain moisture and proper drainage.
Add moss on top.
Take a cotton ball and soak it in this water.
Then incubate the orchid roots.
Incubate for a day then take out. This helps stimulate rapid root and sprout growth.
From now on spray this water on the leaves once a week.
and water the roots with this water once a week.
Place in a cool, well-lit place for 1 day.
After 1 day, remove the cotton from the orchid roots.
Take the transparent plastic box and snap it up.
and place it in a cool, well-lit place.
Spray aloe vera water and B1 once a week.
Water aloe vera and B1 once a week.
1 MONTH LATER.
The orchid has grown two sprouts on both sides.
Continue spraying aloe vera water and B1 once a week.
and Continue watering aloe vera and B1 once a week
AFTER NEXT 1 MONTH.
The 2 shoots are growing healthily but have not yet taken root.
Continue watering aloe vera and B1 once a week.
And continue to spray aloe vera water and B1 once a week.
After the next 2 months.
The orchid has developed healthy roots, stems, and leaves.
and has developed more buds (flower branches)
Thank you for watching the video. Good luck and see you in the next videos!