Welcome to my channel.
In this video, I continue to share a new way to help flower branches continue to revive and bloom after blooming.
If you find it interesting, please support me by subscribing to the channel and clicking like
and sharing so that more people know about this orchid growing tip.
These are the branches after the flowers have faded.
But these buttons can continue to bloom if you know how to care for them.
I cut off all the wilted flowers.
and cut off diseased leaves so they don't spread further.
and cut off all damaged roots.
Then sprinkle cinnamon powder on the cut to help it dry quickly and prevent disease.
Then leave it for 1 day without watering until the cut dries.
1 Day Later.
Take 2 liters of water.
Take 1 tablespoon of rice.
then take 3 teaspoons of soybeans.
Pour in 1 liter of boiled water.
Wait for the water to cool before using.
1 Hour Later.
Decant this rice water.
Mix the water to soak the soybeans with the rice water.
Then take these seeds and sprinkle them into each pot of 10-20 seeds.
and buried deep under tree roots.
Now I use this water to water orchid roots once a week.
Rice water contains many nutrients, including potassium, phosphorus
and several minerals that are beneficial for plant growth.
Soybeans contain a lot of nitrogen, an important element for plant growth.
especially during the stage of bean blooming and leaf development.
And I continue to spray this water on the leaves once a week.
Soybeans also provide protein and amino acids to help plants grow strongly.
and spray on branches to stimulate bud growth.
1 Month Later.
Old orchid branches continue to grow new shoots.
This helps blooming orchids continue to bud and bloom.
After that I continued to water the orchid with rice water once a week.
and I continue to spray the orchids with rice water once a week.
Spraying on branches also helps provide more nutrients so flower buds develop better.
AFTER NEXT 1 MONT.
Flowers continue to bloom many magical flowers.
Hope the video helps you a lot.
Thank you for watching the video. Good luck and see you in the next videos.