Hello everyone, today I share how to recover.
Orchids only have one leaf left, the plant will develop a healthy root system.
with a very simple method.
If an orchid has yellow leaves.
The tree has rotted.
Cut off all damaged roots.
The entire tree's roots are damaged and rotten.
But the leaf above is still very good, don't throw it away.
Rinse with water.
Then you use 1 clove of garlic.
Then puree with 500ml of water.
Filter out residue.
You will wipe to disinfect the leaves
.
This method will help orchids
recover faster,
The leaves will not be susceptible to fungus and rot during the recovery process.
Then you soak the base of the plant for 20 minutes, this will help new roots grow very quickly.
With the excess garlic water, I water the other orchids in the morning.
this will help new roots grow very quickly.
20 Minutes Later.
Wait 1 day for the cut to dry.
1 Day Later.
Pour water into the box.
Then you plant the orchid branches in this box
Note: The water level only reaches the orchid stem.
Place in a cool, well-lit place.
Spray moisturizer every 3-5 days and change the water once.
Place in miniature greenhouse.
1 Month Later.
As a result, after 1 month the roots began to grow very healthy.
With this simple method, the roots will grow very quickly
and healthy.
With this simple method, we can easily restore healthy roots to orchids.
Now you can completely rest assured to replant the tree.
Helps plants grow better in the outside environment.
Don't forget to like, share, subscribe to the channel and ring the bell for easy viewing.
Goodbye and see you again. Good luck.