Welcome to my channel.
In this video, I share how to make orchids bloom at the same time with many flower branches.
Conditions for orchids to bloom require 3 to 5 pairs of leaves or more and healthy roots.
Only a healthy root system can absorb enough nutrients so the orchid can bloom many flowers at the same time.
First you need a small ginger root.
Wash.
then slice thinly.
Then soak in 500ml of hot water and wait for it to cool before using.
Then take 3 more spoons of rice.
Add 1 liter of water.
Then filter this rice water.
Mix the two types together.
Clean the leaves with this water.
Helps eliminate fungi and bacteria to help orchids grow better.
Dip a cotton ball in this water.
Then place it between two leaves, where the flower stem can grow..
Then use this water to water the orchid roots.
This will help stimulate root growth and flower stem growth..
Do it once a week.
Soak in this water for about 30 minutes each time so that the roots can absorb many substances.
then take it out.
Change the cotton once a week.
And you only need to do it 3 times.
On weekdays, you just need to spray mist to moisturize with water.
2 Months Later.
You see my orchid has grown many flower branches at the same time.
New roots also grow and old roots become stronger.
With this simple method,
we can completely stimulate orchids to produce many flower branches at the same time.
To do this, you need to pay attention to choosing healthy orchids with many pairs of leaves to fertilize..
Only then will the orchid have enough nutrients to grow many flower branches at the same time.
Thank you for watching the video. Don't forget to like, share and subscribe to the channel to easily follow orchid growing tips.
Wish you luck and see you in the next videos.