Welcome to my channel.
I just picked up a rotten orchid because people threw it away.
The top part of the orchid has rotted.
I need to remove all the rotten spots.
Throw away the old moss.
Cut off damaged roots.
The flowers have all fallen off but the branches are still fresh.
Next I took 3 spoons of cinnamon powder.
Then soak in 2 liters of boiled water.
Incubate until the water cools.
After the water cools, filter to remove sediment.
Add 4 liters of water.
Water and soak the orchid pot in this solution for 30 minutes
Cinnamon juice has antibacterial and antiseptic properties that help kill fungi and harmful insects.
and protect the orchid from further rot.
Dry the leaves.
Then leave it for 1 week without watering.
A WEEK LATER
Adding new moss helps retain moisture better.
Take 1 spoon of rice flour.
and 1/2 teaspoon yeast.
Soak in 2 liters of warm water for 2 hours.
Rice water combined with yeast will form amino acids that are very good for orchid growth.
AFTER 2 HOURS.
Filter residue.
Apply this fermented rice fertilizer to orchid roots.
This liquid fertilizer stimulates the growth of shoots and roots very quickly.
Pour into the jar about 2 liters of water.
Next I took about 20 grams of aloe vera leaves.
Aloe vera gel moisturizes and stimulates plant growth very well
Then squeeze aloe vera gel into a basin of water.
Then place the orchid pot on top.
Note that the water only reaches the bottom edge of the orchid pot.
Then change the aloe vera gel water once a week.
TWO MONTHS LATER.
Orchids develop more roots and branches.
revive another seedling.
These branches are still blooming very healthily.
Hope the video will help you a lot.
Thank you for watching the video. Wish you luck and see you in the next videos.