Welcome to my channel.
You see that this orchid has rotted and only has 1 leaf left.
The tree is very weak, the leaves are even damaged by worms.
The roots have been damaged by rot.
Therefore, it is necessary to remove all rotten stains.
Then rinse with water.
Dry wipe.
Then take 1 teaspoon of green tea.
Pour in 1 liter of boiled water.
Wait until the water cools.
Then take 3 spoons of rice.
Pour in 1 liter of water at room temperature.
and soak for 1 hour so that the flower nutrients are completely dissolved in the water.
1 Hour Later.
Filter out residue.
Clean the orchid branches with green tea.
Helps eliminate pests and diseases of orchids.
Take dry moss and put it in a jar.
Pour in green tea and steep for 30 minutes.
Soaking orchid branches for 30 minutes helps the plant quickly germinate and take root
Then take the moss out and press it tightly into the basket.
Pour water into the jar.
Control the water level in this position so that the moss always maintains appropriate humidity.
Then create a hole and plant the orchid in.
From now on, spray this rice water on the orchid branches once a week.
Cover with a transparent glass jar.
Place on the windowsill or under a sun filter for orchids.
3 Weeks Later.
The orchid has taken root.
The roots are very strong so the tree will revive very quickly.
Now I plant and do not cover, but let the orchids grow in the outside environment.
Thank you for watching the video. Wish you luck and see you in the next videos.