Welcome to my Happiness Garden channel.
Orchids rot and people throw them away.
If the orchid is rotten but the leaves are still fresh, we can still revive it so it can grow strongly.
This orchid has completely rotten roots.
The leaves appear to have been eaten by worms
Rinse with water after removing all rotten parts.
Remove cuts caused by insect bites.
Sprinkle cinnamon powder on the cut.
Take 500ml of water.
Add 3 vitamin B1 tablets.
Take okra and cut it into thin slices.
Soak okra in Vitamin B1 water for 10 minutes.
Then soak the orchid branches in this solution for 30 minutes.
Recycle plastic boxes into orchid nursery tools.
30 Minutes later.
Apply okra gel to the entire orchid.
This helps the orchid stay moist and take root quickly.
Then place in a cool place to let the orchid dry naturally.
Place industrial cotton under the tree.
Pour some water into the glass.
Place the orchid in a cup of water but don't let the leaves touch the water.
Then spray moisturizer every 5 days.
When water does not touch the leaves, it will help the orchid have enough moisture and not cause the leaves to rot.
Place in a cool place.
1 Month later.
The orchid has grown very strong roots.
If you find the video meaningful, please support me by clicking like and sharing so more people know.
Now I plant it in a pot so the orchid can grow in an outside environment.
I used aquaponic plastic beads and terracotta spread underneath.
and spread moss on the surface to help retain moisture better.
Hope the video will help you a lot.
Wishing you success and happiness in life. Goodbye and see you again in the next videos.