welcome to my channel.
If you want orchids to bloom a lot.
Orchids always grow healthily.
The flowers stay on the branches for a long time before fading.
So let's explore organic fertilizers with me in this video.
To make safe and effective compost I will use tomatoes.
I used about 50 grams of tomatoes.
Then puree with 500ml of water.
Filter out residue.
Then add water to get 5 liters of liquid fertilizer.
METHOD 1: Fertilize orchid roots.
This type of fertilizer contains nutrients necessary for plant growth,
includes nitrogen (N), phosphorus (P), potassium (K), as well as minerals
and trace elements such as magnesium (Mg), iron (Fe), zinc (Zn) and manganese. (Mn).
These substances help orchids grow healthily, flower and promote photosynthesis.
Method 2: Clean the leaves.
Clean the top and bottom of the leaves with this water.
Helps kill fungi, insects, and harmful bacteria very effectively.
If you do this once a month, the leaves will stay green and disease-free.
THIRD METHOD.
You can also spray this fertilizer on the entire orchid plant.
Like foliar fertilization for orchids.
This type of fertilizer also helps orchids grow healthily, flower and promote photosynthesis.
Apply foliar fertilization 1-2 times a month to help increase flower production on orchids,
causing the plant to bloom more and prolong blooming time.
RESULT.
After 3 weeks new roots begin to grow.
After 5 weeks, the roots developed a lot.
This helps the plant roots absorb the most nutrients through the roots.
Sprouts also reproduce quickly.
Each pot will grow more sprouts.
Each orchid grows many buds.
Flowers bloom with more vibrant colors.
Flowers bloom for a long time.
Hope the video will help you a lot.
If you find it interesting, please share and like so more people know about this video.
Thank you for watching the video. Good luck and see you in the next videos.