Welcome to my channel
To help you have many options when caring for orchids at home with organic fertilizer.
Helps develop new shoots. Flowers bloom profusely and last long.
In this video, I share how to make organic fertilizer from pineapple waste.
Because pineapple peel and pulp contain a lot of nutrients for orchids such as nitrogen, phosphorus, potassium
and other micronutrients necessary for the growth and development of orchids.
Take the pineapple peel and put it in a jar.
and pour in 2 liters of warm water.
Add 1 teaspoon of yeast (the type of yeast commonly used to make bread).
Add 3 tablespoons of sugar.
Cover the jar with a plastic bag and create ventilation holes to prevent the jar from exploding during fermentation.
Then leave in a cool place for 1 month.
1 MONTH LATER.
Now I take 3 tablespoons of this GE pineapple fertilizer.
Mix with 2 liters of water.
FIRST METHOD.
Use this liquid fertilizer to fertilize orchid roots.
Using GE fertilizer from pineapple helps orchids grow stronger and bloom more..
Fertilizer from GE pineapple also helps improve flower quality, making flowers larger, brighter in color and with a unique aroma.
You can fertilize this fertilizer 1-2 times/month.
SECOND METHOD.
You can also use a spray bottle to spray this liquid fertilizer on the leaves, stems, and roots of your orchid.
This type of fertilizer not only provides nutrients but also has a very good bactericidal effect.
GE Pineapple fertilizer will create a favorable environment for beneficial microorganisms,
help improve the metabolic process in the orchid growing environment and create good conditions for orchids to grow.
This method is also performed 1-2 times/month.
3 WEEKS LATER
The tree has sprouted.
6 WEEKS LATER.
Shoots grow very healthily.
only these new shoots are capable of flowering.
Therefore, the more new buds there are, the more flower buds the orchid pot will have in the future.
GE fertilizer helps flowers grow bigger and brighter, with bright colors and unique fragrance.
Using GE fertilizer from pineapple waste is a way to protect the environment,
helps reuse and recycle organic waste, reduce environmental pollution and minimize waste of resources.
Hope the video will help you a lot.
Thank you for watching the video. Good luck and see you in the next videos.