Hello friends
In my hand is a wilted orchid branch, the flowers have all fallen
But in this place can still sprout
so I will cut this sprout to propagate
I use 1 teaspoon of cinnamon powder
Add 1 liter of boiled water
Wait for it to cool
After cooling, filter out the residue
Soak moss in cinnamon water for 30 minutes
Use 1 aloe leaf
100ml of water at room temperature
1 Tablet of Vitamin B1
Mix B1 water with aloe vera leaves
puree
Soak orchid branches in aloe vera and B1 water for 20 minutes
After soaking for 20 minutes, remove the branches
Dry the orchid branch
Dip the tip of the cut into the molten candle solution
This helps the cut heal quickly and the orchid does not rot
After soaking for 30 minutes, proceed to remove the moss
then mix aloe vera juice and B1 with moss
B1 and aloe vera juice promote sprouting and rooting very well
Put moss in a transparent jar
plant branches like this
Packed in transparent nylon
Then put it in a cool place, away from direct sunlight
1 MONTH LATER
Orchid sprouts grow very well
I continue to plant in this jar
From now on, it is necessary to spray moisturizing mist every 5 days
NEXT 1 MONTHS
Orchids grow very well
If you find it interesting, please like, share and subscribe to my channel to support me
Roots grow very healthy
Now let's plant the orchid outdoors to let it grow naturally
Wish you success and always happy in life