Welcome to my channel.
When the orchid is sick and rotten like this,
Don't rush to throw it away,
Let me guide you on how to help it recover quickly.
Remove all rotten leaves so they do not spread to the stem.
The roots are still very healthy.
Use about 1/4 small lemon.
Add 500ml of water.
Soak in this water for about 5 minutes
AFTER 5 MINUTES OF WAIT.
Keep in a cool place to dry.
Use dry paper to absorb water.
Sprinkle some cinnamon powder here to dry and prevent rot.
Keep in a cool place and do not water for 1 week.
AFTER 1 NEXT WEEK
Use about 10g of aloe vera leaves.
Add 500ml of water.
Take a portion into a spray bottle
Watering aloe vera for orchids.
AFTER 3 NEXT WEEKS.
Has sprouted small.
Periodic 7 to 10 days watering and moisturizing 1 time.
AFTER THE NEXT 2 MONTHS.
From now on, fertilize once every 2 weeks and keep the orchid moist to grow stronger.