Welcome to my channel.
In this video, I continue to share how to make orchids bloom at the same time with many flower branches.
Orchids after flowers fade.
We cut off all the spent flower stems.
If the plant has never bloomed, it must have 3 or more pairs of leaves.
and healthy roots.
Sprinkle cinnamon powder on the wound to help it heal quickly.
Then wait 1 day for the cut to dry.
Then take 1/2 small onion and cut it into thin slices.
Add 1 liter of water and bring to a boil.
Wait a day then use.
Next take 3 spoons of rice.
Then soak in 1 liter of water and leave for 1 day before using.
After a day, filter out the residue.
Mix the two types together.
Clean the leaves with this water.
Helps eliminate fungi and bacteria to help orchids grow better.
Do it once a week.
Then use this water to water the orchid roots.
This will help stimulate root and flower stem growth.
Do it once a week.
Place cotton balls between 2 leaves
Then spray this water on the cotton pad.
This stimulates flower stems to grow.
and spray on the top and bottom of the leaves to help supplement nutrients through the leaves for the orchids.
This should be done early in the morning, so that by noon the leaves will dry before the sun shines.
After 30 minutes, remove the cotton and repeat once a week.
and take out the orchid pot.
2 Months Later.
Many flower stems grow at the same time.
Orchids also grow many new roots.
With this simple method, you can easily care for blooming orchids at home.
Thank you for watching the video. Don't forget to like, share and subscribe to the channel to easily follow orchid growing tips.
Wish you luck and see you in the next videos.
Next, I share a small trick to help stimulate the growth of many small orchids on old orchid branches.
I used a small clove of garlic.
Squeeze water.
Apply fresh garlic juice to the places where small orchids can grow.
AFTER 1 WEEK.
Small orchids have grown bigger.
AFTER 2 MONTHS
This orchid I also apply this little trick and it also grows a lot of small orchids.
The video I have created many subtitles with many different languages. You can choose the appropriate language to understand your shared content.