hello
everyone welcome to my channel in
today's video I will continue to share
how to make organic fertilizer that
helps weak Orchids with yellowing leaves
recover and leaves and Bloom abundantly
and
[Music]
sustainably let's get
started when growing orchids it is
impossible to avoid the phenomenon of
yellowing leaves and leaf Rod which
weakens the
[Music]
Orchid if you have an orchid with yellow
or rotten leaves like this Orchid this
is the video to help you take better
care of it in the
[Music]
future first remove all damaged leaves
on the Orchid to prevent the rot from
spreading
[Music]
further then remove the damaged roots on
the
[Music]
Orchid damaged Roots can lead to
diseases removing them helps prevent the
spread of bacteria and
fungi by removing damaged Roots the
plant can focus on developing new
healthy Roots improving its ability to
absorb water and new
[Music]
nutrients then spread a little moss on
top of the Orchid pot to help uh retain
moisture better and stimulates new Roots
better
[Music]
Moss adds a natural beauty and decorates
the Orchid pot making the planting area
more vibrant
[Music]
which country are you watching the video
from please comment
below um it's great that we can chat
together from all over the world
[Music]
um if you haven't subscribed yet please
subscribe to support my channel thank
you very
[Music]
much then I use bananas as fertilizer to
care for this
Orchid take one banana and cut it into
thin slices
bananas are rich in essential nutrients
like potassium phosphorus and magnesium
which are crucial for orchid growth
especially during
[Music]
flowering put the bananas in the the
jar do you have aloe
vera take one aloe vera leaf and cut it
into thin
[Music]
slices aloe vera contains many vitamins
and minerals providing a essential
nutrients for orchid
growth put aloe vera in the
jar aloe vera gel improves the plant's
ability to absorb water and nutrients
keeping the soil moist without water
logging
[Music]
then add 600 M of warm
water um if you haven't subscribed yet
please subscribe to support my channel
thank you very much
now I add beer for
[Music]
fermentation beer contains various B
vitamins and minerals providing
essential nutrients for orchid
growth the sugars and yeast in beer help
stimulate the growth of the root system
allowing orchids to develop
stronger add 100 mm of
[Music]
beer beer can enhance the plant's
ability to absorb water water and
nutrients making the orchids
healthier then cover and leave in a cool
place for 3 weeks to create synthetic GE
from banana and aloe vera
[Music]
and this is the GE banana and aloe vera
product I fermented 3 weeks
ago take 50 m of this synthetic g
[Music]
e add 2 L of water
stir well so that the nutrients dissolve
evenly in the
[Music]
water step
one water and soak the Orchid pot in
this liquid
[Music]
fertilizer the combination of bananas
aloe vera and beer creates a natural
liquid fertilizer with many positive
effects for
[Music]
orchids the fermented extract from
bananas and aloe vera contains a variet
of vitamins minerals and enzymes um
providing essential nutrients for the
holistic development of the
[Music]
plants the enzymes in aloe vera and
compounds and bananas stimulate root
growth enabling orchids to absorb water
and nutrients more effectively
[Music]
then soak the Orchid pot in this
fertilizer solution for about 20 minutes
to help the roots absorb nutrients and
water best
[Music]
step
two use a soft cotton to absorb this
liquid fertilizer and gently wipe the
top and bottom of the
[Music]
leaves wiping the leaves provides
additional vitamins and minerals from
the extract supporting the plant's
growth
this method of cleaning leaves will
remove dust and debris allowing better
air circulation and enhancing the
plant's ability to
[Music]
photosynthesize the antibacterial and
antifungal properties of the extract
help protect the leaves from harmful
bacteria and fungi
the antibacterial and antifungal
properties of the extract help protect
the leaves from harmful bacteria and
[Music]
fungi uh wiping the leaves with the
extract helps orchids enhance their
resilience against environmental factors
and diseases
[Music]
which country are you watching videos
from please comment
[Music]
below um it's nice that we can chat with
each other from all over the world
[Music]
step
three then you put this amount of liquid
fertilizer into a spray bottle
then you spray the entire
[Music]
Orchid spraying the liquid fertilizer
helps strengthen the plant's resistance
against diseases and unfavorable
environmental factors
using the liquid fertilizer supports
robust growth of the orchids from Roots
to leaves and
[Music]
flowers uh after soaking for 20 minutes
take the Orchid pot out and place it in
a place with lots of sunlight so the
Orchid can photosynthesize well
[Music]
results after 3
weeks the orchid has grown many new
[Music]
Roots new Roots play a very important
role in the growth and development of
orchids
new Roots help the plant absorb water
and uh essential nutrients from the
environment supporting its growth and
development healthy Roots enhance the
orchid's resistance to diseases and
unfavorable environmental conditions
[Music]
new Roots help the plant establish a
strong connection with its habitat
thereby providing more
[Music]
stability uh Roots can also store
nutrients helping the plant maintain its
life and growth during difficult times
[Music]
the development of new Roots stimulates
the growth of other parts such as stems
leaves and
flowers um new roots are a decisive
factor in the healthy growth and
development of orchids directly
affecting the plant's ability to absorb
nutrients and its resilience
[Music]
and this is the result after the next 45
days
as you can see the orchid has come back
to life and is growing three new flower
spikes with these three new flower
spikes the Orchid promises to bring an
even more vibrant and colorful blooming
season ahead
the leaves have become Lush glossy and
stronger than ever
even the old wilted leaves have
completely recovered and now look
vibrant green and
healthy the strong thriving root system
reaches deep into the soil to absorb
water and nutrients nurturing the plant
to produce the largest most beautiful
and vibrant blooms
this is an orchid that was once weak but
thanks to this method I've been able to
restore it completely and as you can see
it is now thriving and healthy
[Music]
in addition to its strong thriving root
system this orchid has produced three
new flower spikes promising an upcoming
blooming season that will be vibrant and
full of color
[Music]
finally give your love and care to your
plant companions
[Music]
nurture your Orchids with all your heart
and you will be rewarded with their
amazing
[Music]
Beauty hope you likeed the video please
comment to let me know how you liked
[Music]
it goodbye and see you again in the next
videos um wishing you luck and success
in your plant care Journey