Welcome to my channel
Roots are the soul of orchids
Orchids grow healthy thanks to healthy roots
If the roots are healthy, the orchid will also grow many flower buds
In this video I will show you how to make orchids grow roots and flower buds quickly
You need 1 fresh ginger (about 50g)
Cut ginger into small pieces
put in a jar (recommended plastic jar)
add 3 tablespoons sugar (any sugar will do)
Add in 100ml of filtered water
Add in 100ml of beer (any beer is fine)
Cover and keep in a dark place for 1 month
Open the lid once every 3 days to let the gas out
1 MONTH LATER
The smell of GE ginger is fermented so it's very fragrant
ratio of mixing 3ml GE ginger for 1 liter of water
FIRST WAY
Soak cotton balls in water mixed with ginger GE
Place cotton balls soaked in GE ginger between the leaves
Helps keep moisture and GE ginger stimulates rooting and flower sprout differentiation very quickly
Change this cotton once every 3 days
On normal days when the cotton is dry,
you just need to mist it with water to keep it moist.
WAY 2
Use this water to wash the top and bottom of the leaves,
Helps provide nutrients through leaves,
clean stomata,
Eliminate harmful insects and fungi,
help orchid photosynthesis the best
Wipe the orchid leaves with GE ginger once a month
so that orchids are best protected and developed
WAY 3
Use GE ginger water to water orchids
Yeast brewed from fresh ginger has the effect of stimulating sprouting,
strong rooting, repelling insects, killing fungi, stimulating buds, and stimulating growth.
GE ginger also helps orchids increase their ability to absorb nutrients from the fertilizer you fertilize them.
Only do this 1-2 times a month
Do not use too much will affect the growth of orchids
SEE THE RESULTS
After 1 week of use, new roots grow very quickly
These roots will help the orchid absorb nutrients more easily and more
Orchids grow well or not thanks to the photosynthesis of roots and leaves
when the orchid is healthy, after the orchid branch blooms the last flowers,
Then there will be new flowers that will continue to grow.
With this simple way you can do it yourself to take care of orchids at home,
at very low cost and convenience
Hope the video content will help you take better care of orchids at home
My videos have subtitles in many other languages ​​for you to choose from