Welcome to my channel.
If you have an orchid with wilted and rotten leaves like this.
Cut off all wilted leaves and damaged roots.
Leave for 1 day without watering so that the cut heals quickly.
Then take 2 cloves of garlic.
and take about 20 grams of aloe vera leaves.
Add 1 liter of water at room temperature.
and wait 1 day before using.
1 day later.
Cleaning the leaves with this water helps eliminate fungal diseases and insects.
Spraying this water on the entire orchid helps kill mold, insects and adds necessary nutrients.
Helps orchids increase resistance and stimulate growth.
Then you use this water to water the orchid roots.
Soaking in this water for 5 minutes helps kill fungal diseases on the orchid growing medium.
Recycle plastic bottles into orchid rooting tools.
Add sterilized dry moss here.
Then regularly water and keep moist to stimulate root growth..
I usually water every 3 days.
and spraying moisturizing mist with water helps leaves stay fresh and recover quickly.
Place in a cool place with enough light for the orchids to photosynthesize.
1 month later.
The orchid leaf has gotten stronger and has grown a new leaf at the top.
This method stimulates the root system to develop very well.
Apply toothpaste to the cut to help it heal quickly and prevent tooth decay.
I also apply the same method to this orchid.
The lower stem has been rejuvenated and the baby orchid has been revived
The top has grown very healthy and has many flower buds.
Thank you for watching the video. Wish you luck and see you in the next videos.