Hello orchid lovers!
Today, we will explore together the secret of orchid watering,
so that they always bloom and grow with magical roots.
With a little patience and care,
You will find that taking care of these plants is not as difficult as you think!.
First of all, the irrigation technique is not correct.
Do not water directly from the faucet for orchids like this.
And you should not water directly on the top of the orchid like this.
You should also not water directly on the flowers.
The above 3 watering methods are easy to make orchids stamp leaves, rot leaves, and rot flowers.
like these orchids.
You need to observe the roots and the growing medium to decide whether to water or not.
If the roots are still green and the substrate is still moist like this, no watering is needed.
But when you see the roots turn white and the medium is too dry like this, you need to water the orchid immediately.
First way.
Soak the orchid pot in water for 20-30 minutes every month.
This helps to remove excess mineral salts in the orchid growing medium.
This also helps the orchid get the best water.
2nd way.
You water directly on the root but do not wet the stem and leaves of the orchid.
3rd way.
Spray a moisturizing mist on the top and bottom of the leaves.
In this way, after watering, you need to dry the shoots and interstitial leaves.
This way I apply regularly and the leaves are always green and clean.
When the orchid is watered with enough moisture and nutrition,
it will develop a lot of flower buds like this orchid of mine.
Leaves are sturdy and disease free.
Blooming flowers are brightly colored.
very fat flower buds.
This helps the petals bloom wider and stay fresh longer.
spread enough water will not wilt.
Enough moisture roots easily absorb nutrients.
If the orchid has enough water and nutrients, the flower can be kept on the branch for up to 6 months before it falls.
Adequate watering will help the roots grow stronger.
Healthy roots will also better absorb water and nutrients.
Helps orchids increase resistance to pests.
Hope the video content will help you in taking better care of orchids at home.
If you find it interesting, don't forget to like, share and subscribe to my channel to support me.
Wishing you success and happiness in life.
Goodbye and see you in the next videos.