welcome to my
[Music]
channel if you have an orchid after
blooming like
[Music]
this which country are you watching the
video from please leave a comment for me
it's wonderful that we can chat with
each other from all around the
[Music]
world cut off the withered flower
stems this helps nutrients no longer
concentrate on wilted flower branches
[Music]
and the rot from the flower stem will
not spread down the
[Music]
stem uh if you haven't subscribed to the
channel yet please hit the Subscribe
button to support
[Music]
me then remove all yellow leaves
if you encounter any difficulties a
while caring for your orchids don't
hesitate to leave a comment and I will
always be ready to support
you cut off rotten leaves so the rot
doesn't spread to other leaves
[Music]
and this is a weak Orchid its leaves
wither
[Music]
then sprinkle cinnamon powder on the cut
to help it heal quickly
[Music]
cinnamon has antibacterial and
antiseptic properties that help Cuts
prevent further rot and heal quickly
then leave it for one day without
watering to let the cut heal
[Music]
completely this is a potato including
potato
[Music]
Sprouts potato Sprouts contain a lot of
oxin a plant growth stimulant
this will stimulate weak orchids to grow
strongly especially roots and
[Music]
chots then peel and use the potato peels
as fertilizer for the
[Music]
orchids potato peels contain many
vitamins and minerals providing
nutrients for plants
[Music]
p cut the potato skin into small pieces
then put all the potato peels into a
glass
[Music]
jar add 1 lit of boiled water
then incubate for one day so that the
flour nutrients can completely dissolve
into the
water one day later
[Music]
filter this potato juice
add 1 liter of
[Music]
water method
one water your orchid with this
[Music]
water potato sprouts and potato peels
contain some plant hormones such as oxin
which helps stimulate root growth
[Music]
water each Orchid pot thoroughly
apply every 2
[Music]
weeks uh after watering for about 3 to 4
weeks the weak Orchid will grow new
roots
soaking the roots in this water for 20
minutes helps the roots absorb nutrients
better method two
use this water to thoroughly wipe the
top and bottom of the
leaves this helps remove dirt insects
and fungal diseases residing on the
leaves that harm the
[Music]
Orchid create favorable conditions for
orchids to photosynthesize light to
create
chlorophyll helps orchids grow and
increase resistance to fungal
diseases thanks to that your orchid
leaves will always be lush green and
sturdy
[Music]
uh this is a spider nest so it needs to
be removed immediately from the Orchid
okay
[Music]
um if you haven't subscribed to the
channel yet please hit the Subscribe
button to support me and to not miss any
orchid care
tips for
[Music]
uh this is a mbug species that harms or
or kids if cleaned regularly mbgs will
be
[Music]
eliminated fertilize one to two times a
month to protect orchids
[Music]
then you pour the remaining water into
the spray
[Music]
bottle method three spray this water on
the entire orchid
potato peels and potato Sprouts
decompose and provide organic matter to
the soil improving soil structure and
[Music]
moisture certain compounds and potato
Sprouts help fight fun and bacteria
protecting orchids from
[Music]
disease nutrients and potato Sprouts
help keep leaves green and healthy
promoting photosynthesis
[Music]
helps improve soil structure enhance
water holding capacity helping orchid
leaves Stay Green and
[Music]
healthy do it twice a month and can
combine with other organic fertilizers
as I shared
[Music]
results after 3
weeks after only 3 weeks this weak
orchid has developed a very strong root
system
[Music]
this orchid has Greener and stronger
leaves and grow many new roots
[Music]
this orchid's Roots grow very large and
healthy
[Music]
when the roots are strong they will
absorb nutrients
[Music]
easily results after the next
month as you can see the orchid has
grown new healthy leaves
and it has grown many new flower
branches
wow I see up to five new flower branches
growing on the same orchid
here is another Orchid that I also
revived using natural fertilizer it has
recovered well and grown many healthy
new flower branches
and if if you provide enough fertilizer
as I instruct and keep the Orchid in
diffused sunlight the orchids will Bloom
and the flowers will stay on the
branches for a long time before
fading I hope this video will be very
help for you in caring for orchids at
home if you enjoyed the video don't
forget to like share and subscribe to
the channel to support me in reaching 10
million subscribers
soon thank you for watching the video I
wish everyone good health luck and
happiness in life
[Music]