Welcome to this video! This is a dendrobium orchid.
a type of orchid that is said to be beautiful and has a gentle fragrance.
In this video I share an easy way to propagate the most beautiful orchids in the world?
If you haven't subscribed to the channel yet, please subscribe so you don't miss any tips on your channel.
And share so as many people know.
Let's start
I cut this old orchid for propagation.
Cut again so the cut is flat and will not rot further
Applying cinnamon powder to the cut helps the wound heal quickly and not rot.
Then wait a day for the cutting to dry completely before planting the orchid.
1 Day Later
Take 1 aloe vera leaf and cut it into thin slices
Aloe vera gel is very good at restoring wilted orchids and reviving baby orchids.
Then take 2 cloves of garlic and cut them into thin slices.
Garlic has antibacterial and antiseptic properties that help protect orchids from rotting.
Put garlic and aloe vera in the jar and add 500ml of water
The cut is completely dry
Soaking in this water for 30 minutes helps stimulate germination and rooting.
Recycle used plastic bottles as orchid nursery tools.
Then put the dry orchid branches into this plastic bottle.
Place the bottle here and insert moss around it to help retain moisture.
Water regularly to keep the environment moist.
This helps the orchid germinate faster.
Then put it in a cool place and wait for the orchid to revive.
45 Days Later
With this method, after only 45 days, old withered orchid branches have been revived.
Now I cut them out to plant in pots.
I plant with pine bark soaked in antiseptic to prevent the tree from rotting.
Adding a little moss helps retain moisture and protect the roots better.
Then you water it to keep it moist and take care of it like other normal orchids.
Thank you for watching the video! Wishing you luck and happiness in life!