Welcome to my channel.
In this video, I continue to share how to make orchids bloom at the same time with many flower branches.
Orchids after flowers fade.
We cut off all the spent flower stems.
If the plant has never bloomed, it must have 3 or more pairs of leaves.
and healthy roots.
Sprinkle cinnamon powder on the wound to help it heal quickly.
Then wait 1 day for the cut to dry.
Then take 1/2 small onion and cut it into thin slices.
Add 1 liter of water and bring to a boil.
Wait a day then use.
Next take 3 spoons of rice.
Then soak in 1 liter of water and leave for 1 day before using.
After a day, filter out the residue.
Mix the two types together.
Clean the leaves with this water.
Helps eliminate fungi and bacteria to help orchids grow better..
Do it once a week.
Then use this water to water the orchid roots.
This will help stimulate root and flower stem growth..
Do it once a week.
Place cotton balls between 2 leaves
Then spray this water on the cotton pad.
This stimulates flower stems to grow.
and spray on the top and bottom of the leaves to help supplement nutrients through the leaves for the orchids.
This should be done early in the morning, so that by noon the leaves will dry before the sun shines..
After 30 minutes, remove the cotton and repeat once a week.
and take out the orchid pot.
2 Months Later.
This is the orchid I took care of using that method.
The roots develop healthily.
Orchids also grow many new roots.
There is only 1 tree but there are nearly 10 flower branches growing at the same time.
Old flower branches also continue to grow new flower buds.
Orchids are healthy, so when they bloom, they will stick to the branches for a long time before falling.
Orchids can bloom continuously for up to 6 months.
With this simple method, you can easily care for blooming orchids at home.
Thank you for watching the video. Don't forget to like, share and subscribe to the channel to easily follow orchid growing tips.