Welcome to my channel.
If you want your orchid to bloom abundantly all year round, this is the video I made just for you. 🌸
So if you haven't subscribed to the channel yet, make sure to do so to support me
and not miss any great tips on Tips 365! 🌸
It would be wonderful to have you accompany me. 🌸
When the orchid has finished blooming or the plant is stunted, slow to grow and has not yet bloomed.
Cut all dry branches, roots and leaves.
This helps orchids focus their energy on healthy growth.
Removing dead parts helps prevent disease, improves air circulation,
and encourages the growth of new roots and leaves, resulting in stronger and more vibrant blooms. ✨
then take 3 teaspoons.
Add 4 cups of boiled water (about 1 liter of water).
then brew until the water cools.
After the water cools, filter to remove sediment.
After the water cools, filter to remove residue.
Please comment to me which country you are watching the video from!
It's great that we can chat together from all over the world!
In addition to the English dub, we've now created dubs in French, German, Italian, Spanish, Portuguese,
Japanese, Hindi, and Indonesian to help you hear and understand the content more easily.
Then add 1 US gallon of water (about 3.8 liters) to the mixture.
First, use this water to thoroughly wipe the top and bottom of the leaves.
This clears dirt and removes fungus, disease and insects that damage the leaves.
Apply this method once a month.
Helps leaves stay green, strong and resistant to pests.
Then you use this water to water the orchid roots.
This helps roots grow healthily and prevents root rot.
Coffee contains many minerals necessary for the growth of orchids.
Organic phosphorus and potassium found in coffee help roots and flowers develop outstandingly.
Do this twice a month for your orchids so they grow and bloom profusely.
Or you can also use this water to spray the entire orchid.
Thoroughly spray the top and bottom of the leaves to remove dirt and insects from the leaf surface.
Do this every 2 weeks.
Coffee water helps repel orchid pests very effectively.
After spraying and soaking in this water for about 5 minutes, the insects will run away from the orchid pot.
If you encounter any difficulties during the orchid growing process, don't hesitate to comment!
I am always ready to support you so you can grow healthy orchids and bloom lots of flowers. 🌸
Then take the orchid pot out and place it in a cool place with enough light for the orchid to grow.
2 Months later.
Orchids will begin to sprout and bloom profusely.
Blooming flowers have bright colors.
Shoe petals will stay fresh longer.
The flowers bloom for up to 6 months before fading.
Hopefully the video will help you a lot in taking better care of orchids at home.
If you find it useful, don't forget to subscribe to the channel so you don't miss any orchid growing tips on your channel.
Thank you for watching the video. Good luck and see you in the next videos.