welcome to happiness Garden Channel um
happiness Garden Channel specializes in
Sharing tips for caring for orchids using
natural fertilizers promoting sustainable
growth abundant blooms and Environmental
Protection if you love orchids as much as
I do subscribe to my channel to support me and
never miss any tips today I'm sharing how to
make a natural fertilizer from garlic that's
both simple and effective for your orchids
I just need a clove of [Music]
garlic garlic promotes harmonious growth
and Lush long- lasting flowering of
orchids it repels most pests and kills
spores of fungi viruses and bacteria
[Music] substances in garlic water
strengthen the immune system of [Music]
[Music]
orchids I pour crushed garlic
with 1 liter of hot water
[Music]
and this is turmeric powder was rich in
vitamins and minerals potassium calcium
magnesium sodium phosphorus iron manganese
copper selenium and zinc increases plant
resistance to fungi and diseases while
stimulating growth and flowering [Music]
uh incubate until the water cools so
that the nutrients from the garlic and
turmeric starch are completely
dissolved in the water [Music]
after the water cools we
filter it to remove sediment
[Music]
fertilizer for orchids must be carefully filtered
so that organic fragments do not rot in the
substrate guys please write a
comment letting me know which
country you're watching my video from the of
fence it's great to know that
we can communicate worldwide
[Music]
uh to know if it's time to water
orchids I look at the color of the
roots when the Orchid Roots have a light
silver color it's time to water the Orchid
if the roots are bright green you should
wait until the roots turn pale silver before
watering if you water when the
roots are still green The Roots
will easily become water logged and cause root rot
My Maids are tired and
sleeping and the cat seems to be hunting down the
mice that are destroying my orchids
orchids grown in pots with drainage
holes I water this one to two times a
month soak the roots in the this water for about
20 minutes to help the roots absorb nutrients
[Music]
best um the finished infusion
for orchids helps strengthen
the immune system promotes the
development of the root system
this water is also very good when sprayed on
Orchids spraying your Orchids
with garlic and turmeric water
will protect them from diseases
pests and boost their immune system
spray the entire Orchid from leaves to
Roots but you should not water the flowers
because wet flowers will quickly fall off
do it one to two times a
month if you have a very humid climate
orchids are susceptible to Leaf base rot to
prevent orchids from rotting at the base of the
leaves you can use cotton balls to protect them
now spray the cotton with garlic and
turmeric water and spray it on your
orchids to protect them from diseases
pests and boost the immune system
leave the cotton there for
20 minutes then remove it
then you take the Clear Water above
if you don't have access to spraying orchids you
can wipe the leaves with a
cotton pad soaked in this
[Music] water will help remove mineral
salts still attached to the leaf
surface helps orchid leaves avoid
burning when exposed to sunlight
uh this not only clears the dust but also provides
them with nutrients and protects
them from diseases and [Music]
pests thoroughly wipe both
the top and bottom of the leaf
do this one or two times a
month uh it is enough to keep the
Orchid in this water for 20 minutes
soaked in this water The Roots will change
from Silver to purple blue like this
[Music]
then place the Orchid pot
in a warm place with lots
of diffused light so the Orchid will grow quickly
[Music]
after 20 minutes remove the
cotton ball and place the
Orchid pot in a warm place with lots of diffused
[Music]
light
result um the leaves are always
green and shiny like this
the roots are green large and
healthy thanks to the clean Leaf
surface orchid leaves photosynthesize
better when orchids have enough light for
photosynthesis they will always be healthier than
usual thanks to this care the Orchid produces many
[Music]
flowers vibrant flower colors
orchids bloom all year round
flowering very long and
boldly hope you like this video
thank you for viewing good
luck and success in life
[Music]