Welcome to my channel.
To help you have many choices when caring for orchids at home with organic fertilizer.
In this video, I continue to share new methods.
Subscribe to the video so you don't miss any tips on my channel.
To make this compost you need eggs.
To be more precise, it takes about 10 eggshells.
Then rinse with water to remove the gel in the eggshell.
then dry in the sun
After drying for about 3 hours in the autumn sun, the eggshell was completely dry.
Grind into dry powder.
Take 1 teaspoon of eggshell powder.
Add one liter of boiled water.
then brew until the water cools.
After cooling, filter to remove residue.
FIRST METHOD.
Wipe the top and bottom of the leaves with eggshell water.
Eggshells contain a lot of calcium, an important mineral for plant growth.
Helps leaves become stronger than usual.
This method helps kill fungi and insects very well.
SECOND METHOD.
Spray eggshell water on the entire orchid.
Calcium in eggshells helps strengthen plant structures very well,
especially creating strong branches and leaves.
THIRD METHOD.
Apply liquid fertilizer from eggshells to orchid roots.
Calcium from eggshell water helps enhance orchid root growth,
Helps plants absorb nutrients from the growing medium better.
Calcium also helps orchids increase disease resistance,
making them less susceptible to infection and disease.
FOURTH METHOD.
Sprinkle eggshell powder on the surface of the orchid pot.
Calcium helps orchids absorb water better.
This makes the plant more resistant to water depletion.
RESULT.
After 1 month of application, the orchids developed many new roots.
This helps orchids best absorb nutrients for outstanding growth.
Flowers bloom hard and last long.
Many flowers bloom at the same time without exhausting the orchids.
Hope the video will help you a lot.
Thank you for watching the video.
Good luck and see you in the next videos!