welcome to my channel happiness
Garden um in this video I will share
three methods to help you care for and
restore orchids quickly and bloom all
year
round now let's start learning about the
uses of the first type of
[Music]
fertilizer take 3 L of water at room
temperature
[Music]
take 50 mm of Coca-Cola
then you just need to mix Coca-Cola with
water and you can use it right
[Music]
away then you clean the surface of the
orchid leaves with this Coca-Cola
[Music]
wipe both the top and bottom of the
leaves
[Music]
this way helps to repel insects and
fungi on leaves very well
[Music]
do it once every 2 weeks orchid leaves
will be very well protected
[Music]
you can also use this water to spray the
entire orchid
[Music]
pay attention to spray carefully the
underside of leaves and between leaves
[Music]
because insects and fungi often
congregate
there this is also done every 2
[Music]
weeks if you use use the wiping and
spraying method of Coca-Cola regularly
leaves will always be green because they
are not damaged by insects and
[Music]
fungi like my orchid the leaves are
always green and healthy
[Music]
now take care of the
roots you just need to water this Orchid
as much as possible
[Music]
Coca-Cola contains phosphoric acid which
has a mild bleaching effect so it will
eliminate fungal diseases in pots and
Roots very well
[Music]
in addition Coca-Cola also has the
ability to kill some insects that damage
plant roots such as snails and
cockroaches very
[Music]
effectively Coca-Cola helps neutralize
acid in the pot when you use too much
chemical fertilizer to help balance the
pH in the Orchid pot this will stimulate
new roots to grow
[Music]
Coca-Cola contains sugar that helps
flowers grow very well
[Music]
well if combined with Organic
fertilizers it will help spread more
[Music]
flowers my orchids when applying this
method have grown a lot of flower
branches on One Tree
[Music]
the sugar and Coca-Cola helps flow stay
fresh and long
[Music]
lasting Orchid after blooming will not
be
[Music]
exhausted uh Orchid can bloom
continuously from one batch to another
[Music]
new roots are always
growing helps orchids absorb the most
[Music]
nutrients hope the video will help you
in taking care of orchids at home
[Music]
better and I I also hope you enjoy this
first
[Music]
tip uh if you find it interesting please
like share the video and subscribe to
help my channel reach 10 million
subscribers
[Music]
soon and don't rush to leave the screen
tip number two and tip three will be
even better
if you have an orchid did that has rot
causing the leaves to turn
yellow so don't rush to throw it away I
will share how to revive it quickly and
easily
[Music]
this Orchid may be suffering from
inorganic fertilizer shock leading to
root Rod causing the leaves to turn
[Music]
yellow so I need to check the roots to
cut off all damaged roots
[Music]
removing damaged Roots helps prevent the
rot from spreading causing the entire
root of the Orchid to
[Music]
rot and stimulates new root formation
faster
[Music]
then rinse with water
Take 2 L of water and put it in a jar
[Music]
then add 1 teaspoon of baking soda to
help kill bacteria and eliminate
[Music]
pests soak Orchid roots in this water
for 10
[Music]
minutes then use dry moss to grow
orchids
[Music]
after soaking for 10 minutes take the
Orchid out and plant
[Music]
it when planting dry sterilized Moss it
will help absorb moisture from The Roots
this helps the cut heal quickly and the
rot does not spread
[Music]
further then place in a cool place and
do not water for one week
[Music]
after one week start watering the Orchid
once a week
[Music]
soak in water for 10 minutes to keep the
Moss
[Music]
moist then take it out and cover it with
a transparent plastic box
[Music]
and remember to water it every week to
keep it moist
[Music]
1 month
later the orchid has revived and grown
healthy roots
[Music]
but it seems like the leaves are a bit
wilted once the root system is strong
you need to add more nutrients to help
the Orchid grow quickly
[Music]
Take 2 L of
water and add 5 tspoons of rice
[Music]
rice contains a variety of minerals and
amino acids that are important for
orchid growth
[Music]
then use this rice water to water the
orchids once a week
[Music]
in addition to providing necessary
nutrients rice water also creates a
favorable environment for beneficial
microorganisms to grow in Orchid
[Music]
pots soak for 10 minutes then take out
the Orchid pot
[Music]
regularly spray mist to keep the soil
moist when the growing medium is dry try
[Music]
2 months
later from an orchid with Leaf rot
causing the leaves to turn completely
yellow it has now grown healthily
[Music]
strong roots fresh green
leaves if you find the video interesting
please please like and share so more
people know and subscribe to support my
[Music]
channel my videos have subtitles in many
different languages please choose the
appropriate language to clearly
understand the content I
share welcome to tip number
three to help you have many choices when
caring for orchids at home with organic
fertilizer in this video I continue to
share new
[Music]
methods um subscribe to the video so you
don't miss any tips on my channel
now let's get
started to make this type of organic
fertilizer you need black tea or tea
grounds I use 3 tpoon of black tea
add 1 liter of boiled
[Music]
water incubate until the water cools
after the water cools filter to remove
sediment
[Music]
add water to make 5 L of black tea
solution
[Music]
next add 1 teaspoon of baking soda
first
[Music]
method water this fertilizer Solution on
the Orchid roots
[Music]
black tea contains many minerals and
organic substances that help provide
nutrition for
[Music]
orchids it contains nitrogen potassium
and phosphor
important nutritional factors for orchid
[Music]
growth baking soda bicarbonates soda has
the ability to increase the pH level in
Orchid pots this is helpful in reducing
acidity if you use too much chemical
fertilizer
[Music]
baking soda has the ability to kill
insects and fungi that are harmful to
[Music]
plants second method
spray this fertilizer on the entire
orchid
[Music]
this method is similar to using foler
fertilizer baking soda has the ability
to kill insects and fungi that are
harmful to plants PS
[Music]
third
method clean the leaf surface with this
fertilizer solution
[Music]
the leaf surface will always be clean
and the stamato will not be
[Music]
clogged orchids will photosynthesize
better
[Music]
um plant roots are protected and
supplemented with nutrients so they grow
very healthily
[Music]
we'll help orchids absorb the most
nutrients because they are provided with
enough nutrition the flowers bloom more
[Music]
brilliantly many flowers bloom on the
same
[Music]
Branch the flowers stay on the branches
for a long time before
[Music]
fading thank you for watching the video
wishing you luck and success success in
life goodbye and see you again in the
next videos