Hello everyone, to easily care for orchids to always grow healthily.
There are more flower buds and flowers stay on the branches longer.
Today I share a very easy way to keep orchids growing healthy.
This is soybeans
I used 1 tablespoon of soybeans
Soybeans contain many nutrients, especially organic nitrogen and potassium.
And this is the yeast, I took 1 spoon of yeast
Add 1 tablespoon brown sugar
And finally, you need bread. When eating leftover bread, don't rush to throw it away
Bread provides a carbon source for microorganisms in the orchid growing environment such as fungi and beneficial bacteria,
Helps increase organic decomposition in soil and improve orchid growth
Add 500ml of water
Remember to leave space so that the jar does not explode when fermenting.
Leave in a cool place for 3 weeks before using
3 weeks later
Take 5 liters of water
Then take 50ml of this fertilizer solution made from soybeans and bread
Method one: Water the roots with this liquid fertilizer
Doing this every 2 weeks helps stimulate leaf and flower growth very well
This fertilizer provides nitrogen and potassium, an important mineral that improves plant health and vitality.
This type of fertilizer also helps retain water and enhances the plant's ability to absorb water.
The beneficial fungus Mycorrhiza will grow to help the plant more easily absorb nutrients from the orchid growing medium.
Method 2.
Use this water to spray on the leaves.
Helps supplement nutrients through leaves very effectively.
Helps orchid leaves become strong and healthy.
You should do it early in the morning and by noon the leaves will dry very quickly.
Do this once a week to keep the orchid healthy.
Method 3:
Now I wash the leaves with this water.
Beneficial microorganisms will help kill mold and insects very effectively.
Do this every 2 weeks to protect your orchids.
Result
After fertilizing, the orchid will always be green and healthy.
Nitrogen and Potassium in soybeans and bread help flower buds grow strongly.
The leaves are always green and hard
Helps orchids increase their resistance to pests.
The potassium in this fertilizer helps spread more buds
When the flowers bloom, they will stay on the branches for a long time.
Flowers can last on branches for up to 6 months before fading.
Hopefully the video will help you a lot in taking better care of orchids at home.
Thanks for watching. If you find it interesting, please like, share and subscribe to my support channel.