Hello friends!
Today we will take care of orchids with natural fertilizer from lemon.
More precisely, lemon peel contains a lot of vitamin C and essential oils,
which are very beneficial for orchid care, supporting the plant's healthy growth from roots to leaves and flowers. ðŸ‹âœ¨
Choose 1 lemon.
then just take the shell.
If you haven't subscribed to the channel yet, please click the subscribe button to support me
and not miss any orchid growing tips! It's great to have company!
Chopped.
In addition to the English dub, we now create dubs in French, German, Italian, Spanish, Portuguese,
Japanese, Hindi and Indonesian to help you listen and understand Content. Video content is easier.
To listen to the language, open the video and click the Settings (gear icon) to select the appropriate audio language. âœ¨
Then puree with 2 cups of water equivalent to about 500ml of water.
Please comment to me which country you are watching the video from!
It's great that we can chat together from all over the world!
Filter out residue.
Take 100ml of juice from lemon peel (about 1/3 cup).
Add water to get 1 liter of solution.
First way:
Clean the leaves with a solution of the juice from the lemon peel.
This protects them from pests.
Wipe the underside of the leaves carefully because this is where fungi,
bacteria, and insects often gather to harm the orchid.
Second way:
Spray this solution on the entire orchid.
This helps wash away dirt,
and eliminate fungal diseases, bacteria and harmful insects.
Spray this mixture on orchids every 2 weeks.
But do not spray on flowers and buds.
because wet flowers will quickly fall off.
3rd way:
Now we water this solution to take care of the roots.
Lemon peel acidifies the orchid juice, which contributes to better absorption of nutrients.
Essential oils repel pests and protect orchid leaves and roots from harmful bacteria.
Or soak the orchid pot in this solution for 30 minutes, it will be better.
Do this every 2 weeks and the orchid will always be protected.
If you don't use all of it, you can freeze the juice from the lemon zest for later use.
Now let's see the results after caring for orchids with natural fertilizer.
After 3 times of use, the roots grow very well.
Branched roots develop to help the orchid absorb more nutrients.
Leaves are clean, always green and free from pests.
help orchids photosynthesize better.
flower buds grow and do not fall.
Flowers bloom brightly and stay fresh.
Flowers stay on the branch for up to 6 months before falling.
Hope this sharing will help you a lot.
Subscribe to my channel to support me and don't miss any tips on my channel.
Next we will explore a simple method for creating a beautiful flower season.
Surely you are wondering how to help your flower plants grow strong and vibrant, right?
This simple method helps your orchids stay green and have lots of buds.
The buds always grow plump.
Flowers bloom well and last a long time.
New roots are always growing.
Helps orchids absorb nutrients best.
Now let's make fertilizer together.
This is garlic powder that every home has, right?
Take 1 teaspoon of garlic powder and add 1 liter of boiled water.
Then wait for it to cool before using.
then filter out the residue.
After filtering, use a towel to wipe the top and bottom of the leaves with this water.
Garlic has antibacterial properties so it helps eliminate fungi and insects on leaves very well.
In addition, garlic also has many natural minerals necessary for orchid growth.
Apply once a month for better protection and growth.
If you do this regularly, your orchids will always be green and disease-free.
Next you can also spray this water on the entire orchid.
This also helps provide nutrients through the leaves to the orchid.
You should thoroughly spray both the underside of the leaves and the leaf interstices.
Because that is where insects and fungi often reside, causing harm to orchids.
Finally, you use this water to care for the roots.
Water each orchid pot with about 10 tablespoons of garlic soaking water.
This and the way you spray you apply it every 2-3 weeks.
Garlic contains natural compounds that have antibacterial and antifungal properties.
Helps protect orchids from pests and other harmful agents.
Garlic powder also helps strengthen the plant's natural immune system and reduces the risk of infection.
Nutrients found in garlic such as potassium and fosfor
, nitrogen provides essential nutrients for orchid growth.
After 1 month of fertilizing with garlic powder, the plant has grown many new roots.
This will help the orchid more easily absorb more nutrients.
When new roots grow a lot, it is necessary to combine the use of other types of organic fertilizers such as:
Fish protein and soy protein follow my instructions to help orchids absorb a variety of nutrients.
If you encounter any difficulties during the orchid growing process, don't hesitate to comment!
I am always ready to support you so you can grow healthy orchids and bloom lots of flowers. ðŸŒ¸
Using garlic powder as fertilizer helps orchids grow strongly.
Orchids grow many flower stems at the same time in the same orchid pot.
Orchids become more vibrant and have a characteristic fragrance.
Now I share how to care for Phalaenopsis orchids that bloom continuously from season to season,
In the summer orchids often rot like this.
This is a disease caused by bacteria.
It spreads very quickly but don't worry.
Take 1 liter of water at room temperature.
This is an anti-rot medicine for cabbage.
Its composition includes Steptomycin 40%.
it will remove bacteria very quickly.
You only put in 1/4 of the tablet.
Put it in a spray bottle and spray it all over the orchid.
I intentionally did not remove the rotten leaves to show you how Steptomycil works.
Any rotten areas need to be sprayed more.
Spray even disease-free leaves.
After spraying, leave the orchid pot in a cool place and do not water for 1 week.
See results after 1 week.
All leaves affected by bacterial rot are dry.
Do you see the effectiveness of steptomycin against bacteria that cause orchid leaf rot?
The rotten orchid has recovered and grown new leaves.
After recovering from the disease, recovery care is needed to help the orchid grow and bloom quickly.
This is a multivitamin.
Dissolve 1 tablet in 1 liter of water.
Wait for the vitamins to dissolve and then add 2 liters of water to get 3 liters of great fertilizer.
Use cotton soaked in this water to wipe the leaves.
Helps supplement nutrition and clear stomata.
Helps orchids photosynthesize better.
Strong orchid leaves increase resistance to fungi and insects.
Or you can also spray this liquid fertilizer on the entire orchid.
This method works as well as mopping leaves.
Spraying evenly at the base is very good for orchids.
But don't spray it on the flowers because if the flowers are wet they will quickly fade.
Now you take care of the roots.
You water this liquid fertilizer on the orchid roots.
This helps orchids absorb the most nutrients.
Because the roots are the main nutrient absorbers of the orchid.
For infected plants, do this every 2 weeks.
With normal orchids, you do this once every 1-2 months.
helps orchids grow very quickly and increase resistance.
It is best to soak the orchid pot in this water for 30 minutes and then take it out.
After only 2 weeks of care, the orchid has grown many new roots.
Many flower buds grow on the same tree.
Thank you for watching the video. Good luck and see you in the next videos.