welcome to my channel
Today I continue to share how to quickly revive a rotten orchid like this.
All the leaves are rotten.
This flower has also dried.
The top of the flower is still fresh so I decided to leave it to propagate from this flower
Next, cut off all the damaged roots.
Although the orchid has rotted, there are still some fresh roots
Rinse with plain water
take 1 aloe leaf
add 2 cloves of germinated garlic,
If you don't have germinated garlic, you can substitute it with regular garlic,
Garlic sprouts contain very rich AUXIN content
AUXIN is a plant growth stimulant
so it will help the orchid respawn very quickly
add about 30g of aloe leaves
add 1 liter of water
puree
filter out residue
Soak orchids in this water for 20 minutes
I recycle plastic bottles as tools to revive orchids
This recycling tool will also contribute to creating a favorable environment for the orchid to revive quickly,
It also helps to reduce environmental pollution
wash
make vents
Use dry pine bark
let dry for 1 week without watering
The dry pine bark will absorb moisture to help protect the orchid from further rot
AFTER 1 WEEK
Now start watering to keep the orchid moist
Every 5 days, spray mist to keep the orchid moist
and put in a cool place to spread recovery
AFTER 3 WEEKS
Sprout has revived
and the roots are also revived
Continue periodically for 5 days misting to keep the orchid moist
Continue to keep in a cool place for the spread to recover
AFTER 2 MONTHS
Lan has revived and grown healthy
With this approach, orchids will have the right environment to grow
Steam from below always evaporates, creating the right moisture for orchids to revive and grow.
Hope this content will help you take care of orchids at home better
If you find it interesting, please like, share and subscribe to the channel so you don't miss my next videos
Now I will show you which fertilizer is best for orchids.
it will help the orchid grow from roots, leaves and flowers
There will be many flower buds growing after fertilizing
Let's start
I used 5 cloves of garlic
is rich in nutrients such as Potassium, Magnesium, Calcium, Phosphorus,
B vitamins (B1, B2, B3, B6)
Garlic is a rich source of raw materials providing essential nutrients for growth
and plant growth.
Use an additional 30 grams of fresh potatoes
Potatoes also contain many vitamins and amino acids
and natural minerals such as Nitrogen, Phosphorus, Potassium
The starch content in potatoes also helps beneficial microorganisms grow
Helps protect healthy orchid roots
I grind garlic and potatoes in 300 ml of water
filter out residue
Add water to get 3 liters of organic fertilizer solution from garlic and potatoes
Put this organic fertilizer in a spray bottle
Spray the top and bottom of the leaves thoroughly
When provided with this organic nutrition, orchids will grow very well
Garlic contains strong essential oils and also has an acidic component,
so it helps to repel insects and fungi very well
Fertilizing once every 2 weeks will be very good for orchids
Use this organic fertilizer to water the orchid pot
The potassium and phosphorus content will promote the growth of roots and flowers very quickly
And the nitrogen in this organic fertilizer will help keep the leaves big and green
Apply once every 2 weeks
You can soak the orchid pot in this organic fertilizer for 20 minutes,
so that the roots can absorb the most nutrients.
Results after 1 month
Many new roots grow
New roots help orchids absorb water and nutrients better
When we provide nutrients, the roots will immediately absorb and transport to the entire orchid plant
if you fertilize once every 2 weeks in combination with other organic fertilizers that I have shared
I guarantee the orchid will always grow well
Potassium in garlic and potatoes helps orchids bloom many flowers on the same branch
Potassium helps to resist drought very well
Potassium helps carry water from the roots to the highest and farthest parts of the orchid such as the tops and buds
so the buds don't wilt due to lack of water
so the flower will keep on the branch for a long time without wilting
Flowers can bloom up to 6 months without falling