Welcome to my channel.
In this video, I share the method of recovering weak orchids.
Helps them quickly take root and grow strongly.
I picked up a rotten orchid that someone had thrown away.
All the roots have rotted.
This original part has completely rotted so it can no longer be used.
Wash orchid branches with water.
Then take 1 clove of garlic and mince it.
Add 500ml of water and soak for 30 minutes.
Let the flower nutrition completely dissolve in water.
AFTER 30 MINUTES.
Wiping orchid branches with garlic water helps disinfect and eliminate fungal diseases.
Then soak the orchid branches in garlic water for 10 minutes.
This helps stimulate root and shoot growth.
10 Minutes Later.
because this orchid has many scars from previous insect bites.
So I waited a day for the orchid to dry completely before planting it.
1 Day Later.
I recycle sponges as orchid nursery tools.
Soaking the sponge in garlic water for 20 minutes helps disinfect and kill fungus.
20 MINUTES LATER.
Insert the orchid stem into the sponge and place it in the vase.
Pour some water into the jar and change it every time it gets dirty.
Spray moisturizer every 3 days.
and Place in a cool, well-lit place.
5 WEEKS LATER
The roots have grown very healthy.
With this simple method, the roots have grown and the orchid has revived very well.
I planted it in a pot so the orchid could grow better.
If you find the video interesting, please like and share so more people know this tip.
Water orchids regularly to keep them moist.
Subscribe to my channel to support me and don't miss any tricks on my channel
Hello friends.
In this video, I share how to take care of orchids to help them grow and flower
You see my orchids.
New flowers always grow after the old ones fall
so my orchids bloom all year round.
bloom from branch to branch.
flowers bloom on long branches
Flowers can be kept on branches for up to 6 months
Many flowers grow on the same tree
New roots grow a lot to help absorb nutrients best
chubby flower buds
Help flowers bloom long on branches
brilliant flowers
How to make fertilizer as follows:
Use 1 small carrot weighing about 30g
Cut into small pieces
Add 1 liter of filtered water
Puree
filter out residue
Add 1 liter of filtered water
How to use
Use a cotton ball to soak up carrot juice
Wipe both the top and bottom of the leaves
help get rid of insects
and open stomata
Orchid will have better photosynthesis and metabolism
At the same time, orchids also absorb some nutrients through the leaves
Help keep the leaves green
2nd way
Water this carrot for orchids
Carrot juice is a good source of nutrients for orchids,
including vitamins and minerals like beta-carotene, potassium, magnesium, and phosphorus.
When the carrot juice is poured into the orchid pot,
it provides nutrients to the orchids and helps to promote their health.
In addition, carrot juice is also acidic, which helps regulate the pH of the potted soil
and enhances the orchid's ability to absorb nutrients.
You can soak the orchid pot in this carrot juice for 20 minute
Do this 1-2 times a month
3rd way
mist moisturizing carrot juice for orchids
Spray both the top and bottom of the leaves
help wash away dirt, wash away insects on orchids
Nutrients in carrot juice help orchids thrive and bloom
However, be careful not to over-water the carrot juice as it can clog the water lines in the orchid.
Do not water the flowers because the flowers fall off quickly
Hope the video content will help you in caring for orchids at home to bloom easily
If you find it interesting, please like, share and subscribe to my support channel
Next
To help you have many choices when caring for orchids at home with organic fertilizer.
In this video, I continue to share new methods.
Subscribe to the video so you don't miss any tips on my channel.
No.1
To make this fertilizer you need apples.
Apples contain potassium, an important mineral for orchid growth.
Potassium helps orchids develop stronger leaves, roots and flowers.
I took the apple peel and put it in a bottle.
Soak in boiled water and leave overnight.
No. 2
To make this type of fertilizer you need more eggshells.
Soak the eggshells in boiled water and leave overnight.
Leave overnight
After 1 night, filter the water.
So we have fertilizer from apples and eggshells.
FIRST METHOD.
Water this fertilizer solution on the orchid roots.
Eggshells provide natural calcium which is very good for orchids.
Helps orchids stay healthy and increase resistance.
Apple peels contain a lot of Phosphorus, which is also an important nutrient for orchid growth.
especially during the flowering and flower development stage.
Do this 1-2 times/month to supplement nutrition and increase the orchid's resistance.
SECOND METHOD.
Spray this fertilizer on the entire orchid.
This method is similar to using foliar fertilizer.
Calcium in eggshells helps orchids stay healthy and increases their resistance to pests.
Apples contain nitrogen, an important nutrient.
Helps orchids develop green parts and increase photosynthesis ability.
Do not spray on flowers.
Because wet flowers will easily fall off.
THIRD METHOD
Clean the leaf surface with this liquid fertilizer.
The leaf surface will always be clean and airy.
Orchids will photosynthesize better.
Fertilizing regularly 1-2 times/month will help keep the leaves healthy.
No. 3
You can reuse eggshells and apple peels to make fertilizer again.
RESULT.
This type of fertilizer stimulates rooting very quickly.
After 1 month of use you will see great results.
Many flower buds develop and do not fall.
Blooming flowers stay on the branches for a long time before fading.
Flowers can remain on branches for up to 6 months before falling.
4/4
if you have orchids after blooming.
If all the flowers have fallen, don't rush to throw them away.
Let me tell you how to help these branches continue to bloom strongly again.
These nodes can continue to bloom very well.
When you eat bananas.
Don't throw away the peel.
Thinly sliced ​​banana peels contain many vitamins and minerals that are very good for the bud formation process.
Soak banana peels in 1 liter of boiled water.
Then take 3 tablespoons of coffee grounds.
Then soak this coffee grounds in 1 liter of boiled water.
Then wait for the water to cool.
After the water cools, filter to remove sediment.
Dip a cotton ball in water extracted from coffee grounds and wash the leaves.
Helps eliminate pests and diseases of orchids.
and leaves will photosynthesize better.
Mix these two types together.
Dip cotton balls in this water and clip them to nodes that are likely to continue blooming.
Do it once a week.
will help stimulate rapid sprout growth.
Keep the cotton pad on the branch like that for 20 minutes and then remove it.
then water the roots once a week.
Soak it for 10 minutes then lift it out.
And spray this water once a week to help supplement nutrients through the leaves.
After 20 minutes, remove the cotton pad.
Then place the plant in a place with lots of light so it can bloom easily.
1 MONTH LATER.
Many buds have grown.
Continue watering and spraying the orchid with this water once a week.
Then place the plant in a place with lots of light so it can bloom easily.
After the next 1 month.
From the dry branches, many beautiful flowers have sprouted and bloomed.
The leaves are strong and sturdy, very resistant to pests and diseases.
The flower color is also more vibrant than usual.
Hope the video will help you a lot.
If you find it interesting, please like, share and subscribe.
to the channel to help my channel reach 1 million subscribers soon.
My videos have subtitles in many different languages ​​so you can choose the appropriate language.
Thank you for watching the video. Good luck and see you in the next videos.