Welcome to my channel.
Today I will show you how to revive a rotten orchid like this.
When the orchid has withered all the leaves and only the stem and roots, do not rush to throw it away.
Here the branches are still fresh
I will remove all wilted and rotten leaves
and I remove all the broken roots
I keep only the fresh roots that are left over
I cut off the flower stalk so that the orchid can concentrate nutrients for the new sprout to grow
rinse with water
Apply melted candle solution to the cut to prevent water from seeping into the tree.
Use 3 cloves of garlic and mince
Soak garlic in 1 liter of water at room temperature
Incubate for 1 day
At the same time, spread in a cool place for 1 day.
1 DAY AFTER
filter out residue
Soak orchid branches in garlic water for 20 minutes
The rest of the water I will spray on other orchids to help protect the orchid from insects and fungi
At the same time, garlic juice also stimulates the development of roots and flower sprouts very well
20 MINUTES AFTER
After soaking for 30 minutes, plant.
Using pine bark or dry pumice stone to plant will help absorb moisture in the roots, making the orchid roots not rot.
Put in a cool place for 1 week without watering
1 WEEK LATER
From now on, water the orchid to keep it moist
Then put it in a place with a temperature of 20-25 degrees Celsius and avoid direct sunlight
Regularly spray moisture to spread life and revive faster
2 WEEKS AFTER
Use 3ml of GE Ginger water mixed with 1 liter of water
GE ginger juice is considered an organic fertilizer that helps to stimulate plant growth very well
Water this GE Ginger every 10 days
Continue to place in a cool place and avoid direct sunlight
Cover with a clear, vented plastic container and wait for the plant to revive.
1 MONTH LATER
The roots have grown very well, so we fertilize the orchid with organic fertilizer as I have shared to make the orchid grow healthier
Hope this sharing content will help you in resurrecting weak orchids to grow again
If you find it interesting, remember to click like, share and subscribe so that my channel will soon reach 1,000,000 subscribers.
The video I have created many subtitles, you can choose the appropriate language to understand my sharing.
welcome to my channel,
Today I share with you an amazing organic fertilizer,
And anyone can do it easily.
Just 1 to 2 ripe bananas,
And the orchid garden will bloom all kinds of flowers.
Now I will revive this orchid with new flowers,
You've seen this orchid lose all its flowers, leaving only withered branches
And here are the withered orchids that have been revived with lots of new flowers.
STEP
cut off the withers
Apply toothpaste on the cut
This will disinfect and help prevent rot
Don't throw away banana peels when eating bananas
Use 1 to 2 ripe banana peels
Clip the banana peel to the place where the flower buds can grow
and note to remove after 6 hours
This helps to create the right moisture, provide essential nutrients and stimulate flower sprouts,
do this once a week
STEP 2
Use a banana peel to wipe the top and bottom of the leaves,
Helps eliminate insects, fungi, bacteria hiding on orchid leaves,
and at the same time provide a part of nutrients through the leaves for orchids
Orchids will be protected and will not be affected by yellowing and rotten leaves.
After wiping, you will see green leaves,
Orchids will photosynthesize better to increase resistance.
STEP 3
1 liter of water
Leave in a cool and dark place for 1 day
AFTER 1 DAY
banana juice is darker
Use this absorbent cotton
Clip a cotton ball where the flower buds can grow
and note to remove after 6 hours
This helps to create the right moisture, provide essential nutrients and stimulate flower sprouts,
do this once a week
STEP 4
Normally after 3-4 weeks flower buds will be formed and develop like this,
With a flower sprout this big, there's no need to sandwich banana peels with cotton balls
You will be surprised how amazing this is
Don't forget to subscribe to see my next videos
STEP 5
Add water to make 2 liters
Water this banana for orchids once every 2-3 weeks
Banana peel is rich in potassium, phosphorus and essential vitamins
will promote the growth of orchid roots
In particular, the potassium in banana peels stimulates flowering very well.
In addition, you need to combine using other organic fertilizers for orchids,
like manure made from soybeans, peas, fish poop... as I shared,
Hope this sharing content will help you in taking better care of orchids at home
then make sure the orchid will grow healthy and produce many flowers.
welcome to my channel.
Today I share a new way to help spread more roots, branches and flower buds.
Join me in discovering this wonderful way to make organic fertilizer.
To make this type of fertilizer you need 1 branch of ginger.
After slicing, put into a glass jar.
Then add 1 spoon of yeast.
This is the yeast used to make bread.
and add 1 teaspoon of honey.
and 1 liter of warm water.
Incubate in a dark place for 1 week.
1 WEEKLATER
Take 3 tablespoons of fermented ginger solution.
Add 1 liter of water.
First Method
Use cotton balls dipped in organic fertilizer solution from fermented ginger.
Then place it in the places where you want to take root and sprout.
After 6 hours, take the cotton out.
Do it once a week.
Method 2
If you want this branch to continue blooming.
Then add cotton and clip it.
After 6 hours, take the cotton out.
Do it once a week.
Method 3
If you want this button to continue growing flower buds.
Peel off the protective film of the sleeping sprouts.
This helps the buds grow faster.
Apply toothpaste to the cut.
This helps the cut heal quickly.
Then stuff cotton into the button with this sleeping bud.
After 6 hours, take the cotton out.
Method 4
Use a fertilizer solution from fermented ginger after the leaves.
Helps kill fungi and insects very well
Cleaning the stomata helps orchids photosynthesize well.
Method 5
Apply this liquid fertilizer to the base of the orchid.
This type of fertilizer helps stimulate the growth of roots, branches and buds very well.
Method 6
Spray the fertilizer solution from fermented ginger on the entire orchid.
Supports nutritional supplementation through leaves very well.
RESULT
After 2 months, the sprouts and roots developed very well.
The flower buds have also developed and are ready to bloom.
The buds at the tips of the branches continue to grow and bloom.
Sprouts also grow in leaf axils.
Many branches grow on the same tree.
The flowers bloom on the branches for up to 6 months before falling.
The roots are likened to the soul of the orchid
Orchids grow healthy thanks to healthy roots
If the roots are healthy, the orchid will also grow many flower buds
In this video I will show you how to make orchids grow roots and flower buds quickly
You need 1 fresh ginger (about 50g)
Cut ginger into small pieces
put in a jar (recommended plastic jar)
add 3 tablespoons sugar (any sugar will do)
Add in 100ml of filtered water
Add in 100ml of beer (any beer is fine)
Cover and keep in a dark place for 1 month
Open the lid once every 3 days to let the gas out
1 MONTH LATER
The smell of GE ginger is fermented so it's very fragrant
ratio of mixing 3ml GE ginger for 1 liter of water
FIRST WAY
Soak cotton balls in water mixed with ginger GE
Place cotton balls soaked in GE ginger between the leaves
Helps keep moisture and GE ginger stimulates rooting and flower sprout differentiation very quickly
Change this cotton once every 3 days
On normal days when the cotton is dry,
you just need to mist it with water to keep it moist.
WAY 2
Use this water to wash the top and bottom of the leaves,
Helps provide nutrients through leaves,
clean stomata,
Eliminate harmful insects and fungi,
help orchid photosynthesis the best
Wipe the orchid leaves with GE ginger once a month
so that orchids are best protected and developed
WAY 3
Use GE ginger water to water orchids
Yeast brewed from fresh ginger has the effect of stimulating sprouting,
strong rooting, repelling insects, killing fungi, stimulating buds, and stimulating growth.
GE ginger also helps orchids increase their ability to absorb nutrients from the fertilizer you fertilize them.
Only do this 1-2 times a month
Do not use too much will affect the growth of orchids
SEE THE RESULTS
After 1 week of use, new roots grow very quickly
These roots will help the orchid absorb nutrients more easily and more
Orchids grow well or not thanks to the photosynthesis of roots and leaves
when the orchid is healthy, after the orchid branch blooms the last flowers,
Then there will be new flowers that will continue to grow.
With this simple way you can do it yourself to take care of orchids at home,
at very low cost and convenience
Hope the video content will help you take better care of orchids at home
My videos have subtitles in many other languages ​​for you to choose from.
Welcome to part 5 of the video
To help you have many choices when caring for orchids at home with organic fertilizer.
In this video, I continue to share new methods.
Subscribe to the video so you don't miss any tips on my channel.
Now, let's get started.
To make this type of organic fertilizer you need black tea (or tea grounds).
I use 3 teaspoons of black tea.
Add 1 liter of boiled water.
Incubate until the water cools.
After the water cools, filter to remove sediment.
Add water to make 5 liters of black tea solution.
Next add 1 teaspoon of baking soda.
FIRST METHOD
Water this fertilizer solution on the orchid roots.
Black tea contains many minerals and organic substances that help provide nutrition for orchids.
It contains nitrogen, potassium and phosphorus,
Important nutritional factors for orchid growth.
Baking soda (bicarbonate soda) has the ability to increase the PH level in orchid pots,
This is helpful in reducing acidity if you use too much chemical fertilizer.
Baking soda has the ability to kill insects and fungi that are harmful to plants.
SECOND METHOD
Spray this fertilizer on the entire orchid.
This method is similar to using foliar fertilizer.
You can use it as a natural pesticide to protect orchids from insects and diseases.
THIRD METHOD
Clean the leaf surface with this fertilizer solution.
The leaf surface will always be clean and the stomata will not be clogged.
Orchids will photosynthesize better.
RESULT
Plant roots are protected and supplemented with nutrients so they grow very healthily.
will help orchids absorb the most nutrients.
Because they are provided with enough nutrition, the flowers bloom more brilliantly.
Many flowers bloom on the same branch.
The flowers stay on the branches for a long time before fading.
Thank you for watching the video.
Wishing you luck and success in life.
Goodbye and see you again in the next videos.