Welcome to this video!
This is dendrobium orchid.
an orchid that is said to be beautiful and has a gentle fragrance.
They have the ability to bloom all year round and keep the flowers on the branches for a long time.
If you are looking for an easy way to breed this most beautiful orchid in the world?
Let me show you the simple yet effective secret!
I cut this old orchid to propagate.
Apply toothpaste to the cut to help it heal quickly.
then wait for the toothpaste to dry.
Recycle plastic bottles into tools to stimulate rooting and sprouting.
Dry cuts.
Take 1 aloe vera leaf.
Apply aloe vera gel all over this dry orchid.
Then wait for the aloe vera gel to dry.
Put the dry orchid branches into this plastic bottle.
Place the bottle here and insert moss around it to help retain moisture.
Water regularly to keep the environment moist.
This helps the orchid germinate faster.
Then put it in a cool place and wait for the orchid to revive.
2 MONTHS LATER
With this method, after only 2 months, the old withered orchid branches were revived.
Now I cut them out to plant in pots.
Hope the video will help you a lot.
If you find it interesting, please like, share and subscribe to my support channel.
Wishing you success and happiness in life
Goodbye and see you in the next videos.