Welcome to my channel.
To help you have many options when caring for orchids at home with organic fertilizer.
Helps develop new shoots. Flowers bloom profusely and last long.
In this video, I continue to share new methods.
To make this fertilizer, I reuse rice water when cooking rice.
You can use 200 grams of rice like me or more which is also very good.
After washing the rice, cover tightly and leave in a cool place for 24 hours.
Next I used about 10 grams of fresh ginger.
Ginger has the ability to stimulate plant growth, helping orchids grow strongly and produce more leaves and flowers.
After mincing, soak in 1 liter of boiled water.
and place in a cool place for 24 hours.
24 HOURS LATER.
Only decant the clear water above.
I do not use this cloudy water.
FIRST METHOD.
Clean the leaf surface with this liquid fertilizer.
The leaf surface will always be clean and the stomata will be clear.
Orchids will photosynthesize better.
If applied regularly, you will not encounter this problem.
Leaves will always be green.
SECOND METHOD.
Spray this fertilizer on the entire orchid.
Minerals contained in ginger and fermented rice water will help stimulate rooting and shoot growth very well.
Do this once a month to supplement nutrition and increase the orchid's resistance.
THIRD METHOD.
Now take this liquid fertilizer mixture and water it on the orchid roots.
Fertilizer from ginger and naturally fermented rice water helps supplement nutrients
and amino acids that are beneficial for orchid growth.
Especially helps stimulate germination and rooting extremely quickly.
ONE MONTH LATER.
Roots begin to sprout.
AFTER 2 MONTH.
The roots grow very healthily, helping the orchid absorb the most nutrients.
AFTER THE NEXT 2 MONTHS.
Many buds develop.
New sprouts grow very strong and grow quickly.
AFTER THE NEXT 3 MONTHS.
bloom many flowers.
The flower color is more vibrant than usual.
The flowers stay on the branches for a long time before fading.
If you find this video meaningful, please share it so more people know about this video.
And don't forget to subscribe to the channel so you don't miss any tips on my channel.
The video I have has subtitles in many different languages
Please choose subtitles in the appropriate language to clearly understand the content I share
Thank you for watching the video.
Good luck and see you in the next videos.