Welcome to my channel.
Today I will restore an exhausted orchid with wrinkled leaves in a very simple way.
Wake up any weak orchid pot, under any conditions.
Helps any orchid pot grow healthily, bloom brightly, and brighten up your living space.
To restore orchids I use garlic.
Please comment to me which country you are watching the video from!
It's great that we can chat together from all over the world!
Take 3 cloves of garlic and slice them.
If you haven't subscribed to the channel yet, please hit the subscribe button to support me
and not miss any orchid growing tips! It's great to have you along!
Put in a jar and soak with 2 liters of water for 2 hours.
An orchid has withered leaves and is exhausted.
Cut off all flower stems.
Then cut off all damaged roots.
Rinse with water.
Then leave it in a cool place and wait for the water to dry.
AFTER 2 HOURS.
Filter out residue.
Add water to make 3 liters of solution.
Add 3 Vitamin B1 tablets.
Soak for 20-30 minutes.
Next I recycled the plastic box to help restore the orchid.
Pour in some water.
Place the orchid branch in.
Regularly change the water when dirty.
And keep the orchid pot in a cool place, away from direct sunlight.
2 MONTHS LATER.
The orchid has recovered, its leaves are green and strong.
Roots grow very healthily.
How do you find the way to restore your weak orchid? Please write a comment to let me know your opinion. 🌸
I continue to grow orchids in new pots using the semi-hydroponic method.
This way of planting you will not have to water the orchids as much as with normal planting.
Hope the video will help you a lot.
Thank you for watching the video. Wish you luck and see you in the next videos.