Welcome to my channel.
This is an orchid infected with a fungus that leads to rot.
All roots are damaged
The entire root should be cut off
Only this leaf is still fresh so I will proceed to revive this orchid
Rinse with water to remove pathogenic fungi.
When eating garlic, don't throw away the peel because it has a very good antiseptic effect.
In addition, garlic peels also contain many nutrients to help orchids grow quickly.
Put the entire peel of 1 garlic bulb into the jar
Add 1 liter of boiled water
This is rice, it contains many amino acids and minerals such as:
Nitrogen, phosphorus, potassium and vitamins are necessary for orchid growth.
Add 3 tablespoons of rice and let it brew until the water cools so that the nutrients dissolve into the water.
1 hour later
Filter to remove residue
Now wipe the top and bottom of the leaves with this water
Helps kill fungi and insects, protecting orchids from pests and diseases
Then soak the orchid roots in this water for about 30 minutes to help stimulate root growth
Now you can recycle used plastic containers to make orchid pots like me
Use floral foam to grow orchids
Plant the orchid and clamp it tightly so the plant is not damaged when it roots
Add some water
The water level does not reach the orchid roots
and change the water when it seems dirty
Spray moisturizer every 3 days
Place the orchid in a cool place - Where there is light and a temperature of 25-30 degrees Celsius, the orchid will grow faster.
The remaining water is used to water weak orchids to help them take root quickly
Helps weak orchids recover quickly
You can also water blooming orchids with this water
Helps flower buds not fall off and flowers stay on branches long before fading
Flowers can bloom for up to 6 months before fading.
Doing this every 2 weeks for any orchid is good
1 month later
Many new roots grow
Orchids grow many young leaves and roots
The roots will help the orchid absorb nutrients and grow quickly
With this simple method, you can easily restore orchids at home..
I grow orchids in pots so they can grow naturally in the outside environment
Hopefully the video will help you a lot in taking care of orchids at home
If you find it interesting, please subscribe to the channel, like and share so more people know this orchid growing tip.
Thank you for watching the video. Good luck and see you in the next videos!