welcome to my
[Music]
channel in this video I share the method
of recovering weak orchids helping them
quickly take root and grow strongly
[Music]
I picked up a rotten Orchid that someone
had thrown away
[Music]
all the roots have
rotted which country are you watching
this video from please comment and let
me
know uh it's wonderful that we can
connect and chat with each other from
all around the
[Music]
world this original part has completely
rotted so it can no longer be used
[Music]
wash Orchid branches with
water then take one clove of garlic and
mince it
[Music]
is
add 500 mL of water and soak for 30
minutes letting the flour nutrition
completely dissolve in water
[Music]
after 30
minutes wiping Orchid branches with
garlic water helps disinfect and
eliminate fungal diseases
[Music]
then soak the Orchid branches in garlic
water for 10 minutes this helps
stimulate root and choot growth
[Music]
10 minutes later
because this orchid has many scars from
previous insect bites so I waited a day
for the Orchid to dry completely before
planting it
[Music]
one day
later I recycle sponges as orchid
nursery tools
[Music]
soaking the sponge in garlic water for
20 minutes helps disinfect and kill
[Music]
fungus 20 minutes later
insert the Orchid stem into the sponge
and place it in the
[Music]
vase pour some water into the jar and
change it every time it gets dirty
[Music]
spray moisturizer every 3 days and place
it in a cool well-lit
[Music]
place 5 Weeks Later
The Roots have grown very
[Music]
healthy The Roots have grown very
healthy
[Music]
I planted it in a pot so the Orchid
could grow
[Music]
better if you find the video interesting
please like and share so more people
know this tip
[Music]
water orchids regularly to keep them
moist subscribe to my channel to support
me and don't miss any tricks on my
channel
[Music]
welcome to part two of this video uh in
part two of this video I share how to
care for orchids to help them grow and
Bloom you can see that my orchids always
develop new flower stems after the old
flowers have fallen
off so my orchids bloom all year round
blooming from Branch to branch
[Music]
the flowers on the stems take a long
time to fall off they can even last up
to 6 months before the petals drop
[Music]
many flowers grow on the same
tree new Roots grow a lot to help absorb
nutrients best
[Music]
chubby flower
buds help flowers bloom long on branches
[Music]
brilliant
flowers how to make fertilizer as
follows use one small carrot weighing
about 30
[Music]
G cut into small pieces
add 1 liter of filtered
[Music]
water puree
filter out residue
[Music]
add 1 L of filtered
water then use cotton to soak carrot
juice and wipe both the top and bottom
sides of the leaves
[Music]
this method helps repel insects and open
the stamata the orchids will
photosynthesize and exchange nutrients
better
[Music]
at the same time orchids also absorb
some nutrients through the leaves
helping keep the leaves
[Music]
green for
second
[Music]
way water this carrot for
orchids carrot juice is a good source of
nutrients for orchids including vitamins
and minerals like beta carotene
potassium magnesium and
[Music]
phosphorus uh when the carrot juice is
poured into the Orchid pot it provides
nutrients to the orchids and helps to
promote their
[Music]
health in addition carrot juice is also
acidic which helps regulate the pH of
the Potted soil and enhances the
orchid's ability to absorb nutrients
[Music]
you can soak the Orchid pot in this
carrot juice for 20
[Music]
minutes do this one two times a
month Third Way
[Music]
Mist moisturizing carrot juice for
orchids by spraying both the top and
bottom of the leaves this helps wash
away dirt and eliminate insects on your
orchids the nutrients in carrot juice
support Orchid Health helping them
Thrive and Bloom beautifully
[Music]
however be careful not to overwater with
carrot juice as it can clog the water
channels in the
Orchid avoid spraying directly on the
flowers as this can cause them to fall
off
quickly I hope this video helps you take
better care of your orchids at home and
encourages them to bloom
easily um if you find it helpful and
interesting please like share And
subscribe to support my channel thank
you welcome to part three of today's
video to give you more options for
taking care of your orchids at home
using organic fertilizer in this video I
continue to share methods for making
natural fertilizer from everyday kitchen
ingredients you can find in your
[Music]
home subscribe to the video so you don't
miss any tips on my
[Music]
channel number
one to make this fertilizer you need
[Music]
apples apples contain potassium and
important mineral for orchid
[Music]
growth potassium helps orchids develop
stronger leaves roots and flowers
[Music]
uh I took the apple peel and put it in a
bottle soak in boiled water and leave
overnight
[Music]
number
two to make this type of fertilizer you
need more egg shells
[Music]
soak the eggshells in boiled water and
leave overnight
[Music]
after one night filter the water
so we have fertilizer from apples and
eggshells
[Music]
first
method water this fertilizer Solution on
the Orchid
[Music]
Roots eggshells provide natural calcium
which is very good for orchids they help
orchids stay healthy and increase
[Music]
resistance apple peels contain a lot of
phosphorus which is also an important
nutrient for orchid
[Music]
growth especially during the flowering
and flower development stage
[Music]
do this one to two times a month to
supplement nutrition and increase the
orchid's
[Music]
resistance second
method spray this fertilizer on the
entire
[Music]
Orchid this method is similar to using
folar fertilizer
[Music]
calcium and eggshells helps orchids stay
healthy and increases their resistance
to
[Music]
pests apples contain nitrogen an
essential nutrient that helps orchids
develop healthy green growth and
enhances their ability to
photosynthesize
[Music]
do not spray on flowers because wet
flowers will easily fall
[Music]
off third method
clean the leaf surface with this liquid
fertilizer the leaf surface will always
be clean and Airy
[Music]
orchids will photosynthesize
better fertilizing regularly one to two
times a month will help keep the leaves
[Music]
healthy number
three you can reuse eggshells and apple
peels to make fertilizer again
[Music]
let's check out the results
together this type of fertilizer
stimulates rooting very quickly
[Music]
after 1 month of use you will see great
results many flower buds develop and do
not fall
[Music]
blooming flowers stay on the branches
for a long time before
[Music]
fading flowers can remain on branches
for up to 6 months before
[Music]
falling thank you for watching the video
good luck and see you in the next videos
[Music]