Welcome to my channel.
You can see that this orchid is heavily attacked by fungi and bacteria.
It makes orchid leaves yellow and black rot.
If not handled promptly, this orchid can die very quickly.
First, remove all diseased leaves,
Otherwise, it will spread to the whole tree,
It even spreads to other healthy plants.
Cut off even damaged roots.
Since the orchid has no leaves, I have to cut off the flower bud,
Prioritize nutrients for small orchids to revive.
This is white cement.
Use 1 small spoon,
Add 0.5 liters of water
Wait 30 minutes.
AFTER 30 MINUTES OF WAIT.
Decant to see the clear water above.
Remove turbid water underneath.
Soak the whole orchid in this water for about 30 minutes.
AFTER WAITING FOR 30 MINUTES BILLION.
Hang in a cool place for 1 day.
After hanging for 1 day.
This is cinnamon powder.
I put cinnamon powder on all the cuts to disinfect.
Growing orchids with dry pine bark.
Leave in a cool place for 1 week without watering.
After 1 week without watering.
The cut is dry.
Use 1 liter of water.
Add 20 grams of aloe leaves.
Watering freshly made aloe vera for orchids.
Aloe vera juice contains many essential minerals and vitamins that help stimulate root growth,
It also stimulates germination.
Leave in a cool place and wait.
AFTER 3 WEEKS.
new sprouts.
From now on, water once every 5-7 days to keep moisture.
AFTER THE NEXT 2 MONTHS.
Orchid has revived and grown healthy.
From every 2 weeks, you fertilize organically as I have shared so that the orchid grows and flowers a lot