Hello everyone, to easily care for orchids to always grow healthily.
There are more flower buds and flowers stay on the branches longer.
Today I share a very easy way to keep orchids growing healthy.
I took a small aloe vera leaf and cut it into thin slices
Aloe vera contains many nutrients,
Very good for the growth of buds, flowers, roots and leaves
Aloe vera gel also has very good anti-drought effects
I cut aloe vera leaves thinly and put them in a jar.
Next I took a piece of bread.
Bread contains phosphorus, which plays an important role in plant growth, especially stimulating root growth.
Adding 1 teaspoon of yeast helps decompose organic matter faster and prevents it from rotting.
And adding a spoonful of sugar helps nourish the growth of beneficial microorganisms.
Add 500ml warm water.
Then leave in a cool place for 3 weeks.
3 weeks later.
Take 2-3 liters of water.
After 3 weeks of composting, we have this wonderful fertilizer.
Take 50ml.
then mix into water.
Method 1: Apply fertilizer to the roots.
Water each orchid pot with this water 10 spoons per week.
This fertilizer provides natural potassium, phosphorus and nitrogen which are important minerals that help improve plant health and vitality.
This type of fertilizer also helps retain water and enhances the plant's ability to absorb water.
The beneficial fungus Mycorrhiza will grow to help the plant more easily absorb nutrients from the orchid growing medium.
Method 2.
Use this water to spray on the leaves.
Helps supplement nutrients through leaves very effectively.
Helps orchid leaves become strong and healthy.
and sprayed on aerial roots to help aerial roots grow and easily absorb nutrients in the air.
You should do it early in the morning and by noon the leaves will dry very quickly.
Do this once a week to keep the orchid healthy.
Method 3:
Now I wash the leaves with this water.
Beneficial microorganisms will help kill mold and insects very effectively.
Do this every 2 weeks to protect your orchids.
Result
After fertilizing, the orchid will always be green and healthy.
Potassium and phosphorus found in aloe vera leaves and breadfruit help flower buds grow strongly.
When the flowers bloom, they will stay on the branches for a long time.
Flowers can last on branches for up to 6 months before fading.
Hopefully the video will help you a lot in taking better care of orchids at home.
Thanks for watching. Good luck and see you in the next video