Welcome to my channel.
In this video, I continue to share how to make orchids bloom at the same time with many flower branches.
Orchids after flowers fade.
We cut off all the spent flower stems.
If the plant has never bloomed, it must have 3 or more pairs of leaves.
and healthy roots.
Which country are you watching this video from? Please leave a comment and let me know!
It's amazing that we can chat together from all around the world!
Sprinkle cinnamon powder on the wound to help it heal quickly.
Then wait 1 day for the cut to dry.
Then take 1/2 small onion and cut it into thin slices.
Add 1 liter of water and bring to a boil.
Wait a day then use.
Next take 3 spoons of rice.
Then soak in 1 liter of water and leave for 1 day before using.
After a day, filter out the residue.
Mix the two types together.
Clean the leaves with this water.
Helps eliminate fungi and bacteria to help orchids grow better.
Do it once a week.
Then use this water to water the orchid roots.
This will help stimulate root and flower stem growth.
Do it once a week.
Place cotton balls between 2 leaves.
Then spray this water on the cotton pad.
This stimulates flower stems to grow.
and spray on the top and bottom of the leaves to help supplement nutrients through the leaves for the orchids.
This should be done early in the morning, so that by noon the leaves will dry before the sun shines.
After 30 minutes, remove the cotton and repeat once a week.
and take out the orchid pot.
2 Months Later.
Many flower stems grow at the same time.
Orchids also grow many new roots.
With this simple method, you can easily care for blooming orchids at home.
Tips for recovering rot-infected orchids
When orchids are old and have poor resistance, we need to rejuvenate them.
First you need to cut off all damaged leaves and roots.
Keep only fresh roots.
Onions have very good antiseptic and growth stimulating effects
Take about 20 grams of thinly sliced ​​onion.
Take 1 teaspoon of baking soda.
Helps balance PH levels and eliminate fungal diseases harmful to orchids.
Add 2 liters of water at room temperature.
Wait 30 minutes before using.
After 30 minutes, filter to remove residue.
Then water the orchid with onion water and baking soda.
Soak in this water for 30 minutes.
Cover the pot with a layer of dry moss.
Place the dried moss in this transparent plastic box.
Leave in a cool place for 1 day without watering.
1 Day Later.
From now on, water your orchids once a week.
Or water when the moss is dry.
Be careful to keep the moss moist. If the moss is waterlogged, the orchid will easily rot.
Then place it in a cool place with enough light for the orchid to grow.
3 Weejs Later.
Many baby orchids have sprouted.
Take 2 liters of water at room temperature.
Then add 5 spoons of rice.
Water the orchid with rice water once a week.
Helps stimulate baby orchids to grow and take root quickly.
Continue to place in a cool, well-lit place for the orchid to grow
After the next 1 month
The baby orchids grow very healthy.
Hopefully the video will help you a lot in taking care of orchids at home.
If you find it interesting, please click like and share so more people know.
And don't forget to subscribe to the channel so your channel can soon reach 1 million subscriptions.
Next, to help you have many options when caring for orchids at home with organic fertilizer.
Helps orchids grow and bloom with many, long-lasting flowers.
In this video, I continue to share new methods.
When eating oranges, don't rush to throw away the peel.
Right now I will share this tip for making organic fertilizer from orange peels.
If you haven't subscribed yet, please subscribe to support me and to not miss any orchid care tips.
And don't forget to share so more people can learn these great tips!
I cut the peel of an orange and put it in a jar.
Add 2 liters of warm water.
Then add 1 spoon of sugar and 1 spoon of yeast.
Punch holes in the lid, close the lid and leave in a cool place for 1 month.
1 MONTH LATER.
I already have GE orange peel fertilizer.
I took 4 tablespoons of GE orange peel.
mix 2 liters of water.
FIRST METHOD.
Use a GE orange peel to thoroughly wipe the top and bottom of the leaf.
Orange peels contain essential oils that after incubation will help repel insects very effectively
Helps leaves photosynthesize and create chlorophyll better.
Do this 1-2 times a month to protect orchids and keep the leaves green.
SECOND METHOD.
Applying this fertilizer to the roots 1-2 times per month helps provide organic substances such as:
humic acid, fulvic acid and enhance water retention in orchid growing media.
Orange peel also contains many important minerals such as potassium, magnesium, calcium and trace elements.
GE fertilizer helps orchids grow strongly and increase flower production.
GE fertilizer helps improve the ability of plants to absorb nutrients,
helping orchids make better use of available nutrients in the environment.
Let's see the results.
The flower color is more vibrant than usual.
Orchids bloom many flowers on the same tree but do not fall.
Flowers bloom continuously from season to season all year round.
The flowers stay on the branches for a long time before fading.
Thank you for watching the video. Good luck and see you in the next videos.