Hello friends
Nice to meet you on my channel
For orchids to grow healthily, they need strong roots.
Thanks to that, the orchid will grow sustainably and bloom with many flowers
In this video, I share a new type of organic fertilizer with ingredients available in every kitchen.
Cucumber products are excellent organic fertilizers for orchids
When eating cucumbers, keep the peel to use as fertilizer
Cucumber peel contains many nutrients such as potassium, magnesium,
and other vitamins, help plants grow strongly, especially stimulating the rooting and blooming process.
Take the cucumber peel and put it in a mortar
Next I need rice
Take 1 spoon of rice
500ml water
Incubate for 6 hours
6 Hours later
puree
Filter residue
Add 3 liters of water
First we need to clean the leaves
Take a cotton ball and wipe the leaves with this water
Thoroughly wipe both the top and bottom of the leaves 1-2 times a month
Helps remove dirt and residue from leaves
This method also kills fungi and insects that reside on leaves and harm orchids.
Carefully wipe the underside of the leaves as well.
Because the underside of leaves is often wet, insects and fungal diseases often hide there.
They just wait for an opportunity and when they encounter favorable conditions, they will cause diseases that destroy orchids.
This will also help keep the leaf's stomata open
and your orchid will photosynthesize the light better
Helps increase resistance for orchids
Method 1
Water each orchid pot with about 10 tablespoons of this water.
This type of fertilizer helps stimulate new roots very well
At the same time, it has the ability to keep the orchid growing environment moist.
Helps improve absorption
and nutrient exchange of the orchid growing environment.
This helps orchids grow stronger.
Do this regularly 1-2 times a month for sustainable orchid growth.
Promotes better rooting, budding and photosynthesis.
Stimulates blooming and produces more beautiful flowers.
Next, pour this water into the jar
Method 2
Now you spray the leaves and roots of the orchid.
Cucumber peel has good water retention properties,
Helps maintain essential moisture for plants, especially during dry periods.
This helps orchids grow steadily.
Some substances in cucumber peel have antibacterial properties,
Helps orchids resist some diseases and harmful bacteria.
Rice water contains many important nutrients such as starch,
protein, B vitamins and trace minerals,
Helps provide necessary nutrients for orchid growth.
These nutrients support growth, especially root and flower development.
Be careful not to spray this fertilizer on the flowers
Because when flowers get wet, they easily fall off
How to care for weak orchids
This orchid has withered leaves
Orchid roots are fresh but very weak
Clean the leaves to help remove dust and remove disease-causing fungi and leaf-damaging insects
This helps orchids photosynthesize light better
thereby making the tree more resistant
When orchid roots turn silver, it means the orchid needs watering
Water the orchid thoroughly with this water
Then spray this water on the entire orchid
Then place the plant in a cool place with enough light so the orchid can grow
Result
This weak orchid has developed many new roots
Other orchids' roots also grow very healthy
flowers bloom brilliantly
The flowers stay on the branches for a long time before fading
Thank you for viewing. Wishing you luck and success in life