Hello
friends when the new Orchid Withers all
its flowers this is the best time to cut
the flowers to help them Sprout
faster which country are you watching
this video from please comment below
it's so great that we can chat with each
other from all around the
[Music]
world uh peel off the protective film so
that the buds will germinate faster
[Music]
cut back the branch with a sharp knife
so as not to crush the cut
[Music]
pour melted candle solution into the cut
to help the cut heal quickly and not rot
[Music]
sprinkle cinnamon powder on the freshly
cut wound at the base to help protect
the Orchid from
rot use one large garlic clove or two
small garlic cloves
[Music]
hash small
put the garlic in the
[Music]
jar pour in 500 mL of water at room
temperature wait 30 minutes for the
nutrients from the garlic to dissolve
into the water
[Music]
use foam to arrange
flowers e
[Music]
uh after soaking for 30 minutes filter
out the
[Music]
residue soak Orchid branches in garlic
water for 30 minutes
[Music]
30 minutes
later take
out plug in the
[Music]
sucker pour in filtered water just
enough to moist
[Music]
close the lid and wait for the Orchid
Branch to
sprout after the next 3 weeks
[Music]
Sprouts have woken up
after one next
[Music]
month the Orchid Sprouts have grown and
The Roots have grown
[Music]
after the next 2 months
the small orchid has grown
[Music]
healthy now let's plant the Orchid in
pots so that it can adapt to the outside
[Music]
environment for
in my hand is a withered Orchid
[Music]
branch and in this video I will share so
you can propagate from any Orchid
Branch we cut off the spots that have
[Music]
bloomed just keep these three segments
and the Orchid can
[Music]
Sprout applying candle solution to the
cut will help protect the Orchid from
rotting
[Music]
peel off the protective film of the
sleeping sprout that's
[Music]
use one chopped fresh ginger
Branch boil 500 M of water and wait one
day
[Music]
after one day take it out and filter to
remove
[Music]
residue soak orchids in ginger water for
30 minutes
[Music]
soak the moss in ginger water for 30
minutes
[Music]
I use recycled plastic boxes to make
miniature green houses to help propagate
orchids
[Music]
faster there's a vent here
place the Orchid in a miniature
greenhouse and spray it with moisture
once a
[Music]
week place in a bright Place away from
direct
[Music]
sunlight 21 days later
continue misting to keep it moist and
keep it in a cool well-lit place away
from direct
[Music]
sunlight after next 10 days
continue misting to moisturize and leave
in a well-lit place avoiding direct
[Music]
sunlight after next 2 weeks
I
[Music]
plant in a pot so the Orchid can adapt
and grow in the outside environment
[Music]
if you find it interesting please
subscribe to the channel like and share
so more people know
[Music]
remember to plant the base higher than
the pot to prevent the Orchid from
rotting
[Music]
when the orchid has just lost all its
flowers it is the best time to propagate
from the flower
[Music]
stem buttons that have bloomed cannot be
propagated so so I cut off the nodes
that have finished
[Music]
blooming uh repair the cut to avoid
crushing the flower stem
[Music]
sprinkle cinnamon powder on the cut to
help it heal quickly and prevent
rot leave for one day for the cut to dry
completely
[Music]
one day
later peel off the protective film on
the flower
[Music]
button this helps baby orchids easily
germinate for
[Music]
now I use tomatoes to revive young
orchids from flower
[Music]
stems Tomatoes contain many important
nutrients such as nitrogen n phosphorus
p and potassium K which are essential
factors to promote the growth of orchids
[Music]
then you tie the Tomato core to this
position to awaken the baby Orchid
Sprouts to
[Music]
revive this helps baby orchids quickly
revive from flower stocks
[Music]
leave for about 30 minutes for the
nutrients to penetrate into the flower
stem
[Music]
after 30 minutes remove it
my
[Music]
then insert the flower stem into the
sponge place in a transparent
jar and pour a little water to always
have the right humidity for the baby
orchids to revive
[Music]
cover with transparent plastic and keep
in a cool
[Music]
place 3 weeks later
the flower branches have begun to revive
the baby orchids
[Music]
continue to put it in the vase and place
it in a cool place for the baby orchids
to grow
[Music]
after the next one
month baby orchids have formed from
flower stems
[Music]
the baby orchids also take root at the
same
[Music]
time both the small Orchid and its roots
are healthy
[Music]
continue to put it in the vase and place
it in a cool place for the baby orchids
to
[Music]
grow after the next 2 months
uh this simple method helps baby orchids
grow very
[Music]
healthily now plant them in pots so they
can grow outside
[Music]
uh if you find it interesting please
like share and subscribe to the channel
to support
[Music]
me I have created subtitles in many
different languages so you can choose
the appropriate language
[Music]
now plant in a pot so the Orchid can
grow in an outdoor environment
if you find it interesting please
subscribe to my channel to support me
don't forget to hit the like button and
share this video so others can Discover
it too every bit of support from you
motivates me to create even better
[Music]
videos thank you for watching ing the
video good luck and and see you in the
next videos