Hello friends
To help you actively propagate orchids at home
Today I share how to propagate from phalaenopsis branches
After all the flowers have faded
Peel off the protective film of the sleeping sprout
This will make it easier for this sleeping sprout to germinate
1. Apply toothpaste on the freshly cut wound
Toothpaste has antiseptic properties, so it will help the cut heal quickly and protect the orchid from rotting
Wait for the toothpaste to dry
Chopped
Squeeze to let the aloe vera gel come out
Aloe vera helps stimulate sprouts to germinate faster
3. Use 1 teaspoon of cinnamon powder with 500ml of boiled water
Incubate for 2 hours
Filter out residue
Mix aloe vera gel with cinnamon juice in the ratio 1/1
4. Soak orchid branches in solution of aloe vera gel and cinnamon water for 20 minutes
5. Soak moss in cinnamon water for 20 minutes
6. Recycle plastic boxes into miniature greenhouses to help propagate orchids faster
Perforated air vents above and below the box
After soaking for 20 minutes, remove the moss
7. Put orchid branches in miniature greenhouse
Mist once every 5 days and keep it in a shady place, away from direct sunlight
Continue misting once every 5 days and keep in a shady place, away from direct sunlight
If you find it interesting, don't forget to like, share and subscribe to the channel to support me
Now let's plant pots so that the orchid can adapt to the outside environment
Now goodbye and see you in the next videos