Welcome to Happy Garden channel! Wish everyone a good day
This is dendrobium orchid.
an orchid that is said to be beautiful and has a gentle fragrance.
They have the ability to bloom all year round and keep the flowers on the branches for a long time.
If you are looking for an easy way to breed this most beautiful orchid in the world?
Let me show you the simple yet effective secret!
I cut this old orchid to propagate.
Which country are you watching videos from? Please comment for me.
It's great that we can chat together from all over the world.
Apply toothpaste to the cut to help it heal quickly.
then wait for the toothpaste to dry.
Recycle plastic bottles into tools to stimulate rooting and sprouting.
If you haven't subscribed to the channel yet, please hit the subscribe button to support me
and to not miss any orchid care tips on my channel! Thank you so much!
You can see the cut after applying the toothpaste has dried.
Take 1 aloe vera leaf.
Apply aloe vera gel all over this dry orchid.
Then wait for the aloe vera gel to dry.
Put the dry orchid branches into this plastic bottle.
Place the bottle here and insert moss around it to help retain moisture.
Water regularly to keep the environment moist.
This helps the orchid germinate faster.
Then put it in a cool place and wait for the orchid to revive.
2 MONTHS LATER
If you haven't subscribed to the channel yet, please hit the subscribe button to support me
and to not miss any orchid care tips on my channel! Thank you so much!
With this method, after only 2 months, the old withered orchid branches were revived.
Now I cut them out to plant in pots.
Hope the video will help you a lot.
If you find it interesting, please like, share and subscribe to my support channel.
Wishing you success and happiness in life
Take care of your orchids with all your love and dedication,
and you will be greeted by the vibrant Dendrobium flowers,
emitting a gentle fragrance that makes life more beautiful and full of joy.
Welcome to part 2 of the video!
Today I share how to propagate orchids from old withered branches.
This is a vegetable glue. It prevents water from seeping inside.
You can also replace this glue by burning a candle and putting it on to prevent it from getting waterproof.
Scrape off the outer membrane so that the sprouts are easy to germinate.
You use 1 clove of garlic.
Apply garlic juice to newly shaved areas to wake up the sprouts.
I use a type of moss (the type of moss used to grow orchids).
Fill with water and check the humidity.
Put the orchid branch in.
Cover up.
Place it in a place that gets daylight but don't leave it in direct sunlight.
after 1 month.
As you can see, from an old and withered orchid branch,
it has now been revived into many healthy orchid seedlings,
and they are growing very strong and rooting very well.
Now plant in a pot so the orchid can grow in the outside environment.
Hope you like this video! Please comment and let me know.
If you enjoyed the video, don't forget to like, share it so more people can see it,
and subscribe to the channel to support me in reaching 10 million subscribers soon!
Take care of your orchids with all your love and dedication,
and you will be greeted by the vibrant Dendrobium flowers,
emitting a gentle fragrance that makes life more beautiful and full of joy.
Thank you for watching the video. Wish you luck and success in life.