Welcome everyone to my channel
This is an orchid with leaf rot caused by a fungus
We need to separate the diseased plant from other orchids
Now I will share how to restore this rotten orchid with only 1 leaf
Cut off all damaged roots
Cut off all rotten parts of the orchid stem
This will help prevent the orchid stem from rotting further
Cut off wilted branches
Helps remove dust, mold, and insects on orchidsThis will help prevent the orchid stem from rotting furtherRinse with water
Rinse with water
Helps remove dust, mold, and insects on orchids
This is saffron starch
Take 3 teaspoons of saffron starch and put it in a glass
Add 500ml of water
Wait 10 minutes for the saffron essence to completely dissolve in the water
10 minutes later
Filter out residue
Step 1
Thoroughly wipe the top and bottom of the leaf
Helps remove dirt, mold, and insects hiding on leaves that harm orchids
Saffron starch is rich in antioxidants and has antibacterial properties,
Helps orchids increase their resistance to mold, bacteria and other harmful agents.
This helps the plant avoid root rot or disease during growth.
Then place the orchid roots in this glass
Step 2
Soak orchid roots in saffron starch water for 20 minutes
Saffron starch contains natural nutrients
Has the ability to promote root growth and rapid germination.
Dissolve the remaining safaron water and add 1 liter of water
Then water each orchid pot with about 10 tablespoons of water.
Saffron provides a large amount of essential nutrients
helps orchids grow healthily.
Plants can grow faster,
Leaves and stems become strong and full of vitality.
Fertilize orchids with this fertilizer 1-2 times/month,
combined with other organic fertilizers that I have shared on the channel.
will help your orchids stay healthy and full of vitality
After soaking for 20 minutes, take the orchid out and use cotton to absorb all the water from the roots
Then sprinkle saffron starch on the cut
This helps the cut heal quickly
At the same time, saffron starch also stimulates faster rooting
Then leave it for 1 day for the cutting to dry completely before planting
1 Day later
Recycle plastic bottles into orchid nursery tools
Place a cotton ball here to help absorb water and retain moisture better
Then place the orchid root on top of the flower and put it all in the vase
Pour in filtered water but do not let the filtered water touch the roots
The water will seep through the cotton pad and create moisture for the orchid roots to grow
Spray mist with water to keep orchid leaves moist once a day
Results after 50 days
The roots grow many new roots
From the old orchid stem, two baby orchids have grown on both sides
There was a small orchid that was attacked by insects and ate its leaves
I planted the orchid in a new pot so the orchid can grow in an outside environment
Planting with bark will help the roots breathe and reduce root rot
After planting orchids, water with saffron starch again
Thank you for watching this video. Good luck and happiness in life