Welcome to my channel.
If you want orchids to grow well.
and blooms all year round.
vibrant flower color.
Roots grow strongly to absorb more nutrients.
The flowers bloom for a long time before fading.
Many flowers bloom at the same time on the same branch.
Let's start exploring.
To make this wonderful fertilizer you need to take about 5 teaspoons of rice.
Then soak the rice in 1.5 liters of water.
Then incubate for 30 minutes to let the nutrients dissolve into the water.
After 30 minutes, filter the water.
Next take 1 spoon of yeast (yeast used to make bread).
Incubate for 2 hours to increase beneficial microbial biomass in yeast.
After 2 hours of composting I had a great amount of fertilizer.
FIRST METHOD.
Wipe the top and bottom of the leaves with this fermented rice water solution
Yeast helps eliminate fungi and harmful microorganisms very effectively.
With this method, you do it 1-2 times/month to protect orchid leaves.
SECOND METHOD
Use this liquid fertilizer to water the roots.
Rice water contains many minerals and nutrients that are beneficial to plants such as:
potassium, phosphorus and trace minerals.
These nutrients help provide good energy for orchids to grow.
The enzymes in rice water help orchids absorb water and nutrients from the substrate better.
Soaking orchid pots in this solution for 30 minutes will be better.
THIRD METHOD.
You can spray this fermented rice water on the entire orchid plant.
Spray thoroughly on both the top and bottom of the leaves.
This method of watering roots and spraying leaves is also applied 1-2 times/month.
But you should not spray it on flowers because wet flowers will quickly fall off.
RESULT
If you regularly apply this method, the orchid will always be green.
Yeast protects and stimulates root growth very well.
When orchids have healthy roots, they will help absorb nutrients best.
If the orchid is nutritious and healthy, the flowers will have more vibrant colors.
The flowers bloom on the branches for a long time before fading.
and bloom continuously from one season to the next.