Welcome to my channel
If you have an orchid with yellow leaves like this,
Don't rush to throw it away.
What to do is: Remove all damaged leaves and roots.
This orchid only has 1 leaf that is still fresh and can recover.
The original part is completely damaged so it should be thrown away.
Rinsing with water helps remove mold and dirt
Take 1 clove of garlic.
cut into thin slices.
Add 1 liter of warm water.
Use honey
Take 1 spoon of honey.
Honey and garlic have antiseptic properties that help eliminate fungal orchid diseases
Leave for 30 minutes for the nutrients to completely dissolve in the water before restoring the orchid
30 minutes later
Use cotton to clean the top and bottom of the leaves
Helps remove mold, dirt and larvae that damage orchids
Then soak the orchid leaves in this water for 30 minutes
Helps kill fungal diseases and stimulate rooting
I recycle plastic bottles into orchid nursery equipment
Please use makeup remover cotton and do like me
Cotton helps retain moisture so this orchid roots quickly
You pour water into the jar like I did
Just let the water level reach this position
The water will be absorbed and the orchid will quickly take root
Then every 3 days spray the orchid with water to keep it moist
When the water is dirty, change the water to keep the orchid from rotting
and place it in a cool place with lots of light, the orchid leaves will revive quickly
3 Weeks Later
Even though the leaves are still withered, the orchid roots still grow very healthily,
and orchids grow new leaves.
As the roots grow, they will absorb water and nutrients and the leaves will become fresh again very quickly.
Now I plant it in a new pot so the orchid can grow in an outside environment
With this simple method, you can completely revive weak orchids at home easily
Hopefully the video will help you a lot in taking better care of orchids at home
If you find the video meaningful, don't forget to subscribe to the channel and click like and share so more people know
My videos have subtitles in many different languages. Please choose the appropriate language to clearly understand the video content
And don't rush to leave the video because part 2 of the video is also very interesting
Next To help you have many options when caring for orchids at home with organic fertilizer.
In this video, I continue to share new methods.
Subscribe to videos so you don't miss any Tips on my channel.
To perform this type of analysis, you need soybeans.
Take 60 grams of soybeans.
Then soak in 600ml of boiled water.
Wait until the water cools.
Once cooled, grind the soybeans with a blender.
Pour into jar.
Next add 30 grams of sugar.
Then add 30 grams of composting microorganisms.
Cover this hole with cotton wool.
This prevents insects from entering the jar and air can still circulate in and out of the jar.
Store in a cool place, away from direct sunlight for 3 weeks.
This is the product I made after 3 weeks.
Take 10ml of fermented soybean fertilizer.
and dilute with 3 liters of water.
FIRST METHOD
Water this fertilizer solution on the orchid roots.
Soybean fertilizers are often rich in nitrogen, potassium and other nutrients,
Helps provide necessary nutrients for orchids.
Nitrogen helps plants grow green leaves, potassium promotes flowering
and keeps flowers on branches for a long time.
Fermented soybean fertilizer provides adequate nutrients for plants to help strengthen the immune system,
Helps plants become more resistant to diseases and pests.
Do this 1-2 times/month to supplement nutrition and increase the orchid's resistance.
SECOND METHOD.
Spray this fertilizer on the entire orchid.
This method is similar to using foliar fertilizer.
Spraying aerial roots helps aerial roots develop.
THIRD METHOD.
Clean the leaf surface with this liquid fertilizer.
The leaf surface will always be clean and airy with stomata.
Orchids will photosynthesize better.
Fertilizing regularly 1-2 times/month will help keep the leaves healthy.
RESULT
After 3 times of applying this fertilization method, the root system has developed very strongly.
Soybean fertilizer helps orchids grow strongly and bloom more.
Nutrients like phosphorus and potassium in this fertilizer
Promotes plants to bloom
and produce more beautiful flowers.
Thank you for watching the video. Good luck and see you in the next video.