Welcome to my channel
This is a wilted orchid that people throw away
wilted, wrinkled leaves
Orchid has all its roots damaged
I will remove all damaged roots
Cut out all the flowers
Rinse thoroughly under running water
Remove infected leaves
Sprinkle cinnamon powder on the freshly cut wound and sprinkle on the root
Cinnamon powder helps wounds dry quickly and kills fungi
Soak 5 tablespoons of rice in 500ml of water at room temperature
Stir well and wait 30 minutes for the nutrients to mix into the water
Use the shells of 5 poultry eggs soaked in 500ml of boiled water
Close the lid and wait 2 hours for the nutrients to mix into the water
Decant the water inside to wash the leaves
Rice water helps to get rid of fungi and insects
At the same time, rice water also contains many vitamins, amino acids and minerals such as:
vitamins A, B, E and natural protein, phosphorus, potassium
will help spread the recovery quickly
I grow orchids with gravel and moss
Mix rice water with water to soak egg shells
The combination of eggshell and rice water will create special nutrients
Place the orchid pot in a cool place, out of direct sunlight
2 months later
Lan has grown 2 new leaves
2 old leaves are still wilted at first
The orchid has grown a lot of new roots
Strong roots will help the plant absorb enough water and nutrients
Only then will the withered leaves be restored and become lush
here orchids have buds
Here is another big bud
From now on, take care of it like any other normal orchid
That's all I want to share in this video
Thank you for watching.
I will be very happy if you like, share and subscribe to the video to help the channel reach 10 million subscribers soon
Now goodbye and see you in the next videos