Hello friends.
In this video, I share the method to restore love orchids.
causes even the weakest orchids to take root immediately and bloom continuously
This orchid has withered leaves and is so weak that it cannot bloom.
Remove old growing medium.
Cut off all damaged roots.
Cut off wilted flower stems.
Rinse with water
Use 2 spoons of rice, rice is rich in polyphenols, calcium, magnesium, vitamins,...
Add 1 liter of water.
Take 2 spoons of cinnamon powder.
Cinnamon powder will help orchids fight bacteria and disinfect.
At the same time, it helps the tree recover very quickly.
Add 1 liter of water to boil.
Wait for the water to cool before using.
1 Hour later.
Mix cinnamon water with rice water.
Use this water to thoroughly wipe the top and bottom of the leaves.
It will help these leaves recover so the plant doesn't get fungus.
At the same time, adding nutrients, vitamins, and amino acids helps orchids recover quickly.
Then soak the roots in this water for 30 minutes.
Helps destroy fungi and insects that damage roots and stimulates rapid root growth.
30 minutes later.
Now I grow semi-hydroponic orchids in cups like this
Then pour water to cover 1/2 of the roots..
When the water is dirty, change the water immediately.
And every week you soak the roots in rice water for 30 minutes to stimulate orchid growth.
Spray moisturizer once every 3 days to keep the leaves from wilting further.
Place the orchid in a cool, well-lit place.
With this remaining water, you can take care of the blooming orchids.
It will help the orchid cling to the branch for a long time before it withers.
Blooming flowers will have more vibrant colors than usual.
1 Month later
The leaves have gotten stronger and have grown many new roots.
These new roots will absorb water and nutrients better, helping wilted orchid leaves recover faster.
When the roots grow healthy like this, you can plant them in a pot to help the orchid grow better.
My videos have subtitles in many different languages. You can choose the appropriate language.
and you take care of it like other normal orchids.
The orchid will quickly recover and bloom again.
With this care, my orchid recovered and bloomed after 3 months.
Don't rush to leave the video because part 2 will be more interesting
In my hand is a withered orchid branch
And in this video I will share so that you can propagate from any orchid branch
We cut off the spots that have bloomed
Just keep these 3 paragraphs can still sprout
Applying candle solution on the cut will help protect the orchid from rot
Peel off the protective film of the sleeping sprout
Use 1 sprig of chopped fresh ginger
500 ml of boiled water
wait 1 day
Soak orchids in ginger water for 30 minutes
Soak moss in ginger water for 30 minutes
I use recycled plastic boxes to make miniature greenhouses to help propagate orchids faster
There's a vent here
Put the orchid in a miniature greenhouse and spray it with moisture once a week
Place in a bright place and avoid direct sunlight
21 DAYS AFTER
Continue misting to keep moisture and keep in a light place, avoid direct sunlight
AFTER 1O NEXT DAY
AFTER 2 NEXT WEEKS
Plant in pots to let the orchid adapt and grow in the outside environment
If you find it interesting, please subscribe to the channel, like, share to let more people know
My videos have subtitles in different languages. Please select the appropriate language to understand the video content clearly
Remember to plant the root higher than the pot so that the orchid does not have root rot
That's all I want to share with you in this video
Now goodbye and see you in the next videos