Hello friends
Today I will show you how when we need to water the orchid
When the orchid's roots are green like this, the orchid has enough water
The leaves will be green and sturdy
But if the roots turn white, the plant is lacking water
check the potting medium you will find it very dry
Leaves will wilt very quickly if we don't water them in time
In this case, we need to quickly water the orchid
HOW TO WATER AS FOLLOWING:
Place the orchid pot in a deep dish and water the substrate completely
If the roots are still fresh but the leaves are wilted, we can soak the orchid in water for 20-30 minutes
With pots using moss growing medium, the ability to retain moisture is very good,
so we only need to water enough moisture.
and no need to soak.
Eat bananas, don't throw away the peels
Banana peel contains a lot of vitamins and minerals:
vitamins A, B, C, E and protein, phosphorus, especially rich in potassium.
Potassium resists drought very well, helps the orchid to transport water from the root to the top, so the orchid does not wilt
At the same time, potassium helps to stimulate flower growth and keep flowers fresh for a long time
We cut banana peels
Put all banana peels in a jar and pour 500ml of boiled water
Then incubate for 1 day for the nutrients to dissolve into the water
5 vitamin b1 tablets mixed with 500ml of filtered water
B1 helps plants to better absorb nutrients
and growth regulator
It also stimulates root growth very well
After 1 day of incubation, we mix banana juice with vitamin B1 water to get 1 liter of synthetic organic fertilizer solution.
Divide into a spray bottle
Spray the top and bottom of the leaves evenly
Orchid plants are provided with a part of nutrients that are supplemented through the leaves
At the same time, it also eliminates insects to help the orchid stay green
You can also use a cotton ball soaked in this synthetic organic fertilizer solution to wipe the leaves
Do this 1-2 times a month, the orchid will always be protected and green
Next, you use this liquid synthetic organic fertilizer solution to irrigate the orchid
do 1-2 times a month and combine with other organic fertilizers that I have shared on the channel
It will help orchids easily absorb nutrients
Vitamin B1 helps stimulate root growth
Potassium in banana juice will stimulate flower growth and help flowers stay fresh for a long time
It is truly the perfect formula for the full development of roots, leaves and flowers
It's very good, but you should not overdo it, it will harm the orchid
You should only fertilize according to my instructions so that your orchid garden always blooms without affecting the growth of orchids.
Please comment below about your results
Please comment in the video so that I can help you further if your lan has problems
My videos have subtitles in different languages, please choose the right language to understand the video content I share.
If you find it interesting, don't forget to like, share and subscribe to support me
Don't rush to leave this video and continue watching part 2/2 to support me
If there is anything you don't understand, please comment below the video so I can help you
Thank you for watching the video!
Welcome to part 3 of the video
To easily care for orchids to always grow healthily.
A healthy root system helps absorb the most nutrients.
and have more flower buds, flowers stay on the branches longer.
These are coffee grounds.
I took about 50 grams of coffee grounds and put them in a jar
When eating bananas, don't throw away the peel.
Because banana peels contain many nutrients, especially organic potassium.
Very good for the growth of buds, flowers and has anti-drought effects.
I cut the banana peel thinly and put it in a jar.
Then add 3 tablespoons of sugar.
Sugar helps nourish beneficial microorganisms.
and add 3 tablespoons of dry yeast to help decompose organic matter quickly and not rot.
And add 1 liter of warm water.
Warm water helps beneficial microorganisms grow and ferment faster than cold water.
Then place in a cool place for 21 days to let the organic matter decompose before using.
with orchids with wilted leaves and slow growth.
I take care of it with organic fertilizer from coffee grounds and banana peels and it will be very good.
Checking the roots, I found that this orchid had many damaged roots underneath.
The cause may be that the growing medium is moldy and dry.
All damaged roots need to be removed.
Then rinse with water.
I replanted the orchid with a more porous growing medium, which helps retain moisture better.
After composting, the compost ferments so there is a white scum on top.
I took 50ml of this organic nutrient.
Mix with 3 liters of water.
Step 1
Wiping the top and bottom of leaves with this water helps kill fungi and insects that harm orchids.
Do this every 2 weeks to protect your orchids.
Step 2
Use this water to spray the leaves once a week.
Helps supplement nutrients through leaves very effectively.
Helps leaves recover quickly, orchid leaves will be strong and healthy quickly
Step 3
Water each orchid pot with this water once a week.
This fertilizer provides potassium, an important mineral that improves plant health and vitality.
The beneficial fungus Mycorrhiza will grow to help the plant more easily absorb nutrients from the orchid growing medium.
Soak in this water for 10 minutes then take out.
Place in a cool place with enough light for the orchid to recover.
2 MONTHS LATER
Many new roots develop to help the orchid absorb nutrients better.
When the roots absorb enough water and nutrients, the orchid will recover faster.
Thanks to that, the leaves have completely recovered and are no longer wilted.
I continue to wash the leaves with this water once a week.
Then continue to spray this water on the orchid once a week.
and continue watering and soaking the roots once a week with this water.
After the next 2 months.
The orchid has completely recovered and is growing very strongly.
It blooms many flower buds.
Roots grow very healthy.
If you find it interesting, don't forget to like, share and subscribe to the channel so you don't miss any tips.
Thank you for watching the video. Good luck and see you in the next videos.