Welcome to my channel.
In this video, I share about the mystery behind the growth speed of orchid roots that few people know.
These are orchids that people throw away.
The leaves of this tree are still fresh so I will restore them.
This orchid's damage may be due to inorganic fertilizer shock.
Orchid growing media contaminated with many molds are also harmful to orchids.
We need to cut off all damaged branches, leaves, and roots.
The roots were completely damaged.
The orchid stem has also completely dried up.
Only 1 leaf left on the top is still fresh.
Remove yellow leaves due to disease.
then rinse with water.
Sprinkle cinnamon powder on the cut to help it heal quickly.
Leave for 1 day without watering until the wound is completely healed before planting.
Using vinegar helps reduce the pH of the soil, creating good conditions for the growth of orchids.
Take 3 tablespoons of vinegar.
Honey is antibacterial and contains natural sugars such as glucose and fructose,
which help energize orchids and stimulate their growth.
Take 1 teaspoon of honey.
Add 500ml of water.
Leave for 1 day before using.
1 Day Later
Wiping orchid leaves with this water helps eliminate fungi and bacteria that cause diseases in orchids.
Soak the leaf stalks in this water for 30 minutes.
This helps stimulate roots and sprouts to grow very quickly.
The remaining water is used to irrigate other normal orchids.
Helps roots grow healthily.
The flowers bloom on the branches for a long time before fading.
Fertilizing 1 to 2 times a month will help orchids bloom more and stay fresh longer.
The flowers bloom more brightly than usual.
Increases resistance to fungi and bacteria that cause orchid diseases.
I use jute rope to grow orchids.
Then wrap the jute rope around the leaf stem.
Jute rope has the ability to absorb water and retain moisture very well.
Pour filtered water into the jar.
This wire will absorb water to help keep the leaf drain moist.
then put in a cool place.
1 Month Later
You can see the roots are growing very well.
and also grew another young leaf
If the roots grow healthy like this, plant it in a pot so it can grow in the outside environment.
My videos have subtitles in many different languages. Please select subtitles in the appropriate language.
If you find it interesting, remember to like, share and subscribe to my support channel.
Thank you for watching the video. Good luck and see you in the next videos!.