Welcome to Happiness Garden channel
In this video, I share how to grow it to grow fast
When I just bought orchids,
We remove all this moss,
Because these orchid pots are grown in an industrial environment,
controlled by temperature, humidity, and light Ideal for orchids.
but when brought back, the environment has been changed, making these roots easy to rot
You should cut off the damaged roots.
Then wash the roots.
Use used plastic bottles
I recycle to grow semi-hydroponic orchids
This way of growing will not need watering
but still help the orchid grow very strong,
the flowers are more beautiful and brilliant, invite you to watch.
I need to wash the plastic bottle to make sure it's clean from fungi,
and bacteria that are harmful to the orchid.
Using the drill bit will cut out the positions here
This part will be used as an orchid pot
The rest is for water storage
Using a glass jar on the bottom will help the roots not absorb too much water.
Put the orchid in
Put terracotta seeds around the pot
grown in a semi-hydroponic environment, often in contact with water
so we use breathable terracotta beads is the best
If it's breathable, it's very rarely rotten
And after planting, the roots will grow very fast
I finished planting
you water the potted plants,
We only water once, next time you don't need to water anymore
With this simple planting method, you save a lot of time to take care of
With this planting method, you will let the water level cover part of the bottom of the pot
The water will absorb itself, helping to maintain the moisture in the growing medium,
we will not need to water anymore.
When the water in the container is empty, remember to add more water to keep the growing medium in a moist state
This is an orchid, I planted it according to this method, it is growing very fast now
The flowers are long-lasting and have many branches on the same branch.
This orchid I grow semi-hydroponic with pine bark
Flowers bloom brilliantly, boldly, and last longer
growing semi-hydroponic orchids, the moisture is always well maintained,
the roots will grow very quickly
It will help plants perform metabolism, absorb organic fertilizer and water very well.
With this simple planting method, we will get orchids that grow faster.
Hope the video will help you a lot.
Next, I share how to help restore this wilted orchid.
First you need to cut off the damaged roots
Next, apply the candle to the spot you just cut so that the water does not seep into the body of the orchid.
Take filtered water at room temperature
Add coconut fiber to keep moisture
Apply the gel of the onion to the stem of the orchid to stimulate growth
Keep in a place with daylight and do not place in direct sunlight because sunlight will cause orchids to rot.
AFTER 2 WEEKS
The orchid stem is fresh again and grows a small sprout
AFTER 2 MONTHS
This is an old and wilted phalaenopsis orchid
Don't rush to throw it away
I will share tips to help it recover quickly
I use aloe vera to revive it
There are many gels in aloe vera leaves
Aloe vera gel contains a lot of nutrients, vitamins and minerals to help plants revive quickly
I pour water at room temperature to wet the orchid growing medium
Fill this tray with water so that the steam rises to help the medium and the environment in the orchid growing area stay moist
To tree lan into
cover back. Keep in a place with soft light. Be careful not to expose to direct sunlight.
After 1 week I will open it. You will be very surprised to see
If you find it interesting, please like, share and subscribe to help the channel reach 1 million subscribers soon
Next, I share how to propagate orchids from old, withered branches
This is a vegetable glue. It prevents water
This is a vegetable glue. It prevents water from seeping inside
You can also replace this glue by burning a candle and putting it on to prevent it from getting waterproof
Scrape off the outer membrane so that the sprouts are easy to germinate.
You use 1 clove of garlic
Apply garlic juice to newly shaved areas to wake up the sprout
I use a type of moss
Fill with water and check the humidity
Put the orchid branch in
Cover up
Keep in a place with daylight. You must not leave it in direct sunlight
after 1 month
Next, I share how to propagate and stimulate rooting for orchids easily.
Blot the cut dry
Light a candle and apply it on the cut so the water doesn't get in.
That way the orchid will not rot.
Take 1 small piece of ginger
Store in a place with daylight and take care not to expose to direct sunlight.
After 3 weeks
after 3 months
Next, I share how to help wilted orchids quickly produce new flowers
These are withered branches. I helped it grow many new branches quickly.
My secret is to use a potato.
Choosing germinated potatoes will be very good
Potato sprouts are very good growth stimulants for plants
Use 10 grams of potatoes
Add 500ml room temperature water and puree
Cut off the top because there are no sprouts
Let the cut dry naturally
Peel off the outer dry film so that the sprouts can grow easily
Dip a sponge in the potato water you just made and place it where the sprouts are
Repeat this once a week to allow the potato juice to penetrate and stimulate germination
On normal days, you just need to mist to keep moisture
Wait 2-3 weeks, new flower sprouts like this
Hope this sharing content will help you in taking care of orchids at home better.
If you find it interesting, please like, share and subscribe to the channel to help me reach 1,000,000 subscribers
The video I have created many subtitles in many different languages, so you can choose the appropriate language
Good luck. See you in the next video.