Welcome to a unique video tutorial on water orchid propagation!
We will show you how to simply and effectively regenerate all your favorite orchids.
Let's discover how to create amazingly beautiful flowers from these fun propagation methods.
See now to become a master gardener and enjoy the natural beauty of your beautiful orchids!
This is a pot of Dendrobium orchids.
This old orchid won't be able to resurrect itself, so I cut it off from the base.
These nodes can sprout into small orchids.
Now I cut the nodes to propagate.
After cutting, you should immediately apply toothpaste on the cut to disinfect.
This helps protect the cut from rot.
then wait for the toothpaste to dry.
I recycle used plastic baskets for orchid propagation.
After the toothpaste at the tip of the cut had dried, I clipped the orchid to a plastic basket.
Pour 1 liter of room temperature water into the bowl.
Soak 2 vitamin B1 tablets in this water.
Add 3 cloves of garlic.
Cut into small pieces.
Soak the garlic in this water for 2 hours so that the nutrients in the garlic dissolve into the water.
AFTER 2 HOURS
Then soak the orchid branch in garlic juice mixed with vitamin B1 for 30 minutes.
AFTER 30 MINUTES.
Remove the orchid from the pot of water.
Pour room temperature water into the basin.
Use a sponge to form a float.
It helps the orchid to always float on the water.
The steam that rises will help the orchid germinate easily.
1 MONTH LATER.
The nodes of the orchid branch have developed into small orchid sprouts.
With this simple method, after only 1 month, the old orchid branch was revived.
I continue to put the orchid branch in the pot of water so that the small orchid branch grows more.
Remember to change the water weekly.
AFTER 1 NEXT MONTH.
Small orchids grow very fast.
Roots grow very healthy.
This way you can apply propagation to all other types of orchids.
Hope the video will help you in self-propagating orchids at home.
If you find it interesting, don't forget to like, share and subscribe to the channel to support me.
Now you take it out and plant the little orchid in a pot.
Let the orchid grow normally like other orchids.
Goodbye and see you in the next videos.