welcome to my channel
Today I would like to introduce to you an interesting video on how to use carrots
help orchids bloom many times a year
There are many people who are passionate about growing orchids and want them to always bloom and stay lush wherever they are.
However, sometimes you have a situation where your orchid doesn't bloom
or slow flowering.
make orchid growers feel disappointed
But don't worry, because in the video you will be shown how to help orchids bloom several times a year.
Carrots are not only a nutritious dish, but also a simple and effective solution to this problem
With just a few simple steps as shown in the video, you can stimulate flowers to bloom quickly
So watch the video and learn how to use the carrot tool to
help your orchid bloom instantly and bloom many times a year.
Use the peel of 1 carrot,
add 10 grams of fresh ginger,
add 1 liter of water
puree
Leave in a dark place for 6 hours
After incubation for 6 hours
filter out residue
Add water to make 4 liters of solution
now irrigate this way,
Soak orchid root in carrot juice for about 5 minutes
This will make it easier for the roots to absorb nutrients.
and repeat this once a month
Carrots contain many vitamins, amino acids and minerals such as:
protein, phosphorus and lots of potassium.
The nutrients and vitamins in carrots will help orchids grow better,
Increase the resistance and vitality of plants,
help it easily adapt to the living environment.
In addition, watering plants from carrots also helps to increase the humidity of the surrounding environment,
help orchids have better growing conditions.
The natural sugar and potassium content in carrots makes it easier for orchids to absorb
Potassium and sugar stimulate flower growth very quickly
It also helps orchids tolerate drought very well
so that the flowers don't fall
and lots of buds
As you can see this orchid has 5-6 flower branches
However, to help orchids bloom all year round, it is necessary to create suitable environmental conditions such as:
the right light, the right humidity, and the right wind
You should also not overuse the use of carrots.
because it will make the orchid have a disorder in nutrient absorption,
it will not benefit the orchids,
Best to only apply once a month
and need to combine the use of other organic fertilizers such as fish protein, soy protein
and pea protein fertilizer like the video I guide to take care of
so orchids will grow and bloom all year round
Thank you for watching the video! Good luck