hello everyone to easily care for
orchids to always grow healthily there
are more flower Buds and Flowers stay on
the branches longer today I share a very
easy way to keep orchids growing
healthily
[Music]
when eating bananas don't throw away the
peel because banana peels contain many
nutrients especially organic potassium
very good for the growth of buds flowers
and has anti-d drought effects
[Music]
I cut the banana peel thinly and put it
in a jar
[Music]
next I took a piece of
bread bread contains phosphorus which
plays an important role in plant growth
especially stimulating root growth
[Music]
adding one teaspoon of yeast helps
decompose organic matter faster and
prevents it from
[Music]
rotting and adding a spoonful of sugar
helps nourish the growth of beneficial
microorganisms
[Music]
add 500 M warm
water then leave in a cool place for 3
weeks
[Music]
3 weeks
later take 2 L of water which is
equivalent to about 528 us gall
[Music]
um after 3 weeks of composting we have
this wonderful
[Music]
fertilizer take 50 mm which is
equivalent to about
0.0132 us
[Music]
Gall then mix into water
method one fertilize The
[Music]
Roots water each Orchid pot with this
water 5 to 10 spoons per week
[Music]
this fertilizer provides potassium an
important mineral that improves plant
health and vitality
[Music]
this type of fertilizer also helps
retain water and enhances the plant's
ability to absorb
[Music]
water beneficial fungi microa will grow
to help the plant more easily absorb
nutrients from the Orchid growing medium
[Music]
method
two use this water to spray on the
leaves
[Music]
helps supplement nutrients through
leaves very
[Music]
effectively helps orchid leaves become
strong and healthy
[Music]
and spray it on aerial roots to help
aerial Roots grow and easily absorb
nutrients in the
[Music]
air um you should do it early in the
morning and by noon the leaves will dry
very quickly
[Music]
do this once a week to keep the Orchid
healthy
[Music]
method
three now I wash the leaves with this
[Music]
water beneficial microorganisms will
help kill mold and insects very
effectively
do this every two weeks to protect your
[Music]
orchids let's check the result together
after fertilizing orchids will always be
green and
[Music]
healthy potassium in banana peels and
bread helps flower buds grow strongly
[Music]
when the flowers bloom they will stay on
the branches for a long
[Music]
time flowers can last on branches for up
to 6 months before fading
[Music]
hopefully the video will help you a lot
in taking better care of orchids at home
[Music]
next I will show you how to revive a
rotten Orchid like
[Music]
this when the orchid has withered all
the leaves only the stem and Roots
remain do not rush to throw it away
[Music]
here are still fresh
fruits first cut off all damaged rotten
roots
[Music]
fire
apply a molten Candle on the cut so that
the water does not penetrate the
[Music]
tree use 2 tpoon of cinnamon powder
[Applause]
adding 1 liter of boiled water is
equivalent to about 2642 us gall
[Music]
close the lid and wait for the water to
cool the water has cooled down
[Music]
filter out residue
soak orchids in this water for 30
minutes
[Music]
the rest of the water I will spray on
other orchids to help protect the Orchid
from insects and fungal diseases
[Music]
after soaking for 30 minutes plant
it uh using pine bark and dry pmus Stone
to plant will help absorb moisture in
the roots making the Orchid roots not
[Music]
rot add some dry moss on the
face put in a cool and well- lit place
for 7
days after 7 days you can spray water to
keep the plants moist
[Music]
cover with a clear vented plastic
container and wait for the plant to
revive after 3 weeks
a sprout has
[Music]
sprouted uh spray water once every 5
days to keep the Sprouts
[Music]
moist after 2 months
hope this sharing content will help you
in resurrecting weak orchids to grow
[Music]
again if you find it interesting
remember to like share and subscribe so
that my channel can soon reach 10
million
subscribers the video I've created many
subtitles you can choose the appropriate
language to understand my
[Music]
shares good luck to you
all see you in the next videos