Welcome to my channel
Today I continue to share a new organic fertilizer to help stimulate flowering for orchids.
It is made from part of the red beetroot.
It is really a great fertilizer for flower growth
Using this fertilizer will always have beautiful orchids,
Your garden always blooms,
Each orchid will bloom again and again many times a year
STEP 1
This is red beetroot
Eat beets, do not rush to throw away the skin
Beetroot contains many minerals
vitamins like B1, B6, B12
They are essential nutrients important for orchid growth
Use the peel of 1 red beetroot
This young shoot will contain many plant stimulants called AUXIN
will stimulate the budding of plants and flower buds.
Add 1 liter of water
Closed
Leave in a cool and dark place for 6 hours
AFTER 6 HOURS
Add water to get 4 liters
Now water the orchid with this water
Red radish is rich in natural potassium,
so orchids are easier to absorb than chemical potassium and safe
Potassium helps balance water and ions,
Potassium also controls stomatal activity,
prevent excessive water loss in dry conditions,
Therefore, potassium is one of the essential macronutrients provided to plants during the maturation and flowering stages,
Same goes for orchids,
So, if you want orchids to have flowers, pay attention to fertilizing with high potassium content,
Do this once a month for your orchid to bloom
Note that you should not apply too much potassium because if you apply too much potassium, the orchid will have atrophy of its roots, small and bad leaves.
Applying this fertilizer once a month is enough.
STEP 2
Use 1/3 teaspoon of baking soda
add 1 liter of water
use cotton balls
Wipe the top and bottom of the orchid leaves with baking soda salt water,
Baking soda is a very good disinfectant,
Please clean the orchid leaves once a month,
it helps to remove dirt on the leaves,
and kill fungi and bacteria on orchids,
and also kill insects such as aphids, aphids, mosquitoes... clinging to orchids,
Helps protect orchid leaves always beautiful shine,
Orchid leaves photosynthesize better,
When the orchid is healthy, it will always bloom with many beautiful and long-lasting flowers
Welcome to part 2 of the video
When orchids are old and have poor resistance, we need to rejuvenate them.
First you need to cut off all damaged leaves and roots.
Keep only fresh roots.
Onions have very good antiseptic and growth stimulating effects
Take about 20 grams of thinly sliced ​​onion.
Take 1 teaspoon of baking soda.
Helps balance PH levels and eliminate fungal diseases harmful to orchids
Add 2 liters of water at room temperature.
Wait 30 minutes before using
After 30 minutes, filter to remove residue
Then water the orchid with onion water and baking soda
Soak in this water for 30 minutes
Cover the pot with a layer of dry moss
Place the dried moss in this transparent plastic box
Leave in a cool place for 1 day without watering
1 Day later
From now on, water your orchids once a week
Or water when the moss is dry
Be careful to keep the moss moist. If the moss is waterlogged, the orchid will easily rot.
Then place it in a cool place with enough light for the orchid to grow
3 Weeks Later
Many baby orchids have sprouted
Take 2 liters of water at room temperature
Then add 5 spoons of rice
Water the orchid with rice water once a week
Helps stimulate baby orchids to grow and take root quickly
Continue to place in a cool, well-lit place for the orchid to grow
After the next 1 month
The baby orchids grow very healthy.
Hopefully the video will help you a lot in taking care of orchids at home
If you find it interesting, please click like and share so more people know
And don't forget to subscribe to the channel to help your channel reach 1 million subscriptions soon
Thank you for watching the video. Good luck and see you in the next videos.