Hello friends!
Today we will take care of orchids with the help of a very useful and fragrant lemon.
Or more precisely, lemon peel contains a lot of vitamin C and essential oils.
Choose 1 lemon.
then just take the shell.
Chopped.
Then puree with 500ml of water.
Filter out residue.
Take 100ml of juice from lemon peel.
Add water to get 1 liter of solution.
First way:
Clean the leaves with a solution of the juice from the lemon peel.
This protects them from pests..
Wipe the underside of the leaves carefully because this is where fungi,
bacteria, and insects often gather to harm the orchid.
Second way:
Spray this solution on the entire orchid.
This helps wash away dirt,
and eliminate fungal diseases, bacteria and harmful insects.
Spray this mixture on orchids every 2 weeks.
But do not spray on flowers and buds.
because wet flowers will quickly fall off.
3rd way:
Water this solution to take care of the roots.
Lemon peel acidifies the orchid juice, which contributes to better absorption of nutrients.
Essential oils repel pests and protect orchid leaves and roots from harmful bacteria..
Or soak the orchid pot in this solution for 30 minutes, it will be better.
Do this every 2 weeks and the orchid will always be protected.
If you don't use all of it, you can freeze the juice from the lemon zest for later use.
View results.
After 3 times of use, the roots grow very well.
Branched roots develop to help the orchid absorb more nutrients.
Leaves are clean, always green and free from pests.
help orchids photosynthesize better.
flower buds grow and do not fall.
Flowers bloom brightly and stay fresh.
Flowers stay on the branch for up to 6 months before falling.
Hope the video will help you a lot.
Thank you for watching the video
Wish you all success and happiness in life.
Goodbye and see you again.