Hello friends.
Nice to meet you on my channel.
You see here a withered orchid.
Maybe it's because you didn't water it.
or due to direct sunlight shining on the orchid.
If you want orchids to be nourished and grow quickly.
Please watch this video carefully.
Now I will share this amazing trick with you.
You need 1 aloe vera leaf.
This aloe vera gel is great for reviving orchids.
Now apply aloe vera gel on the top and bottom of the leaf.
Aloe vera gel has a very good moisturizing effect.
In addition, aloe vera also contains vitamins A, B, and C
and minerals such as nitrogen, phosphorus and potassium.
Do this every 5 days and leave the orchid pot in a cool place for 3 weeks.
Next, take 1 liter of warm water and put it in the bottle.
Then take 1 spoon of rice and soak it in this water for about 30 minutes.
Let the nutrients in the rice completely dissolve into the water.
Chop the remaining aloe vera leaves into small pieces.
Then puree with 300ml of water.
Filter out residue half past four Add 2 liters of water at room temperature.
After soaking for 30 minutes, filter this rice water.
Mix rice water with aloe vera juice.
So I ended up with about 3 liters of this wonderful liquid manure solution.
Cover the pot with moss to retain moisture better.
Now you use this solution to water the orchid every 5 days.
Soak the orchid pot in this water for 2 hours.
After soaking for 2 hours, remember to lift the orchid pot and place it in a cool place to let the orchid recover.
2 WEEKS LATER.
Fertilize after 2 weeks for fresher orchid leaves.
New roots develop very well.
Many new roots are growing.
New roots will help transport water and nutrients from the roots to the stem.
If the leaves are provided with enough water and nutrients from the roots,
The leaves will gradually become lush again.
1 MONTH LATER.
You see the leaves are very fresh.
and the orchid grows a new leaf.
after the next 2 months
The orchid has grown two branches (two buds).
But the leaves at the base have turned yellow so I will cut off these yellow leaves.
Instinctively, when an orchid buds, if the plant lacks nutrients,
the base leaves will turn yellow and fall off to provide nutrients for the buds to develop.
Now I need to supplement the orchid's nutrition by taking 3 spoons of rice.
Then soak in 2 liters of water at room temperature
and wait 30 minutes for the nutrients to completely dissolve in water before using.
30 Minutes Later
Add 3 tablespoons of milk
Rice water and milk are excellent sources of nutrients for orchids to grow
Now you water the orchid with this solution once a week to help the orchid recover quickly.
After the next 1 month.
After 3-4 times of applying liquid fertilizer from milk and rice water, the orchid had many roots.
When the roots grow, they will absorb enough water and nutrients
and the leaves will turn green again very quickly.
After the next 1 month.
The orchid grew more leaves and the withered leaves were completely recovered.
Roots grow very healthily.
The leaves have completely recovered so they are very sturdy and green.
Many buds develop.
The flowers have bright colors and hang on the branches for a long time before fading.
Hope the video will help you a lot.
Hello friends.
This orchid has yellow leaf disease.
The cause is due to insects sucking tree sap and then being infected with fungi and bacteria through insect bites.
This disease leaves the leaves still succulent but falls off very quickly.
Only one healthy leaf remains. The rest are infected.
I cut here to check for disease inside the stem.
All infected leaves need to be removed.
Black spots are where the disease resides so they need to be removed.
then take 5 spoons of cement.
Mix 5 liters of water.
Then wait for the sediment to settle.
10 Minutes later.
Take only the clear water at the top.
Clean orchid branches with cement water.
Soak the orchid pot in cement water for 10 minutes
Soak the moss in cement water for 10 minutes.
Soak 10 eggshells in 2 liters of boiled water.
Wait for the water to cool.
In the meantime, I recycle plastic bottles into orchid nursery equipment.
Take 3 more Vitamin B1 tablets and mix them into eggshell water.
Soak the orchid branches in this water for 20 minutes.
20 minutes later.
Sprinkle cement powder on the cut.
Place the orchid branch in.
Pour some water into the plate.
Place in a cool place, avoid direct sunlight.
After 1 week, spray water every 5 days.
Water from eggshells and B1.
Pour some water into the bowl.
Leave in a cool place, after 1 week spray water every 5 days.
1 MONTH LATER.
Roots grow very strongly.
Now plant it in a pot so it can grow outside
Under the orchid tree, two more small orchids have grown.
Hope the video will help you a lot.
If you find the video meaningful, please share, like and subscribe to the support channel to help the channel reach 1,000,000 registrations soon.
Hello friends.
Orchid is a tropical plant with very strong vitality
With an orchid like this, many people probably throw it away because they think it's dead
When you see this orchid, don't rush to throw it away
Today I will show you how to revive orchids like this quickly
First, cut off all damaged roots
Remember to subscribe to the channel so you don't miss any videos
Rinse with water.
Dry the cut
Drop the molten candle solution on the freshly cut wound
Will help orchids not lose water and also work against fungal diseases
Use 1 teaspoon of cinnamon powder
1 Liter of boiled water
Close the lid and wait for the water to cool
Now the water has cooled
Filter out the residue
Soak orchids in cinnamon water for 30 minutes
Water the cinnamon evenly on the top and bottom of the leaves
Cinnamon has antiseptic properties, so it helps to eliminate fungi and insects that are harmful to orchids very well
Cinnamon also contains many minerals, vitamins and amino acids that are very beneficial for the revival of orchids
Do this once a month to keep your orchid protected and healthy
30 minutes after soaking in cinnamon water
Use dry pine bark to grow orchids
Spread 1 turn of dry moss on top of the pot
Leave in a cool place and do not water for 1 week so that the fungus does not grow harmful
1 week later, start watering to keep the orchid moist
Pour water into the dish at the bottom of the pot to create the right humidity for the orchid to revive quickly
Recycling plastic bottles into miniature greenhouses makes it easier for orchids to revive
1 Month Later
Since the tree has grown roots, I use organic fertilizer made from fish waste to fertilize the orchid
The baby orchid is still very small, so I only apply it on the outside edge of the pot to avoid causing the baby orchid to be shocked with feces
Watering and moisturizing once a week
2 Months Later
From now on take care like other mature orchids
See you in the next videos