Welcome to my Happiness Garden channel.
In my hand is a phalaenopsis orchid with bacterial rot.
First I need to check the roots for damage.
So this orchid is completely root damaged.
All damaged roots need to be removed.
Rinse with water.
Take 100ml of boiled water and let it cool.
Take 1 teaspoon of dried garlic powder.
Soak the orchid root in garlic water for 30 minutes.
In the meantime I recycle this foam sheet into a tool to revive orchids.
Pour filtered water into the tank.
then put the orchid in a cool place.
and change the water when the water is dirty.
3 WEEKS AFTER.
orchids have taken root in the water.
In this way, the orchid's roots grow very quickly.
If this is your first visit to my channel, please subscribe to my channel.
Please help my channel reach 1,000,000 subscribers soon.
Now I plant in pots so that the orchids grow in the outside environment.
Orchid growing medium I choose aquaponic medium and a little moss to keep the surface moist.
Thank you for watching my video.
Wish you success and always happy in life.
Goodbye and see you in the next videos.