Hello everyone, to easily care for orchids to always grow healthily.
A healthy root system helps absorb the most nutrients.
and have more flower buds, flowers stay on the branches longer.
These are coffee grounds.
I took about 50 grams of coffee grounds and put them in a jar
When eating bananas, don't throw away the peel.
Because banana peels contain many nutrients, especially organic potassium.
Very good for the growth of buds, flowers and has anti-drought effects.
I cut the banana peel thinly and put it in a jar.
Then add 3 tablespoons of sugar.
Sugar helps nourish beneficial microorganisms.
and add 3 tablespoons of dry yeast to help decompose organic matter quickly and not rot.
And add 1 liter of warm water.
Warm water helps beneficial microorganisms grow and ferment faster than cold water.
Then place in a cool place for 21 days to let the organic matter decompose before using.
with orchids with wilted leaves and slow growth.
I take care of it with organic fertilizer from coffee grounds and banana peels and it will be very good.
Checking the roots, I found that this orchid had many damaged roots underneath.
The cause may be that the growing medium is moldy and dry.
All damaged roots need to be removed.
Then rinse with water.
I replanted the orchid with a more porous growing medium, which helps retain moisture better.
After composting, the compost ferments so there is a white scum on top.
I took 50ml of this organic nutrient.
Mix with 3 liters of water.
Step 1
Wiping the top and bottom of leaves with this water helps kill fungi and insects that harm orchids.
Do this every 2 weeks to protect your orchids.
Step 2
Use this water to spray the leaves once a week.
Helps supplement nutrients through leaves very effectively.
Helps leaves recover quickly, orchid leaves will be strong and healthy quickly
Step 3
Water each orchid pot with this water once a week.
This fertilizer provides potassium, an important mineral that improves plant health and vitality.
The beneficial fungus Mycorrhiza will grow to help the plant more easily absorb nutrients from the orchid growing medium.
Soak in this water for 10 minutes then take out.
Place in a cool place with enough light for the orchid to recover.
2 MONTHS LATER
Many new roots develop to help the orchid absorb nutrients better.
When the roots absorb enough water and nutrients, the orchid will recover faster.
Thanks to that, the leaves have completely recovered and are no longer wilted.
I continue to wash the leaves with this water once a week.
Then continue to spray this water on the orchid once a week.
and continue watering and soaking the roots once a week with this water.
After the next 2 months.
The orchid has completely recovered and is growing very strongly.
It blooms many flower buds.
Roots grow very healthy.
If you find it interesting, don't forget to like, share and subscribe to the channel so you don't miss any tricks on my channel.
Next, I share the secret to quick recovery for orchids with yellow and wilted leaves.
Cut off all damaged roots and yellow leaves.
I use aloe vera leaves to restore growth and reactivate this orchid.
Aloe vera gel contains essential vitamins, amino acids, and minerals to help spread recovery quickly.
Aloe vera gel is also a very good natural antiseptic. It helps to eliminate fungal diseases for orchids very quickly.
Place the orchid in a sunny spot or by a window. Do not leave the orchid in a place with direct sunlight because the sun will make it easy to rot.
AFTER 1 WEEK
new roots grow
there is a new seedling growing
There's a new one growing here
AFTER 2 MONTHS
have lots of healthy roots growing