Welcome to my channel Happiness Garden.
First I poured 3 liters of water into the jar.
And join us in discovering the magical power of Cocacola.
Using Coca-Cola helps stimulate flowering without requiring too much care.
Take 50ml of Coca-Cola.
Then you just need to mix coca-cola with water and you can use it right away.
Then you clean the surface of the orchid leaves with this coca-cola.
Wipe both the top and bottom of the leaves.
This way helps to repel insects and fungi on leaves very well.
Do it once every 2 weeks, orchid leaves will be very well protected.
You can also use this water to spray the entire orchid.
Pay attention to spray carefully the underside of leaves and between leaves.
because insects and fungi often congregate there.
This is also done every 2 weeks.
if you use the wiping and spraying method of coca-cola regularly,
Leaves will always be green because they are not damaged by insects and fungi.
like my orchid.
Leaves are always green and healthy.
Now take care of the roots.
You just need to water this orchid as much as possible.
Coca-Cola contains phosphoric acid which has a mild bleaching effect.
so it will eliminate fungal diseases in pots and roots very well.
In addition, Coca-Cola also has the ability to kill some insects that damage plant roots such as:
snails and cockroaches are very good.
Coca-Cola helps neutralize the acid in the pot when you use too much chemical fertilizer.
balance pH in orchid pots.
This will stimulate new root growth.
Coca-Cola contains sugar that helps flowers grow very well.
If combined with organic fertilizers, it will help spread more flowers.
My orchids when applying this method have grown a lot of flower branches on one tree.
The sugar in coca-cola helps flowers stay fresh and long-lasting.
Orchid after blooming will not be exhausted.
Orchid can bloom continuously from one batch to another.
New roots are always growing.
Helps orchids absorb the most nutrients.
Hope the video will help you in taking care of orchids at home better.
If you find it interesting, please like, share the video and
Subscribe to help my channel reach 1,000,000 subscribers soon.
Good luck. See you in the next videos.