Welcome to my channel.
Today I will show you how to revive a rotten orchid like this.
When the orchid has withered all the leaves, only the stem and roots remain, do not rush to throw it away.
Here are still fresh roots.
First, cut off all damaged, rotten roots.
Apply a molten candle on the cut so that the water does not penetrate the tree.
Use 2 teaspoons of cinnamon powder.
Add 1 liter of boiled water.
Close the lid and wait for the water to cool.
The water has cooled down
Filter out residue.
Soak orchids in this water for 30 minutes.
The rest of the water I will spray on other orchids to help protect the orchid from insects and fungal diseases.
After soaking for 30 minutes, plant it.
Using pine bark and dry pumice stone to plant will help absorb moisture in the roots, making the orchid roots not rot.
Add some dry moss on the face.
Put in a cool and well-lit place for 7 days.
After 7 days, you can spray water to keep the plants moist.
Cover with a clear, vented plastic container and wait for the plant to revive.
AFTER 3 WEEKS,
A sprout has sprouted,
Spray water once every 5 days to keep the sprouts moist
AFTER 2 MONTHS
Hope this sharing content will help you in resurrecting weak orchids to grow again
Now let's explore the second tip to revive dying orchids.
When the orchid has withered all the leaves and only the stem and roots, do not rush to throw it away.
Here the branches are still fresh.
I will remove all wilted and rotten leaves.
and I removed all the damaged roots.
I keep only the fresh roots that are left over.
I cut off the flower stalk so that the orchid can concentrate nutrients for the new sprout to grow.
rinse with water.
Apply melted candle solution to the cut to prevent water from seeping into the tree.
Use 3 cloves of garlic and mince.
Soak garlic in 1 liter of water at room temperature.
Incubate for 1 day.
At the same time, spread in a cool place for 1 day.
1 DAY AFTER
filter out residue
Soak orchid branches in garlic water for 20 minutes
The rest of the water I will spray on other orchids to help protect the orchid from insects and fungi.
At the same time, garlic juice also stimulates the development of roots and flower sprouts very well
20 MINUTES AFTER.
After soaking for 30 minutes, plant.
Using pine bark or dry pumice stone to plant will help absorb moisture in the roots, making the orchid roots not rot.
Put in a cool place for 1 week without watering.
1 WEEK LATER
From now on, water the orchid to keep it moist.
Then put it in a place with a temperature of 20-25 degrees Celsius and avoid direct sunlight.
Regularly spray moisture to spread life and revive faster.
2 WEEKS AFTER
Use 3ml of GE Ginger water mixed with 1 liter of water.
GE ginger juice is considered an organic fertilizer that helps to stimulate plant growth very well.
Water this GE Ginger every 10 days.
Continue to place in a cool place and avoid direct sunlight
1 MONTH LATER
The roots have grown very well, so we fertilize the orchid with organic fertilizer as I have shared to make the orchid grow healthier.
Hope this sharing content will help you in resurrecting weak orchids to grow again.
Orchid is a tropical plant with very strong vitality.
With an orchid like this, many people probably throw it away because they think it's dead.
When you see this orchid, don't rush to throw it away.
Today I will show you how to revive orchids like this quickly.
First, cut off all damaged roots
Remember to subscribe to the channel so you don't miss any videos
Rinse with water.
Dry the cut.
Drop the molten candle solution on the freshly cut wound.
Will help orchids not lose water and also work against fungal diseases
Use 1 teaspoon of cinnamon powder
1 Liter of boiled water.
Close the lid and wait for the water to cool.
Now the water has cooled.
Filter out the residue.
Soak orchids in cinnamon water for 30 minutes.
Water the cinnamon evenly on the top and bottom of the leaves.
Cinnamon has antiseptic properties, so it helps to eliminate fungi and insects that are harmful to orchids very well.
Cinnamon also contains many minerals, vitamins and amino acids that are very beneficial for the revival of orchids.
Do this once a month to keep your orchid protected and healthy.
30 minutes after soaking in cinnamon water.
Use dry pine bark to grow orchids.
Spread 1 turn of dry moss on top of the pot.
Leave in a cool place and do not water for 1 week so that the fungus does not grow harmful
1 week later, start watering to keep the orchid moist
Pour water into the dish at the bottom of the pot to create the right humidity for the orchid to revive quickly.
Recycling plastic bottles into miniature greenhouses makes it easier for orchids to revive.
1 month later.
Since the tree has grown roots, I use organic fertilizer made from fish waste to fertilize the orchid.
The baby orchid is still very small, so I only apply it on the outside edge of the pot to avoid causing the baby orchid to be shocked with feces.
Watering and moisturizing once a week.
2 months later.
You can see that this orchid is heavily attacked by fungi and bacteria.
If not handled promptly, this orchid can die very quickly.
First, remove all diseased leaves,
Otherwise, it will spread to the whole tree,
It even spreads to other healthy plants..
Cut off even damaged roots.
Since the orchid has no leaves, I have to cut off the flower bud,.
Prioritize nutrients for small orchids to revive.
This is white cement.
Use 1 small spoon,
Add 0.5 liters of water.
Wait 30 minutes.
AFTER 30 MINUTES OF WAIT.
Decant to see the clear water above.
Remove turbid water underneath.
Soak the whole orchid in this water for about 30 minutes..
AFTER WAITING FOR 30 MINUTES BILLION.
Hang in a cool place for 1 day.
After hanging for 1 day.
This is cinnamon powder.
I put cinnamon powder on all the cuts to disinfect.
Growing orchids with dry pine bark.
Leave in a cool place for 1 week without watering.
After 1 week without watering.
The cut is dry.
Use 1 liter of water.
Add 20 grams of aloe leaves.
Watering freshly made aloe vera for orchids..
Aloe vera juice contains many essential minerals and vitamins that help stimulate root growth,
It also stimulates germination.
Leave in a cool place and wait.
AFTER 3 WEEKS.
new sprouts.
From now on, water once every 5-7 days to keep moisture.
AFTER THE NEXT 2 MONTHS.
Orchid has revived and grown healthy.
From now on, apply organic fertilizer every 2 weeks as I shared to help the orchid grow and produce many flowers
Now comes the 5th tip to quickly revive a rotten orchid like this.
All the leaves are rotten.
This flower has also dried.
The top of the flower is still fresh so I decided to leave it to propagate from this flower.
Next, cut off all the damaged roots.
Although the orchid has rotted, there are still some fresh roots.
Rinse with plain water.
take 1 aloe leaf
add 2 cloves of germinated garlic,
If you don't have germinated garlic, you can substitute it with regular garlic,
Garlic sprouts contain very rich AUXIN content.
so it will help the orchid respawn very quickly
add about 30g of aloe leaves
add 1 liter of water
puree
filter out residue
Soak orchids in this water for 20 minutes
I recycle plastic bottles as tools to revive orchids
This recycling tool will also contribute to creating a favorable environment for the orchid to revive quickly,
It also helps to reduce environmental pollution.
wash
make vents
Use dry pine bark
let dry for 1 week without watering.
The dry pine bark will absorb moisture to help protect the orchid from further rot
AFTER 1 WEEK
Now start watering to keep the orchid moist
Every 5 days, spray mist to keep the orchid moist
and put in a cool place to spread recovery
AFTER 3 WEEKS
Sprout has revived
and the roots are also revived
Continue periodically for 5 days misting to keep the orchid moist.
Continue to keep in a cool place for the spread to recover
AFTER 2 MONTHS
Lan has revived and grown healthy
Steam from below always evaporates, creating the right moisture for orchids to revive and grow.
Hopefully the above tips for growing orchids will help you take better care of orchids at home.
If you find it interesting, please like, share and subscribe to the channel so you don't miss my next videos.