Hi everybody
If you have an orchid with wilted leaves like this.
Cut off all wilted leaves and damaged roots.
The top can still continue to grow more leaves
Leave for 1 day without watering so that the cut heals quickly.
Now we make fertilizer to promote the growth of orchids
Take 1 spoon of sugar
Then add 2 tablespoons of white wine
Mix with 2 liters of water
Then you clean the leaves with this water to help eliminate fungal diseases and insects.
Then you use this water to water the orchid roots.
Do it every 2 weeks
Soaking in this water for 10 minutes helps stimulate rooting very well
Recycle plastic bottles into orchid root nursery tools.
Add sterilized dry moss here.
Then water regularly and keep moist to stimulate root growth.
Watering the orchid with water mixed with sugar and white wine once every 2 weeks will stimulate rapid root growth
and spraying moisturizing mist with water helps leaves stay fresh and recover quickly.
Place in a cool place with enough light for photosynthesis.
1 Month Later
The orchid leaf has gotten stronger and has grown a new leaf at the top.
WOW!!! This method stimulates the root system to develop very well.
We cut it into 2 orchid pots
Apply toothpaste to the cut to help it heal quickly
Then plant the upper stem of the orchid in a new pot to help the plant grow faster
Previously we applied this method to this orchid species and obtained the following results:
The lower stem has been rejuvenated and the baby orchid has been revived.
The orchid's upper stem has grown very healthy and has many flower buds.
If you haven't subscribed to the channel yet, please subscribe to support me
Thank you for watching the video. Wish you luck and see you in the next videos.