Welcome to my Happiness Garden channel.
Today I continue to share how to make a free but very special fertilizer.
Made from banana peels and rotten bananas.
But with this new way you will have a great fertilizer for orchids and other plants.
Chop finely for easier and quicker fermentation.
After slicing, you put all the bananas in a plastic jar.
This is the yeast I usually brew with barley to make craft beer.
I put a spoonful of brewer's yeast in the jar.
Then add 800ml of warm water.
Stir well and incubate in a cool place for 2 weeks.
2 WEEKS AFTER.
So we've got a great fertilizer.
I filter the pulp.
it smells like beer.
When the last flowers have withered.
Cut off all flower stalks that have bloomed.
Let me share with you how to revive from flower stalks.
then you peel off the protective film so that this button can easily grow new buds.
Apply toothpaste on the cut,
It will help the cut heal.
Fill the tank with 3 liters of water at room temperature.
Add 3 tablespoons of fermented banana juice.
Use a cotton ball soaked in water mixed with banana juice.
Then clamp in place where the buttons are likely to grow into sprouts.
Fermented banana juice contains many nutrients such as potassium, nitrogen, phosphorus, calcium, and magnesium.
All of which have a stimulating effect on plant growth and development.
Repeat once a week with fermented banana juice.
On normal days, you just need to spray water to keep it moist.
Then, you use fermented banana juice to water the orchid root.
The potassium content in banana juice helps to strengthen and support the growth of branches and roots very well.
and nitrogen supports the process of nitrogen formation and the development of reproductive organs of the plant.
Fertilize periodically once every 2 weeks for spreading roots.
Soaking in fermented banana juice for 30 minutes each time will be very good.
Helps reduce the onset of disease.
With leaves: you also use fermented banana juice to spray the whole plant.
Apply 1-2 times per month.
1 MONTH LATER.
There are many shoots growing from the nodes.
The sprouts that sprout and take root immediately.
With this flower stalk, both young shoots and flower buds develop.
And this flower stalk has revived very large flower buds.
This flower branch is smeared with fermented banana juice,
the flower stays fresh for a long time.
Fermented banana juice has properties equivalent to the natural fermentation medium.
When used as a fertilizer, it helps to improve soil structure and the plant's ability to absorb nutrients.
The enhanced ability to absorb nutrients helps plants grow stronger,
and absorb maximum nutrients from the soil.
Hope the video helps you a lot.
If you like it, don't forget to like and share.
and subscribe to my support channel.