Welcome to my channel.
If you have an orchid that has rot causing it to lose all its leaves.
So don't rush to throw it away. I'll share how to revive it quickly and easily.
This orchid has a bacterial disease that causes it to rot.
First, cut off and clean the rotten areas.
Then completely cut off the damaged roots.
And this is hydrogen peroxide.
Place pure hydrogen peroxide on the rotten area.
Helps eliminate pathogens and prevent rot from spreading.
and you pour it on the cut to help disinfect it.
Then leave it for 1 day without irrigation to let the wound heal completely.
Take 3 liters of water.
Take 1 teaspoon of baking soda and mix it with water.
Baking soda helps eliminate pathogens and needs to balance pH levels.
Soak the entire orchid in this water for 10 minutes.
will eliminate pathogens and need to balance the PH level in the orchid growing environment.
Then take it out.
Pour water into the plate.
helps the substrate always have the right moisture for orchids to germinate.
Place in a cool, well-lit place.
Spray moisturizer regularly when the substrate feels dry.
Take 2 spoons of rice.
Rice water contains many nutrients that are very good for the growth of orchids.
Soak orchid roots in rice water for 20 minutes.
Helps stimulate the growth of sprouts and roots
Do it once a week.
After soaking for 20 minutes, take it out.
1 MONTH LATER.
From the rotten orchid root, a small healthy orchid is revived.
Continue watering the orchid with rice water once a week.
Soak for 20 minutes then take out.
After the next 1 month.
Baby orchids are getting healthier and stronger.
Orchid roots also grow very healthily.
Hopefully the video will help you a lot in recovering rotten orchids.
If you find the video interesting, please like and share so more people know.
and subscribe to my channel to support me.
Thank you for watching the video, good luck and see you in the next videos on this channel.