Welcome to my channel.
In this video, I share how to treat rotten orchids.
and take care of weak orchids to bloom all year round.
Let's start.
This orchid has a very severe leaf rot disease.
This rot spreads very quickly.
First you need to cut off all rotten leaves.
Then use antibacterial and antiseptic cement to sprinkle on the cut.
Just apply it once to completely cure the disease.
Then leave in a cool place for 5 days without watering for the orchid to recover.
And here the orchid has finished blooming, the plant becomes weak and the leaves are wrinkled.
Cut off all dried flower stems.
and cut off all damaged roots.
Adding shredded pine bark helps retain moisture better.
Then take 1 clove of garlic and cut it into thin slices.
Put in a jar and pour in 1 liter of warm water.
And here is the soy sauce "BRAGG - Liquid Aminos"
It has the effect of enhancing the resistance of plants to unusual environmental impacts
(drought, high temperature, intense sunlight, shock when plants change growth stages,...)
and especially plants are poisoned by inorganic fertilizers, environmental pollution, etc.
Mix 1 spoon of soy sauce
Then leave it for 1 day before using it.
1 Day later.
Mix in 2 liters of water.
Step 1: Thoroughly wipe the top and bottom of the leaves with this water.
Helps eliminate fungal diseases, harmful insects and at the same time adds nutrition through leaves to orchids.
The stomata become clear, helping orchids photosynthesize better.
Step 2: Water the orchid roots with this liquid fertilizer 1-2 times a month.
Helps detoxify orchid roots and prevent shock very effectively.
3 Weeks Later
After being detoxified, the roots grow very quickly.
This helps the orchid quickly absorb water and nutrients.
Therefore, the tree recovers quickly and the leaves become stronger.
These are weak orchid pots after 3 months of care using this method.
The roots grow very healthy and the flowers continue to bloom with many brilliant flowers.
With this simple method, you can take care of orchids at home very easily.
Hope the video will help you a lot. If you find it interesting, remember to Like and share with as many people as possible.
Thank you for watching, good luck and see you in the next videos!