Welcome to Hapiness Garden channel
I am a nutritionist for orchids
In this video I show you how to make an organic fertilizer
to help restore weak, yellowed, and wilted orchids
To make fertilizer you use 1 aloe leaf
Aloe vera gel helps to stimulate roots very well
At the same time, it helps to retain moisture and restore wilted leaves very quickly
next you use 1-2 more eggshells
Remember to wash it to remove the fungus
Eggshells contain 70% calcium
Will help the orchid grow stronger,
improve resistance to fungi and insects
Then puree aloe vera leaves and egg shells with 300ml of filtered water
Filter out the residue
Add water to get 3 liters of aloe vera solution
first way
Wipe the top and bottom of orchids with wilted leaves every 2 days
Aloe vera gel contains many vitamins and minerals necessary for plants
and aloe vera gel also moisturizes well, so it helps to recover wilted leaves very quickly
Wipe the top and bottom of orchids with wilted leaves every 2 days
If you do this regularly, the orchid's leaves will always be green and not be attacked by fungi and insects
Second way:
Watering aloe vera for wilted orchids once a week
Will provide the orchid with essential vitamins and minerals through the roots
At the same time, it is also a fertilizer that helps to revive roots very quickly
For normal growing orchids, water aloe vera every 2 weeks
3rd way
Spray aloe vera juice on wilted orchid once every 3 days
like we fertilize the orchid leaves
For normal orchid growth, just mist with aloe vera juice every 2 weeks
This helps the orchid grow and keep the flower on the branch for a long time
Let's see the results together
After 2 weeks of use, my wilted orchid has grown new roots
This orchid has also grown many new roots
Growing roots help absorb more nutrients and water
help wilted orchid quickly recover wilted leaves
As for orchids that are growing normally, it will promote faster growth
Orchids have developed roots, flowers bloom longer and keep on branches longer
If you haven't received any value, don't leave the video.
Part 2/2 I share easy tips for propagating orchids that anyone can do themselves