Welcome to Happiness Garden
where the simplest things become magical
moments that nurture the beauty of nature
Today I'm sharing another simple
yet highly effective way to grow and care for orchids
with this easy to make natural fertilizer at home
even weak orchids can recover
grow well and bloom beautifully
when growing orchids at home
everyone hopes their orchid spikes will produce lots of buds
and bloom with vibrant
healthy flowers just like the orchids I take care of every day
please comment
and let me know which country you're watching the video from
uh it's wonderful that we can chat together from all around the world
when orchids begin to bloom
each flower stays on the spike for a long time before fading
as if trying to prolong its gentle and pure beauty over time
and right now
I'll guide you through the steps in a simple and detailed way
so you can start applying it to your beloved orchid pots right away
each month you only need to water each orchid pot one to two times
just like the way I always do
simple yet surprisingly effective
regular watering helps orchids maintain the necessary moisture
allowing them to absorb nutrients more effectively
when provided with enough moisture
the flowers will bloom fully and stay on the spike for a long time
before fading like a lasting gift from nature
you can keep the orchid in its pot
and soak it in water for about 10 to 20 minutes
this method allows the roots to absorb enough moisture
without causing the plant to become waterlogged
after that don't forget to take the orchid pot out and let it drain
allowing the roots to breathe and preventing rot
if you haven't subscribed to the channel yet
please hit the subscribe button to support me
and never miss any orchid growing tips
it's wonderful to have you along
to start making natural fertilizer for orchids
you only need one very familiar ingredient from the kitchen garlic
take 2 cloves of garlic and slice them very thinly
so the nutrients can easily dissolve into the water
after slicing place the garlic into a clean bottle
to prepare the watering solution for your orchids
next pour about 1 liter of room temperature water into the bottle
to help the garlic release its natural compounds effectively
the next ingredient is honey
a natural component rich in nutrients that help stimulate root growth
and boost the plant's resistance
just add 1 teaspoon of honey to the mixture
and stir gently until the honey is completely dissolved in the water
garlic and honey combined
create a mixture with natural antibacterial and antiseptic properties
helping eliminate harmful fungi in the orchid growing medium
while also providing nutrients that support healthy growth
from root to tip
after finishing you just need to wait about 1 hour for the nutrients
from the garlic and honey
to fully infuse into the water
creating a nutrient rich solution ready for your orchids
if you have a weak orchid that hasn't been able to bloom
start by checking its roots
remove any damaged roots and leaves
then replant the orchid in a clean growing medium
this is the first step to help it recover
and prepare for the next blooming cycle
this helps prevent the spread of fungal diseases
while allowing the plant to focus on nourishing its healthy parts
as a result new roots will grow vigorously
helping the plant recover quickly
and get ready for the next blooming cycle
after soaking for about 1 hour
strain out the residue to get a clear solution
which helps the orchid absorb nutrients more effectively
and prevents clogging in the growing medium
step 1 use a soft cloth soaked in the solution
then gently wipe both the top and underside of the leaves
this method not only helps clean dust and effectively kill bacteria
uh but also delivers nutrients directly through the leaves
allowing the plant to absorb them quickly and recover better
you can also apply this method to healthy orchids
to boost their resistance
keep the leaves glossy green and help the flowers last longer
apply this method regularly
one to two times a month for the orchid pots in your garden
to maintain their health and vibrant beauty all year round
step 2 soak the orchid roots in the garlic and honey solution
for about 10 to 20 minutes
this method not only helps naturally disinfect
but also stimulates new root growth to be stronger and healthier
creating a solid foundation for the orchid to recover and thrive
the remaining
solution can be used to water each orchid pot in your garden
this is a simple way to provide extra nutrients
and boost the plant's resistance
regularly watering with the garlic and honey mixture
helps orchids strengthen their resistance against fungi
and harmful bacteria in the growing medium
as a result the plant stays healthy
and is less affected by its surrounding environment
um this nutrient rich solution helps the roots grow strong
and absorb water and minerals more efficiently
when the roots are healthy
the orchid has enough energy to produce more blooms that are vibrant
and long lasting
you can also pour the remaining solution into a spray bottle
and lightly mist the leaves of the orchid pots in your garden
this method helps clean the leaves
kill bacteria and provide nutrients directly through the leaf surface
you can apply this fertilizer every two weeks
or flexibly alternate it with other natural fertilizers
such as banana aloe Vera
fish emulsion soybean
or molasses to provide a diverse range of nutrients
for your orchid's overall growth
spraying the garlic and honey mixture on the leaves
helps clean the leaf surface
eliminate harmful bacteria and fungi
and at the same time
provide a natural layer of nutrients that keeps the leaves glossy
healthy and enhances their photosynthesis capacity
after soaking gently take the orchid out and replant it in
a new pot with clean well aerated growing medium
this is an important step to help the plant start fresh
in a better environment
and here is another weak orchid that I treated with this care method
three weeks ago as you can see
it has started to grow many new roots
a very positive sign of recovery
when the root system becomes healthy again
the plant will start to absorb water and nutrients more effectively
and gradually the once wilted leaves will come back to life
when the roots absorb enough water and nutrients
the orchid can sustain its flowers more effectively
as a result the petals on the spike stay fresh
vibrant and retain their beauty for a long time before fading
after soaking for about 10 to 20 minutes
once the roots have absorbed enough nutrients
take the orchid pot out and place it in a spot with gentle sunlight
uh this helps the plant photosynthesize better
recover quickly and grow healthily
when provided with good fertilizer and enough light for photosynthesis
the orchid will grow healthily and its leaves will always be lush
green and glossy a clear sign of a happy plant
thanks to proper care orchids will bloom more brilliantly than usual
shining dazzlingly and brightening up the surrounding space
many petals can bloom simultaneously on the same spike
and those flowers will stay fresh for a long time before fading
creating a truly vibrant and impressive scene
what do you think about how I care for these small orchids
don't hesitate to leave a comment and share your thoughts
I'm really eager to hear your feedback and experiences
I hope you will enjoy this video if you find it helpful uh
don't forget to hit like and subscribe to the channel
so you won't miss upcoming tips on how to care for orchids
naturally and simply
thank you for taking the time to watch wishing you happiness
joy and wonderful experiences with your beloved orchid pots
see you in the next video
welcome to my channel
when orchids have enough nutrients and good soil environment
the plant will grow stronger and flower more
to help create the best conditions for flower development
at the same time make orchids bloom more beautiful
both roots and flowers grow beyond imagination
in this video I share a new fertilizer that few people know about
let's explore with me now
when when you plant a lot of orchids the orchid rot is inevitable
if it accidentally rots you need to cut off the rotten part right away
then isolate the rotten orchid pot from other normal orchid pots
this helps prevent rot from spreading to normal orchids
after cutting off the rotten part you need to dry the rot solution
uh if you haven't subscribed to the channel yet
please hit the subscribe button to support me
and not miss any orchid growing tips
it's amazing to have you as a companion
please comment to me which country you are watching the video from
it's great that we can chat together from all over the world
um waste from rotten orchids should be isolated from the garden
as far as possible
this is activated carbon it is made from natural dry firewood
I took a piece of activated carbon like this and ground it into powder
then sprinkle activated charcoal powder on the newly cut wound
helps cuts heal faster and eliminates fungal diseases
because activated carbon has a very good sterilization function
then you sprinkle more in between the two leaves and on the base
then put the orchid pot in a cool place and do not water for one week
the orchid will recover from the disease
next way
mix 1 teaspoon of activated carbon with 1 liter of water
then use this water to water the base of the orchid
perform periodically once every two weeks for normal orchids
helps prevent disease and improve pH in growing media
in activated carbon there is also a high content of Calcium
and natural minerals that are very good for orchids
help stimulate rooting
soaking this water for 30 minutes is better
the next way you filter this water to get clear water
then use this water to wash the leaves
orchid will be protected from fungi and insects
the Calcium content in activated carbon helps to strengthen the leaves
do it regularly once every two weeks and you will be healthy like this
you can also use this water to spray the entire orchid
it helps to eliminate fungi and insects on leaves very well
and it also provides some nutrients through the leaves
now let's see the results
lots of new roots growing
this helps orchids absorb nutrients best
the potassium and phosphorus content in activated carbon
stimulates extremely fast rooting
the flowers are brighter and stronger
many flower buds growing on the same tree
surely you will be surprised with this fertilizer
if you find it interesting
please like and share it with many people
and don't forget to subscribe to my channel
thank you for watching the video
goodbye and see you again in the next videos