Welcome to my channel.
To help you have many choices when caring for orchids at home with organic fertilizer.
In this video, I continue to share new methods.
Subscribe to the video so you don't miss any tips on my channel.
To make this type of organic fertilizer you need soybeans
Take 3 small spoons of soybeans
Next you need 5-10 small garlic cloves
Add 350ml of water
Next we need yogurt
Add 3 small spoons of yogurt
Yogurt helps ferment quickly, preventing soybeans and garlic from rotting
Cover tightly and leave in a cool place for 3 weeks before using
3 Weeks Later
Take 3 liters of water
After incubation for 3 weeks, we have obtained organic fertilizer from soybeans, garlic and fermented yogurt
Take 50ml
FIRST METHOD
Clean the leaf surface with this liquid fertilizer.
The leaf surface will always be clean and airy with stomata.
Orchids will photosynthesize better.
Regularly cleaning the leaves 1-2 times a month will help keep the leaves healthy.
SECOND METHOD
Spray this fertilizer on the entire orchid.
This method is similar to using foliar fertilizer.
Garlic contains essential oils that help kill fungi and insects very well.
Soybeans contain a lot of nitrogen, which helps leaves grow exceptionally well
Spraying aerial roots helps aerial roots develop.
THIRD METHOD
Water this fertilizer solution on the orchid roots.
Milk-based fertilizer provides natural calcium which is very good for orchids.
Helps orchids stay healthy and resistant to pests.
And milk contains a lot of nutrients for orchids.
Do this 1-2 times a month to supplement nutrition and increase the orchid's resistance.
RESULT
After 3 times of applying this fertilizer method, the root system has developed very strongly.
Roots help orchids absorb and transport nutrients to nourish plants and flowers.
Flowers bloom in more vibrant colors.
The orchid blooms many flowers at the same time but is still healthy.
Flowers bloom for a long time before fading.
Thank you for watching the video. Good luck and see you in the next video.