Welcome to my channel
In my hand is an orchid with leaf rot disease
We need to remove rotten leaves from the garden so that it does not spread the rot to other orchids
Now I will show you how to revive a rotten orchid like this.
Then cut off all damaged roots
This will help the orchid roots escape further root rot
I keep only the fresh roots that are left over
then rinse with water
Then leave the orchid branch in a cool place for 1 day to let the cut heal completely
Use 2 cloves of garlic and mince
Soak garlic in 1 liter of water at room temperature
Incubate for 1 day
1 DAY AFTER
Filter the garlic water
Soak orchid branches in garlic water for 20 minutes
Pour the remaining garlic liquid into the jar
The rest of the water I will spray on other orchids to help protect the orchid from insects and fungi
At the same time, garlic juice also stimulates the development of roots and flower sprouts very well
Spray the underside of the leaves thoroughly because this is where insects
and fungi often hide, leaving orchids behind
Caring for it this way, my orchid has a very healthy root system
20 MINUTES AFTER
Use soft cotton to dry the orchid roots
Then plant orchids with dry pine bark
At the bottom of the pot I spread large pine bark to help the roots breathe
On top I spread small pieces of pine to help retain moisture better
Dried pine bark will help absorb moisture from the orchid roots, dry the cut, and help the cut heal quickly
Then leave in a cool place and do not water for 1 week
1 WEEK LATER
Spread a little moss on top of the orchid pot to help retain moisture better
From now on, water the orchid to keep it moist
Recycle clear plastic bottles to make greenhouses for growing orchids
Remember to water when the growing medium is dry
Place the orchid pot in a cool, well-lit place to help the orchid photosynthesize
Results after 3 weeks
So after 3 weeks of incubation in the greenhouse, the orchid has germinated and given new roots
Once the plant has sprouted and roots, I use GE solution to take care of it
Ge solution is a microbial fertilizer made from banana and aloe vera
Contains many enzymes and amino acids that are very good for orchid growth
Take 36 spoons of GE mixed with 1 liter of water
Water this liquid fertilizer for orchids every 2 weeks
GE fertilizer is very good for recovering weak orchids
It also helps plants detoxify when using too much chemical fertilizer
Continue caring for orchids in this miniature greenhouse
And remember to water every time the orchid growing medium dries out
The substrate is always moist but not waterlogged, good for orchid roots
Use the remaining liquid fertilizer to water other orchids
Applying once every 2 weeks will be very good for your orchids
GE bananas and aloe vera also provide natural potassium to help orchids bloom for a long time
Results after 2 months
The roots have grown very well
The leaves are sturdy and bright green
From this dying orchid, a healthy orchid was miraculously revived
With strong roots like this,
We fertilize orchids with organic fertilizer like I shared to help orchids grow healthier.