Welcome to my channel.
You can see that this orchid is heavily attacked by fungi and bacteria.
It makes orchid leaves yellow and black rot.
If not handled promptly, this orchid can die very quickly.
First, remove all diseased leaves,
Otherwise, it will spread to the whole tree,
It even spreads to other healthy plants.
Cut off even damaged roots.
Since the orchid has no leaves, I have to cut off the flower bud,
Prioritize nutrients for small orchids to revive.
This is white cement.
Use 1 small spoon,
Add 0.5 liters of water
Wait 30 minutes.
AFTER 30 MINUTES OF WAIT.
Decant to see the clear water above.
Remove turbid water underneath.
Soak the whole orchid in this water for about 30 minutes.
AFTER WAITING FOR 30 MINUTES BILLION.
Hang in a cool place for 1 day.
After hanging for 1 day.
This is cinnamon powder.
I put cinnamon powder on all the cuts to disinfect.
Growing orchids with dry pine bark.
Leave in a cool place for 1 week without watering.
After 1 week without watering.
The cut is dry.
Use 1 liter of water.
Add 20 grams of aloe leaves.
Watering freshly made aloe vera for orchids.
Aloe vera juice contains many essential minerals and vitamins that help stimulate root growth,
It also stimulates germination.
Leave in a cool place and wait.
AFTER 3 WEEKS.
new sprouts.
From now on, water once every 5-7 days to keep moisture.
AFTER THE NEXT 2 MONTHS.
Orchid has revived and grown healthy.
From every 2 weeks, you fertilize organically as I have shared so that the orchid grows and flowers a lot
Next, I share how to fertilize to help flower branches continue to revive and bloom after the flowers wither
Please subscribe to the channel so you don't miss any orchid growing tips on my channel.
These are the branches after the flowers have faded.
I cut off all the dry branches.
Then sprinkle cinnamon powder on the cut to help the wound heal quickly.
Then leave it for 1 day without watering to let the cut heal completely.
Take 1 aloe vera leaf and cut it into thin slices.
Then I applied aloe vera gel to the spent flower stems.
This helps the flower branches recover very quickly.
I do it once a week.
and I continue to apply aloe vera gel to the leaves once a week.
This helps eliminate pathogens and wilted orchids recover very quickly.
I put sliced ​​aloe vera leaves in a jar and add 2 liters of boiled water.
Add 1 spoon of rice.
Then add 3 crushed egg shells.
Wait for the water to cool before you can use it.
After cooling, filter to remove residue.
Water this once a week.
Helps supplement nutrition and orchids recover very quickly.
Soak the orchid pot in this water for 20 minutes then take it out.
Spray this water once a week.
Helps supplement nutrients through the leaves so the leaves recover very quickly.
At the same time, it effectively destroys disease-causing fungi and bacteria.
After 20 minutes lift it out.
After 1 month.
From withered branches, many new flower buds have grown.
This method helps the sprouts grow very quickly.
After only 1 month, many buds have grown.
Continue watering this and spray this water once a week.
after the next 1 month.
Orchids bloom many beautiful flowers.
Even though the flower branches have withered, the newly bloomed flowers have very bright colors.
The flowers are very healthy and sturdy so they will hang on the branches for a long time before fading.
With this simple method we can care for orchids at home and bloom all year round.
If you find the video interesting, don't forget to like and share so more people know.