welcome to my channel.
In this video, I continue to share methods to help infected orchids recover quickly.
and they continue to bloom all year round.
This is an orchid with rot disease, the leaves at the top are rotten.
I need to cut off all the rotten leaves so they don't spread and rot the entire plant.
and I cut out all the rotten areas.
Remove old growing medium.
Remove all rotten roots.
and cut off the flower stalks so that nutrients can be concentrated on growing the sprouts later.
Rinse with water.
Take 1 aloe vera leaf.
300ml water.
Add 1 teaspoon cinnamon powder.
then puree them.
Filter out residue.
Add water to make 2 liters of solution.
Soak the entire orchid in this water for 10 minutes.
This helps eliminate pathogens and stimulates germination and rooting.
After 10 minutes, take it out and dry it.
Then sprinkle cinnamon powder on the cut.
Helps cuts heal quickly and prevents orchids from rotting further.
Then I planted the orchid in a new pot.
Planting material needs to be soaked and disinfected before planting.
Then place in a cool, well-lit place and do not water for 1 week.
After 1 week.
Put 2 liters of water into the jar.
Add 3 teaspoons of rice.
After 1 week of not watering, the cut was dry.
From now on water this once a week.
Rice water contains ingredients that help stimulate sprouting and rooting very quickly.
Then continue to place the orchid pot on the windowsill or under the sun filter.
Regularly spraying water helps maintain appropriate humidity for orchid growth.
2 Months later.
The orchid root has produced two very healthy orchids.
Continue watering the orchid with rice water once a week.
Rice water is very suitable for orchids at all stages of growth.
After the next 3 months.
A rotten orchid has revived and grown into a very healthy orchid pot.
Orchid leaves from this old root can be removed from the orchid pot to help the orchid grow better.
The orchid has developed many buds.
Thank you for watching the video. Wish you luck and see you in the next videos.