Welcome to my channel.
These orchids were about to die so they threw them away.
This plant still has green leaves so I brought it home to restore.
It is necessary to remove all old planting material and examine the root system.
Cut off all damaged roots.
Then rinse with water.
I took the outer skin of the onion.
Put onion peels in a jar and soak in 2 liters of boiled water.
Then brew until the water cools.
Next I recycled the plastic box into a tool to revive orchids.
After the water cools, filter to remove sediment.
Soak moss in onion water for 30 minutes.
Clean the leaves with onion juice.
This helps eliminate fungi and bacteria that cause rot in orchids.
Soak orchids in onion water for 30 minutes to help stimulate root growth.
Take a few pebbles and place them at the bottom of the box.
Then spread moss on top of the gravel layer.
Plug the orchid into the box.
Pour some water into this plastic box.
The water level is only allowed to reach this point.
Then place the orchid in this water container.
Cover with vented lid on top.
This way you won't need to water and the orchid will still have enough moisture.
ONE MONTH LATER.
WOW
From an orchid with no roots, it was revived and developed many strong roots.
When the roots are strong, they will absorb nutrients and water to help the orchid recover very quickly.
Now the orchid can be planted in a pot so it can grow in an outdoor environment.
If you find the video meaningful, please like and share so that more people know.
Thank you for watching the video. Good luck and see you in the next videos.