welcome to my channel
When eating cucumbers, don't throw away the skins
I will guide you to recycle cucumber peel to make organic fertilizer for orchids
it will become a free but extremely good fertilizer for orchids
Cucumber peel is a rich source of nutrients,
including potassium, calcium and magnesium.
When recycled into organic fertilizer,
These nutrients can help power orchids,
helping them to grow and bloom better.
Use the rind of 1 cucumber
1 liter of water at room temperature
puree
filter out residue
take 1 part of this water
Use this water to care for the leaves
Clean both the top and bottom of the leaves
Organic fertilizer from cucumber peel can help strengthen the resistance of orchids
and reduce the risk of diseases and pests.
Next, you clip cotton soaked in cucumber juice to the flower branches like this
Will help flower buds grow faster
The flower branches will grow very quickly
Do this once a week
The flowers backed by recycled organic cucumber peel are brilliant.
Many flowers bloom on the same branch.
But flowers bloom for a long time.
Do this once a week for flower buds.
New flower buds are revived very quickly in this way from flowers that have already withered
weekdays When the cotton pad is dry, you just need to mist it with normal water
This way has created 100 flowers on 1 orchid
Next, you use this water to water your orchid
The nutrient content in cucumber juice will be absorbed through the roots
This also improves the permeability and ventilation of the orchid growing medium.
At the same time, it helps to improve the growth of beneficial microorganisms in the orchid growing medium.
Helps protect orchid roots from rotting
should do this every 2 weeks.
Next, you also use this water to spray evenly over the entire orchid.
This also only needs to be done once every 2 weeks.
Next, use pieces of cucumber to place on the base of the orchid.
Cucumbers will attract small snails to eat
Please book in the afternoon
in the evening and the next morning the snail eats melon, we will catch the snail and leave.
Thank you for watching
Remember to subscribe to the channel to support me
goodbye and see you again in the next videos.