Welcome to my channel!
If you have an orchid after flowering like this, don't rush to throw it away.
Please pay attention and follow me to recover and help the orchids bloom again.
Remove old growing medium.
When the moss is green like this, it proves that the humidity in the orchid pot is very suitable.
so I only removed part of the old substrate so the roots could grow faster.
If the growing medium is dark green or viscous, it means the humidity is too high, easily rotting the orchid roots
If you haven't subscribed to the channel yet, please click the subscribe button to support me
and don't miss any orchid growing tips! Truly great company!
Please comment to me which country you are watching the video from!
It's great that we can chat together from all over the world!
Cut off all damaged roots.
In addition to the English dub, we've now created dubs in French, German, Italian, Spanish, Portuguese,
Japanese, Hindi, and Indonesian to help you hear and understand the content more easily.
Cutting off wilted flower branches will help the orchid quickly recover and quickly produce new flower branches.
These black spots are caused by fungal growth that rots the roots.
When there is too much moisture, fungi will grow and cause root rot.
Upon closer inspection, I saw fungal disease thriving inside the substrate.
Therefore, it is necessary to remove all old planting material so that the fungus does not spread further.
If you encounter any difficulties during the orchid growing process, don't hesitate to comment!
I am always ready to support you so you can grow healthy orchids and bloom lots of flowers. 🌸
Then rinse with water helps eliminate some fungal diseases.
Then leave in a cool place for 2 hours to drain.
Next make fertilizer for orchids.
Take 1 spoon of oatmeal.
Add 500ml boiled water (about 2 cups).
Wait until it cools before using it as fertilizer.
Take 1 spoon of dry yeast.
Adding 2 cups of warm water (about 500ml of warm water) helps the yeast grow better.
Be careful not to use hot water because it will kill the microorganisms in the yeast.
Wait 1 hour for the yeast to develop before using it as fertilizer.
1 Hour later.
Filter the oatmeal solution.
Mix the yeast solution with the oatmeal solution.
Add 1 liter of room temperature water (about 4 cups).
Then soak the orchid roots in this solution for 30 minutes.
Beneficial microorganisms in the yeast will protect the roots from rot.
and vitamins and minerals in oats help stimulate rapid rooting.
The remaining solution is used to fertilize other orchids in the garden.
This fertilizer helps stimulate root growth.
A strong root system will help orchids absorb nutrients best.
You can see that my orchid pots have developed very healthy roots.
This fertilizer also contains a large amount of natural potassium to help bloom more and flowers last longer.
Apply this liquid fertilizer to orchids every 2 weeks for healthy growth.
After soaking for 30 minutes, take the orchid out and plant it in a new pot
I plant with pine bark, which helps drain water quickly and has appropriate moisture so it doesn't cause root rot.
After planting, apply this liquid fertilizer to the orchids every 2 weeks.
Place the orchid pot in a place with light sunlight so that the orchid can photosynthesize.
and the orchid will grow faster.
On weekdays, when the foundation is dry, you just need to spray mist to keep it moist.
Or watering to keep the substrate moist will help the roots take root quickly.
When growing orchids, always follow the principle of "the substrate is moist but not wet,"
which will be good for your orchids.
Results after 1 month.
After only 1 month orchid roots have grown many and healthy.
Leaves become stronger.
These new roots will help the orchid absorb nutrients and water best.
When the leaves and roots grow healthy like this, the orchid will quickly produce new flower branches.
Hope the video will help you a lot.
If you find it interesting, please like, share and subscribe to my support channel.
Thank you for watching video.
Wish you luck and see you in the next videos.