Welcome to my channel.
To help you have many choices when caring for orchids at home with organic fertilizer.
In this video, I continue to share new methods.
Subscribe to the video so you don't miss any tips on my channel.
Now, let's get started.
To make this type of organic fertilizer you need black tea (or tea grounds).
I use 3 teaspoons of black tea.
Add 1 liter of boiled water.
Incubate until the water cools.
After the water cools, filter to remove sediment.
Add water to make 5 liters of black tea solution.
Next add 1 teaspoon of baking soda.
FIRST METHOD
Water this fertilizer solution on the orchid roots.
Black tea contains many minerals and organic substances that help provide nutrition for orchids.
It contains nitrogen, potassium and phosphorus,
Important nutritional factors for orchid growth.
Baking soda (bicarbonate soda) has the ability to increase the PH level in orchid pots,
This is helpful in reducing acidity if you use too much chemical fertilizer.
Baking soda has the ability to kill insects and fungi that are harmful to plants.
SECOND METHOD
Spray this fertilizer on the entire orchid.
This method is similar to using foliar fertilizer.
You can use it as a natural pesticide to protect orchids from insects and diseases.
THIRD METHOD
Clean the leaf surface with this fertilizer solution.
The leaf surface will always be clean and the stomata will not be clogged.
Orchids will photosynthesize better.
RESULT
Plant roots are protected and supplemented with nutrients so they grow very healthily.
will help orchids absorb the most nutrients.
Because they are provided with enough nutrition, the flowers bloom more brilliantly.
Many flowers bloom on the same branch.
The flowers stay on the branches for a long time before fading.
Thank you for watching the video. Wishing you luck and success in life.
Goodbye and see you again in the next videos.