Hello friends
Today I will show you how when we need to water the orchid
When the orchid's roots are green like this, the orchid has enough water
The leaves will be green and sturdy
But if the roots turn white, the plant is lacking water
check the potting medium you will find it very dry
Leaves will wilt very quickly if we don't water them in time
In this case, we need to quickly water the orchid
HOW TO WATER AS FOLLOWING:
Place the orchid pot in a deep dish and water the substrate completely
If the roots are still fresh but the leaves are wilted, we can soak the orchid in water for 20-30 minutes
With pots using moss growing medium, the ability to retain moisture is very good,
so we only need to water enough moisture.
and no need to soak.
Eat bananas, don't throw away the peels
Banana peel contains a lot of vitamins and minerals:
vitamins A, B, C, E and protein, phosphorus, especially rich in potassium.
Potassium resists drought very well, helps the orchid to transport water from the root to the top, so the orchid does not wilt
At the same time, potassium helps to stimulate flower growth and keep flowers fresh for a long time
We cut banana peels
Put all banana peels in a jar and pour 500ml of boiled water
Then incubate for 1 day for the nutrients to dissolve into the water
5 vitamin b1 tablets mixed with 500ml of filtered water
B1 helps plants to better absorb nutrients
and growth regulator
It also stimulates root growth very well
After 1 day of incubation, we mix banana juice with vitamin B1 water to get 1 liter of synthetic organic fertilizer solution.
Divide into a spray bottle
Spray the top and bottom of the leaves evenly
Orchid plants are provided with a part of nutrients that are supplemented through the leaves
At the same time, it also eliminates insects to help the orchid stay green
You can also use a cotton ball soaked in this synthetic organic fertilizer solution to wipe the leaves
Do this 1-2 times a month, the orchid will always be protected and green
Next, you use this liquid synthetic organic fertilizer solution to irrigate the orchid
do 1-2 times a month and combine with other organic fertilizers that I have shared on the channel
It will help orchids easily absorb nutrients
Vitamin B1 helps stimulate root growth
Potassium in banana juice will stimulate flower growth and help flowers stay fresh for a long time
It is truly the perfect formula for the full development of roots, leaves and flowers
It's very good, but you should not overdo it, it will harm the orchid
You should only fertilize according to my instructions so that your orchid garden always blooms without affecting the growth of orchids.
Please comment below about your results
Please comment in the video so that I can help you further if your lan has problems
My videos have subtitles in different languages, please choose the right language to understand the video content I share.
If you find it interesting, don't forget to like, share and subscribe to support me
Don't rush to leave this video and continue watching part 2/2 to support me
Welcome to part 2 of the video
When you plant a lot of orchids,
you will not be able to avoid rotten orchids.
You see my orchid has been infected with a fungus
If not handled promptly, this orchid is very easy to die
Even though it's rotten, it's still fresh when cut across
It is also a favorable condition for the spread to respawn faster
We need to cut off the branches and remove all the rot
This will prevent rot from spreading
Then rinse with water
Use 300ml of water at room temperature
Mix 1 tablespoon of unsweetened fresh milk into the water
add 1 vitamin B1 tablet
Use a cotton ball to absorb the mixture of B1 water and milk
Then wipe the top and bottom of the leaves
This water mixture has a disinfecting effect
Helps get rid of fungal diseases
Then use this mixture of water B1 and milk to soak the orchid root for 20 minutes
The rest is used to spray other normal orchids
Helps get rid of fungal diseases
and supplement necessary nutrients for orchids
After soaking for 20 minutes, take out the branches
dry the cut
use toothpaste
Applying it on a cut will help it heal faster
will protect orchids from rot
While waiting for it to dry,
I recycle old plastic containers to make tools to revive orchids
Use industrial cotton to put it in the pot
then let the orchid in
Next, every 3 days, spray moisturizing mist with normal water
Then put the orchid pot in a cool place
The most suitable temperature for reviving orchids is from 20-30 degrees Celsius
1 MONTH LATER
The orchid has rooted very well
and grow 1 more young leaf
B1 stimulates rooting very well
Milk contains natural calcium to help orchids stay strong
and increase resistance
Now I grow orchids in pots with moss so that it adapts to the outside environment
Note: When the roots are firmly attached to the substrate, fertilize the orchid
Welcome to part 3 of the video
There are many flower buds, the flowers stay on the branches longer.
Today I share a very easy way to make orchids always grow healthily.
lush green and flowers will bloom all year round.
Water it once a week.
and leave for 10 minutes.
to help the roots turn green.
then take it out.
I use a small teaspoon of cinnamon powder mixed into 1 liter of boiled water.
Cinnamon powder is very good, helping orchids grow very quickly.
Wait for this water to cool.
After the water cools, will filter this water.
And I use 1 tablespoon of flour, which contains a lot of nutrients.
Add 1 liter of water.
The nutrients in wheat flour also help plants grow very quickly.
and mix with cinnamon water.
will create a great organic nutrient for orchids.
And water immediately at the base of the tree.
You should fertilize orchids every 2 weeks.
Use this water to spray on the leaves.
Helps prevent insects such as thrips and mealybugs.
You should do it early in the morning and by noon the leaves will dry very quickly.
Leave it like that for 20 minutes.
Wheat always contains many organic nutrients.
Helps orchids grow healthily.
This type of water also helps a lot for weak, underdeveloped plants.
If the orchid has been planted for many years and still hasn't bloomed, repot it.
Cut off damaged roots.
use this water wipe the leaves.
Helps leaves recover from fungus.
Cinnamon powder has antibacterial and antiseptic properties and wheat contains a lot of minerals.
and essential vitamins, helping plants recover very quickly.
Adding this amount of water helps new roots grow quickly.
Soak in this water for 20 minutes.
Then take it out.
Place the plant in a bright place.
Helps plants photosynthesize, create chlorophyll, keep leaves green and roots strong.
and the flowers will bloom more beautifully.
Hope it will always help you a lot.
Don't forget to like, share, subscribe to the channel and ring the bell for easy viewing.
Thank you for watching the video. Good luck and see you in the next videos.