welcome to my channel have a nice
day so that you have more choices in caring
for orchids at home using natural methods
helps orchids grow healthily produce many Buds
and flower branches new Roots grow many and
fat today I will introduce to you
a simple and extremely effective
organic fertilizer helps orchids
absorb maximum nutrients and grow
quickly let's get started when an
orchid lacks nutrients especially
potassium its flower buds will
easily Wilt and fall off while
the blooms will fade quickly with petals
becoming weak and dropping soon after
therefore we can create our own
fertilizer to improve this condition
allowing the Orchid to grow healthily
bloom regly and remain more vibrant
to make this type of fertilizer I use
coffee put two teaspoons in the
pot add 0.5 liters of boiling water
and this is eggshell powder a wonderful
lateral ingredient that provides calcium
to orchids promoting healthier
growth and better development
just add one teaspoon of eggshell powder which is
which is enough to provide the
essential nutrients for your
orchid cover and incubate for 2
hours pour 500 ml of warm water into the cup
this is bread
yeast put one spoon of yeast into the cup
stir well so that the yeast
is completely dissolved in the
solution leave it for 2 hours to allow the
beneficial microorganisms in the yeast to
develop after 2
hours you take the coffee
solution then filter out the
residue what country are you watching
the video from please comment
below it's so wonderful that we can
chat together from all around the
world continue diluting further with 2 L of
water step one use a soft cloth to
dampen it with a coffee and eggshell
mixture then gently wipe both
the top and bottom of the leaves
wiping the leaves with a mixture
of coffee and eggshells helps clean
off dust provide direct nutrients to
the leaves and enhance photosynthesis
keeping the plant healthy
and promoting better growth
um the mixture of coffee and eggshells
also creates a natural protective layer
on the leaf surface reducing the risk
of pest infestations and fungal diseases
additionally it makes the leaves shinier
giving the plant a fresh and vibrant appearance
which country are you watching
this video from let me know in the
comments uh it's so wonderful that we can connect
and chat with each other from all around the
world step two pour this mixture into
a spray bottle to spray on your orchids
if you haven't subscribed yet don't forget to hit
the Subscribe button so you won't miss any new
videos then spray it over the entire
orchid plant this helps remove dirt
pests and mold that may be sticking to the Orchid
spraying this mixture on the Orchid
also helps provide moisture to the
leaves and stems especially in
dry environments promoting better
growth additionally it aids the plant in absorbing
nutrients more effectively accelerating the growth
process however you should not spray
this mixture on the flower petals
because it may damage the delicate
surface and affect their appearance
additionally in a humid environment
the flower petals can become moldy
causing the Buds and Flowers to drop prematurely
next we mix the yeast solution with the coffee and
eggshell mixture to create a
fertilizer solution for the
roots uh step three water
the roots with this mixture
watering the roots with this mixture
provides essential nutrients promotes
root growth and helps the Orchid
absorb water and nutrients more
effectively additionally this
mixture helps improve the soil's pH
creating an ideal environment for the plant's
growth this mixture also stimulates
the growth of new Roots enhancing
the plant's ability to withstand
harsh environmental conditions
it also AIDS in the recovery of
the plant after illness or damage
it also enhances the plant's
ability to absorb minerals
and Trace elements promoting
Healthy Growth and consistent
blooming it also helps maintain soil
moisture preventing drought conditions
and ensuring the plant has enough water to thrive
step four use a cloth to soak up any water
droplets on the leaves especially in the leaf
axles uh soaking up the water droplets
on the leaves helps prevent the growth
of mold and bacteria protecting the
leaves from rot or damage it also
helps the leaves dry faster reducing
the risk of infection due to prolonged
moisture additionally soaking up
the water on the leaves helps the
plant maintain a clean appearance
preventing water stains from forming
this also allows the plant to absorb light
more efficiently supporting the photosynthesis
process care for your Orchids with the four steps
above about once every 10 days to
ensure they grow healthy and Bloom
beautifully on regular days you
should water the plant when you
notice that the medium and roots
are dry let's take a look at the
results um you can see that the roots of the
orchids are growing very strong which helps
the plant absorb water and nutrients better
leading to Stronger growth and consistent
blooming uh if you enjoyed this video don't
forget to like share and subscribe to support the
channel and many new flower Spikes
have sprouted on the same Orchid plan
plant proving that the plant is growing very
well and is preparing to bloom for the next
season this also shows that the Orchid is being
properly cared for with the right nutrients and
growing conditions allowing the plant to maintain
long-term vitality and continuously produce blooms
care for your Orchids with sincere love
and they will return with beautiful
blooms those flowers will make life
more beautiful and filled with joy
I hope this video provides you
with valuable insights thank you
for staying with me until the end wishing you
all good health and see you in the next videos