welcome to my channel.
if you have orchids after blooming.
If all the flowers have fallen, don't rush to throw them away.
Let me tell you how to help these branches continue to bloom strongly again.
These nodes can continue to bloom very well.
When you eat bananas.
Don't throw away the peel.
Thinly sliced ​​banana peels contain many vitamins and minerals that are very good for the bud formation process.
Please comment to me which country you are watching the video from!
It's great that we can chat together from all over the world!
Soak banana peels in 1 liter of boiled water.
Then take 3 tablespoons of coffee grounds.
Then soak this coffee grounds in 1 liter of boiled water.
Then wait for the water to cool.
After the water cools, filter to remove sediment.
Dip a cotton ball in water extracted from coffee grounds and wash the leaves.
Helps eliminate pests and diseases of orchids.
and leaves will photosynthesize better.
If you haven't subscribed to the channel yet, please subscribe to support me and not miss any orchid care tips!
Mix these two types together.
Dip cotton balls in this water and clip them to nodes that are likely to continue blooming.
Do it once a week.
will help stimulate rapid sprout growth.
Keep the cotton pad on the branch like that for 20 minutes and then remove it.
then water the roots once a week.
Soak it for 10 minutes then lift it out.
And spray this water once a week to help supplement nutrients through the leaves.
After 20 minutes, remove the cotton pad.
Then place the plant in a place with lots of light so it can bloom easily.
1 MONTH LATER.
Many buds have grown.
If you encounter any difficulties during the orchid growing process, don't hesitate to comment!
I am always ready to support you so you can grow healthy orchids and bloom lots of flowers. 🌸
Continue watering and spraying the orchid with this water once a week.
Then place the plant in a place with lots of light so it can bloom easily.
After the next 1 month.
From the dry branches, many beautiful flowers have sprouted and bloomed.
The leaves are strong and sturdy, very resistant to pests and diseases.
The flower color is also more vibrant than usual.
Hope the video will help you a lot.
If you find it interesting, please like, share and subscribe
to the channel to help my channel reach 1 million subscribers soon.
My videos have subtitles in many different languages ​​so you can choose the appropriate language.
Thank you for watching the video. Good luck and see you in the next videos.