Welcome to my channel.
To help you have many choices when caring for orchids at home with organic fertilizer.
In this video, I continue to share new methods.
Please subscribe to the video so you don't miss any tips on my channel.
Now let's get started.
To make this organic fertilizer you need coffee or coffee grounds.
I use 3 teaspoons.
Add 1 liter of boiled water.
Incubate until cool.
After the water cools, filter to remove residue.
Add water to make 5 liters of coffee solution.
Next add 1 teaspoon of baking soda.
FIRST METHOD
Water this fertilizer solution on the orchid roots.
Coffee contains many minerals and organic matter helps provide orchid nutrition.
It contains nitrogen, potassium and phosphorus,
Important nutritional elements for orchid growth.
Baking soda (bicarbonate soda) has the ability to increase the PH level in orchid pots,
This is helpful in reducing acidity if you use too much chemical fertilizer.
Baking soda has the ability to kill insects and fungi that damage plants.
SECOND METHOD
Spray this fertilizer on the entire orchid.
This method is similar to using foliar fertilizer.
You can use it as a natural pesticide to protect orchids from insects and diseases.
THIRD METHOD
Clean the leaf surface with this fertilizer solution.
The leaf surface will always be clean and airy with stomata.
Orchids will photosynthesize better.
RESULT
Plant roots are protected and supplemented with nutrients so they grow very healthily.
will help orchids absorb the most nutrients.
Because of enough nutrition, the flowers bloom more brilliantly.
Many flowers bloom on the same branch.
The flowers stay on the branches for a long time before fading.
Thank you for watching the video. Wish you luck and success in life.
Goodbye and see you again in the next videos.