hi everyone to give you more options for
taking care of your orchids at home
today I'll be sharing a new way to make
a natural fertilizer it's simple and
[Music]
effective let's dive
in Weak orchids have been thrown away by
people
[Music]
this orchid has completely rotted so it
cannot be
[Music]
restored this Orchid although its leaves
are wilted is still fresh and can be
revived
[Music]
then cut off all the damaged
Roots damaged rotting or moldy Roots can
be a breeding ground for bacteria and
fungi which can harm the entire plant
cutting them off helps prevent the
spread of disease
[Music]
when you cut off the damaged Roots the
plant won't waste energy on
nonfunctioning Roots allowing it to
focus on growing strong new roots
[Music]
then cut off all the old flower
spikes when you cut off the old flower
spikes the plant will focus its energy
on growing new flower spikes helping it
to bloom continuously and more
beautifully in the following seasons
[Music]
then wash the plant with water to remove
dirt bacteria mold and other impurities
from the leaves and stem reducing the
risk of the plant getting infected
washing the plant also helps improve air
circulation for the leaves and stem
allowing the plant to exchange gases
more easily and perform photosynthesis
more
effectively then place the wilted orchid
in a container and soak it in water for
about 1 hour this helps the plant absorb
moisture into the roots and leaves ESP
especially when the plant is dry or
lacking water this helps the plant
recover quickly and reduce wilting
[Music]
take one teaspoon of cinnamon
powder add 1 lit of boiling
water cinnamon powder has strong
antibacterial and anti-fungal properties
helping to prevent the growth of
bacteria and mold which are common
threats to orchids
[Music]
cinnamon powder also stimulates the
growth of new Roots by improving
metabolism and enhancing the plant's
ability to absorb
nutrients cover the container and wait
for the water to
cool next take 3 teaspoons of
breadcrumbs
[Music]
add 50 m of
beer and mix it into one liter of water
warm
water stir
[Music]
well cover the container and wait for
the water to cool
[Music]
after 1 hour the water has
cooled stir well to ensure the nutrients
are completely dissolved in the
water strain to collect the cinnamon
water
step one use a soft cotton pad to gently
wipe the top and bottom of the orchid
leaves with cinnamon water
cinnamon water has strong antibacterial
and anti-fungal properties helping to
remove bacteria mold or impurities that
could harm the
plant wiping the orchid leaves with
cinnamon water helps clean off potential
pathogens on the leaves protecting the
plant from bacterial and fungal
attacks now place the roots of the
Orchid into the cup like this
[Music]
mix the breadcrumb soaking solution with
the cinnamon water solution
[Music]
step two soak the Orchid roots in this
solution for 20
[Music]
minutes uh this mixture can help improve
the absorption of water and nutrients by
the Orchid Roots while also stimul ating
the growth of new Roots the Orchid Roots
will have a better chance to grow
stronger and more easily absorb
nutrients from the surrounding
[Music]
environment after soaking for 20 minutes
we proceed to plant the Orchid in a new
pot with a growing medium of sterilized
and dried spagna Moss
[Music]
sagum Moss has excellent moisture
retaining properties helping to maintain
the necessary humidity for the Orchid
especially when the plant is wilted or
weak orchids need stable humidity to
recover and grow and the Moss will
provide continuous moisture to the roots
without causing water
[Music]
logging uh from now on we will water
this Orchid with the cinnamon water and
breadcrumb water mixture once a week
[Music]
then place the Orchid pot in a spot with
gentle sunlight to allow the plant to
photosynthesize and carry out its
metabolic processes
effectively we use the remaining liquid
fertilizer solution to water the other
[Music]
orchids both cinnamon water and bread
crumbs contain natural comp components
that help stimulate blooming cinnamon
water contains antifungal and
antibacterial properties which keep the
plant healthy while breadcrumbs provide
essential nutrients to promote the
plant's growth especially during the
flowering preparation stage
breadcrumbs contain starch and sugar
which are rich energy sources for the
plant these nutrients help stimulate the
growth of new Roots supporting the
Orchid in quickly recovering and
developing a strong root system
after watering with this liquid
fertilizer soak the Orchid 20 minutes
then remove the
[Music]
pot results after 1
month as you can see the new Roots have
developed very
strong and the orchid has developed a
new Leaf at the
[Music]
top when the new Roots grow strong they
will be able to absorb water and
essential nutrients from the growing
medium more effectively this helps the
Orchid develop healthily with enough
energy and nutrients to bloom and
produce new spikes
[Music]
continue to apply this liquid fertilizer
to the Orchid once a week
regular fertilizing provides the Orchid
with A continuous supply of nutrients
preventing any deficiencies this
supports the plant's growth at all
stages from Roots to Stems leaves and
flowers
[Music]
results after the next 3 months
as you can see the old Orchid Leaf is
still wilted but the new leaves have
developed healthy and
[Music]
strong for
here a new flower Spike has
emerged and over here a large flower
Spike has developed and grown
long it's wonderful to see a weak Orchid
recover grow strong and continue to
bloom after a period of meticulous care
from Reviving The Roots regular
fertilizing to protecting the plant from
harmful factors the orchid has overcome
difficulties and shows its vibrant life
through beautiful blooms watching the
healthy Orchid Thrive and flower is an
invaluable Joy the result of patience
and love for nature each flower that
blooms is a testament to the care and
perseverance making us feel proud and
happy