Welcome to my Happiness Garden channel.
If you plant a lot of orchids, the spread of rotten orchids due to bacteria or fungi is unavoidable.
In this video I show you how to get your rotten orchid to recover and grow quickly.
First, check if the roots are healthy.
This orchid of mine has all roots damaged.
so I will cut all the rotten part from the orchid.
Then rinse with water.
then wipe dry.
Apply toothpaste on the cut.
This helps the cut heal faster and protects the orchid from rot.
Take 1 aloe leaf.
sliced.
Add 1 teaspoon of honey.
Add 500ml of water at room temperature.
Stir well so that the nutrients from the aloe vera gel and honey dissolve into the water.
Soak orchid branches in this water for 30 minutes.
Put 500ml of warm water in the bottle.
add 1 teaspoon of cinnamon powder.
Allow 30 minutes for the drug to dissolve in water to be used.
After 30 minutes of soaking, filter out the residue.
Soak moss in cinnamon water for 30 minutes.
Put the orchid in a bottle and mist it to keep it moist every 5 days.
Put in a cool place to wait for the orchid to take root.
1 MONTH LATER.
With this simple way, after 1 month the orchid has taken root
Roots grow very healthy.
If you find it interesting, remember to subscribe to my support channel.
Now I will plant it in a pot so that the orchid can grow in the outside environment.
Plastic seeds for growing hydroponic vegetables are placed at the bottom of the pot.
On the face is moss to help retain moisture better.
After planting, water and care like other normal plants.
Hope the video will help you a lot.
Wish you success and always happy in life.
Goodbye and see you in the next videos.