Welcome to my channel.
Today I share a new way,
Helps support the growth of super orchids.
Like my orchid.
To have super giant orchids, orchids must be disease-free.
Leaves must be green and free from fungal diseases.
It is the most important way for orchids to photosynthesize and absorb nutrients.
When there is enough nutrition, the flower will be very big.
THIS IS A MILK WITHOUT SUGAR.
I would use a ratio of 1 part milk to 3 parts water.
Use this absorbent cotton and wipe the entire front and back of the leaf,
Fix has very good disinfecting properties,
Will help get rid of fungus and bacteria,
Lan will be safe and protected.
At the same time, milk contains many essential minerals for plants
Will indirectly absorb nutrients through orchid leaves.
Do this every 2 weeks for better protection and growth
This is an eggshell
I dried and ground it
Use 1 spoon
Add 200ml of boiled water
Close the lid and wait for it to cool
Use 1 teaspoon of honey
Add 2 liters of water
Use this water to water every 3 weeks for orchids that are flowering.
Honey contains many vitamins, minerals and natural sugars.
Orchids will easily absorb and make the flowers super big and long lasting.
You see this is a withered orchid.
Now let me show you how to revive this orchid.
I use 1 small ginger.
Squeeze out the water to soak the orchid branches in ginger water.
Wait for it to dry.
Use a molten candle to apply on the cut
Doing so will not allow water to seep inside the orchid,
This will prevent the orchid from rotting and from losing water.
I will recycle it into a miniature greenhouse to revive the orchid.
Place the orchid in the moss and mist it to keep it moist.
Put it in a cool place and mist it every 5 days.
AFTER 3 WEEKS
The little sprout has come back to life.
Continue to keep in a cool place and mist once every 5 days.
AFTER 3 MONTHS
Lan has successfully revived with extremely strong roots
To prevent the orchid from root rot, I will replant it with pine bark and pumice stone.
From now on, water once every 7-10 days to keep moist.
combine using organic fertilizers like I shared on the channel to take care of them,
Will help orchids grow better
If you find it interesting, please like, share and subscribe to the channel,
Help the channel reach 100,000 subscribers soon