Hello friends! How are you?
In this video, I continue to share natural fertilizers that are easy to make from things in the kitchen
Help your orchids grow strongly and bloom continuously.
If you haven't subscribed to my channel yet, please subscribe so you don't miss any orchid growing tips on my channel.
Let's get started!
To make this fertilizer I need bananas.
Banana peels contain a lot of potassium, phosphorus and nitrogen, essential elements for plant growth.
Potassium helps enhance resistance and flowering ability.
Compounds in banana peels help plants resist pests and mold.
Cut banana peel into small pieces.
Banana peel is a natural material, easy to find and environmentally friendly,
helps you reduce waste.
This is aloe vera leaf.
Aloe vera contains many vitamins and minerals,
helping to increase the plant's resistance.
Cut aloe vera into small slices.
Then add aloe vera and banana peel into the jar.
Next I need beer.
Take 100ml of beer, which is equivalent to about 7 tablespoons.
Beer after fermentation helps prevent aloe vera and banana peels from rotting
Beer contains sugar and carbohydrates,
which help provide energy to plants, promoting growth and flowering.
Add 2 cups of warm water (about 500ml) to help GE ferment better.
The vitamins in beer can support metabolism in plants.
Use cotton to cover the hole in the bottle cap.
Helps prevent bacteria and mold from entering the GE during fermentation.
Place in a cool place and incubate for 3 weeks.
3 Weeks Later.
This is a GE jar made from banana peels and aloe vera that I made 3 weeks ago.
Take 20ml of this GE (about more than 1 tablespoon).
Add 1 liter of water (about 1 liter).
When the roots are silvery white like this, we need to water the orchid.
Use this water to water orchid roots.
GE made from banana peels and aloe vera helps improve soil structure
and retain moisture for plant roots.
Nutrients help roots grow healthily, allowing the plant to absorb nutrients better.
When combining two types of banana peel and aloe vera to make GE,
You will provide a rich source of nutrients for the orchid, helping the plant develop comprehensively.
Banana peel adds potassium and phosphorus, while aloe vera adds vitamins and moisture,
creates a perfect formula for plant growth.
Doing this 1-2 times a month or combining it with other organic fertilizers will help orchids develop comprehensively.
Remember that GE organic fertilizer made from aloe vera and banana peels is great.
But if the orchid does not absorb enough light, the orchid will not grow.
Soaking the roots in this water for 20 minutes helps the orchid absorb nutrients better.
When the substrate is still moist and the roots are still green like this, you do not need to water the orchid.
If you water too much, the roots can easily rot.
While the orchid is absorbing moisture and nutrients, we can take advantage of this time to take care of the plant's leaves.
Do you see any white streaks left on the leaves from the spray?
Wiping leaves with tea water not only cleans dirt and dust,
but also provides nutrients to the plant through the leaves.
Be sure to clean the undersides of leaves as well because that's where pests like to hide.
Look how green and shiny the leaves are after cleaning!
This method not only cleans the leaf surface but also provides nutrients through the leaves to the orchid.
After cleaning, the orchid's photosynthetic organs will function better.
Helps improve orchids' metabolism.
Do this 1-2 times a month to keep the orchids protected.
Now put this water in a spray bottle.
Banana peel solution is not only great for watering orchids but can also be used to mist them.
This helps provide nutrients, freshen the leaves, increase humidity and clean dust from the leaves.
You can mist orchids once a week with this GE water.
On weekdays, you only need to spray water regularly when you see the roots turn silvery white.
Treat your plants with love and they will repay you with lush green leaves and blooming flowers.
Please let me know in the comments where you are watching!
It's wonderful that we can connect from all over the world, united by our love for plants.
Thank you for watching the video. Wish you luck and success in life!