Welcome to my channel.
If you have a rotten or damaged orchid and you want to restore it quickly.
And if you don't want to miss any orchid growing tips, subscribe to my channel today.
This is a rotten orchid that people threw away, I picked it up to restore it.
The cause of rot is disease-causing fungi and bacteria.
I remove all damaged roots and damaged leaves.
Then rinse with water.
Then hang in a cool place for 2 hours to let the orchid dry naturally.
I took 1 aloe vera leaf.
Then filter to get aloe vera jelly.
I cut the rest into thin slices.
Then puree with 500ml of water.
Then filter out the residue.
Next I took 3 spoons of rice.
Add 500ml of water.
Then leave for 2 hours for the nutrients to completely dissolve in the water.
2 HOURS LATER.
Take aloe vera jelly and wipe the leaves.
This helps wilted orchids recover and grow very quickly.
At the same time, it also kills disease-causing bacteria and fungi very effectively.
Mix the two types together.
Soak the roots in this water for 30 minutes.
This helps the roots not rot and grow new roots very quickly
Then plant the orchid in a new pot for the orchid to recover.
Covering the pot with a layer of moss helps retain moisture better.
From now on water this once a week.
And spray this water on the leaves once a week.
Place in a light and airy place so the orchid can recover easily.
1 MONTH LATER.
The leaves become stronger and a new leaf grows.
And many new roots grow.
These new roots help absorb nutrients better, so the orchid will recover very quickly
Continue watering this once a week.
and Continue spraying this water once a week.
AFTER THE NEXT 2 MONTHS.
This leaf has completely recovered and become lush
The roots grow strongly and produce many new roots.
With this simple method, the orchid recovered completely very quickly.
Thank you for watching the video. Please share the video so more people know..
Good luck and see you in the next videos!