Welcome to my Happiness Garden channel.
If you plant a lot of orchids, the spread of rotten orchids due to bacteria or fungi is unavoidable.
In this video I show you how to get your rotten orchid to recover and grow quickly.
First, check if the roots are healthy.
This orchid of mine has all roots damaged.
so I will cut all the rotten part from the orchid.
Then rinse with water.
then wipe dry.
Apply toothpaste on the cut.
This helps the cut heal faster and protects the orchid from rot.
Take 1 aloe leaf.
sliced.
Add 1 teaspoon of honey.
Add 500ml of water at room temperature.
Stir well so that the nutrients from the aloe vera gel and honey dissolve into the water.
Soak orchid branches in this water for 30 minutes.
Put 500ml of warm water in the bottle.
add 1 teaspoon of cinnamon powder.
Allow 30 minutes for the drug to dissolve in water to be used.
After 30 minutes of soaking, filter out the residue.
Soak moss in cinnamon water for 30 minutes.
Put the orchid in a bottle and mist it to keep it moist every 5 days.
Put in a cool place to wait for the orchid to take root.
1 MONTH LATER.
With this simple way, after 1 month the orchid has taken root
Roots grow very healthy.
If you find it interesting, remember to subscribe to my support channel.
Now I will plant it in a pot so that the orchid can grow in the outside environment.
Plastic seeds for growing hydroponic vegetables are placed at the bottom of the pot.
On the face is moss to help retain moisture better.
After planting, water and care like other normal plants.
Hope the video will help you a lot.
And don't rush to leave because in the next part of the video I share extremely effective tips for recovering rotten orchids.
Today I will show you how to revive a rotten orchid like this.
When the orchid has withered all the leaves, only the stem and roots remain, do not rush to throw it away.
Here are still fresh roots.
First, cut off all damaged, rotten roots.
Apply a molten candle on the cut so that the water does not penetrate the tree.
Use 2 teaspoons of cinnamon powder.
Add 1 liter of boiled water.
Close the lid and wait for the water to cool.
The water has cooled down
Filter out residue.
Soak orchids in this water for 30 minutes.
The rest of the water I will spray on other orchids to help protect the orchid from insects and fungal diseases
After soaking for 30 minutes, plant it.
Using pine bark and dry pumice stone to plant will help absorb moisture in the roots, making the orchid roots not rot.
Add some dry moss on the face.
Put in a cool and well-lit place for 7 days
After 7 days, you can spray water to keep the plants moist.
Cover with a clear, vented plastic container and wait for the plant to revive.
AFTER 3 WEEKS,
A sprout has sprouted,
Spray water once every 5 days to keep the sprouts moist
AFTER 2 MONTHS
Hope this sharing content will help you in resurrecting weak orchids to grow again
If you find it interesting, remember to click like, share and subscribe so that my channel will soon reach 100,000 subscribers.
The video I have created many subtitles, you can choose the appropriate language to understand my shares.
Good luck to you all.
See you in the next videos.