Welcome to my channel.
Today's video I share how to easily make your own fertilizer
But its effects are miraculous.
Let's start.
To make this magical fertilizer you need flour.
I took 3 tablespoons of flour.
And take another spoonful of yeast (the type of yeast used to make bread).
Add a little warm water.
Then incubate for 2 hours for the beneficial microorganisms in the yeast to take effect.
AFTER 2 HOURS.
Currently, the beneficial microorganisms in yeast have multiplied many times over.
Mix with 5 liters of water.
FIRST METHOD
Water the orchid roots with this microbial fertilizer solution.
Beneficial microorganisms will grow in the orchid pot.
Helps protect orchid roots from rot caused by fungi and bacteria.
This type of fertilizer also balances the PH level in orchid pots.
Helps stimulate orchid roots to grow and not be damaged by acid.
This type of fertilizer also provides many necessary nutrients for orchids such as:
Potassium, phosphorus, nitrogen, magnesium, calcium, iron, zinc and vitamins...
It would be better to soak the orchid pot for 30 minutes.
This type of fertilizer is especially good for weak, stunted orchids with underdeveloped root systems.
because it does not shock weak orchids like chemical fertilizers.
SECOND METHOD
Wipe the leaves clean with this microbial fertilizer solution.
Helps eliminate insects and leaf-damaging fungi.
THRD METHOD
Spray this fertilizer solution over the entire orchid.
Especially with weak orchids, it will help recover quickly.
RESURT
If you do this every 2 weeks, after only 1-2 months the orchid will have many new roots.
This helps the orchid absorb maximum nutrients through its roots.
Flowers bloom brightly and colorfully.
Many flowers bloom on the same branch.
Thank you for watching the video. Good luck
Goodbye and see you again in the next video.