Welcome to my channel.
This orchid pot has rot disease.
and the leaves also wither.
When leaves wilt, the cause may be due to damaged roots and not absorbing enough water, leading to wilted leaves.
And you see these roots have rotted due to waterlogging.
Cut off all rotten roots.
then rinse.
Take 1 clove of garlic.
Then puree with 500ml of water.
Filter out residue.
Add water to make 2 liters of garlic water.
Step 1: Clean the leaves thoroughly with garlic water.
Garlic juice helps eliminate fungal diseases and harmful insects.
Step 2: Soak orchid roots in garlic water for 10 minutes.
Then take it out and put it in a jar.
Pour in water.
Keep the water level at this position.
Place on the windowsill or under a sunshade for orchids.
1 WEEK LATER.
Take 1 liter of water.
Take 1 spoon of rice.
Soak orchid roots in rice water for 20 minutes.
Then take it out and put it in a jar.
Pour in water.
From now on, soak orchid roots in rice water once a week.
3 weeks later.
Orchid leaves are sturdy and less likely to wilt.
New roots grow a lot, helping the orchid quickly recover withered leaves.
I continue to take 1 spoon of rice mixed with rice water to take care of the orchids.
Continue soaking orchid roots in rice water once a week.
After 20 minutes, take it out and put it in a jar.
3 MONTHS LATER.
So with this simple method, after only 3 months the orchid has recovered and grown very healthy.
Both roots, leaves and flowers grow strongly.
If you find the video good, please subscribe to my support channel.
And share so more people know this orchid care tip.
My videos have subtitles in many different languages
Please choose the appropriate language to clearly understand the video content
Thank you for watching the video.
Good luck and see you in the next videos!