welcome to my
channel in this video I continue to
share how to make orchids bloom at the
same time with many flower
branches orchids after flowers fade
[Music]
we cut off all the spent flower
stems if the plant has never bloomed it
must have three or more pairs of
leaves and healthy roots
which country are you watching this
video from please leave a comment and
let me
know it's amazing that we can chat
together from all around the
world sprinkle cinnamon powder on the
wound to help it heal quickly
[Music]
then wait one day for the cut to
dry then take half small onion and cut
it into thin slices
[Music]
add 1 liter of water and bring to a boil
wait a day then
[Music]
use next take three spoons of
rice then soak in 1 liter of water and
leave for 1 day before
[Music]
using after a day filter out the residue
mix the two types together
[Music]
clean the leaves with this
water helps eliminate fungi and bacteria
to help orchids grow
[Music]
better do it once a week
then use this water to water the Orchid
[Music]
Roots this will help stimulate root and
flower stem
[Music]
growth do it once a
week Place cotton balls between two
leaves
[Music]
then spray this water on the Cotton
pad this stimulates flower stems to
[Music]
grow and spray on the top and bottom of
the leaves to help supplement nutrients
through the leaves for the orchids
[Music]
this should be done early in the morning
so that by noon the leaves will dry
before the sun
[Music]
shines after 30 minutes remove the
cotton and repeat once a
[Music]
week and take out the Orchid pot
2 months
[Music]
later many flower stems grow at the same
time
[Music]
orchids also grow many new
roots with this simple method you can
easily care for Blooming orchids at home
[Music]
tips for recovering rot infected orchids
uh when orchids are old and have poor
resistance we need to rejuvenate
[Music]
them first you need to cut off all
damaged leaves and
[Music]
Roots keep only fresh roots
onions have very good antiseptic and
growth stimulating effects
[Music]
take about 20 G of thinly sliced onion
take one teaspoon of baking soda helps
balance pH levels and eliminate fungal
diseases harmful to
[Music]
orchids add 2 L of water at room
temperature
[Music]
wait 30 minutes before
using after 30 minutes filter to remove
residue
[Music]
then water the Orchid with onion water
and baking soda
[Music]
soak in this water for 30 minutes
cover the pot with a layer of dry moss
[Music]
place the dried moss in this transparent
plastic box
[Music]
leave in a cool place for one day
without
[Music]
watering one one day
later from now on water your orchids
once a
[Music]
week or water when the Moss is dry
be careful to keep the Moss moist if the
Moss is water loged the Orchid will
easily
[Music]
rot then place it in a cool place with
enough light for the Orchid to grow
[Music]
3 weeks later
many baby orchids have sprouted
[Music]
Take 2 L of water at room temperature
then add five spoons of rice
[Music]
water the Orchid with rice water once a
week helps stimulate baby orchids to
grow and take root quickly
[Music]
continue to place in a cool well-lit
place for the Orchid to
[Music]
grow after the next one month
the baby orchids grow very
[Music]
healthy hopefully the video will help
you a lot in taking care of orchids at
home
[Music]
if you find it interesting please click
like and share so more people
[Music]
know and um don't forget to subscribe to
the channel so your channel can soon
reach 1 million subscriptions
[Music]
next to help you have many options when
caring for orchids at home with organic
fertilizer helps orchids grow and Bloom
with many long lasting flowers in this
video I continue to share new methods
[Music]
when eating oranges don't rush to throw
away the
[Music]
peel right now I will share this tip for
making organic fertilizer from orange
peels
[Music]
if you haven't subscribed yet please uh
subscribe to support me and to not miss
any orchid care tips and don't forget to
share so more people can learn these
great tips
[Music]
I cut the peel of an orange and put it
in a
jar add 2 L of warm water
then add one spoon of sugar and one
spoon of
[Music]
yeast punch holes in the lid close the
lid and leave in a cool place for 1
[Music]
month 1 month later
I already have GE orange peel
[Music]
fertilizer I took four tablespoons of GE
orange peel
[Music]
mix 2 L of
water first
method use a GE Orange Peel to
thoroughly wipe the top and bottom of
the leaf
[Music]
orange peels contain essential oils that
after incubation will help repel insects
very
[Music]
effectively helps leaves photosynthesize
and create chlorophyll better
[Music]
do this one to two times a month to
protect orchids and keep the leaves
green
[Music]
second
method applying this fertilizer to the
roots one to two times per month helps
provide organic substances such as humic
acid fulvic acid and enhance water
retention in Orchid growing media
[Music]
Orange Peel also contains many important
minerals such as potassium magnesium
calcium and Trace
[Music]
elements GE fertilizer helps orchids
grow strongly and increase flower
production
[Music]
GE fertilizer helps improve the ability
of plants to absorb
[Music]
nutrients helping orchids make better
use of available nutrients in the
environment
[Music]
let's see the
results the flower color is more vibrant
than usual
[Music]
orchids bloom many flowers on the same
tree but do not
[Music]
fall flowers bloom continuously from
season to season all year round
[Music]
the flowers stay on the branches for a
long time before
[Music]
fading thank you for watching the video
good luck and see you in the next videos