Hello friends.
Nice to meet you on my channel.
You see here a withered orchid.
Maybe it's because you didn't water it.
or due to direct sunlight shining on the orchid.
If you want orchids to be nourished and grow quickly.
Please watch this video carefully.
Now I will share this amazing trick with you.
You need 1 aloe vera leaf.
This aloe vera gel is great for reviving orchids.
Now apply aloe vera gel on the top and bottom of the leaf.
Aloe vera gel has a very good moisturizing effect.
In addition, aloe vera also contains vitamins A, B, and C
and minerals such as nitrogen, phosphorus and potassium.
Do this every 5 days and leave the orchid pot in a cool place for 3 weeks.
Next, take 1 liter of warm water and put it in the bottle.
Then take 1 spoon of rice and soak it in this water for about 30 minutes.
Let the nutrients in the rice completely dissolve into the water.
Chop the remaining aloe vera leaves into small pieces.
Then puree with 300ml of water.
Filter out residue half past four Add 2 liters of water at room temperature.
After soaking for 30 minutes, filter this rice water.
Mix rice water with aloe vera juice.
So I ended up with about 3 liters of this wonderful liquid manure solution.
Cover the pot with moss to retain moisture better.
Now you use this solution to water the orchid every 5 days.
Soak the orchid pot in this water for 2 hours.
After soaking for 2 hours, remember to lift the orchid pot and place it in a cool place to let the orchid recover.
2 WEEKS LATER.
Fertilize after 2 weeks for fresher orchid leaves.
New roots develop very well.
Many new roots are growing.
New roots will help transport water and nutrients from the roots to the stem.
If the leaves are provided with enough water and nutrients from the roots,
The leaves will gradually become lush again.
1 MONTH LATER.
You see the leaves are very fresh.
and the orchid grows a new leaf.
after the next 2 months
The orchid has grown two branches (two buds).
But the leaves at the base have turned yellow so I will cut off these yellow leaves.
Instinctively, when an orchid buds, if the plant lacks nutrients,
the base leaves will turn yellow and fall off to provide nutrients for the buds to develop.
Now I need to supplement the orchid's nutrition by taking 3 spoons of rice.
Then soak in 2 liters of water at room temperature
and wait 30 minutes for the nutrients to completely dissolve in water before using.
30 Minutes Later
Add 3 tablespoons of milk
Rice water and milk are excellent sources of nutrients for orchids to grow
Now you water the orchid with this solution once a week to help the orchid recover quickly.
After the next 1 month.
After 3-4 times of applying liquid fertilizer from milk and rice water, the orchid had many roots.
Hope the video will help you a lot.
Next, I share how to make orchids bloom at the same time with many flower branches.
Orchids after flowers fade.
We cut off all the spent flower stems.
If the plant has never bloomed, it must have 3 or more pairs of leaves.
and healthy roots.
Sprinkle cinnamon powder on the wound to help it heal quickly.
Then wait 1 day for the cut to dry.
Then take 1/2 small onion and cut it into thin slices.
Add 1 liter of water and bring to a boil.
Wait a day then use.
Next take 3 spoons of rice.
Then soak in 1 liter of water and leave for 1 day before using.
After a day, filter out the residue.
Mix the two types together.
Clean the leaves with this water.
Helps eliminate fungi and bacteria to help orchids grow better.
Do it once a week.
Then use this water to water the orchid roots.
This will help stimulate root and flower stem growth.
Do it once a week.
Place cotton balls between 2 leaves
Then spray this water on the cotton pad.
This stimulates flower stems to grow.
and spray on the top and bottom of the leaves to help supplement nutrients through the leaves for the orchids.
This should be done early in the morning, so that by noon the leaves will dry before the sun shines.
After 30 minutes, remove the cotton and repeat once a week.
and take out the orchid pot.
2 Months Later.
Many flower stems grow at the same time.
Orchids also grow many new roots.
With this simple method, you can easily care for blooming orchids at home.
If you find the video interesting, don't forget to like, share and subscribe to the channel to easily follow tips on growing orchids.
Now I share with you a wonderful organic fertilizer,
And anyone can do it easily.
Just 1 to 2 ripe bananas,
And the orchid garden will bloom all kinds of flowers.
Now I will revive this orchid with new flowers,
You've seen this orchid lose all its flowers, leaving only withered branches
And here are the withered orchids that have been revived with lots of new flowers.
STEP
cut off the withers
Apply toothpaste on the cut
This will disinfect and help prevent rot
Don't throw away banana peels when eating bananas
Use 1 to 2 ripe banana peels
Clip the banana peel to the place where the flower buds can grow
and note to remove after 6 hours
This helps to create the right moisture, provide essential nutrients and stimulate flower sprouts,
do this once a week
STEP 2
Use a banana peel to wipe the top and bottom of the leaves,
Helps eliminate insects, fungi, bacteria hiding on orchid leaves,
and at the same time provide a part of nutrients through the leaves for orchids
Orchids will be protected and will not be affected by yellowing and rotten leaves.
After wiping, you will see green leaves,
Orchids will photosynthesize better to increase resistance.
STEP 3
1 liter of water
Leave in a cool and dark place for 1 day
AFTER 1 DAY
banana juice is darker
Use this absorbent cotton
Clip a cotton ball where the flower buds can grow
and note to remove after 6 hours
This helps to create the right moisture, provide essential nutrients and stimulate flower sprouts,
do this once a week
STEP 4
Normally after 3-4 weeks flower buds will be formed and develop like this,
With a flower sprout this big, there's no need to sandwich banana peels with cotton balls
You will be surprised how amazing this is
Don't forget to subscribe to see my next videos
STEP 5
Add water to make 2 liters
Water this banana for orchids once every 2-3 weeks
Banana peel is rich in potassium, phosphorus and essential vitamins.
will promote the growth of orchid roots
In particular, the potassium in banana peels stimulates flowering very well.
In addition, you need to combine using other organic fertilizers for orchids,
like manure made from soybeans, peas, fish poop... as I shared,
then make sure the orchid will grow healthy and produce many flowers
Hope this sharing content will help you in taking better care of orchids at home
I wish you luck and success
Thank you guys, see you in the next video!