Hello friends
When the orchid has all its leaves rotten like this
Don't rush to throw it away
I will show you how to revive it in a simple way
Just by applying this recipe correctly,
anyone can easily revive rotten orchids at home.
oh
This orchid has rotten leaves but the roots are still very strong
First, cut off all the damaged roots
Then rinse with water
Use 1 clove of garlic
and add 1 sprig of fresh ginger
Then slice and mince both garlic and ginger
Filter out the residue
Soak orchid branches in ginger and garlic juice for 20 minutes
20 MINUTES AFTER
Take it out and hang it in a cool place for 2 hours
2 HOURS AFTER
Orchid branch has dried
then sprinkle cinnamon powder on the cut
This helps the cut heal quickly and the roots do not rot
Then plant orchids with pine bark or dry soil
Then leave in a cool place for a week without watering
AFTER 1 WEEK WITHOUT WATERING
Cover the pot with a layer of moss to keep it moist
and from now on start watering and moisturizing once a week
Next you take a plate and pour water in like I did
put the orchid pot in the dish of water
Cover the orchid with a clear plastic bottle like this
and the orchid will grow like a greenhouse
1 MONTH LATER
Orchid root has germinated very healthy
New roots have also grown
Continue misting to keep moisture waiting for orchids to grow
EXTRA 1 MONTH
The orchid branch has revived strongly
New roots grow very well
So with this simple way
Anyone can revive rotten orchids at home
If you find it interesting, don't forget to like, share and subscribe to support me
Thank you for watching the video. Wish you successful and lucky.