I'm so glad you came to my channel
If you have an orchid, make sure you want it to bloom for a long time
so many flowers bloom all year round
Now I will show you what is the best fertilizer for orchids.
If you follow us till the end of this video,
you will learn how to make orchids bloom all year round.
Now get on with it
When the flowers have all bloomed
I cut off all the places that are no longer able to flower.
Then sprinkle white cement on the cut
and let the cut dry naturally
White cement helps disinfect and heal cuts quickly
A location like this will have the potential for budding or flower buds
I peel off the protective film that will make it easier to germinate
Using Tomatoes
Use 1 slice of tomato like this
Tomatoes contain a lot of Vitamin A,
vitamin C and rich in Potassium, Calcium, Phosphorus
When orchids are cared for with tomatoes, they will grow very quickly
Puree tomatoes in 300ml of water
Then filter the water
I add water to get 1 liter of tomato juice
Method 1
I use cotton pads soaked in tomato juice
i put it here
You should do it every 7 days to help keep these buds moist
for the flower top when it's still green like this
you still use this water we put it here
to maintain moisture for the flower spike and the flower top is very quickly revived
On normal days, you only use water to keep the flower branches moist
Way 2
You use this water we take care of the leaves will always be green
and healthy, because tomatoes have very good antioxidant
and antibacterial properties
please apply this every two weeks to the tree
The leaves after being taken care of will be green and healthy like this
Way 3
You can also use this tomato juice to spray on the top and bottom of the leaves
and spray evenly on the root
Way 4
Use this water to water the orchid once every 2 weeks
Orchids grow because nutrients are transported from the roots to all parts of the orchid
Before fertilizing, it is necessary to water a sufficient amount of moisture first
This will help the plant absorb the fertilizer better
Result
And with this simple way,
the regenerated flower branches will be very big and fat
This way I also get a seedling orchid
This way also helps flower buds to be big and healthy
so many flower buds are reborn in this way
So my house always has flowers blooming all year round.
If you want orchids to bloom more,
The flowers bloom for a long time on the branches before fading
brilliant flower color.
Like my orchid,
Flowering can last up to 6 months.
Flowers bloom all year round, one after another.
There are always many flowers growing on the same branch.
If you want that, do the following:
1. Place the orchid pot in a place with light sunlight.
Or leave it on the windowsill.
Avoid the sun and strong wind
2. Before fertilizing, water the orchid.
This will make it easier for the roots to absorb nutrients from the fertilizer.
Every time you water you can,
Soak orchid roots in water for 30 minutes to absorb enough water.
For leaves you use spray,
Spray to wet leaves with water to help open stomata.
After soaking for 30 minutes the roots absorb enough water will turn green like this.
We took it out and waited 30 minutes before fertilizing.
3. Use lemon as an organic fertilizer for orchids.
Use the remaining juice of half a lemon.
Mix lemon juice in 3 liters of water
Pour the lemon juice mixture into a spray bottle
Then spray evenly on the top and bottom of the leaves
Lemon juice is packed with nutrients like vitamin C, citric acid, potassium, and magnesium,
These substances are quickly absorbed through the leaves of the orchid,
helping to provide the nutrients needed to promote the health and growth of the plant.
After spraying, use cotton to dry the leaves
Pay attention to drying the leaf buds
Regular application of orchid leaves will always be green like this,
Leaves are not infected with fungal diseases.
4. Add 1 teaspoon of honey to the lemon juice solution earlier
Water this solution for orchid roots 1-2 times/month
Honey has the ability to stimulate growth and cell division in plants.
When using honey mixed with lemon juice as a fertilizer,
it will help the plant thrive, produce many new shoots, beautiful petals.
Honey has antibacterial and antifungal properties,
help orchids better disease resistance.
When using honey mixed with lemon juice as fertilizer,
it also helps orchids have bright colors, sweet fragrance and prolong the life of flowers.
You can also soak in this water for 30 minutes,
Let the roots absorb the most nutrients.