welcome to my channel wishing you a nice
day to help you have many choices when
caring for orchids at home using natural
methods in this video I continue to
share new methods helps orchids bloom
continuously all year round with large
beautiful flowers the Orchid grows many
new plump and healthy
[Music]
Roots let's get started
do you have
coffee put one teaspoon into the jar
[Music]
add 500 mL boiling
water
[Music]
stir C cover brew and let the water
cool next I need
oatmeal add 500 M boiled water
if you haven't subscribed to the channel
yet please do so to support me and to
make sure you don't miss any Orchid
growing tips on my
channel wait for the water to cool
[Music]
2 hours
later
[Music]
stir filter out coffee
grounds which country are you watching
the video from please comment
below it's amazing that we can connect
and chat from all around the world
add 500 mL of
[Music]
water method one
use soft cotton to absorb this water
then wash both the top and bottom of the
orchid leaves helps leaves clean of dirt
mold and insects residing on leaves
[Music]
cleaning the leaves regularly will keep
your orchid Lush and shiny the stom will
open and the plant will photosynthesize
better it also helps quickly heal Leaf
damage
[Music]
coffee contains a lot of nitrogen an
important element for plant growth
nitrogen helps plants grow green and
healthy leaves
coffee has antibacterial properties and
can help repel certain pests
washing leaves with coffee grounds helps
remove dirt and impurities helping the
leaves receive light better and
photosynthesize more effectively
doing this one to two times a month will
help protect the Orchid
then pour this water into the
[Music]
jar you use a spray bottle containing
the solution and spray mist on all
leaves and roots of the Orchid
this method has the same effect as using
foler
fertilizer provides plants with
nutrients that are easy to penetrate and
absorb through the leaf surface
with powerful antioxidant compounds this
type of fertilizer will help orchids
increase their
resistance protect orchids from
developing comprehensively from roots
stems and leaves promotes Buds and
Flowers to bloom
regularly water your orchid every 2
weeks this
way um you should do it in the morning
so that by noon when the sun comes up up
the leaves will be
dry
stir filter and mix the oatmeal with
coffee water
method
two when the roots turn silver white
it's best to water the roots
[Music]
you water each Orchid with this liquid
fertilizer coffee and oats contain many
minerals and organic substances that
help provide nutrients for orchids to
grow it contains very high levels of
nitrogen potassium and magnesium
important nutritional elements for the
Healthy Growth of or orchids it
stimulates orchids to bloom early with
more vibrant flowers
[Music]
uh if you water your orchids regularly
every 1 to two weeks it will be very
good once a month you can soak the
Orchid pot in this fertilizer solution
for about 20 minutes
[Music]
after 20 minutes take out the Orchid pot
and place it in a place with lots of
scattered sunlight so that the Orchid
can photosynthesize and exchange
nutrients well
[Music]
please join us to see if the tree is
growing
[Music]
well after only 3 weeks many new Roots
have
[Music]
grown new Roots help the plant absorb
water and necessary nutrients from the
environment this is very important for
plant growth especially during the
flowering
stage Roots help keep the tree standing
creating stability and reducing the risk
of falling especially in strong wind
environments or when the tree is
[Music]
tall the growth of new Roots often
stimulates the growth of other parts of
the plant including leaves and flowers
the plant will have enough energy to
grow and flower
[Music]
although roots are not directly involved
in photosynthesis they provide water and
nutrients to leaves where photosynthesis
takes place
[Music]
uh newly developed Roots often signal
that the plant is in healthy condition
creating favorable conditions for
flowering and blooming
[Music]
Roots also participate in the plants
respiration process helping to provide
oxygen to cells this is very important
for the life of the
tree Orchids with strong roots will
produce many buds
this Orchid of mine produces a lot of
buds when the flowers bloom they are
bright and plump the flowers stay on the
branches for a long time before fading
[Music]
hope you like this video please comment
to let me know if you like this
[Music]
video thank you for watching the video
good luck and success in life