🌿 Welcome to the little garden full of joy! Let's explore the beauty of orchids.
If your orchids become weak or fail to bloom due to improper care, don’t worry!
🌸 Improve their environment, provide proper nutrition, and adjust watering.
With patience, they will recover and bloom again! 💜✨
Let's get started!
This is an orchid infected with leaf rot caused by a fungus.
We need to separate the diseased plant from other orchids.
Now I will share how to restore this rotten orchid with only 1 leaf left.
Cut off all damaged roots.
If you haven't subscribed to the channel yet, please click the subscribe button to support me
and not miss any orchid growing tips! It's great to have company!
Leave fresh roots like this.
then rinse with water.
In addition to the English dub, we've now created dubs in French, German, Italian, Spanish, Portuguese,
Japanese, Hindi, and Indonesian to help you hear and understand the content more easily.
OH! This leaf also falls.
Watch me restore this leafless orchid.
Cut off all rotten parts of the orchid stem.
This will help prevent the orchid stem from rotting further.
Then sprinkle cinnamon powder on the cut to help the wound heal quickly.
Cinnamon powder has very good antibacterial and antiseptic properties.
Then place in a cool place for 2 hours to let the cut dry completely.
Take 1 clove of garlic and mince it.
Garlic contains allicin, a substance with powerful antibacterial and antifungal effects
helps prevent diseases and infections in orchids.
Add 500ml of water at room temperature.
Cover and leave for 2 hours so that the garlic's nutrients are completely dissolved in the water.
After 2 hours, filter out the residue to get garlic juice.
After seeing that the cut has dried, soak the orchid roots in garlic water for 10 minutes. 🌸
This helps to disinfect the orchid, preventing rot while also stimulating its growth and quick recovery. 🌸
After soaking for 10 minutes, take the orchid out and plant it in a new pot to help it recover and grow faster. 🌸
Use sterilized dry moss to grow plants.
Dry moss will absorb moisture and help the cut heal completely.
Then leave it in a cool place and do not water it for 1 week to let the cut heal completely.
This garlic water is used to water other orchids in the garden.
Nutrients found in garlic such as calcium and potassium
and selenium helps stimulate the growth of orchid roots, helping the plant recover quickly.
Do this every 2 weeks to increase the orchid's resistance and supplement nutrients for the orchid.
Garlic also has the effect of repelling insects, so it helps protect plant leaves.
After 1 week, we start watering the orchids again.
Then use recycled plastic bottles to create a miniature greenhouse to grow orchids.
Spray water every time the growing medium and orchid are dry.
Cover and place in a cool, well-lit place.
Results after 1 month.
You can see a new baby orchid being revived from the trunk of an old dying orchid.
New roots also grow a lot, which will help the baby orchids grow faster.
From a bare orchid stem, an extremely healthy baby orchid has now been revived.
When the root system is strong, we fertilize it to help the orchid grow faster.
Take 1/2 teaspoon of flour.
Add 500ml of room temperature water (about 2 cups).
Using wheat flour helps stimulate the growth of beneficial microorganisms in orchid pots,
Helps increase the plant's ability to absorb water and nutrients.
Wait 1 hour before using to fertilize orchids.
01 Hour later.
Filter out residue.
Then water this mixture every 2 weeks.
Continue to cover and place in a cool place with enough light.
Results after 2 month.
The baby orchids have grown and developed very healthily.
The root system grows very healthy.
Leaves are green and sturdy.
Continue using fertilizer from wheat flour to water the orchids.
Wheat flour contains a lot of carbohydrates,
which serves as food for beneficial microorganisms in the soil or orchid growing medium.
These microorganisms help improve soil structure,
Enhances the ability to decompose organic substances, helping plants absorb nutrients better.
Results after 3 month.
The orchid has grown stronger and produced buds.
Growing roots help the orchid absorb nutrients best.
The leaves are green and strong.
This leaf has a rot disease so it must be removed immediately.
Continue to use wheat flour fertilizer to water the orchids every 2 weeks.
Results after 4 month.
From the bare orchid stem, it has now revived and grown into a mature orchid.
The flowers bloom brightly and beautifully.
If you find the video meaningful, please like and share so more people know.
And don't forget to subscribe to the channel to help my channel reach 10 million subscriptions soon.
Thank you for watching and supporting my channel.
Wishing you success and joy in life.
Hello and see you again in the next videos