Welcome to my Happiness Garden channel.
In this video, I share how to fertilize to help weak orchids produce many flowers.
To make this fertilizer you need to take 5 teaspoons of rice
Rice contains many nutrients that are important for the growth of orchids
then add 1 liter of warm water
Then add 1 teaspoon of dry yeast (yeast used to make bread)
Yeast helps prevent organic matter from decomposing and rotting
When eating bananas, don't throw away the peel
Adding 1 banana peel helps ferment quickly and enhances nutrition very well
Leave in a cool place to ferment naturally for 3 days
When the last flowers have withered.
Cut off all flower stalks that have bloomed.
Let me share with you how to revive from flower stalks.
then you peel off the protective film so that this button can easily grow new buds.
Apply toothpaste on the cut,
It will help the cut heal.
3 days after fermentation, filter this water
Add 3 liters of water
Then clamp in place where the buttons are likely to grow into sprouts.
This fermented juice is packed with nutrients like potassium, nitrogen, phosphorus, calcium and magnesium.
It helps stimulate the growth and development of plants.
Repeat once a week with this fermented water.
On normal days, you just need to spray water to keep it moist.
Then, you use the fermented water to water the orchid roots.
The potassium content in this fermented water helps strengthen and support the growth of branches and roots very well.
and nitrogen supports the process of nitrogen formation and the development of reproductive organs of the plant.
Apply this liquid fertilizer every 2 weeks to help the plant take root.
Soaking this fermented water for about 30 minutes at a time will be very delicious.
Helps increase the pest resistance of orchids
For leaves: you also use this fermented water to spray on the entire plant.
Apply 1-2 times per month.
1 MONTH LATER.
There are many shoots growing from the nodes.
The sprouts that sprout and take root immediately.
With this flower stalk, both young shoots and flower buds develop.
And this flower stalk has revived very large flower buds.
This flower branch is smeared with fermented banana juice,
the flower stays fresh for a long time.
This water helps improve soil structure and increase the plant's ability to absorb nutrients.
thereby helping plants grow healthier,
Roots will absorb maximum nutrients from the soil.
Hope the video helps you a lot.
If you like it, don't forget to like and share.
and subscribe to my support channel.