Welcome to my channel.
For orchids to grow healthy, produce more flower buds.
My orchid has a lot of flower buds.
Flowers bloom for a long time.
Today I share this organic fertilizer will be very good for orchids.
it's tea.
I use about 10 grams of tea.
Add 200ml of boiled water.
Wait 5 minutes for the tea to dissolve in the water.
AFTER 5 MINUTES
Filter out residue
add 500ml water at room temperature
Tea residue applied to the base of the orchid
Pour some tea into a spray bottle
Water each root with about 10 teaspoons of freshly brewed tea.
Tea contains tannins that will help disinfect and protect orchids from fungal diseases that damage the roots and leaves.
In addition, it contains many vitamins and minerals that help orchids absorb nutrients better
You can also spray diluted tea on the leaves to help control fungal diseases and repel insects.
Do this once every 2 weeks in combination with other organic fertilizers that I have shared on the channel,
Then the orchid will be protected and increased resistance.
Lan sẽ lớn nhanh và khỏe mạnh
If provided with enough nutrients, orchids will produce many buds and flowers for a long time.
Hope this content will help you in taking better care of orchids at home.
If you find the video meaningful, please like, share and subscribe so that the channel can soon reach 100,000 subscribers
Good luck to all
Hello and see you in the next video.