welcome to my channel
After purchasing the orchid, the orchid has finished blooming
and entered the withering stage of the flower branch
Don't rush to throw it away. Let me share how they can thrive and continue to bloom
Remove old orchid pots
Then cut off all damaged roots
This helps the roots branch quickly and not rot.
When transplanted into a new pot, these branched roots will grow very strongly
But if we don't replant it in a new pot, those branched roots will rot very quickly.
Now I plant it in this new pot
OH! Mischievous cat. Do you like cats??
I plant with fine pine bark
When planted with small pine bark and moss When watering, water will drain slowly
Therefore, we only water when the substrate is no longer waterlogged.
Because watering too much will cause the roots to rot
After planting, fertilize the orchids
Take 1 onion and peel it
Onions contain many useful vitamins.
Potassium, calcium, iron, phosphorus, diaphragm.
Very good for the growth of orchids
Then take the onion peel and put it in a jar
Add 500ml boiled water
Cover and let the water cool before using as fertilizer
then take 20ml of milk
Mix with 2 liters of water at room temperature
1. Clean the leaves
Use soft cotton to absorb this water
and gently wipe each leaf
Milk has antiseptic properties, helping to kill fungi and insects that harm orchids
and calcium supplementation is an important factor in forming the cell structure of plants,
Helps increase strength and resistance.
Thoroughly wipe the top and bottom of the leaf
Because the underside is where fungi and insects live, causing harm to orchids
Do this 1-2 times a month to protect the orchid
After the water cools, filter to get the onion juice.
Onion peels contain many essential nutrients such as potassium, phosphorus, and calcium
and organic compounds that are beneficial for plant growth.
In particular, potassium is very important for the flowering process,
helping orchids bloom more beautifully and sustainably.
2. Apply liquid fertilizer to the roots
Water each orchid pot with this water every 2 weeks
Onion peels are rich in antioxidants and compounds that have natural antifungal properties.
Helps protect plants from fungal attacks.
This is useful for keeping orchids healthy and avoiding disease.
As milk is decomposed, it helps grow beneficial microorganisms in the soil.
These microorganisms can help improve soil structure and provide nutrients to orchid roots.
Soak in this water for 20 minutes for better results
Pour the remaining water into the jar
3. Foliar fertilization for orchids
Spray the top and bottom of the leaves thoroughly
Milk helps prevent some fungal and viral diseases when used as a spray solution on orchid leaves or roots.
The protein layer in milk creates a protective barrier against the invasion of harmful bacteria.
Then place the orchid in a cool, well-lit place to take care of it
Normally, you only water orchids when the growing medium is dry
Or spray mist on the leaves and entire orchid to help keep the plant moist
Use the remaining water to water other orchids in the garden
Milk helps improve the water-holding capacity of soil or orchid growing medium,
Helps plants avoid water shortage.
Onion peels, when decomposing, will help create favorable conditions for beneficial microorganisms in the soil to grow.
This helps improve soil structure and the plant's root system, increasing its ability to absorb nutrients.
Results after 1 month
Orchids are very sturdy and healthy
The leaves are greener and harder than before
Many new roots develop, helping the plant absorb nutrients through the roots most effectively
Many new flower buds are formed
I continue to care for the orchids with onion peel and milk
And I expose the orchids to more sunlight so the flowers can bloom brilliantly
Results after 2 month
Orchids have bloomed many brilliant flowers
With this simple way you can care for orchids at home and bloom all year round
Hope the video will help you a lot
If you find it interesting, please like, share and subscribe to the channel to support me
I have created many subtitles in many different languages ​​for you to choose from
Thank you for viewing. Wishing you a happy and successful life
goodbye and see you again in the next videos