Welcome to my Happiness Garden channel.
When the last orchids on the branch are about to fall.
is when I cut branches to propagate orchids from flower stalks.
Where flowers bloom, I cut off to go there.
At this node is the place where orchids can be propagated from flower stalks.
I cut it back so the cut doesn't break the cut.
Take 1 Amoxicillin tablet.
Dab the cut with amoxilin to help it heal faster.
Pour into a 500ml bottle of room temperature water.
Then mix amocillin in water.
This is a plastic seed for growing aquaponic vegetables.
Soak in water mixed with amocillin for 30 minutes.
Helps kill fungi and bacteria very well.
In the meantime, I recycle used plastic containers into orchid propagating tools.
Peeling off the film helps orchid sprouts to grow more easily.
Use a sprig of fresh ginger.
Then squeeze the pure ginger juice.
Dip cotton balls in ginger water.
Incubate this button for 5 minutes to stimulate germination and fast rooting.
Put this button on the plastic pellets and spray moisturizing mist every 2 days.
Place the flower pot in a cool and well-lit place.
1 MONTH LATER.
Sprouts have sprouted.
But still no roots.
Continue misting to moisturize every 2 days.
AFTER THE NEXT 10 DAYS
The orchid sprout has grown and has taken root.
But the sprouts are still weak, so I continue to take care of them.
AFTER THE NEXT 2 MONTHS.
Orchids have grown very healthy.
Roots grow very well.
Now I plant it in a pot to let the orchid grow in the natural environment outside.
Hope the video will help you in propagating orchids at home more easily.
If you find it interesting, please like, share and subscribe to my support channel so that I can soon reach 10,000,000 subscribers.
Wish you success and always happy in life.
Thank you for watching the video
Goodbye and see you in the next videos.