Welcome to my channel
There are different ways to propagate orchids
For you to have more options in orchid breeding.
Today I share how to make a new guide to propagate orchids from ginger root.
It will be very simple but extremely effective.
Please watch to the end of the video to understand my comments.
First peel off this film so that small orchids can grow easily.
Use 10g of fresh ginger
Add 300ml of water
Ginger is a very good plant growth stimulant.
At the same time, ginger also has antiseptic properties that will help eliminate fungus for orchids.
Ginger prevents rot disease on orchids very well.
Soak orchid branches in ginger water for 10 minutes.
Use 1 teaspoon of turmeric powder
Add 600ml of water
Turmeric contains many minerals such as magnesium, calcium, zinc, protein, phosphorus, and natural potassium,
very good for the growth of orchids
And turmeric also has very high antibacterial properties
take it out and wait for it to dry
Mix ginger juice with turmeric water
Soak moss in this water for 20 minutes,
Helps kill mold and bacteria in orchid growing media.
Spread a molten candle on the top of the cut so that the orchid does not lose water,
Doing so does not allow water to penetrate inside the orchid,
will protect orchids from rot.
I reuse plastic boxes to make orchid propagation tools.
I made many drainage holes here
and this is the vent that helps to circulate the air inside with the outside of the box.
Put the orchid branch in, pay attention to the sprouts facing up,
Then spray moisturizing mist every 5 days.
Place in a cool place
AFTER 2 MONTHS
From a small sprout that has grown into a seedling.
Roots grow healthy,
but the orchid is small and weak,
so I continue to grow orchids in this mini greenhouse for a while longer.
Continue misting to moisturize every 5 days
Continue to keep in a cool place
AFTER THE NEXT 20 DAYS.
Orchid is bigger and healthier
The roots are also much healthier
In order for the orchid to not rot later, I will plant it with a more ventilated medium
I grow with a medium that includes: pine bark, pumice and terracotta.
This medium will help the orchid's roots to always be ventilated and ha,ve the right humidity for the orchid
help orchids not root rot.
Add some moss on your face for better moisturizing.
Now take care of it like any other orchid
Apply organic fertilizer once every 2 weeks for good growth.
I'm so glad you came to my channel
If you have an orchid, make sure you want it to bloom for a long time.
Orchids are known for their ability to keep flowers on their branches for 3 to 6 months.
For that to happen, you need to nurture, water, and feed it well.
Now I will show you what is the best fertilizer for orchids.
If you follow us till the end of this video, you will learn how to make orchids bloom like crazy.
Now let's get started
Take a bowl and put 5 tablespoons of rice in it.
Pour in 500ml of water at room temperature.
Mix the rice well and wash the rice before cooking.
Then filter the water to wash the rice.
Use a cotton ball soaked in water to wash this rice
Then wipe on the top and bottom of the leaves
Will help clean the surface of the leaves
remove disease fungi and insects on orchids
At the same time, it provides the necessary nutrients for the orchid's growth
Repeat after 2 weeks will help the orchid stay green
Or you can also pour the rice water into a spray bottle.
Then spray evenly on the top and bottom of the leaves
This method also has the same effect as the previous method using cotton balls
Note Do not spray rice water on flowers
Now take a deep bowl in which you will place the orchid ready for watering and soaking.
Rice water is a great natural fertilizer for orchids, as it encourages the flowering of this beautiful plant.
You can soak the orchid in this rice water for about 1 hour so that the orchid roots can absorb the most nutrients.
Then, remove and repeat this treatment every 14 days.
You can also freeze rice water to water your orchids.
When needed, you just need to take a few dice.
Wait for them to defrost and reach room temperature, you can feed your orchids again.
Never place frozen blocks directly on the base of the orchid
Because orchids don't like the cold.
After only 2-3 weeks of use, the leaves will be green
New roots will grow
This will help the orchid best absorb nutrients through the roots
With enough nutrition, your orchid will flower all year round
And that will be all we have prepared for you for this video.