Welcome to my channel!
To help you have many choices when caring for orchids at home using natural methods.
In this video, I continue to share new methods.
Helps orchids grow healthily and comprehensively.
When the flowers fade, cut off the wilted flower stems
If you are new, please subscribe to the channel so you don't miss any tips on how to grow and care for orchids!
Cut off wilted flowers and buds as soon as you see them
Remove yellow and rotten leaves from orchids
Prune damaged roots
After pruning and cleaning the orchids, we proceed to make natural fertilizer to care for the orchids.
To make this type of fertilizer, I use
Take 2 teaspoons
Add 500ml boiled water
Wait 2 hours before using
Then take 2 tablespoons of dry yeast
Add 500ml warm water
Wait 2 hours before using
After 2 hours
filter the coffee water
Then use the coffee solution to wipe the orchid's leaves.
Helps remove dirt, mold and harmful insects
This fertilizer contains compounds that help prevent the growth of certain types of bacteria
and some fungi that cause diseases on orchids.
This helps reduce the risk of disease for orchids.
Protected orchids will always be green.
Thoroughly wipe the underside of the leaf
because fungi, bacteria and insects often concentrate and thrive on the underside of leaves
before damaging the upper surface of the leaves
This is where insects, fungi and bacteria wreak havoc on the underside of leaves
Wipe as soon as the leaves are still healthy so the orchid is protected
Mix the coffee solution with the yeast solution
Add 1 liter of water at room temperature
Method 1
You use a spray bottle containing this type of fertilizer
and mist irrigation for all orchids.
It has the same effect as foliar fertilization for orchids.
Fertilize every 2 weeks to supplement nutrition for orchids
Method 2
You water each orchid with this liquid fertilizer.
This type of fertilizer contains many minerals such as Nitrogen,
Phosphorus, potassium, carbohydrates, calcium, iron, magnesium,Vitamin C, E, vitamin B,...
are important nutrients for orchid growth.
It helps retain water in the orchid growing medium
Helps maintain stable soil moisture, especially in dry weather.
You can soak your orchid pots in this fertilizer for about 20-30 minutes and it will be very effective
After 30 minutes, take the orchid pot out and place it in a cool, well-lit place
You should fertilize orchids 1-2 times/month for best growth
Results after 3 weeks
Many new roots grow
Leaves are green and sturdy, healthier
Thick and strong roots will help the orchid absorb the most nutrients through the roots
The flowers stay on the branches for a long time and grow many new buds
The root system is important for the growth of orchids
The health of orchids depends greatly on the root system
When the orchid absorbs enough nutrients, the flower branches continuously produce new buds
Other types of orchids are treated with coffee-based fertilizers and baking powder
Their roots also grow healthily
Hope you will like this fertilizer.
Thanks a lot! Goodbye and see you again in the next videos!