welcome to my channel
If you have an orchid with yellow leaves and weak roots, don't miss this video
First, remove all yellow leaves and damaged roots
Tell me where you come from
Let me create subtitles for your country's language so we can communicate easily
Then use small pine bark to replant this orchid
If you haven't subscribed to the channel yet, please click the subscribe button to support me
Spread a layer of moss on the surface of the orchid pot to help retain moisture better
Take 2 tablespoons of white vinegar
mix 4 liters of water
Step 1: Clean orchid leaves with this water
Vinegar water helps remove limescale and dirt from leaves
Leaves will photosynthesize sunlight better
At the same time, it eliminates leaf-damaging insects that often hide on the underside of leaves
such as red spider mites, leafhoppers, aphids and thrips are harmful
If you don't understand, don't hesitate to comment so we can help you
Doing this 1-2 times a month will help orchid leaves stay green and prevent disease on the leaves
Then take 1 teaspoon of sugar and mix it with the vinegar water
Step 2: Water this water on the orchid roots
Vinegar combined with sugar helps stimulate rooting very quickly and extremely well
Vinegar helps kill insects that damage orchid roots
Sugar helps provide nutrients and create an environment for beneficial root microorganisms to grow
Soak in this water for 30 minutes
Then take it out and place it in a cool place with enough light for the orchid to grow
Use the remaining water for other healthy orchids
Helps plants grow and increase resistance to pests
Water weak orchids and healthy orchids twice a month with this water
1 MONTH LATER
After only 1 month, the orchid has developed many new roots
These new roots will absorb the best water and nutrients, helping the orchid grow quickly
Hopefully the video content will help you how to care for orchids at home
Thank you for watching, good luck and see you in the next videos