Hello friends. Nice to meet you on my channel.
In this video, I share how to care for orchids so that orchids thrive.
You have seen here a dry orchid.
Maybe they haven't watered this orchid for a long time.
You need to cut off the flower stem
and cut off all damaged roots
Then take 1 aloe vera leaf and cut it into thin slices.
This aloe vera gel is great for revitalizing orchids.
Put aloe vera in a jar and add 2 liters of warm water
Then add 1 spoon of rice
Cover and leave for 1 hour for nutrients to completely dissolve in water
1 Hour Later
Step 1: Clean the leaves with this water
Aloe vera gel has a very good moisturizing effect.
Helps orchids recover and stay fresh quickly.
Step 2:
Soak orchid roots in this water for 30 minutes
After 30 minutes
Plant the orchid in another pot using chopped pine bark
And add a little moss to the surface of the orchid pot to help retain moisture better
.
Spray rice water and aloe vera gel on the orchid every 3 days.
Then water the orchid with rice water and aloe vera gel once a week.
On normal days, when the orchid growing medium is dry, you just need to water the orchid regularly.
Place the orchid pot in a cool place with temperature and light from 25-320 degrees Celsius and the orchid will grow quickly.
45 Days Later
The orchid grows many new, very healthy roots.
The roots will help absorb water and nutrients better, so the orchid will recover faster.
Continue watering the orchid with rice water and aloe vera gel once a week.
and continue to spray rice water and aloe vera gel on the orchid every 3 days.
On weekdays, you only need to water when the orchid growing medium is dry.
3 Months Later
The orchid has completely recovered.
and the flower buds have grown.
Orchid leaves are sturdy and completely green.
Hope the video will help you a lot in recovering weak orchids at home.
If you find it interesting, please share it with as many people as possible! Thank you and see you in the next video!