Welcome to my channel
Nice to meet you on my channel
Let orchids grow healthily and bloom with lots of flowers
In this video, I share a new type of organic fertilizer with ingredients available in every kitchen.
Helps new roots and flower buds grow abundantly and continuously.
If you are new! Subscribe to the channel so you don't miss any tips on growing and caring for orchids!
Let's start
These are dried bay leaves
You can easily buy it at the supermarket
You use 10 bay leaves
Crush or cut into small pieces
Add 500ml boiled water
Cover and let it brew until the water cools
Next is rice
Use 3 tablespoons of rice
Add 500ml of room temperature water
Cover and wait 1 hour
1 hour after the water cools
Remember, no amount of fertilizer will help your orchids if they are not receiving enough diffused light, at least 12 hours a day.
Filter residue
Mix rice water with bay leaf water
Add 1 liter of water
METHOD 1
You water the orchid roots with this fertilizer.
Fertilizer made from bay leaves and cinnamon rice contains a lot of minerals.
Helps stimulate orchid growth
Fertilizer from bay leaves helps protect plants from harmful fungi and bacteria,
thereby enhancing the health of orchids.
Rice water also promotes the growth of beneficial bacteria in the soil,
helps improve aeration and soil structure,
Helps plant roots absorb nutrients.
Do this 1-2 times a month to provide nutrition and help protect the orchids
Soaking orchid roots in this water for about 20 minutes will be better
Pour this water into the jar
METHOD 2
Spray this fertilizer on the entire orchid 1-2 times/month
Spray thoroughly on both the top and bottom of the leaves
This is similar to foliar fertilizing plants
Spray both the top and bottom of the leaves
You should do it in the morning so that by noon when the sunlight shines, there is no more water left on the leaves.
Rice water helps keep orchid roots moist without causing water retention.
Bay leaves are rich in minerals,
especially iron and calcium,
can help improve the cell structure and health of orchid roots.
When the orchid roots have turned pale silver, it's time to water the orchid.
After watering, the roots turn green
METHOD 3
Use a soft cotton pad to absorb this water and gently wipe the leaves
You should wipe the leaves of the plant at least once a month.
Thoroughly wipe the top and bottom of the leaves to remove dirt
Eliminate insects and fungal diseases that harm orchids
The stomata open and the plant will photosynthesize better.
This not only cleans the dust but also provides them with nutrients.
This is similar to fertilizing orchids through the leaves.
will always grow healthy and green.
This is a nest of red spider eggs, I need to clean it up right away before they hatch into spiders
Never underestimate natural fertilizers.
They are as effective as pre-formed mineral compounds but are safer.
Natural fertilizers take time to work, helping plants grow sustainably and survive longer.
After soaking for 20 minutes, take out the orchid pot
After fertilizing the plant, I put the orchid in a warm place with enough light to let the water evaporate.
Result
After 2-3 times of fertilizing, the orchid has grown many new roots
This helps orchids absorb the best nutrients through their roots
This type of fertilizer provides nutrients and protects the leaves so the leaves are always green and shiny
Orchids should be kept at a temperature of 20-25 degrees during the day and 15-18 degrees at night.
Such a difference in temperature will promote abundant flowering.
I hope my video is useful to you.
Wishing you in taking care of plants brings you joy and great results.
Hope you like this composting recipe!
Don't forget to like and share the video with your friends and family!