Welcome to my channel
In my hand is a dry orchid branch
And I will revive it to become a healthy orchid
First, it is necessary to remove damaged roots
Then apply glue to the cut to help the bark heal quickly and prevent rot.
and wait 1 day for the glue to dry
After 1 day, apply aloe vera gel on the orchid stem
This helps retain moisture and stimulates germination on dry orchid stems
Then place the orchid stem on a layer of damp moss
Spray moisturizer every 3 days
Cover tightly with a transparent plastic box like a miniature greenhouse
3 Weeks Later
The old orchid stem has sprouted a small sprout
Continue to place in a cool, well-lit place and spray with moisturizing mist every 3 days
2 MONTHS LATER
From a small sprout, it has grown into a healthy baby orchid
The new root system is very strong
This will help the orchid absorb nutrients through the roots best
Now I need to plant them in pots so they can grow in their natural environment outside
I plant with charcoal and pumice which helps keep moisture well and the roots are always well ventilated
Cover the top of the pot with a little moss to help retain moisture better
Spray moisturizer on orchids every 3 days
Note: Only when the roots cling to the orchid growing medium can you fertilize the orchid
Thank you for viewing
Good luck and see you in the next video