Hello everyone, today I share a simple and easy way to care for orchids at home.
Helps plants grow quickly and always have lots of flower buds.
Flowers will stay on the branches longer.
Let orchids grow quickly and be healthy and lush.
and blooms brilliantly all year round.
Water the plant weekly.
This method will help orchids grow very quickly and healthy.
Soak the potted plant in water for 10 minutes.
then take it out.
Using the outer layer of garlic contains many nutrients.
helps orchids grow very quickly.
Garlic peel always has strong antibacterial and antiseptic properties.
That's enough.
Add 1 liter of boiling water.
Incubate until this water cools and you can use it immediately.
When orchids are purchased or grown for a long time, they do not flower.
Cut off all damaged yellow leaves.
and You should repot the plant.
Cut off all damaged roots.
After cooling, filter to remove residue.
The water from the garlic peel will help the plant take root quickly and flower abundantly.
Then water this water at the base of the tree.
You should apply this method once a week.
Soak it like this for 30 minutes.
Then use this water to spray on the leaves.
Helps prevent mealybugs, thrips, and spiders from sticking to orchid leaves.
Garlic peels have antibacterial and antiseptic properties.
Helps plants to be protected and healthier.
Should you do this early in the morning.
Please use this water.
Cleans leaves, helps remove dirt.
and helps plants grow better when replanted.
Then add the garlic peel water.
Soak all these roots for 30 minutes, which helps new roots developed faster.
This is very beneficial for taking care of weak orchids.
The tree will continuously develop new roots very quickly.
Then take it out and place it in a bright place.
to help plants photosynthesize and create chlorophyll.
The flowers will bloom more, more beautifully and brilliantly.
Use sterilized pine bark and moss for planting.
will help protect roots from rot.
I have created a lot of subtitles, you can view and choose the appropriate language.
Water just enough to keep it moist.
Don't forget to like, share, subscribe to the channel and ring the bell for easy viewing.
Goodbye and see you again. Good luck.