Hello everyone, so that the orchid garden always has many long-lasting and sustainable blooming flowers
We need to create many small orchids
Helps plants grow lush green
Today I share how to propagate baby orchids
from this flower branch.
You only need to use a small clove of garlic, garlic contains a lot
Many vitamins and nutrients help plants quickly root and grow very well
and contains many substances necessary for bud growth.
Add 500 ml of room temperature water
You cover it and leave it for a day.
You need to choose flower branches that are still green
The tree grows well
Peeling off the protective film will help the sprouts grow more easily and quickly.
Although garlic is great for growing small plants,
But garlic is very spicy, you cannot use it directly.
Leave it for a day to reduce the heat of the garlic.
When used directly, the flower branches will dry immediately
1 Day later
I will put the orchid here
You need to leave it on for 5 minutes, you can't leave it on too long.
After soaking for 5 minutes,
Sprinkle cinnamon powder on the cut to help the wound heal quickly and not rot.
Soaking the moss in garlic water for 5 minutes helps disinfect the substrate and stimulates rooting.
Then take the moss out and squeeze the water dry.
Place the orchid branch in
Cover with a clear plastic bottle with vents
You should water and mist regularly to keep the growing medium moist.
We place it in places with temperatures from 24 to 29 degrees
after 1 month
Baby orchids develop very healthy leaves and roots.
When the small tree has begun to grow, choose a tree that receives light from the tree to help it photosynthesize.
We regularly mist it to moisturize so that this small tree can grow better
and after 2 months the tree has grown very well
Please transfer the tree to another pot and we will replant it with pine bark and moss
Let the plant receive light slowly, don't rush.
To help plants gradually get used to the new environment more easily.
You keep the stem higher than the substrate to avoid stem rot.
Don't forget to like, share,
Subscribe to the channel and ring the bell so you don't miss any tips on my channel
Welcome to part 2 of the video
Now I share tips to revive extremely weak Phalaenopsis orchids
In my hand is a withered stem of a Phalaenopsis, it is extremely weak
Use glue to spread on orchid cuts to prevent rot
Use aloe vera leaves
Applying aloe vera gel to orchid stems helps stimulate germination and rooting
Using moss soaked in water to keep it moist helps create a moist environment so the orchid can easily germinate and root
Place the orchid stem in and cover it with a little moss
Spray moisturizer every 3-5 days
Use a recycled plastic bottle to cover the orchid pot like a greenhouse environment and place it in a cool place
after 3 weeks
After 3 weeks of moisturizing, the dried orchid stem was fresh again and germinated
Continue to place the orchid in a pot with moss to keep it moist
and cover with a recycled clear plastic bottle and spray with moisturizer every 3-5 days
After 45 days
The baby orchid has grown very quickly. Leaves and roots grow rapidly
I planted it in a pot so the orchid could adapt to the outside environment
Use charcoal, dry pine bark and pumice to grow orchids
This helps prevent orchid roots from rotting
Covering the surface with a layer of moss helps the orchid retain moisture better
Spraying moist mist 2-3 times a week helps spread roots quickly and attach to the growing medium
Place the orchid pot on the windowsill or in a place with plenty of light but avoid direct sunlight so the orchid can grow
Thank you for watching the video
Please like and share so more people know this tip
and subscribe to the channel so you don't miss any tips on my channel
Good luck and see you on the next videos