Welcome to my channel
To help spread more buds
The flowers bloom profusely and hang on the branches for a long time before fading
Water orchids twice a month like this
This helps the orchid have enough warmth to absorb nutrients better
When orchids have enough moisture, they will bloom for a long time
After soaking in water for about 10 minutes, take out the orchid pot
Take 2 cloves of garlic and slice thinly
Add 1 liter of water
Add 1 teaspoon of honey
Garlic combined with honey has very good antibacterial and antiseptic properties, helping to kill fungi in orchid substrates.
Leave for 1 hour for nutrients to completely dissolve in water
If you have a weak orchid and it is not blooming
We need to remove damaged leaves and roots and replant
After 1 hour, filter this water
Wiping the top and bottom of leaves helps repel insects and prevent fungal and bacterial attacks
Garlic contains strong acids and essential oils
Can repel or kill insects harmful to orchids.
Do this periodically every 2 weeks with other orchids.
This way adds nutrients and kills insects on orchid leaves
Soak orchid roots in garlic and honey water for 10 minutes
Helps disinfect and stimulate new root growth
Water your orchid with this water
Provides amino acids, vitamins and minerals for orchids, helping orchids grow well.
Garlic combined with honey has very good antibacterial and antiseptic effects, helping to kill fungi in orchid substrates.
Promotes the growth and recovery of new root systems for orchids.
Pour honey garlic water into the vase. You can also spray the orchids.
Helps wash away dirt and insects on orchids and disinfect the entire plant.
You should apply this method every 2 weeks to your plants
Soak for about 10 minutes, then take it out and plant it in a new pot to spread new roots
Soaking in this water will cause it to grow new roots very quickly
I used the method of soaking the roots in garlic and honey water for this orchid
Orchids take root very quickly, so wilted leaves are quickly restored
And this orchid also produces many beautiful flowers
After soaking for 10 minutes, when the roots have absorbed enough nutrients, take out the orchid pot
When you take care of orchid leaves regularly, the leaves will be bright green and shiny
Flowers will bloom more brightly than usual
Many flowers can bloom on the same branch
and the flowers stay on the branches for a long time before fading
Hopefully the video will help you a lot in taking care of orchids at home
Thank you for watching the video. Good luck and see you in the next videos