Hello friends.
Nice to meet you on my channel.
You see here a withered orchid.
Maybe it's because you didn't water it.
or due to direct sunlight shining on the orchid.
If you want orchids to be nourished and grow quickly.
Please watch this video carefully.
Now I will share this amazing trick with you.
You need 1 aloe vera leaf.
This aloe vera gel is great for reviving orchids.
Now apply aloe vera gel on the top and bottom of the leaf.
Aloe vera gel has a very good moisturizing effect.
In addition, aloe vera also contains vitamins A, B, and C
and minerals such as nitrogen, phosphorus and potassium.
Do this every 5 days and leave the orchid pot in a cool place for 3 weeks.
Next, take 1 liter of warm water and put it in the bottle.
Then take 1 spoon of rice and soak it in this water for about 30 minutes.
Let the nutrients in the rice completely dissolve into the water.
Chop the remaining aloe vera leaves into small pieces.
Then puree with 300ml of water.
Filter out residue half past four Add 2 liters of water at room temperature.
After soaking for 30 minutes, filter this rice water.
Mix rice water with aloe vera juice.
So I ended up with about 3 liters of this wonderful liquid manure solution.
Cover the pot with moss to retain moisture better.
Now you use this solution to water the orchid every 5 days.
Soak the orchid pot in this water for 2 hours.
After soaking for 2 hours, remember to lift the orchid pot and place it in a cool place to let the orchid recover.
2 WEEKS LATER.
Fertilize after 2 weeks for fresher orchid leaves.
New roots develop very well.
Many new roots are growing.
New roots will help transport water and nutrients from the roots to the stem.
If the leaves are provided with enough water and nutrients from the roots,
The leaves will gradually become lush again.
1 MONTH LATER.
You see the leaves are very fresh.
and the orchid grows a new leaf.
after the next 2 months
The orchid has grown two branches (two buds).
But the leaves at the base have turned yellow so I will cut off these yellow leaves.
Instinctively, when an orchid buds, if the plant lacks nutrients,
the base leaves will turn yellow and fall off to provide nutrients for the buds to develop.
Now I need to supplement the orchid's nutrition by taking 3 spoons of rice.
Then soak in 2 liters of water at room temperature
and wait 30 minutes for the nutrients to completely dissolve in water before using.
30 Minutes Later
Add 3 tablespoons of milk
Rice water and milk are excellent sources of nutrients for orchids to grow
Now you water the orchid with this solution once a week to help the orchid recover quickly.
After the next 1 month.
After 3-4 times of applying liquid fertilizer from milk and rice water, the orchid had many roots.
Hope the video will help you a lot.
Thank you for watching the video. Wish you luck and see you in the next videos.
Welcome to part 2 of the video
If you have a rotten or damaged orchid and you want to restore it quickly.
And if you don't want to miss any orchid growing tips, subscribe to my channel today.
This is a rotten orchid that people threw away, I picked it up to restore it.
The cause of rot is disease-causing fungi and bacteria.
I remove all damaged roots and damaged leaves.
Then rinse with water.
Then hang in a cool place for 2 hours to let the orchid dry naturally.
I took 1 aloe vera leaf.
Then filter to get aloe vera jelly.
I cut the rest into thin slices.
Then puree with 500ml of water.
Then filter out the residue.
Next I took 3 spoons of rice.
Add 500ml of water.
Then leave for 2 hours for the nutrients to completely dissolve in the water.
2 HOURS LATER.
Take aloe vera jelly and wipe the leaves.
This helps wilted orchids recover and grow very quickly.
At the same time, it also kills disease-causing bacteria and fungi very effectively.
Mix the two types together.
Soak the roots in this water for 30 minutes.
This helps the roots not rot and grow new roots very quickly
Then plant the orchid in a new pot for the orchid to recover.
Covering the pot with a layer of moss helps retain moisture better.
From now on water this once a week.
And spray this water on the leaves once a week.
Place in a light and airy place so the orchid can recover easily.
1 MONTH LATER.
The leaves become stronger and a new leaf grows.
And many new roots grow.
These new roots help absorb nutrients better, so the orchid will recover very quickly
Continue watering this once a week.
and Continue spraying this water once a week.
AFTER THE NEXT 2 MONTHS.
This leaf has completely recovered and become lush
The roots grow strongly and produce many new roots.
With this simple method, the orchid recovered completely very quickly.
Thank you for watching the video. Please share the video so more people know..
Good luck and see you in the next videos!