Welcome to my channel.
If you have an orchid and you plant it forever but it still hasn't bloomed.
Like my orchid, it hasn't bloomed yet.
The tree is weak and its roots are severely damaged.
Remove old planting material and cut off all damaged roots.
Then rinse with water
Using a small aloe vera leaf contains a lot of gel which is very good for the orchid to recover.
Aloe vera also has antiseptic properties that help prevent orchids from rotting roots and leaves.
Add 2 liters of water.
Add 1 teaspoon of honey which has antiseptic properties and is very nutritious for orchids to grow
Leave for 1 hour for nutrients to completely dissolve in water
1 Hour later
Use this water to thoroughly wipe the top and bottom of the leaves
Helps eliminate fungi and bacteria that cause orchid diseases
Then soak the entire orchid in this water for 30 minutes
Helps stimulate rooting and quick recovery
Now I recycle plastic bottles into orchid pots that don't need watering
With this growing method, you will not need to water and the orchid will not dry out and grow very well
Then plant the orchid in this pot with pine bark to keep the roots well ventilated
Add some moss on top to keep it moist.
Water the orchids.
The water level in this location will never dry up, so orchid roots are always kept moist
Therefore, orchid roots will take root very quickly.
Place the orchid pot in a cool and well-lit place.
3 Weeks later
Roots grow very healthy.
When the roots grow healthy like this, you need to use organic foliar fertilizer such as:
Rice water, soy water, honey water, fish protein... as I shared
Apply every 2 weeks to orchids.
3 Months Later
The orchids I applied this method grew healthily and bloomed many flowers
The roots grow very healthy, helping the orchid absorb many nutrients
The leaves are sturdy and very resistant to pests.
The flowers bloom brightly and stay on the branches for a long time before fading.
The flowers stay on the branches for up to 6 months before falling.
I have created video subtitles in many different languages ​​so you can choose the appropriate language
If you find it interesting, please click like and share so more people know this tip
And please subscribe to support my channel to reach 10 million subscribers soon
Thank you for watching the video. Wish you luck and see you in the next videos.