Welcome to my Happiness Garden channel.
This video will reveal an interesting secret:
Using Coca-Cola can stimulate plants to flower without spending too much care.
First I took 1 teaspoon of rice.
then pour in 50ml of Cocacola.
Then incubate for 2 hours so that the nutrients completely dissolve in the cocacola.
2 Hours Later
Puree the rice in this cocacola water.
Filter out residue.
Add water to make 2 liters of solution.
Step 1: Clean the leaves with rice water and cocacola.
You wipe the surface of orchid leaves with this coca-cola water.
Wipe both the top and bottom of the leaf.
This method helps repel insects and fungi on leaves very well.
The nutrients in Cocacola and rice provide nutrients similar to foliar fertilizer for orchids.
If you regularly do this every 2 weeks, the orchid leaves will be very well protected.
The leaves will be healthy, green and pest-free.
Step 2:
Now take care of the roots.
You only need to water orchids once a week.
Coca-Cola contains phosphoric acid which has a mild bleaching effect.
Therefore, it will eliminate fungal diseases on pots and roots very well.
In addition, Coca-Cola also has the ability to kill some insects that harm plant roots such as:
Snails and cockroaches are very good.
Coca-Cola helps neutralize acid in pots when you use too much chemical fertilizer.
Rice water contains nutrients such as protein, potassium, magnesium, and calcium,
are important substances for the growth of ornamental plants, especially orchids.
Substances in rice water act as growth stimulants, encouraging plants to grow and flower.
Rice water creates a favorable environment for beneficial microorganisms to grow in orchid pots.
Result.
When applying this method, my orchid develops a very good and healthy root system.
Helps roots absorb maximum plant nutrients
Because orchids are healthy, each plant has many flower stems on one plant.
An orchid can produce 5-6 flower buds at the same time.
Flower buds are kept on branches and do not fall off
Sugar in Coca-Cola helps flowers stay fresh longer.
Orchids will not be exhausted after blooming.
Hopefully the video will help you take better care of orchids at home.
Thank you for watching the video. Good luck. See you again in the next videos.