welcome to my channel
If you want to take care of orchids at home to stay healthy
and blooms many flowers, the flowers cling to the branches for a long time before fading
Watch this video until the end
First I took 3 spoons of rice
Add 1 liter of water and wait 10 minutes for the nutrients to dissolve in the water
When I eat bell peppers, I keep a piece to use as fertilizer for the orchids
Bell peppers contain many vitamins and minerals such as vitamin C, A, and potassium.
These substances help improve orchid growth by providing micronutrients that make the plant healthier.
Add 300ml of water
puree
Filter residue
Add 1 liter of water at room temperature
After soaking for 10 minutes, I filtered this water
Rice water contains carbohydrates, proteins, B vitamins and minerals such as iron, phosphorus and potassium.
These nutrients help plants grow healthy and stimulate root growth.
Then mix the rice water with bell pepper water
Use soft cotton to absorb this water
Then wipe the leaves thoroughly
Helps eliminate fungal diseases and leaf-damaging insects
The leaf surface will always be clean
The leaf surface will always be clean and the stomata will not be clogged.
Orchids will photosynthesize better.
You need to thoroughly clean the underside of the leaves
Because the underside of leaves is where bacteria, fungi
and insects often reside to harm orchids
Doing this 1-2 times a month will help protect orchid leaves
Leaves will always be green
Insects such as red spiders, leafhoppers, aphids, and thrips will not survive on orchids
Beneficial microorganisms in rice water also protect leaves from fungal diseases
Orchid leaves are always strong and plump
Method 2
Water the orchid roots with this water
Thanks to nutrients such as phosphorus and B vitamins,
Rice water can help orchids develop stronger roots, helping the plants absorb nutrients from the soil better.
Potassium in bell peppers plays an important role in stimulating the flowering process
and making orchids grow stronger.
Antioxidants in bell peppers, especially vitamin C,
It also helps protect plants from attacks by environmental factors and diseases.
Using rice water regularly helps improve beneficial microorganisms in the soil,
Create a better living environment for orchids.
This also helps maintain soil moisture,
which is helpful in keeping the plant from drying out.
Apply once every 2 weeks
Pour this water into a spray bottle
Method 3
Spray this water on orchids every 2 weeks
Spray both the top and bottom of the leaves
This method is similar to using foliar fertilizer.
The nutrients in rice water stimulate the plant to produce more flowers
and last longer, helping the plant become more lush and beautiful.
Beneficial organic compounds in bell peppers contribute to enhancing plant resistance to pests and harsh environments.
Result
When you regularly apply this method, the leaves will always be green and strong
These nutrients help plants grow healthy and stimulate root growth.
A strong root system will help the orchid easily absorb the most nutrients
You can see that the roots of these orchids are very healthy
Potassium in rice water and bell peppers helps flowers bloom brilliantly
and stays on the branches for a long time before fading
Can be kept on branches for up to 6 months before fading
Hope it will help you a lot in taking care of orchids at home
Thank you for watching the video. Wishing you luck and success in life.
Goodbye and see you again in the next videos.