Welcome to my channel.
Today I share how to propagate and stimulate roots for orchids easily.
Blot the cut dry
Light a candle and apply it on the cut so the water doesn't get in.
That way the orchid will not rot.
Take 1 small piece of ginger
Store in a place with daylight and take care not to expose to direct sunlight.
After 3 weeks
after 3 months
Thanks for watching. If you find the video useful, don't forget to click like, share and subscribe to my channel to watch my next videos.
Next, I show you how to revive a rotten orchid like this.
When the orchid has withered all the leaves, only the stem and roots remain, do not rush to throw it away.
Here are still fresh roots.
First, cut off all damaged, rotten roots.
Apply a molten candle on the cut so that the water does not penetrate the tree.
Use 2 teaspoons of cinnamon powder.
Add 1 liter of boiled water.
Close the lid and wait for the water to cool.
The water has cooled down
Filter out residue.
Soak orchids in this water for 30 minutes.
The rest of the water I will spray on other orchids to help protect the orchid from insects and fungal diseases
After soaking for 30 minutes, plant it.
Using pine bark and dry pumice stone to plant will help absorb moisture in the roots, making the orchid roots not rot.
Add some dry moss on the face.
Put in a cool and well-lit place for 7 days
After 7 days, you can spray water to keep the plants moist.
Cover with a clear, vented plastic container and wait for the plant to revive.
AFTER 3 WEEKS,
A sprout has sprouted,
Spray water once every 5 days to keep the sprouts moist
AFTER 2 MONTHS
Hope this sharing content will help you in resurrecting weak orchids to grow again
If you find it interesting, remember to click like, share and subscribe so that my channel will soon reach 1,000,000 subscribers.
The video I have created many subtitles, you can choose the appropriate language to understand my shares.
Good luck to you all.
See you in the next videos.