Welcome to my channel
When the orchids have finished blooming
Cut off all wilted flower stems
and remove diseased leaves
This helps remove pathogens from the orchid.
This is a cement with very good antiseptic properties
Apply it to the cut to help it heal quickly
Then place it in a cool place for 1 day without watering to let the cut dry on its own
And here are soybeans, very rich in nutrients for the growth of orchids
Take a handful of soybeans and soak them in 2 liters of boiled water
Incubate until the water cools
After the water cools, add 3 tablespoons of sugar
Then add 20ml of vinegar
Vinegar and sugar help ferment soybeans quickly
Then leave in a cool place for 5 days to ferment
5 days later filter this water
After fermenting these soybeans, we can fertilize the base of the rose tree and it will be very good
Add 2 liters of water
Now water each orchid pot with this liquid fertilizer every 2 weeks
Fermented soybeans will also provide very good nutrition for orchids to grow
This fermented fertilizer also helps protect roots from fungal diseases that harm orchids very effectively
Soak the orchid pot in this fertilizer solution for about 10 minutes and then take it out
Then we spray this liquid fertilizer on the orchid leaves every 2 weeks
Helps supplement nutrients through leaves and effectively eliminate fungal diseases and insects on leaves
This also helps keep the leaf surface clean, leading to better photosynthesis
Continue to place in a cool, well-lit place to care for orchids
After 2 months
Many baby orchids have been revived from old roots
This type of liquid fertilizer helps stimulate orchid growth very effectively
Continue to water the roots with liquid fertilizer and spray the leaves every 2 weeks
After the next 1 month
After the next 2 weeks
The flowers bloom very fragrant
The flower color is vibrant and long-lasting
The flowers stick on the branches for a long time before falling
Hopefully the video will help you a lot in taking better care of orchids at home
Thank you for watching the video. Wish you luck and see you in the next videos