Hello friends
I'm so glad you came to my channel
If you have an orchid, and you want it to bloom as much as these orchids of mine
Please watch to the end of the video
Now I will show you what is the best fertilizer for orchids.
It will help the orchid grow from the roots and leaves and will bloom a lot
Let's start
These are cooked soybeans
Take 1 handful of cooked soybeans
Soybeans contain many important minerals such as nitrogen, phosphorus and potassium that are good for orchid growth
Add 2 tablespoons of brown sugar
Add 50ml beer
Add 10ml vinegar
500ml warm water
Leave for 1 week to ferment naturally before using
1 Week Later
Take 300ml
add 3 Liters of water
Put this organic fertilizer in a spray bottle
Spray the top and bottom of the leaves thoroughly
When provided with this organic nutrition, orchids will grow very well
Helps leaves stay green and strong
Fertilizing once every 2 weeks will be very good for orchids
Use this organic fertilizer to water the orchid pot
The potassium and phosphorus content will promote the growth of roots and flowers very quickly
And the nitrogen in this organic fertilizer will help keep the leaves big and green
Apply once every 2 weeks
You can soak the orchid pot in this organic fertilizer for 20 minutes,
so that the roots can absorb the most nutrients.
Results after 1 month
Many new roots grow
New roots help orchids absorb water and nutrients better
When we provide nutrients, the roots will immediately absorb and transport to the entire orchid plant
if you fertilize once every 2 weeks in combination with other organic fertilizers that I have shared
I guarantee the orchid will always grow well and always bloom with lots of flowers
Potassium in soybeans and brown sugar helps orchids bloom many flowers on the same branch
Potassium and brown sugar also help fight drought very well
Potassium helps carry water from the roots to the highest and farthest parts of the orchid such as the tops and buds
so the buds don't wilt due to lack of water
so the flower will keep on the branch for a long time without wilting
Flowers can bloom up to 6 months without falling
Hope it will be of great help to you
Next, I share how to help rotten orchids recover quickly
and shoot many baby orchids at the same time.
Helps orchids shoot many plants at the same time in the same pot.
and blooms a lot of flowers.
An orchid has rot disease.
The cause of the disease is fungi and bacteria that cause leaf rot.
If rot is not treated promptly, it will spread and cause the orchid to die.
I need to check the roots.
Then cut off all damaged roots.
Then rinse with water.
Take 2 liters of water.
Add 5 vitamin B1 tablets.
Vitamin B1 helps stimulate rooting and germination very quickly.
Take 1 aloe vera leaf and cut it into thin slices.
Soak aloe vera in Vitamin B1 water.
and wait 10 minutes for the nutrients to completely dissolve in the water.
Then filter this water.
Soak the orchid branches in this water for 20 minutes.
Helps stimulate the growth of roots and sprouts very quickly.
Using a pine bark growing medium helps maintain moisture and proper drainage.
Add moss on top.
Take a cotton ball and soak it in this water.
Then incubate the orchid roots.
Incubate for a day then take out. This helps stimulate rapid root and sprout growth.
From now on spray this water on the leaves once a week.
and water the roots with this water once a week.
Place in a cool, well-lit place for 1 day.
After 1 day, remove the cotton from the orchid roots.
Take the transparent plastic box and snap it up.
and place it in a cool, well-lit place.
Spray aloe vera water and B1 once a week.
Water aloe vera and B1 once a week.
1 MONTH LATER.
The orchid has grown two sprouts on both sides.
Continue spraying aloe vera water and B1 once a week.
and Continue watering aloe vera and B1 once a week
AFTER NEXT 1 MONTH.
The 2 shoots are growing healthily but have not yet taken root.
Continue watering aloe vera and B1 once a week.
And continue to spray aloe vera water and B1 once a week.
After the next 2 months.
The orchid has developed healthy roots, stems, and leaves.
and has developed more buds (flower branches)
Thank you for watching the video. Good luck and see you in the next videos!