Welcome to my channel
In my hand is a package of seaweed.
Seaweed is known to be a versatile food,
nutritious and good for health.
However, few people know that seaweed is also a great material to create fertilizer for plants,
especially for orchids.
In this video, we will show you how to use seaweed to create a divine fertilizer to help orchids grow and bloom abundantly all year round.
you use 1 piece of seaweed like this
and add 15-20 grams of fresh ginger
Add 1 liter of water at room temperature.
puree
filter out residue
STEP 1
Use cotton balls
Clean the top and bottom of the orchid leaves,
Ginger has very good antiseptic properties
Will help eliminate fungi and parasitic insects on orchids
At the same time, ginger and seaweed contain many essential minerals for plant growth
Orchid will be able to absorb some nutrients through the leaves
keep green leaves
Regularly wiping the leaves will help open the stomata
The exchange of oxygen and carbon dioxide will be more favorable
Orchid will synthesize chlorophyll more easily
leaves will always be green
sturdy orchid
thick leaves grow very well
You need to clean the orchid leaves once a month
STEP 2
Use up ginger juice with seaweed
Add 2 liters of water
I soaked the orchid in this water for 5 minutes
Seaweed contains many nutrients and minerals that are beneficial for plant growth, especially for orchids such as:
Nitrogen (N): Helps promote the growth of leaves, shoots, branches and roots,
Phosphorus (P): Plays an important role in promoting root and flower growth.
Potassium (K): Helps plants withstand stress, enhances resistance and minimizes the impact of pests.
Calcium (Ca): Enhances resistance and helps plants develop muscle and bone systems of orchids.
Magnesium (Mg): Has an effect on the metabolism of the plant, helping the plant grow healthy.
Thanks to the abundant nutrition of seaweed, the use of fertilizers from seaweed helps to provide a full range of nutrients
and minerals necessary for orchids to grow healthy.
Contribute to providing enough nutrients for orchids to help plants produce more flowers
The flower is larger and more vibrant.
In addition, seaweed also contains a polysaccharide called carrageenan,
Has the effect of reducing stress of plants, helping plants to resist the effects of UV rays
and inhibit the growth of bacteria and mold.
Thus, orchids are protected from pests, fungi and bacteria and grow abundantly all year round.
Welcome to part 2 of this video
You see this is a withered orchid.
Now let me show you how to revive this orchid.
I use 1 small ginger.
Squeeze out the water to soak the orchid branches in ginger water.
Wait for it to dry.
Use a molten candle to apply on the cut
Doing so will not allow water to seep inside the orchid,
This will prevent the orchid from rotting and from losing water.
I will recycle it into a miniature greenhouse to revive the orchid.
Place the orchid in the moss and mist it to keep it moist.
Put it in a cool place and mist it every 5 days.
AFTER 3 WEEKS
The little sprout has come back to life.
Continue to keep in a cool place and mist once every 5 days.
AFTER 3 MONTHS
Lan has successfully revived with extremely strong roots
To prevent the orchid from root rot, I will replant it with pine bark and pumice stone.
From now on, water once every 7-10 days to keep moist.
combine using organic fertilizers like I shared on the channel to take care of them,
Will help orchids grow better
If you find it interesting, please like, share and subscribe to the channel,
Help the channel reach 10,000,000 subscribers soon
Welcome to part 3 of this video
Today I share a little trick to help stimulate many small orchids on an old orchid branch.
I used a small clove of garlic.
Squeeze water.
Apply fresh garlic juice to the places where small orchids can grow.
AFTER 1 WEEK.
Small orchids have grown bigger.
AFTER 2 MONTHS
This orchid I also apply this little trick and it also grows a lot of small orchids.
The video I have created many subtitles with many different languages. You can choose the appropriate language to understand your shared content.