Welcome to my channel
Today I would like to introduce to you a video on how to use tobacco to irrigate orchids
Helps repel insects and protect orchids from thriving.
We use 1 cigarette
Soak tobacco with 1 liter of water at room temperature
then incubated for 1 day
1 DAY AFTER
Filter out residue
Use a cotton ball to soak up tobacco water
Then wipe the top and bottom of the leaves thoroughly
This helps to protect the orchid leaves from insects and fungi extremely effectively
just do this 1-2 times per month
If you wipe regularly, the orchid leaves will be green like this
Next, you use tobacco water to irrigate the root
do this 1-2 times a month
The ingredients in tobacco reduce the ability of harmful insects
like scorpions, aphids and bugs, rod slugs damage the roots
The rest of the tobacco juice I pour into the spray bottle
Then spray evenly on the top, bottom and the whole root
Can be sprayed on flowers to help protect them
Tobacco is a natural insecticide.
Widely used in agriculture and crop care.
This is an effective way to repel insects that are harmful to orchids.
In addition, the ingredients in tobacco
capable of stimulating the growth of orchids,
The type of fertilizer that helps to stimulate the absorption of nutrients for orchids
use 10ml of fermented milk
mix with 1 liter of water
Then use this fermented milk water to water each orchid pot with 10 spoons
Fermented milk contains many vitamins and minerals
like vitamins A, B, C, D
calcium, protein
Very essential for the growth of orchids
In addition, fermented milk also helps beneficial microorganisms grow,
protects the roots very well
Orchid roots will grow very well if you regularly use fermented milk to care for orchids
Just take care of milk fermentation 1-2 times per month
Combined with other organic fertilizers, orchids will grow extremely well
RESULT
you see my orchid here
There are many flower buds growing on the same branch
Flowers bloom in many colors
Flowers can be kept on branches for up to 6 months before fading
Welcome to part 2 of the video
Today I will show you how to revive a rotten orchid like this.
When the orchid has withered all the leaves, only the stem and roots remain, do not rush to throw it away.
Here are still fresh roots.
First, cut off all damaged, rotten roots.
Apply a molten candle on the cut so that the water does not penetrate the tree.
Use 2 teaspoons of cinnamon powder.
Add 1 liter of boiled water.
Close the lid and wait for the water to cool.
The water has cooled down
Filter out residue.
Soak orchids in this water for 30 minutes.
The rest of the water I will spray on other orchids to help protect the orchid from insects and fungal diseases
After soaking for 30 minutes, plant it.
Using pine bark and dry pumice stone to plant will help absorb moisture in the roots, making the orchid roots not rot.
Add some dry moss on the face.
Put in a cool and well-lit place for 7 days
After 7 days, you can spray water to keep the plants moist.
Cover with a clear, vented plastic container and wait for the plant to revive.
AFTER 3 WEEKS,
A sprout has sprouted,
Spray water once every 5 days to keep the sprouts moist
AFTER 2 MONTHS
Hope this sharing content will help you in resurrecting weak orchids to grow again
If you find it interesting, remember to click like, share and subscribe so that my channel will soon reach 10 million subscribers.
The video I have created many subtitles, you can choose the appropriate language to understand my shares.
Good luck to you all.
See you in the next videos.