Welcome to my channel.
In this video, I continue to share a new way to help flower branches continue to revive and bloom after blooming.
If you find it interesting, please support me by subscribing to the channel and clicking like.
share so more people know this tip for growing orchids.
These are the branches after the flowers have faded.
But these buttons can continue to bloom if you know how to care for them.
This node has bloomed so it should be cut off.
Then sprinkle cinnamon powder on the cut to help it dry quickly and prevent disease.
Then leave it for 1 day without watering until the cut is dry.
Take 1 onion and cut it into thin slices.
Take 2 eggshells and crush them.
Egg shells contain a lot of calcium and minerals that are very beneficial for flower growth.
Add 2 liters of water and bring to a boil.
Incubate until the water cools.
After the water cools, filter to remove residue.
First step.
Water the orchid roots with onion and eggshell soaking water once a week.
Helps orchids develop roots and germinate quickly.
Step 2.
Spray this water on the leaves once a week.
Helps supplement nutrients through leaves, helping leaves stay green.
At the same time, it repels harmful insects and increases pest resistance.
STep 3.
Roll cotton onto the button to stimulate flowers.
Then spray the water soaked in onions and eggshells onto this cotton pad.
This water will help stimulate flowering very quickly.
Do it once a week.
After incubating the cotton for about 30 minutes, we take the cotton out.
Then take the orchid pot out of this water and remember to spray water on weekdays to keep the orchid pot moist.
1 MONTH LATER.
Old orchid branches continue to grow new shoots.
This helps orchids bloom many times a year.
Each batch blooms many beautiful, colorful flowers
Hope the video helps you a lot.
Thank you for watching the video.
Good luck and see you in the next videos.