Welcome to my channel.
Today I will show you how to propagate orchids
from wilted orchids.
Use about 10g of ginger.
Squeeze out ginger juice
Ginger has a very good antiseptic effect
At the same time, ginger also helps to stimulate germination very quickly
Wait 5 minutes for the ginger juice to penetrate the orchid branch.
Then take it out and let it dry.
Do this so that the water does not penetrate the orchid branch.
It will help the orchid not to rot.
Use 1 spoon of white cement.
Add 500ml of water.
Stir well and wait for the water to clear.
Soak moss in clear cement water to disinfect.
I will recycle these plastic items to grow orchids.
Make a drainage hole.
Put the orchid here and spray it with a moisturizing mist once a week.
AFTER 3 WEEKS.
Lan has revived new sprouts.
Continue misting moisturizer once a week.
waiting for the preschool to grow up.
AFTER 2 MONTHS OF WAIT
WOW
The little orchid has grown very healthy.
So with this simple way we can easily propagate orchids.
Hope it helps you guys.
Please subscribe to my channel to support me.