welcome to my channel.
When the orchid has just lost all its flowers, it is the best time to propagate from the flower stem.
Buttons that have bloomed cannot be propagated.
So I cut off the nodes that have finished blooming.
Repair the cut to avoid crushing the flower stem.
Sprinkle cinnamon powder on the cut to help it heal quickly and prevent rot
Leave for 1 day for the cut to dry completely.
1 Day Later.
Peel off the protective film on the flower button.
This helps baby orchids easily germinate.
Now I use tomatoes to revive baby orchids from flower stems.
Tomatoes contain many important nutrients such as nitrogen (N), phosphorus (P) and potassium (K),
are essential factors to promote the growth of orchids.
Then you tie the tomato core to this position to awaken the baby orchid sprouts to revive.
This helps baby orchids quickly revive from flower stalks.
Leave for about 30 minutes for the nutrients to penetrate into the flower stem.
After 30 minutes, remove it.
then dry.
Then insert the flower stem into the sponge.
Place in a transparent jar.
And pour a little water to always have the right humidity for the baby orchids to revive.
Cover with transparent plastic and keep in a cool place.
3 Weeks Later.
The flower stem has begun to revive the baby orchid.
Continue to place in the vase and place in a cool place for the baby orchids to grow.
After the next 1 month.
Baby orchids have formed from flower stems.
Baby orchids also take root at the same time.
Both the small orchid and its roots are healthy.
Continue to place in the vase and place in a cool place for the baby orchids to grow.
After the next 2 months.
This simple method helps baby orchids grow very healthily.
Now plant them in pots so they can grow outside.
If you find it interesting, please like, share and subscribe to the channel to support me.
I have created subtitles in many different languages ​​so you can choose the appropriate language.
Thank you for watching the video.
Good luck and see you again for the next videos.