welcome to my channel.
When you buy an orchid or someone gives it to you.
You need to do the following:
Leave the orchid in a cool place for a few hours to let it adapt to the new climate.
If the growing medium is moss or small wood chips, it is only suitable for industrial orchid gardens.
Because moss retains a lot of moisture, many plant roots rot due to waterlogging.
The humidity was too high so the leaves were also infected with black mold.
Therefore, you need to remove all moss or old growing medium.
Because this type of substrate is only suitable for industrial orchid gardens that can control special humidity.
Then you cut off all damaged roots.
and cut off all wilted flowers.
Then you take 1 aloe vera leaf.
And take a clove of garlic.
Put all the aloe vera and garlic in a jar and soak it with 2 liters of water.
Wait 30 minutes for the nutrients from the garlic and aloe vera to dissolve into the water.
30 MINUTES LATER
Soak the roots in this solution for 30 minutes.
Garlic and aloe vera help stimulate root growth and effectively fight harmful insects and fungi
Spraying this solution on the entire orchid will help repel insects,
eliminate fungal diseases and keep the leaves green.
Then clean the black mold stains with this solution.
This helps prevent orchids from recurring mold.
Now I recycle used plastic containers to make orchid pots.
I put a layer of pumice on the bottom of the orchid pot.
This helps keep the bottom of the orchid pot clear so the roots don't get waterlogged.
For the top, I used dried pine bark as a growing medium.
and mix in some dry moss.
When planting, cushion the substrate tightly so that the roots do not move.
Insert the flower branch into the right position to help prevent the orchid from shaking.
After planting, let it dry for 5 days before watering.
Thank you for watching the video.
Good luck and see you in the next videos.