Welcome to my channel.
When your orchid leaves turn yellow and wilt.
You need to check the roots for damage.
If the roots are damaged, all damaged roots must be cut off.
This will prevent the rotten roots from spreading and causing the orchid stem to rot.
and cut off yellow and rotten leaves.
This helps keep the rot from spreading into the tree trunk
Then rinse under running water to remove dirt.
Place the leaves in a jar to prevent further wilting.
Wait for the roots to dry completely before planting
Put 2 liters of water into the pot.
I took 5-6 eggs and boiled them.
Boil over low heat for 10 minutes.
After 10 minutes take the eggs out.
Pour the water you just boiled the eggs into the jar.
Then take 3 tablespoons of rice and soak it in the water you just boiled the eggs in.
Incubate until the water cools.
After the water cools, filter to remove sediment.
Step 1.
Wipe the leaves thoroughly with this water.
This water helps eliminate fungal diseases and harmful insects.
and also helps restore leaves very well.
then soak the orchid roots in this water for about 30 minutes.
This helps stimulate rooting very quickly.
After 30 minutes, take it out and plant it in a vase.
Pour in water.
Water level control only reaches this position.
Place in a cool, well-lit place and regularly change the water when it is dirty.
Spray water periodically every 3-5 days.
Continue soaking orchid roots in rice water once a week.
1 MONTH LATER.
My orchid has grown a lot of new roots.
This helps orchids quickly recover withered leaves.
Now I plant the orchid in a pot so it can grow in the same environment as other normal orchids.
Once the root system is strong, planting the orchid in a pot will help the orchid grow and recover quickly.
Water regularly to keep moist.
Then take care of it with homemade organic fertilizer that I have shared on this channel.
After the next 2 months.
The orchid has completely recovered, its leaves are normal and sturdy.
A healthy root system helps absorb nutrients well, so the plant recovers very quickly.
and it develops many buds (flower stems) at the same time.
If you find it interesting, please subscribe to the channel, like and share so more people know this tip.
Thank you for watching the video. Good luck and see you in the next videos!