Welcome to my channel
In this video I will show you how to take care of orchids that have died and bloomed again
In my hand is a flower branch that has fallen, only the branch remains
Let these flowers grow and bloom again
need to cut off the places that have bloomed
Just for the places where it can thrive like this
and peel off the membrane for easy flower growth
This cut is left to dry naturally. You should not water until the cut is not dry
This is a sprouted potato
Potato sprouts contain a lot of AUXIN which is a plant growth stimulant
Add 20 grams of fresh ginger
Add 0,6 liter of water at room temperature
puree it all
Filter out residue
Add 0.6 liters of water at room temperature
first use
Soak cotton balls in potato germ water
clamp where sprouts can grow
7 days do it again with potato sprout water 1 time
2nd way
Pour potato juice into a spray bottle
Spray evenly on leaves, roots, roots and surface of orchid growing medium, but do not spray on flowers
Potato sprouts contain many important nutrients for plants such as:
Potato sprouts contain high amounts of protein,
This is one of the important factors needed for plant growth.
The natural potassium content in potato sprouts is an essential nutrient for the growth of plants,
helping to enhance resistance,
resistant to a number of diseases and helps plants resist adverse environmental influences.
3rd way
Water evenly on the roots, roots and surface of the substrate
Potato sprouts also contain phosphorus,
an important nutrient that promotes root growth,
play an important role in plant growth.
Calcium in potato sprouts is also very abundant, which is an essential nutrient for the growth of plant cells
plays an important role in creating strong cellular structures,
while helping to improve the pH of the soil and increase the plant's ability to absorb other nutrients.
Potato sprouts also contain mage
Magnesium is an important nutrient that helps balance pH,
increase the absorption capacity of plants
Apply misting method or root watering once a month
Results after more than 1 month stimulate flowering for faded flowers
This way is very many Hoa used by this way
Care results with potato sprout juice
Orchids bloom many flowers at once
and bloom long on flower branches
can last up to 3 months
The leaves are very thick and sturdy
Roots grow very big and strong