Welcome to my channel
In this video, I share an organic fertilizer that every home has to restore wilted and weak orchids.
Subscribe to the channel so you don't miss any orchid care tips on my channel.
You see this is a withered and weak orchid.
If not restored, the orchid will die or will never bloom.
First you need to cut off all damaged roots.
and cut dried flower stems.
Fix the orchid so that it will not damage the roots when it roots later.
Then take 5 spoons of rice.
Add 2 liters of water at room temperature.
Wait 30 minutes before using.
then take 2 spoons of milk.
Add 1 liter of water at room temperature.
Then thoroughly wipe the top and bottom of the leaf.
This helps remove dirt, fungus and disease-causing bacteria on orchids.
At the same time, adding nutrients through the leaves helps the orchid recover quickly
after 30 minutes.
Mix milk solution with rice water as fertilizer.
Adding moss helps retain moisture better.
From now on, water your orchids with this liquid fertilizer once a week.
Should be done in the morning before the sun is hot.
On normal days, the substrate is dry, just watering to keep it moist is enough.
Place the orchid pot in a cool, well-lit place and the plant will recover faster and the plant will be healthy.
1 Month Later
The orchid has developed many new roots.
Many branched roots develop to help absorb nutrients and water better.
Hopefully the video will help you a lot in taking better care of orchids at home.
Thank you for watching the video. Good luck and see you in the next videos.