Welcome to my channel
When growing orchids, everyone wants the orchid to grow healthy and flower a lot,
And if that's what you want, watch to the end of the video.
Today I will show you how to make a new organic fertilizer, it is made from bell peppers,
It's great because it helps the orchid grow and bloom a lot of flowers for you
You see this orchid of mine,
Thanks to the fertilizer I made myself from bell peppers
so its leaves are always green and sturdy,
The roots are very large, growing healthy,
grow many buds and do not fall,
Flowers bloom brilliantly and long.
Let's start doing it
Use 20 grams of bell pepper
Add 600ml of water
filter out residue
Add water to make 1 liter
Bell peppers contain many vitamins A, C, amino acids and minerals: Calcium, magnesium, zinc.
In particular, bell peppers are very high in sugar and phosphorus and potassium
Those are the organic substances necessary for the growth of orchids
Water this once a month
The nutrients in bell peppers will stimulate orchid growth,
The phosphorus content in bell peppers will stimulate the roots to grow very quickly,
The potassium and sugar content will help the orchid transport water and sugar from the roots to the leaves, to the flower branches,
When there is potassium and sugar, the leaves will never wilt,
Flower buds will also not fall when given enough sugar and potassium in bell peppers
This is milk
milk without sugar
Mix 30ml milk with 70ml water
Clean the surface of orchid leaves with milk
The stomata on the leaves will be ventilated
Insects on leaves are also removed
Disease fungi and bacteria on leaves are also eliminated
At the same time, milk is also a very good source of nutrients for plants
Orchids are also provided with nutrients through their leaves
so the orchid will always be green and sturdy
Note: it is necessary to thoroughly wipe both the top and bottom of the leaves
The underside of the leaf is a humid place, so fungi and bacteria hide and work
Orchids are very susceptible to leaf rot caused by fungi and bacteria
The underside of the leaves is also a shelter for insects,
They will destroy the orchid leaves starting here,
It will then spread causing the entire leaf to turn yellow
you see
After wiping the green orchid leaves
Orchids will photosynthesize well
Orchid's metabolism will also be better
Lan will increase resistance
when the orchid is healthy
and enough nutrition
with good care
When blooming, it will be very fresh and long-lasting.
Healthy roots contribute to good nutrient absorption for orchids
Hope the video content will help you in taking better care of orchids at home
Next I share the video "The faded flowers instantly bloom again in this magical way"
With faded flowers like this,
It is possible to let them continue to bloom in a very simple way,
and the orchid is restored to health.
First, cut off the spots that no longer bloom
Pick 1 aloe leaf
Apply aloe vera gel to the spot you just cut,
It will disinfect and stimulate germination very quickly.
Let this cut dry naturally.
Peel off the membrane to make sprouts easy to grow.
Then apply aloe vera gel on the places where flowers can grow,
Aloe vera will stimulate flower sprout differentiation very quickly.
Crush aloe vera leaves with 1 liter of water.
Water this once every 2 weeks for the orchid to recover.
Combine using other organic fertilizers like peas that I shared on the channel,
for the best orchid growth.
Aloe vera juice also stimulates root development to help plants absorb nutrients faster
After 1 day the cut was dry
AFTER 30 DAYS
Withered orchid branches will revive new flower branches like this
AFTER THE NEXT 20 DAYS
Flowers will grow like this.
You will have flowers that continue to bloom like this,
So with this simple way, you can let orchids bloom all year round
Hope this sharing content will help you in taking better care of orchids at home.
If you find the video interesting, please like, share and subscribe to help the channel reach 10,000,000 subscribers soon.