welcome to my channel.
If your orchid grows forever but does not bloom.
Please watch until the end of the video to learn this tip for growing orchids.
First you need to take the orchid out of the pot to replant it using the new method
Remove all damaged leaves and roots
Rinsing with water helps remove dirt, mold and insects
Take 5 spoons of rice which contains many nutrients such as Protein, Phosphorus, Potassium and amino acids
Add 2 liters of water
Soak orchids in rice water for 10 minutes
This helps stimulate root growth and the orchid recovers quickly
Now I recycle plastic bottles as orchid nursery tools
Then plant the orchid in a new pot
Use sterilized pine bark to grow orchids
After planting, I watered the orchids
This way you won't have to water it and the orchids will still grow
The water level just touches the bottom of the orchid pot
Spray foliar fertilizer for orchids once a week with organic fertilizer as I shared on the channel
Place the plant in a cool, well-lit place and it will grow quickly with good photosynthesis
2 Months Later
After 2 months the orchid has recovered and developed many flower buds
During the care process, if you see dirty water, you need to change the water in the orchid vase
After 3 Months
The orchids have bloomed and the plants are very healthy
The leaves are strong, sturdy and have increased resistance to pests
The roots grow very well and do not rot
Flowers bloom brilliantly
The plant always has enough moisture so that the flowers do not wilt
Therefore, the flowers stick on the branches for a long time and can last up to a year before wilting.