Welcome to my channel Happiness Garden.
In this video, I will share 3 methods to help you care for and restore orchids quickly
and bloom all year round.
Now let's start learning about the uses of the first type of fertilizer.
Take 3 liters of water at room temperature.
Take 50ml of Coca-Cola.
Then you just need to mix coca-cola with water and you can use it right away.
Then you clean the surface of the orchid leaves with this coca-cola.
Wipe both the top and bottom of the leaves.
This way helps to repel insects and fungi on leaves very well.
Do it once every 2 weeks, orchid leaves will be very well protected.
You can also use this water to spray the entire orchid.
Pay attention to spray carefully the underside of leaves and between leaves.
because insects and fungi often congregate there.
This is also done every 2 weeks.
if you use the wiping and spraying method of coca-cola regularly,
Leaves will always be green because they are not damaged by insects and fungi.
Like my orchid, the leaves are always green and healthy.
Now take care of the roots.
You just need to water this orchid as much as possible.
Coca-Cola contains phosphoric acid which has a mild bleaching effect.
so it will eliminate fungal diseases in pots and roots very well.
In addition, Coca-Cola also has the ability to kill some insects that damage plant roots such as:
snails and cockroaches are very good.
Coca-Cola helps neutralize the acid in the pot when you use too much chemical fertilizer.
balance pH in orchid pots.
This will stimulate new root growth.
Coca-Cola contains sugar that helps flowers grow very well.
If combined with organic fertilizers, it will help spread more flowers.
My orchids when applying this method have grown a lot of flower branches on one tree.
The sugar in coca-cola helps flowers stay fresh and long-lasting.
Orchid after blooming will not be exhausted.
Orchid can bloom continuously from one batch to another.
New roots are always growing.
Helps orchids absorb the most nutrients.
Hope the video will help you in taking care of orchids at home better.
And I also hope you enjoy this first tip.
If you find it interesting, please like, share the video
and Subscribe to help my channel reach 10 million subscribers soon.
And don't rush to leave the screen. Tip #2 and tip #3 will be even better.
If you have an orchid that has rot causing the leaves to turn yellow.
So don't rush to throw it away. I will share how to revive it quickly and easily.
This orchid may be suffering from inorganic fertilizer shock leading to root rot causing the leaves to turn yellow.
So I need to check the roots to cut off all damaged roots.
Removing damaged roots helps prevent the rot from spreading, causing the entire root of the orchid to rot.
and stimulates new root formation faster.
Then rinse with water.
Take 2 liters of water and put it in a jar.
Then add 1 teaspoon of Baking Soda to help kill bacteria and eliminate pests.
Soak orchid roots in this water for 10 minutes.
Then use dry moss to grow orchids.
After soaking for 10 minutes, take the orchid out and plant it.
When planting dry, sterilized moss, it will help absorb moisture from the roots.
This helps the cut heal quickly and the rot does not spread further.
Then place in a cool place and do not water for 1 week.
After 1 week, start watering the orchid once a week.
Soak in water for 10 minutes to keep the moss moist.
Then take it out and cover it with a transparent plastic box.
And remember to water it every week to keep it moist.
1 MONTH LATER.
The orchid has revived and grown healthy roots.
But it seems like the leaves are a bit wilted.
Once the root system is strong, you need to add more nutrients to help the orchid grow quickly.
Take 2 liters of water.
and add 5 teaspoons of rice.
Rice contains a variety of minerals and amino acids that are important for orchid growth.
Then use this rice water to water the orchids once a week.
In addition to providing necessary nutrients,
rice water also creates a favorable environment for beneficial microorganisms to grow in orchid pots.
Soak for 10 minutes then take out the orchid pot.
Regularly spray mist to keep the soil moist when the growing medium is dry.
2 MONTHS LATER.
From an orchid with leaf rot causing the leaves to turn completely yellow, it has now grown healthily.
Strong roots, fresh green leaves.
If you find the video interesting, please like and share so more people know.
and subscribe to my support channel.
My videos have subtitles in many different languages,
please choose the appropriate language to clearly understand the content I share.
Welcome to tip number 3.
To help you have many choices when caring for orchids at home with organic fertilizer.
In this video, I continue to share new methods.
Subscribe to the video so you don't miss any tips on my channel.
Now, let's get started.
To make this type of organic fertilizer you need black tea (or tea grounds).
I use 3 teaspoons of black tea.
Add 1 liter of boiled water.
Incubate until the water cools.
After the water cools, filter to remove sediment.
Add water to make 5 liters of black tea solution.
Next add 1 teaspoon of baking soda.
FIRST METHOD
Water this fertilizer solution on the orchid roots.
Black tea contains many minerals and organic substances that help provide nutrition for orchids.
It contains nitrogen, potassium and phosphorus,
Important nutritional factors for orchid growth.
Baking soda (bicarbonate soda) has the ability to increase the PH level in orchid pots,
This is helpful in reducing acidity if you use too much chemical fertilizer.
Baking soda has the ability to kill insects and fungi that are harmful to plants.
SECOND METHOD
Spray this fertilizer on the entire orchid.
This method is similar to using foliar fertilizer.
You can use it as a natural pesticide to protect orchids from insects and diseases.
THIRD METHOD
Clean the leaf surface with this fertilizer solution.
The leaf surface will always be clean and the stomata will not be clogged.
Orchids will photosynthesize better.
RESULT
Plant roots are protected and supplemented with nutrients so they grow very healthily.
will help orchids absorb the most nutrients.
Because they are provided with enough nutrition, the flowers bloom more brilliantly.
Many flowers bloom on the same branch.
The flowers stay on the branches for a long time before fading.
Thank you for watching the video. Wishing you luck and success in life.
Goodbye and see you again in the next videos.