Hello friends
I am an expert in organic fertilizers and orchid care techniques
In this video, I show you how to rejuvenate an old orchid
and the secret to revive the orchid to take root and produce young leaves
Cut off damaged leaves
Cut off damaged roots
Rinse with water
Use 1 clove of garlic
Use 1 sprig of fresh ginger
300ml filtered water
Garlic and ginger have a very good effect on stimulating germination and roots
Puree garlic and ginger with 300 ml of water
Filter out the residue
Soak orchid branches in garlic and ginger juice for 20 minutes
Remove the branches after soaking for 20 minutes
Wipe and wait for the cut to dry
0:03:56.386,1193:02:47.295
Dip the cut in the molten candle solution
Recycle plastic boxes into mini greenhouses to revive weak orchids to grow faster
Put orchid branches in miniature greenhouse
Pour water into the miniature greenhouse but don't let the water reach the orchid's branches
Place the orchid in a cool place, the temperature is 20-30 degrees Celsius, there is light but avoid direct sunlight
Now I will rejuvenate this old orchid
Water once every 2 weeks and keep in a cool place as above
5 Weeks Later
The old orchid root has been rejuvenated
The old root has grown 2 sprouts and produced many new healthy roots
The orchid branch has grown many roots and is very healthy
and grow 1 more young leaf
Now I plant in pots to grow orchids in the outside environment
After planting, you take care of them like any other normal plant
If you find the video meaningful, please subscribe to help the channel reach 1,000,000 subscribers soon
and like, share to as many people as possible
Now I will show you how to make orchids not root or orchids with root rot quickly.
This is a wilted orchid.
Only the top part of the orchid is still fresh.
I dipped the cut into this molten candle solution.
This method helps cuts heal quickly and does not rot.
I use 1 aloe vera leaf.
Put into blender with 300ml of water.
Filter out the residue.
Soak orchid branches in aloe vera water for 30 minutes.
30 MINUTES LATER.
Take out the orchid branches and dry them.
Plug the orchid branches into the foam and then put them in a plastic box.
Water it just enough to keep it moist, then take the orchid pot to a cool place with light light but not direct sunlight.
45 DAYS LATER.
You can see that your orchid has grown very healthy roots.
and even grow very strong new leaves.
Now I need to plant the orchid in a pot so it can grow in a normal outside environment.
Add some moss on top to keep the roots moist.
Water to keep moist.
So with this simple way, anyone can revive a withered orchid to grow again.
Hopefully this little trick will help you take better care of orchids at home.
This is Dendrobium orchid, an orchid with a very beautiful scent and color.
In this video I will show you how to revive denrobium orchids.
1. Cut off all old and damaged roots.
In this video, I have subtitles in all countries.
So you can choose subtitles (CC) in the correct language to understand the video content.
2. Rinse with water.
3. Add 5 drops of rooting and budding stimulant solution mixed with 50ml of filtered water.
4. Soak this dry orchid branch in this water for 30 minutes.
5. Recycle plastic boxes into miniature greenhouses to propagate orchids faster.
Use floral foam.
6. Put the orchid in a miniature greenhouse.
7. Pour in filtered water just enough to moisten it.
I only add enough water and I will add more when the water runs out.
2 Months Later.
So after 2 months the withered denrobium orchid was revived.
Young orchids grow roots very well.
This orchid is smaller but the roots are also very strong.
Now I will plant in pots to grow orchids in an environment outside the greenhouse.
denrobium grows very quickly so I will put it in a larger pot.
After planting, you water and care for it like other normal orchids.
1 YEAR LATER.
Thus, a withered orchid revives after a year of beautiful blooming.
That's all I want to share with you in this video.
If you find it interesting, please like and share it with many people
Wishing you success and happiness in life.
Welcome to Hapiness Garden channel
I am a nutritionist for orchids
In this video I show you how to make an organic fertilizer
to help restore weak, yellowed, and wilted orchids
To make fertilizer you use 1 aloe leaf
Aloe vera gel helps to stimulate roots very well
At the same time, it helps to retain moisture and restore wilted leaves very quickly
next you use 1-2 more eggshells
Remember to wash it to remove the fungus
Eggshells contain 70% calcium
Will help the orchid grow stronger,
improve resistance to fungi and insects
Then puree aloe vera leaves and egg shells with 300ml of filtered water
Filter out the residue
Add water to get 3 liters of aloe vera solution
first way
Wipe the top and bottom of orchids with wilted leaves every 2 days
Aloe vera gel contains many vitamins and minerals necessary for plants
and aloe vera gel also moisturizes well, so it helps to recover wilted leaves very quickly
Wipe the top and bottom of orchids with wilted leaves every 2 days
If you do this regularly, the orchid's leaves will always be green and not be attacked by fungi and insects
Second way:
Watering aloe vera for wilted orchids once a week
Will provide the orchid with essential vitamins and minerals through the roots
At the same time, it is also a fertilizer that helps to revive roots very quickly
For normal growing orchids, water aloe vera every 2 weeks
3rd way
Spray aloe vera juice on wilted orchid once every 3 days
like we fertilize the orchid leaves
For normal orchid growth, just mist with aloe vera juice every 2 weeks
This helps the orchid grow and keep the flower on the branch for a long time
Let's see the results together
After 2 weeks of use, my wilted orchid has grown new roots
This orchid has also grown many new roots
Growing roots help absorb more nutrients and water
help wilted orchid quickly recover wilted leaves
As for orchids that are growing normally, it will promote faster growth
Orchids have developed roots, flowers bloom longer and keep on branches longer
If you haven't received any value, don't leave the video.
Part 2/2 I share easy tips for propagating orchids that anyone can do themselves