Welcome to my channel.
In this video, I share the method of recovering weak orchids.
Helps them quickly take root and grow strongly.
I picked up a rotten orchid that someone had thrown away.
All the roots have rotted.
Which country are you watching this video from? Please comment and let me know!
It's wonderful that we can connect and chat with each other from all around the world!
This original part has completely rotted so it can no longer be used.
Wash orchid branches with water.
Then take 1 clove of garlic and mince it.
Add 500ml of water and soak for 30 minutes.
Let the flower nutrition completely dissolve in water.
AFTER 30 MINUTES.
Wiping orchid branches with garlic water helps disinfect and eliminate fungal diseases.
Then soak the orchid branches in garlic water for 10 minutes.
This helps stimulate root and shoot growth.
10 Minutes Later.
because this orchid has many scars from previous insect bites.
So I waited a day for the orchid to dry completely before planting it.
1 Day Later.
I recycle sponges as orchid nursery tools.
Soaking the sponge in garlic water for 20 minutes helps disinfect and kill fungus.
20 MINUTES LATER.
Insert the orchid stem into the sponge and place it in the vase.
Pour some water into the jar and change it every time it gets dirty.
Spray moisturizer every 3 days.
and Place in a cool, well-lit place.
5 WEEKS LATER
The roots have grown very healthy.
With this simple method, the roots have grown and the orchid has revived very well.
I planted it in a pot so the orchid could grow better.
If you find the video interesting, please like and share so more people know this tip.
Water orchids regularly to keep them moist.
Subscribe to my channel to support me and don't miss any tricks on my channel
Welcome to part 2 of this video!
In Part 2 of this video, I share how to care for orchids to help them grow and bloom.
You can see that my orchids always develop new flower stems after the old flowers have fallen off.
so my orchids bloom all year round.
bloom from branch to branch.
The flowers on the stems take a long time to fall off.
They can even last up to 6 months before the petals drop.
Many flowers grow on the same tree.
New roots grow a lot to help absorb nutrients best
chubby flower buds
Help flowers bloom long on branches
brilliant flowers
How to make fertilizer as follows:
Use 1 small carrot weighing about 30g.
Cut into small pieces.
Add 1 liter of filtered water.
Puree.
filter out residue.
Add 1 liter of filtered water.
Then, use cotton to soak carrot juice and wipe both the top and bottom sides of the leaves.
This method helps repel insects and open the stomata.
The orchids will photosynthesize and exchange nutrients better.
At the same time, orchids also absorb some nutrients through the leaves
Help keep the leaves green
2nd way.
Water this carrot for orchids.
Carrot juice is a good source of nutrients for orchids,
including vitamins and minerals like beta-carotene, potassium, magnesium, and phosphorus.
When the carrot juice is poured into the orchid pot,
it provides nutrients to the orchids and helps to promote their health.
In addition, carrot juice is also acidic, which helps regulate the pH of the potted soil
and enhances the orchid's ability to absorb nutrients.
You can soak the orchid pot in this carrot juice for 20 minute
Do this 1-2 times a month
3rd way
Mist moisturizing carrot juice for orchids by spraying both the top and bottom of the leaves.
This helps wash away dirt and eliminate insects on your orchids.
The nutrients in carrot juice support orchid health, helping them thrive and bloom beautifully.
However, be careful not to over-water the carrot juice as it can clog the water channels in the orchid.
Avoid spraying directly on flowers because it can cause flowers to fall off quickly.
I hope this video helps you take better care of your orchids at home and encourages them to bloom easily.
If you find it helpful and interesting, please like, share, and subscribe to support my channel. Thank you!
Welcome to part 3 of today's video!
To give you more options for taking care of your orchids at home using organic fertilizer, in this video,
I continue to share methods for making natural fertilizer from everyday kitchen ingredients you can find in your home.
Subscribe to the video so you don't miss any tips on my channel.
Number 1:
To make this fertilizer you need apples.
Apples contain potassium, an important mineral for orchid growth.
Potassium helps orchids develop stronger leaves, roots and flowers.
I took the apple peel and put it in a bottle.
Soak in boiled water and leave overnight.
No. 2
To make this type of fertilizer you need more eggshells.
Soak the eggshells in boiled water and leave overnight.
Leave overnight.
After 1 night, filter the water.
So we have fertilizer from apples and eggshells.
FIRST METHOD.
Water this fertilizer solution on the orchid roots.
Eggshells provide natural calcium which is very good for orchids.
Helps orchids stay healthy and increase resistance.
Apple peels contain a lot of Phosphorus, which is also an important nutrient for orchid growth.
especially during the flowering and flower development stage.
Do this 1-2 times/month to supplement nutrition and increase the orchid's resistance.
SECOND METHOD.
Spray this fertilizer on the entire orchid.
This method is similar to using foliar fertilizer.
Calcium in eggshells helps orchids stay healthy and increases their resistance to pests.
Apples contain nitrogen, an important nutrient.
Helps orchids develop green parts and increase photosynthesis ability.
Do not spray on flowers.
Because wet flowers will easily fall off.
THIRD METHOD
Clean the leaf surface with this liquid fertilizer.
The leaf surface will always be clean and airy.
Orchids will photosynthesize better.
Fertilizing regularly 1-2 times/month will help keep the leaves healthy.
Number 3:
You can reuse eggshells and apple peels to make fertilizer again.
Let's check out the results together!
This type of fertilizer stimulates rooting very quickly.
After 1 month of use you will see great results.
Many flower buds develop and do not fall.
Blooming flowers stay on the branches for a long time before fading.
Flowers can remain on branches for up to 6 months before falling.
Thank you for watching the video. Good luck and see you in the next videos!