welcome to my
channel if you have an orchid with
yellow leaves and weak Roots don't miss
this
video first remove all the yellow leaves
and any dead roots
[Music]
um let me know where you're
from let me create subtitles in your
country's language so we can communicate
more easily
[Music]
then use small pieces of pine bark to
replant this orchid
if you haven't subscribed to the channel
yet click the Subscribe button to
support me
[Music]
spread a layer of moss over the surface
of the Orchid pot to help retain
moisture
[Music]
better take two table spoons of
vinegar Mix 4 L of water with the
vinegar
[Music]
step one clean the orchid leaves with
this water
[Music]
vinegar water helps remove lime deposits
and dirt from the leaves allowing them
to photosynthesize more effectively in
sunlight it also kills harmful insects
that often hide on the underside of
leaves such as red spidermites leaf
Hoppers aphids and thrips
[Music]
if you don't understand don't hesitate
to leave a comment so we can help you
[Music]
doing this one to two times a month will
keep your orchid leaves green and
prevent leaf diseases
[Music]
then take one teaspoon of sugar and mix
it with the vinegar water
[Music]
step two pour the solution over the
Orchid
Roots vinegar combined with sugar helps
stimulate root growth very quickly and
effectively uh vinegar helps eliminate
pests harmful to Orchid Roots while
sugar provides nutrients and creates an
environment for beneficial
microorganisms to thrive around the
[Music]
roots soak in this solution for about 30
minutes then take it out and place it in
a spot with gentle sunlight so the
Orchid can photosynthesize and grow
[Music]
well use the remaining mixture to water
other healthy orchids helping them grow
and enhance their resistance to pest and
[Music]
diseases do this twice a month with this
solution for your orchids
[Music]
1 month later
after just one month the orchid has
grown many new
[Music]
Roots these new Roots will absorb water
and nutrients most effectively helping
the Orchid grow quickly
[Music]
I hope this video content will help you
learn how to care for orchids at
home thank you for watching wishing you
good health and good luck in taking care
of your orchids at home
welcome to part two of this video
[Music]
[Applause]
rice is a common and highly effective
organic fertilizer for plants so in this
video I will show you two methods to
make orchid fertilizer using
rice method
one take 3 tbspoon of rice
[Music]
grind it into a fine powder
add 1 liter of boiling water
[Music]
cover it and wait for it to cool down
filter out the
[Music]
residue dilute it with 2 L of water
now use this water to water your
orchids rice contains many nutrients
such as potassium phosphorus and protein
which are essential for the growth of
[Music]
orchids therefore rice washing water
helps the plants grow healthily and
enhances their resistance to pests and
diseases
[Music]
rice washing water helps boost the
activity of beneficial microorganisms in
the orchid's growing medium thereby
protecting the roots and making it
easier for them to absorb
[Music]
nutrients doing this once a month will
help your orchids grow healthily
[Music]
and of course it will also bloom a
lot uh the microorganisms in the
orchid's growing medium help protect the
roots from
rotting when the roots grow they absorb
nutrients that make the flowers more
beautiful allowing them to stay in bloom
for a long time before their petals
wither
[Music]
[Applause]
regular care in this way will ensure the
leaves receive enough nutrients allowing
them to grow very green
[Music]
method
two when cooking rice we usually rinse
the rice from now on don't don't rush to
pour this rice water down the
drain filter this rice washing water and
let it
[Music]
settle after it has settled filter 100 M
of the water from the
[Music]
top dilute it with 200 M of regular
water pour this rice washing water into
a spray bottle
[Music]
use this water to spray evenly on the
surface of the orchid
leaves the vitamin B1 in rice washing
water helps stimulate the conversion of
nutrients especially harmful elements
like manganese iron and copper into more
easily absorbed forms
[Music]
vitamin B1 helps strengthen the orchid's
immune system enabling the plant to
resist pests and other environmental
[Music]
stressors for the rice water that has
settled at the bottom I filter out the
residue then dilute it with an
additional 2 L of
[Music]
water and I use this water to water my
orchids we also do this once a month
just like the first method I shared at
the beginning of the
video Additionally you can combine other
organic fertilizers to ensure your organ
kids receive all the necessary
nutrients thank you for watching the
video wishing you all the best and much
success