Hello everyone, to easily care for orchids to always grow healthily.
There are more flower buds and flowers stay on the branches longer.
Today I share a very easy way to keep orchids growing healthily.
When eating bananas, don't throw away the peel.
Because banana peels contain many nutrients, especially organic potassium.
Very good for the growth of buds, flowers and has anti-drought effects.
I cut the banana peel thinly and put it in a jar.
Next I took a piece of bread.
Bread contains phosphorus, which plays an important role in plant growth, especially stimulating root growth.
Adding 1 teaspoon of yeast helps decompose organic matter faster and prevents it from rotting.
And adding a spoonful of sugar helps nourish the growth of beneficial microorganisms.
Add 500ml warm water.
Then leave in a cool place for 3 weeks.
3 Weeks later.
Take 2 liters of water.
After 3 weeks of composting we have this wonderful fertilizer.
Take 50ml.
then mix into water.
Method 1: Fertilize the roots.
Water each orchid pot with this water 5-10 spoons per week.
This fertilizer provides potassium, an important mineral that improves plant health and vitality.
This type of fertilizer also helps retain water and enhances the plant's ability to absorb water.
Beneficial fungi Mycorrhiza will grow to help the plant more easily absorb nutrients from the orchid growing medium.
Method 2.
Use this water to spray on the leaves.
Helps supplement nutrients through leaves very effectively.
Helps orchid leaves become strong and healthy.
and sprayed on aerial roots to help aerial roots grow and easily absorb nutrients in the air.
You should do it early in the morning and by noon the leaves will dry very quickly.
Do this once a week to keep the orchid healthy.
Method 3:
Now I wash the leaves with this water.
Beneficial microorganisms will help kill mold and insects very effectively.
Do this every 2 weeks to protect your orchids.
Result
After fertilizing, orchids will always be green and healthy.
Potassium in banana peels and bread helps flower buds grow strongly.
When the flowers bloom, they will stay on the branches for a long time.
Flowers can last on branches for up to 6 months before fading.
Hopefully the video will help you a lot in taking better care of orchids at home.
Next I will show you how to revive a rotten orchid like this.
When the orchid has withered all the leaves, only the stem and roots remain, do not rush to throw it away.
Here are still fresh roots.
First, cut off all damaged, rotten roots.
Apply a molten candle on the cut so that the water does not penetrate the tree.
Use 2 teaspoons of cinnamon powder.
Add 1 liter of boiled water.
Close the lid and wait for the water to cool.
The water has cooled down
Filter out residue.
Soak orchids in this water for 30 minutes.
The rest of the water I will spray on other orchids to help protect the orchid from insects and fungal diseases
After soaking for 30 minutes, plant it.
Using pine bark and dry pumice stone to plant will help absorb moisture in the roots, making the orchid roots not rot.
Add some dry moss on the face.
Put in a cool and well-lit place for 7 days
After 7 days, you can spray water to keep the plants moist.
Cover with a clear, vented plastic container and wait for the plant to revive.
AFTER 3 WEEKS,
A sprout has sprouted,
Spray water once every 5 days to keep the sprouts moist
AFTER 2 MONTHS
Hope this sharing content will help you in resurrecting weak orchids to grow again
If you find it interesting, remember to click like, share and subscribe so that my channel will soon reach 1000,000 subscribers.
The video I have created many subtitles, you can choose the appropriate language to understand my shares.
Good luck to you all.
See you in the next videos.