Welcome to my channel
There are different ways to care for orchids at home,
Today I share a new method for you to have more choices.
This is an aloe plant
Use 1 aloe leaf
Add 1 liter of water at room temperature
Leave in the dark for 1 day
AFTER 1 DAY
You will get red aloe vera juice like this
Use cotton balls
Clean the top and bottom of the orchid leaves
Water soaked in aloe vera leaves has many uses
Widely used in cosmetic, hair and skin industries
For plants, aloe vera helps kill fungi and bacteria that cause rot very quickly
Because in aloe vera contains a high content of natural antibiotics
it's many times better than garlic and antibiotics
Pay attention to thoroughly wipe the underside of the leaves because this place contains many fungi, bacteria and insects
Clean the surface of leaves with aloe vera juice every 2 weeks
Helps open stomata on orchid leaves
and kill fungi, bacteria, insects
Watering aloe vera on the entire root and growing medium
Water it like this once a month
Aloe vera juice is also a rich source of nutrients for orchids
because aloe vera contains 75 kinds of nutrients including: 20 kinds of minerals, 12 kinds of vitamins, enzymes and antioxidants,
This will stimulate the orchid to sprout and take root very quickly
If you do it regularly, orchid leaves will always be green
If the orchid is healthy, the flowers will also bloom
flowers also last a long time
Each year will bloom from 2 to 3 times depending on the orchid variety and the growth of the orchid
The flower color is also more beautiful
flower buds won't fall
Hope the video content will help you in taking better care of orchids at home
If you find it interesting, please like, share and subscribe to the channel so that the channel will soon reach 10.000,000 subscribers
Welcome to part 2 of the video
when the orchid has faded,
We can completely propagate from branches,
Today I will show you how to breed very simply.
Peel off the outer membrane
Thus, small orchid sprouts will easily grow
Use about 20 grams of aloe leaves
take 200ml of water
Crush aloe vera leaves in water
Soak in this aloe vera juice for 20 minutes
Take it out and dry it
Wait for it to dry completely
Use candles to apply to the cut so that the orchid does not lose water and does not rot
Use 1 teaspoon of turmeric powder
add 800ml water
Soak moss in turmeric water to remove disease fungi and bacteria in the media
wait 20 minutes
Recycle recycled plastic bottles to make orchid propagating tools
Put the orchid branch in and remember to rotate the orchid branch upwards
Spray moisturizing mist every 5 days
Cover and put in a cool place
AFTER 3 WEEKS
Small orchid sprouts have grown
Continue misting to moisturize every 5 days
Continue to cover and place in a cool place
AFTER THE NEXT 1.5 MONTHS
Small orchids are already quite large
Continue misting to moisturize every 5 days
Close the lid and continue to keep in a cool place
AFTER THE NEXT 1.5 MONTHS
The small orchid has grown healthy,
finished enough leaves and roots
Now we bring it out and plant it under normal conditions for the plant to grow
Reuse recycled plastic bottles to make orchid pots,
This also helps to reduce environmental pollution.
Add some moss on top for moisture
Add 300 ml of water to the mixed aloe vera juice
Irrigate with freshly brewed aloe vera water.
With this planting method, orchids will grow very quickly
So with this simple way you can propagate orchids at home very easily
Now take care of it like any other orchid
Hope the video will be useful for you to take better care of orchids at home
I wish you luck and success