Welcome to my channel.
If you have an orchid that has rot causing the leaves to turn yellow.
So don't rush to throw it away. I will share how to revive it quickly and easily.
This orchid may be suffering from inorganic fertilizer shock leading to root rot causing the leaves to turn yellow.
So I need to check the roots to cut off all damaged roots.
Removing damaged roots helps prevent the rot from spreading, causing the entire root of the orchid to rot.
and stimulates new root formation faster.
Then rinse with water.
Take 2 liters of water and put it in a jar.
Then add 1 teaspoon of Baking Soda to help kill bacteria and eliminate pests.
Soak orchid roots in this water for 10 minutes.
Then use dry moss to grow orchids.
After soaking for 10 minutes, take the orchid out and plant it.
When planting dry, sterilized moss, it will help absorb moisture from the roots.
This helps the cut heal quickly and the rot does not spread further.
Then place in a cool place and do not water for 1 week.
After 1 week, start watering the orchid once a week.
Soak in water for 10 minutes to keep the moss moist.
Then take it out and cover it with a transparent plastic box.
And remember to water it every week to keep it moist.
1 MONTH LATER.
The orchid has revived and grown healthy roots.
But it seems like the leaves are a bit wilted.
Once the root system is strong, you need to add more nutrients to help the orchid grow quickly.
Take 2 liters of water.
and add 5 teaspoons of rice.
Rice contains a variety of minerals and amino acids that are important for orchid growth.
Then use this rice water to water the orchids once a week..
In addition to providing necessary nutrients,
rice water also creates a favorable environment for beneficial microorganisms to grow in orchid pots.
Soak for 10 minutes then take out the orchid pot.
Regularly spray mist to keep the soil moist when the growing medium is dry.
2 MONTHS LATER.
From an orchid with leaf rot causing the leaves to turn completely yellow, it has now grown healthily.
Strong roots, fresh green leaves.
If you find the video interesting, please like and share so more people know.
and subscribe to my support channel.
My videos have subtitles in many different languages,
please choose the appropriate language to clearly understand the content I share.