Welcome to Happiness Garden channel
In this video, I share how to grow it to grow fast
When I just bought orchids,
We remove all this moss,
Because these orchid pots are grown in an industrial environment,
controlled by temperature, humidity, and light Ideal for orchids.
but when brought back, the environment has been changed, making these roots easy to rot
You should cut off the damaged roots.
Then wash the roots.
Use used plastic bottles
I recycle to grow semi-hydroponic orchids
This way of growing will not need watering
but still help the orchid grow very strong,
the flowers are more beautiful and brilliant, invite you to watch.
I need to wash the plastic bottle to make sure it's clean from fungi,
and bacteria that are harmful to the orchid.
Using the drill bit will cut out the positions here
This part will be used as an orchid pot
The rest is for water storage
Using a glass jar on the bottom will help the roots not absorb too much water.
Put the orchid in
Put terracotta seeds around the pot
grown in a semi-hydroponic environment, often in contact with water
so we use breathable terracotta beads is the best
If it's breathable, it's very rarely rotten
And after planting, the roots will grow very fast
I finished planting
you water the potted plants,
We only water once, next time you don't need to water anymore
With this simple planting method, you save a lot of time to take care of
With this planting method, you will let the water level cover part of the bottom of the pot
The water will absorb itself, helping to maintain the moisture in the growing medium,
we will not need to water anymore.
When the water in the container is empty, remember to add more water to keep the growing medium in a moist state
This is an orchid, I planted it according to this method, it is growing very fast now
The flowers are long-lasting and have many branches on the same branch.
This orchid I grow semi-hydroponic with pine bark
Flowers bloom brilliantly, boldly, and last longer
growing semi-hydroponic orchids, the moisture is always well maintained,
the roots will grow very quickly
It will help plants perform metabolism, absorb organic fertilizer and water very well.
With this simple planting method, we will get orchids that grow faster.
Hope the video will help you a lot.
Next, I share an organic fertilizer that every home has to restore wilted and weak orchids.
Subscribe to the channel so you don't miss any orchid care tips on my channel.
If not restored, the orchid will die or will never bloom.
First you need to cut off all damaged roots.
and cut dried flower stems.
Fix the orchid so that it will not damage the roots when it roots later.
Then take 5 spoons of rice.
Add 2 liters of water at room temperature.
Wait 30 minutes before using.
then take 2 spoons of milk.
Add 1 liter of water at room temperature.
Then thoroughly wipe the top and bottom of the leaf.
This helps remove dirt, fungus and disease-causing bacteria on orchids.
At the same time, adding nutrients through the leaves helps the orchid recover quickly
after 30 minutes.
Mix milk solution with rice water as fertilizer.
Adding moss helps retain moisture better.
From now on, water your orchids with this liquid fertilizer once a week.
Should be done in the morning before the sun is hot.
On normal days, the substrate is dry, just watering to keep it moist is enough.
Place the orchid pot in a cool, well-lit place and the plant will recover faster and the plant will be healthy.
1 Month Later
The orchid has developed many new roots.
Many branched roots develop to help absorb nutrients and water better.
Hopefully the video will help you a lot in taking better care of orchids at home.
Thank you for watching the video. Good luck and see you in the next videos.