Hello friends.
In order for Phalaenopsis orchids to grow and produce many flowers, you need to note the following:
Phalaenopsis orchids like temperatures from 20-30 degrees Celsius.
The best place to place the orchid pot is on the windowsill or under the sun filter for the orchid.
If the temperature is below 20 degrees Celsius, you can place the orchid pot in direct sunlight.
Phalaenopsis orchid with its beautiful,
and noble beauty is one of the favorite and popular indoor flowers.
Its beauty is the pride of anyone,
especially because of its ability to produce many flowers and long-lasting flowers.
This is corn kernels.
it can be used as a natural fertilizer for orchids.
Take a small handful and put it in a jar.
Soak in 1 liter of warm water for 2 hours.
2 HOURS AFTER.
put it all in a blender.
Add 1 ripe chili to add vitamins and potassium.
puree.
filter out residue.
Add water to get 3 liters of liquid fertilizer made from corn kernels.
Add 30ml of beer
We now have synthetic fertilizers from ingredients including corn, peppers and beer.
Use:
Spray on leaves and roots once every 2 weeks.
Helps to supplement nutrition through leaves very well.
it is a great organic foliar fertilizer.
After applying this method for 2 weeks you will see green orchids.
At this time, you need to take care of the roots for the plant to grow.
you water this liquid fertilizer at the root.
Corn contains many nutrients such as potassium (potassium), phosphorus (phosphorus), nitrogen (nitrogen),
and important minerals, helping to provide adequate nutrients for orchids.
Corn kernels help stimulate the growth of orchid roots,
helping them to absorb water and nutrients from the soil.
Corn contains gibberellic acid, a natural growth hormone,
which helps stimulate orchids to grow quickly and vigorously.
View results.
after 3 weeks fertilizing from corn, chili and beer.
Orchids grow very well.
This helps the orchid to absorb nutrients best.
With this method, even weak orchids can easily take root very quickly.
You can also combine with other organic fertilizers that I have shared so that the fertilizer is evenly distributed.
Thanks to the supply of nutrients and growth stimulation from corn,
orchids will have a stronger ability to bloom and set fruit,
produce more beautiful flowers and increase fertility.
Orchids can be kept on branches for up to 6 months.
and bloom continuously from batch to batch.