Welcome to my channel
When orchids are old and have poor resistance, we need to rejuvenate them.
First you need to cut off all damaged leaves and roots.
Keep only fresh roots.
Onions have very good antiseptic and growth stimulating effects
Take about 20 grams of thinly sliced ​​onion.
Take 1 teaspoon of baking soda.
Helps balance PH levels and eliminate fungal diseases harmful to orchids
Add 2 liters of water at room temperature.
Wait 30 minutes before using
After 30 minutes, filter to remove residue
Then water the orchid with onion water and baking soda
Soak in this water for 30 minutes
Cover the pot with a layer of dry moss
Place the dried moss in this transparent plastic box
Leave in a cool place for 1 day without watering
1 Day later
From now on, water your orchids once a week
Or water when the moss is dry
Be careful to keep the moss moist. If the moss is waterlogged, the orchid will easily rot.
Then place it in a cool place with enough light for the orchid to grow
3 Weeks Later
Many baby orchids have sprouted
Take 2 liters of water at room temperature
Then add 5 spoons of rice
Water the orchid with rice water once a week
Helps stimulate baby orchids to grow and take root quickly
Continue to place in a cool, well-lit place for the orchid to grow
After the next 1 month
The baby orchids grow very healthy.
Hopefully the video will help you a lot in taking care of orchids at home
If you find it interesting, please click like and share so more people know
And don't forget to subscribe to the channel to help your channel reach 1 million subscriptions soon
Thank you for watching the video. Good luck and see you in the next videos.