Welcome to my channel.
If you are an orchid grower, when you eat an apple, don't throw away the peel.
Today I will show you how to recycle eggshells into organic fertilizers to help spread more flowers.
Just peel an apple like this and put all the peels in a jar
add 1 small aloe leaf
Add 1 liter of boiling water
Cover and leave in a cool place for 12 hours to allow the apple and aloe vera to ferment naturally.
and it will make special organic fertilizer for orchids
Peel off the protective film of the sleeping sprouts
12 hours after soaking in boiled water
filter out residue
Use cotton to soak this water
then clamp the sprout to sleep to wake up the sprout
Do this once a week
when the flower has faded and the flower top has ceased to bloom,
I also put flowers here to spread new flowers
I put a cotton pad soaked in apple juice + aloe vera in between the leaves
When the cotton is dry, on normal days, you just need to mist with water to keep the orchid moist.
Next, I use this water to water my orchid once a week
Apple peel contains a lot of Vitamin A,
vitamin C and rich in Potassium, Calcium, Phosphorus
When you do this, it makes it easier for the nutrients to be absorbed.
Please moisten before watering, the effect will be higher
45 days after use
lots of new flowers are growing
This will help your orchid to continuously bloom again and again
If you regularly fertilize your orchids with specialized fertilizers,
your orchid will bloom all four seasons of the year.
Withered flowers also grow new flowers after 45 days thanks to recycled apple peel + aloe
In the middle of the leaves also sprout new flowers after 45 days of use
New roots also begin to grow after 45 days of use
And with this simple way, the regenerated flower branch will be very big and fat
Don't forget to like, share, subscribe to the Channel and press
bell for easy tracking
Good bye and see you again. Good luck