Welcome to my channel
There are different ways to care for orchids at home,
Today I share a new method for you to have more choices.
This is an aloe plant
Use 1 aloe leaf
Add 1 liter of water at room temperature
Leave in the dark for 1 day
AFTER 1 DAY
You will get red aloe vera juice like this
Use cotton balls
Clean the top and bottom of the orchid leaves
Water soaked in aloe vera leaves has many uses
Widely used in cosmetic, hair and skin industries
For plants, aloe vera helps kill fungi and bacteria that cause rot very quickly
Because in aloe vera contains a high content of natural antibiotics
it's many times better than garlic and antibiotics
Pay attention to thoroughly wipe the underside of the leaves because this place contains many fungi, bacteria and insects
Clean the surface of leaves with aloe vera juice every 2 weeks
Helps open stomata on orchid leaves
and kill fungi, bacteria, insects
Watering aloe vera on the entire root and growing medium
Water it like this once a month
Aloe vera juice is also a rich source of nutrients for orchids
because aloe vera contains 75 kinds of nutrients including: 20 kinds of minerals, 12 kinds of vitamins, enzymes and antioxidants,
This will stimulate the orchid to sprout and take root very quickly
If you do it regularly, orchid leaves will always be green
If the orchid is healthy, the flowers will also bloom
flowers also last a long time
Each year will bloom from 2 to 3 times depending on the orchid variety and the growth of the orchid
The flower color is also more beautiful
flower buds won't fall
Hope the video content will help you in taking better care of orchids at home
If you find it interesting, please like, share and subscribe to the channel so that the channel will soon reach 10,000,000 subscribers
Welcome to part 2 of the video
Orchids are plants with very strong survival ability.
Like this orchid, you can see it has withered.
Today I will show you how to restore this withered orchid with garlic and turmeric.
First, cut off all damaged roots.
Use 1 clove of garlic.
add 10g fresh turmeric.
Squeeze garlic and turmeric juice.
Soak the garlic and turmeric juice on the sponge
Put this water in places where orchids can germinate
WAIT 30 MINUTES for this water to soak into the orchid
AFTER 30 MINUTES,
Plant with moss to keep moisture well.
Put it in a cool place
Every 5 days misting to moisturize 1 time with normal water
AFTER 3 WEEKS
Has grown 1 seedling
AFTER 2 MONTHS
I replanted with pine bark and pumice stone so that the roots of the orchid can be ventilated.
Planting like this will be less rotten.
Add some moss on top for better moisturizing.
Water once every 7 days in combination with organic fertilizer as I shared on the channel for orchids to thrive.
Hope this sharing content will help you in recovering orchids.
Welcome to part 3 of the video
There are many types of fertilizers that help orchids thrive.
Today I share an organic fertilizer that is recycled from potatoes.
It is a very simple but very effective fertilizer for orchids.
Because in potatoes, especially in potato sprouts, there is Auxin which is a natural growth hormone.
It helps plants grow strong
and grow many flowers quickly.
As you can see, my orchid has produced a lot of flower buds with this fertilizer.
and the leaves are big and sturdy.
Flowers bloom for a long time.
Don't throw away the potato skins.
I use the peel of a potato
Use the peel of 1 potato.
Garlic has antiseptic properties to help eliminate fungus for orchids.
And potatoes contain a lot of starch that helps beneficial microorganisms grow and protect the orchid's roots.
Add 1 liter of boiling water.
HOLD FOR 24 HOURS.
AFTER 24 HOURS.
Water this water on the orchid growing medium.
Apply 1-2 times a month.
And fertilize alternately with other organic fertilizers for healthy growth and balance of nutrients.
Potatoes, garlic contain many minerals such as potassium, phosphorus, calcium,
and magnesium, which naturally help orchids absorb easily.
This method is very simple but has provided all the necessary nutrients for orchids.
Try this method and feel the results after 3 uses.
I believe you will be surprised at its effectiveness.
Hope this simple way will help you take better care of your orchid at home.
Please subscribe to the channel so that the channel will soon reach 1,000,000 subscribers.
Good luck to all.