Welcome to my channel!
If you have a wilted orchid like this
Don't rush to throw it away
Now I share how to recover quickly with natural fertilizers
Please remove inorganic fertilizers and damaged roots
Because the roots do not rot, I keep the old planting material to help the orchid recover quickly
and remove all yellow and rotten leaves
Which country are you watching videos from? Please comment for me!
It's great that we can chat together from all over the world.
If you haven't subscribed yet, please subscribe to support me and to not miss any orchid growing tips!
Now you need to soak the entire orchid in water at room temperature for 1 hour.
This helps to quickly restore wilted roots and leaves
Awaken the ability of fresh roots and leaves to absorb water
Place in a cool place for 1 hour
Now you take 1/3 teaspoon of sugar
Mix with 500ml of water at room temperature
Then take 500ml of warm water
Add 1 teaspoon of dry yeast (yeast used to make bread)
Wait 1 hour for the yeast to develop before using it as fertilizer
After soaking for 1 hour, take the orchid out
Then soak the leaves in sugar water for 30 minutes
After soaking for 30 minutes, take the orchid out
Nutrients in sugar penetrate the leaves, helping wilted leaves recover quickly
Now mix the sugar water with the dry yeast solution
This will create a natural fertilizer that will stimulate strong rooting and plant recovery.
Soak the orchid root in this water for 30 minutes
will help stimulate rooting extremely quickly
The remaining liquid fertilizer is used to water orchid pots
Water each orchid pot with 10 tablespoons
This fertilizer helps stimulate root growth
A strong root system will help the orchid absorb nutrients best
Doing this 1-2 times/month will be very good for the orchid
Water the orchid roots with this microbial fertilizer solution.
Beneficial microorganisms will grow in the orchid pot.
Helps protect orchid roots from rot caused by fungi and bacteria.
This type of fertilizer also helps balance the PH level in orchid pots.
Helps stimulate orchid roots to grow and not be damaged by acid.
After soaking for 30 minutes, take the orchid out
The roots have become juicier and greener
I use pine bark to grow orchids
Cover the surface of the orchid pot with a little moss
Helps retain moisture better
Then apply this microbial fertilizer to the orchids every 2 weeks
will create beneficial organisms in the growing environment and stimulate orchid roots
On weekdays, you just need to spray mist to keep it moist and water when the substrate is dry
Then place the orchid pot in a cool place with enough light for the orchid to recover
Results after 1 month
After only 1 month orchid roots have grown a lot and are healthy
These new roots will help the orchid absorb nutrients and water best
and gradually the leaves will become fresh again
Take 1/5 teaspoon of sugar
and Take 1/5 teaspoon of dry yeast
Mix with 300ml warm water
and wait until the water cools to room temperature
Then use this microbial fertilizer to water every 2 weeks
This type of fertilizer is especially good for weak, stunted orchids with underdeveloped roots.
because it does not shock weak orchids like chemical fertilizers.
Placing it in a place with light sunlight will be best for orchids.
after the next 1 month
The orchid has completely recovered
The leaves are normal green and thick
The roots are very fat and have many new roots
Hope the video will help you a lot
If you find it interesting, please like, share and subscribe to my support channel
Thank you for watching
Good luck and see you in the next videos