welcome to my
channel if you have a wilted Orchid like
this don't rush to throw it
[Music]
away um now I share how to recover
quickly with natural
[Music]
fertilizers please remove inor organic
fertilizers and damaged
[Music]
Roots because the roots do not rot I
keep the old planting material to help
the Orchid recover
[Music]
quickly and remove all yellow and rotten
leaves
[Music]
which country are you watching videos
from please comment for
[Music]
me uh it's great that we can chat
together from all over the world
[Music]
if you haven't subscribed yet please
subscribe to support me and to not miss
any Orchid growing tips
[Music]
now you need to soak the entire orchid
in water at room temperature for 1
hour this helps to quickly restore
wilted roots and
leaves awaken the ability of fresh roots
and leaves to absorb
[Music]
water place in a cool place for 1 hour
now you take 1/3 teaspoon of sugar
[Music]
mix with 500 mm of water at room
temperature then take 500 milon of warm
water
[Music]
add 1 teaspoon of dry yeast yeast used
to make bread
[Music]
wait 1 hour for the yeast to develop
before using it as
fertilizer after soaking for 1 hour take
the Orchid out
[Music]
then soak the leaves in sugar water for
30 minutes
[Music]
no
after soaking for 30 minutes take the
Orchid
[Music]
out nutrients and sugar penetrate the
leaves helping wilted leaves recover
quickly
[Music]
now mix the sugar water with the dry
yeast
[Music]
solution uh this will create a natural
fertilizer that will stimulate strong
rooting and plant recovery
[Music]
soak the Orchid root in this water for
30 minutes will help stimulate rooting
extremely quickly
[Music]
the remaining liquid fertilizer is used
to water Orchid
[Music]
pots water each Orchid pot with 10
tablespoons
[Music]
this fertilizer helps stimulate root
growth a strong root system will help
the Orchid absorb nutrients
[Music]
best doing this one to two times a month
will be very good for the Orchid
[Music]
wa
water the Orchid roots with this
microbial fertilizer solution beneficial
microorganisms will grow in the Orchid
pot helps protect Orchid roots from rot
caused by fungi and bacteria
[Music]
this type of fertilzer also helps
balance the pH level in Orchid pots help
stimulate Orchid roots to grow and not
be damaged by
[Music]
acid after soaking for 30 minutes take
the Orchid out
[Music]
The Roots have become juicier and
Greener I use pine bark to grow orchids
[Music]
cover the surface of the Orchid pot with
a little Moss helps retain moisture
better
[Music]
then apply this microbial fertilizer to
the orchids every 2
weeks uh will create beneficial
organisms in the growing environment and
stimulate Orchid roots
uh on weekday you just need to spray
mist to keep it moist and water when the
substrate is
[Music]
dry then place the Orchid pot in a cool
place with enough light for the orcan to
recover
[Music]
results after 1
month after only one month Orchid Roots
have grown a lot and are
[Music]
healthy um these new Roots will help the
Orchid absorb nutrients and water best
[Music]
and gradually the leaves will become
fresh again
[Music]
take 1/5 teaspoon of sugar
[Applause]
[Music]
and take 1/5 teaspoon of dry
yeast mix with 300 mm warm water
[Music]
and wait until the water cools to room
temperature then use this microbial
fertilizer to water every 2
[Music]
weeks this type of fertilizer is
especially good for weak stunted Orchids
with underdeveloped Roots because it
does not Shock weak orchids like
chemical
[Music]
fertilizers um placing it in a place
with light sunlight will be best for
[Music]
orchids after the next 1 month
um the orchid has completely recovered
[Music]
the leaves are normal green and
thick the roots are very fat and have
many new roots
[Music]
hope the video will help you a
lot if you find it interesting please
like share and subscribe to my support
Channel thank you for
watching good luck and see you in the
next
videos Hello
friends in my hand is a withered
dendrobium Orchid and in this video I
will share how you can propagate any
dendrobium
Orchid we cut off the spots that have
bloomed
[Music]
only keep these three parts for
propagation because they still have
dormant buds at the
nodes drip melted wax onto the cut to
protect it from absorbing water
preventing the cut from rotting
which country are you watching this
video from please leave a comment for
me it's amazing that we can chat with
each other from all around the world
[Music]
peel off the protective film of the
sleeping sprout
[Music]
use one sprig of chopped fresh
ginger if you haven't subscribed to the
channel yet click the Subscribe button
to support me
[Music]
500 M of boiled
water wait one
[Music]
day so orchids in ginger water for 30
minutes soak moss in ginger water for 30
minutes
[Music]
I use recycled plastic boxes to make
miniature green houses to help propagate
orchids
[Music]
faster there's a vent here
put the Orchid in a miniature greenhouse
and spray it with moisture once a
[Music]
week uh place in a bright place and
avoid direct sunlight
21 days after
[Music]
continue misting to keep moisture and
keep in a light place avoid direct
[Music]
sunlight after 10 next day
continue misting to keep moisture and
keep in a light place avoid direct
sunlight after two next weeks
[Music]
I hope this video will be very helpful
for you in taking care of orchids at
home
[Music]
plant in pots to let the Orchid adapt
and grow in the outside environment
[Music]
if you find it interesting please
subscribe to the channel like share to
let more people
[Music]
know my videos have subtitles in
different languages please select the
appropriate language to understand the
video content
[Music]
clearly remember to plant the root
higher than the pot so that the Orchid
does not have root
rot that's all I want to share with you
in this
video now goodbye and see you in the
next videos