welcome to my channel.
if you have a rotten orchid like this.
If not treated promptly, rot will spread to other trees very quickly.
This root is rotten so it should be thrown away.
This leaf is still fresh so it can be restored.
Remove all rotten leaves.
Please comment to me which country you are watching the video from!
It's great that we can chat together from all over the world!
then rinse with water.
This helps the tree recover faster.
And this method will remove dirt and insects still attached to these leaves.
helps orchids, even though they only have one leaf, can revive faster and easier.
Cutting extra to avoid crushing the stem will help prevent the orchid from rotting further.
If you haven't subscribed to the channel yet, please subscribe to support me and not miss any orchid care tips!
I use coffee as a natural fertilizer to help orchids recover quickly.
Take 1 teaspoon.
Add 2 cups of boiling water.
If you encounter any difficulties during the orchid growing process, don't hesitate to comment!
I am always ready to support you so you can grow healthy orchids and bloom lots of flowers. 🌸
Wait until it cools before using it as fertilizer.
After cooling, filter to remove residue.
Coffee will be very good and help orchids grow very quickly.
In addition to the US English language, I have added voiceovers in French, German, Italian, Spanish,
Portuguese, Japanese, Hindi, and Indonesian to help you hear and understand the video content easier.
Please click on the settings on the video to select the appropriate language.
Use soft cotton pads. Wipe the leaves again and add nutrients through the leaves
and eliminate insects and fungi. Helps orchid leaves recover. Will not be infected with insects and fungi.
Put the leaves here and then add this coffee water.
Leave for about 30 minutes to help the plant regenerate roots very quickly.
and use the remaining coffee water put in spray bottle.
Spraying directly on the orchid will help the orchid grow quickly.
And remember to spray under the leaves to prevent insect growth.
You should apply this method every 2 weeks.
Or water orchid roots every 2 weeks.
This is a great way to provide nutrients to orchids through the roots.
You can see that orchids cared for by this method have very healthy roots.
A strong root system will help the orchid absorb the most nutrients.
When absorbing enough nutrients, the plant will always be healthy and bloom many flowers.
The flower color is bright and stays on the branch for a long time before fading.
The mineral and nitrogen content in coffee helps leaves stay green and strong.
Potassium in coffee helps flower buds not fall off before blooming.
After 30 minutes, take the leaves out and wipe dry.
Use 1 clove of garlic, garlic has very good antibacterial and antiseptic properties.
Because garlic has good antibacterial properties, it is very effective in preventing orchid rot.
Then leave it in a cool, dry place for 1 day so that the cut will dry and the orchid leaves will recover quickly.
Then take advantage of recycled plastic boxes into orchid growing tools.
Please cut like I do.
Take a cotton pad and place it here.
Cotton will help absorb water better.
Put the leaf in.
Then pour in filtered water.
Adjust the water level so that it does not touch the base of the plant.
And remember to add water when you feel like you're running out of water.
Cover and place in a cool, well-lit place.
With this method, you will not need to spray mist to keep the leaves moist.
And this is the result after the next month the orchid has recovered and grown healthy roots.
The orchid has grown a new leaf.
With these methods you need to be patient, because with orchids there will always
be fast plants and slow plants, so when implementing these methods we need to be persistent.
and the roots have grown very well.
I planted it in a new pot so the orchids could grow in the outside environment.
Planting with pine bark will help the roots always breathe so the orchid will not rot.
I always share many ways for you to easily choose
What are the most suitable and simplest ways?
Add a little moss to the surface of the orchid pot to help retain moisture better.
After planting, water and keep the orchids moist.
I have created many subtitles for you to view and choose from
Which subtitle is suitable?
Hope it will always help you a lot,
Don't forget to like, share and subscribe to the Channel
And press the bell to conveniently follow.
Thank you for watching.
Goodbye and see you again. Wish you always success!!!