Welcome to my channel
In my hand is a withered orchid
and I will revive it with compost
The roots are dry
Cut off all damaged roots
Removing damaged roots helps prevent healthy roots from rotting further
and stimulates new roots to grow
Cut off withered branches
Rinse with water
Soak in this water for 1 hour
Take 1 aloe vera leaf and cut it into small pieces
Aloe vera contains nutrients such as vitamins, minerals, enzymes and amino acids
helps improve root and plant growth,
thereby helping orchids better absorb nutrients from the soil.
Put aloe vera in the jar
Add 500ml of room temperature water
Stir well and wait 1 hour
1 Hour later
Thoroughly wash the back and front of the leaves
Helps remove dirt, mold, and insects on leaf surfaces
will help orchids recover faster
Then put the orchid leaves in the jar
Then pour in aloe vera water and soak for 30 minutes
Aloe vera gel contains many vitamins and also has a good moisturizing effect,
helping wilted orchids quickly recover.
Next I need oatmeal
Take 3 tablespoons of oatmeal
then add 500ml of water
Then stir well and wait 30 minutes for the nutrients to completely dissolve in the water
After soaking for 30 minutes, filter the oatmeal water
Oats contain essential nutrients for plants such as vitamins,
minerals (such as magnesium, iron, zinc), carbohydrates and proteins,
Helps plants grow strongly and improves overall root health.
After soaking for 30 minutes, take the orchid out
Mix aloe vera juice with oatmeal water
Then soak the orchid roots in this water for 30 minutes
will help restore roots and stimulate faster rooting
After soaking the roots for about 30 minutes, take the orchid out and plant it in a new pot
I grow orchids with moss which helps retain moisture better
Because moss retains moisture well, you need to be careful not to water it too much.
Only water when the growing medium is dry
If the growing medium is waterlogged for a long time, the roots will rot quickly
Filter this water
Then water the orchid every 10 days
The carbohydrate components in oats stimulate root growth,
Helps orchid roots grow longer and healthier,
so the plant can absorb water and nutrients from the soil better.
Aloe vera has the ability to stimulate root growth,
especially for plants that are wilted or show signs of weakness.
This helps the orchid regrow healthy roots and improve vitality.
It would be better if you soak the roots in this water for about 30 minutes and then take them out.
On weekdays, you spray the leaves with moisturizing water
Or when the substrate is dry, spray water to keep the substrate moist
Then place the orchid pot in a cool place with enough light for the plant to recover
Remember, no amount of fertilizer will help your orchids if they are not receiving enough diffused light, at least 12 hours a day.
Results after 45 days
Leaves are fresher
New roots grow a lot
When the roots grow, they will easily absorb water and nutrients to nourish the plant
From there, the wilted leaves will quickly become fresh again
Aloe vera gel has the ability to retain water,
Helps keep soil and plant roots moist for longer periods of time.
This is very important when orchids wilt due to lack of water.
I hope my video is useful to you.
Wishing you in taking care of plants brings you joy and great results.
Hope you like this composting recipe!
Don't forget to like and share the video with your friends and family!
goodbye and see you again in the next videos