hello
[Music]
everyone how are
you for orchids to be healthy Bloom many
flowers and even bloom all year
round uh to give you more options for
making natural fertilizers to care for
orchids at home and encourage them to
bloom more today I will continue sharing
a new method of making natural
fertilizer let's get started
First Take 1 tbspoon of baking soda and
put it in a
[Music]
cup then mix it with 1 L of water
uh I don't have pets but I can help you
with any questions you might have about
caring for them do you have
[Music]
pets method one
use a soft cotton pad to soak the baking
soda solution and gently wipe the top
and bottom of the
[Music]
leaves ah baking soda has mild
antibacterial properties helping to
clean the surface of the leaves and
prevent the growth of SP eye and
[Music]
bacteria baking soda helps prevent some
common fungal diseases in orchids such
as powdery mildew
[Music]
the baking soda solution helps remove
dirt and residue making the leaves shiny
and improving photosynthesis
the baking soda solution helps remove
dirt and residue making the leaves shiny
and improving
[Music]
photosynthesis apply this method 1 to
two times a month to protect the orchid
leaves and keep them green and
[Music]
shiny method two
next take two ochre
[Music]
pods add 300 M of water
then blend it until
[Music]
smooth okra contains many vitamins and
natural minerals that help provide
nutrients for orchids
the nutrients in Okra support the
photosynthesis process and the growth of
the
plant then strain out the residue
mix it with 1 liter of
water then mix the baking soda solution
with the okra water
solution stir the solution well and you
will have great liquid fertilizer for
your
orchids now use this water to water each
Orchid pot
[Music]
okra contains many vitamins minerals and
natural growth hormones that help
provide energy for the
[Music]
plant baking soda has mild antibacterial
and antifungal properties helping to
prevent diseases in
uh baking soda can help adjust the pH
level of the environment creating better
conditions for nutrient
absorption the nutrients in Okra support
the photosynthesis process promoting the
growth of leaves and roots
[Music]
the okra solution provides the necessary
moisture for the plant helping to
maintain its freshness
by combining these two solutions you can
take advantage of the nutritional
benefits of okra and the protective
properties of baking
soda soaking in this water for about 20
minutes will be beneficial for your
orchid
method
three if you have many Orchid pots you
can choose to spray with a spray bottle
spray the entire orchid
[Music]
plant spray both the top and bottom of
the leaves
helps remove mold insects and dirt from
the
leaves baking soda helps clean the
residual industrial salt on the leaves
when purchased keeping the leaves green
and shiny
and this is similar to using foler
fertilizer for
orchids perform one to two times a month
to supplement nutrients for the orchids
[Music]
after soaking for 20 minutes take the
Orchid pot and place it in a location
with plenty of indirect light for the
Orchid to photosynthesize
[Music]
result this combination helps orchids
grow healthier thereby increasing their
ability to bloom making the flowers
larger and more beautiful
[Music]
when you combine okra and baking soda
you not only provide nutrients but also
protect the plant from diseases creating
an optimal environment for
[Music]
growth remember fertilizer is is great
but if the Orchid lacks light it will
become weak and grow slowly therefore
you need to place the Orchid pot in a
location with plenty of indirect light
for strong
[Music]
growth the photosynthesis process will
help the orchid's metabolism function
properly
[Music]
take care of your orchid with all the
love you have for plants and flowers and
it will surely Bloom throughout your
garden
[Music]
hope you enjoy the
video if you liked it don't forget to
like and share so more people can see
it and if you haven't subscribed yet
please subscribe to support my channel
[Music]
thank you for watching I always pray
that God blesses everyone wishing
everyone good luck and success in life