Welcome to my channel.
In this video, I share an easy method for propagating Phalaenopsis orchids from cuttings.
when the last flowers are no longer on the branches.
This is a very suitable time for us to propagate orchids
Please choose the parts that contain small sprouts.
When the branches are fresh and have a lot of resin inside, propagation will be faster.
Use cinnamon powder sprinkled on cuts to help disinfect and prevent rot.
then wait a day for the cut to dry completely.
And sprinkle cinnamon powder here to help prevent stem rot.
Take 1 clove of garlic and cut it into thin slices.
Then pour in 600ml of water.
I took 3 spoons of rice.
Wait 30 minutes for the nutrients to completely dissolve in the water.
A DAY LATER
Use flower arranging foam and fixed bar.
Filter out residue.
Then soak the orchid branches in this water for about 20 minutes to help stimulate the cuttings to germinate very quickly.
After 20 minutes, take the orchid out.
Then clamp the orchid branch to the fixed bar.
Pour water up to 2/3 of the floral foam board.
Cover with a transparent lid.
Place in a cool place and change the water weekly.
After 3 weeks.
The orchid cuttings have grown very healthy sprouts.
Put it here so it can grow further.
Continue to place in a cool place with enough light for the orchids to grow.
After the next 2 months.
Small orchids grow very healthy and have many roots.
With this simple method, you can completely propagate small orchids from branches at home.
Now I plant it in a pot so the orchid can grow and adapt to the outside environment.
If you find it interesting, please like and share so more people know this tip
and don't forget to subscribe to the channel to support me.
Thank you for watching the video.
Good luck and see you in the next videos!.