Welcome to my channel.
This orchid pot has rot disease.
and the leaves also wither.
When leaves wilt, the cause may be due to damaged roots and not absorbing enough water, leading to wilted leaves.
And you see these roots have rotted due to waterlogging.
Cut off all rotten roots.
then rinse.
Take 1 clove of garlic.
Then puree with 500ml of water.
Filter out residue.
Add water to make 2 liters of garlic water.
Step 1: Clean the leaves thoroughly with garlic water.
Garlic juice helps eliminate fungal diseases and harmful insects.
Step 2: Soak orchid roots in garlic water for 10 minutes.
Then take it out and put it in a jar.
Pour in water.
Keep the water level at this position.
Place on the windowsill or under a sunshade for orchids.
1 WEEK LATER.
Take 1 liter of water.
Take 1 spoon of rice.
Soak orchid roots in rice water for 20 minutes.
Then take it out and put it in a jar.
Pour in water.
From now on, soak orchid roots in rice water once a week.
3 weeks later.
Orchid leaves are sturdy and less likely to wilt.
New roots grow a lot, helping the orchid quickly recover withered leaves.
I continue to take 1 spoon of rice mixed with rice water to take care of the orchids.
Continue soaking orchid roots in rice water once a week.
After 20 minutes, take it out and put it in a jar.
3 MONTHS LATER.
So with this simple method, after only 3 months the orchid has recovered and grown very healthy.
Both roots, leaves and flowers grow strongly.
If you find the video good, please subscribe to my support channel.
And share so more people know this orchid care tip.
You see that this orchid has rotted and only has 1 leaf left.
The tree is very weak, the leaves are even damaged by worms.
The roots have been damaged by rot.
Therefore, it is necessary to remove all rotten stains.
Then rinse with water.
Dry wipe.
Then take 1 teaspoon of green tea.
Pour in 1 liter of boiled water.
Wait until the water cools.
Then take 3 spoons of rice.
Pour in 1 liter of water at room temperature.
and soak for 1 hour so that the flower nutrients are completely dissolved in the water.
1 Hour Later.
Filter out residue.
Clean the orchid branches with green tea.
Helps eliminate pests and diseases of orchids.
Take dry moss and put it in a jar.
Pour in green tea and steep for 30 minutes.
Soaking orchid branches for 30 minutes helps the plant quickly germinate and take root
Then take the moss out and press it tightly into the basket.
Pour water into the jar.
Control the water level in this position so that the moss always maintains appropriate humidity.
Then create a hole and plant the orchid in.
From now on, spray this rice water on the orchid branches once a week.
Cover with a transparent glass jar.
Place on the windowsill or under a sun filter for orchids.
3 Weeks Later.
The orchid has taken root.
The roots are very strong so the tree will revive very quickly.
Then plant and do not cover but let the orchids grow in the outside environment.
In this video, I continue to share how to help flower branches continue to revive and bloom after blooming.
If you find it interesting, please support me by subscribing to the channel and clicking like.
share so more people know this tip for growing orchids.
These are the branches after the flowers have faded.
But these buttons can continue to bloom if you know how to care for them.
This node has bloomed so it should be cut off.
Then sprinkle cinnamon powder on the cut to help it dry quickly and prevent disease.
Then leave it for 1 day without watering until the cut is dry.
Take 1 onion and cut it into thin slices.
Take 2 eggshells and crush them.
Egg shells contain a lot of calcium and minerals that are very beneficial for flower growth.
Add 2 liters of water and bring to a boil.
Incubate until the water cools.
After the water cools, filter to remove residue.
First step.
Water the orchid roots with onion and eggshell soaking water once a week.
Helps orchids develop roots and germinate quickly.
Step 2.
Spray this water on the leaves once a week.
Helps supplement nutrients through leaves, helping leaves stay green.
At the same time, it repels harmful insects and increases pest resistance.
STep 3.
Roll cotton onto the button to stimulate flowers.
Then spray the water soaked in onions and eggshells onto this cotton pad.
This water will help stimulate flowering very quickly.
Do it once a week.
After incubating the cotton for about 30 minutes, we take the cotton out.
Then take the orchid pot out of this water and remember to spray water on weekdays to keep the orchid pot moist.
1 MONTH LATER.
Old orchid branches continue to grow new shoots.
This helps orchids bloom many times a year.
Each batch blooms many beautiful, colorful flowers
Hope the video helps you a lot.
Thank you for watching the video. Good luck and see you in the next videos.