welcome to my channel
Today I would like to introduce to you an interesting video on how to use carrots
help orchids bloom many times a year
There are many people who are passionate about growing orchids and want them to always bloom and stay lush wherever they are.
However, sometimes you have a situation where your orchid doesn't bloom
or slow flowering.
make orchid growers feel disappointed
But don't worry, because in the video you will be shown how to help orchids bloom several times a year.
Carrots are not only a nutritious dish, but also a simple and effective solution to this problem
With just a few simple steps as shown in the video, you can stimulate flowers to bloom quickly
So watch the video and learn how to use the carrot tool to
help your orchid bloom instantly and bloom many times a year.
Use the peel of 1 carrot,
add 10 grams of fresh ginger,
add 1 liter of water
puree
Leave in a dark place for 6 hours
After incubation for 6 hours
filter out residue
Add water to make 4 liters of solution
now irrigate this way,
Soak orchid root in carrot juice for about 5 minutes
This will make it easier for the roots to absorb nutrients.
and repeat this once a month
Carrots contain many vitamins, amino acids and minerals such as:
protein, phosphorus and lots of potassium.
The nutrients and vitamins in carrots will help orchids grow better,
Increase the resistance and vitality of plants,
help it easily adapt to the living environment.
In addition, watering plants from carrots also helps to increase the humidity of the surrounding environment,
help orchids have better growing conditions.
The natural sugar and potassium content in carrots makes it easier for orchids to absorb
Potassium and sugar stimulate flower growth very quickly
It also helps orchids tolerate drought very well
so that the flowers don't fall
and lots of buds
As you can see this orchid has 5-6 flower branches
However, to help orchids bloom all year round, it is necessary to create suitable environmental conditions such as:
the right light, the right humidity, and the right wind
You should also not overuse the use of carrots.
because it will make the orchid have a disorder in nutrient absorption,
it will not benefit the orchids,
Best to only apply once a month
and need to combine the use of other organic fertilizers such as fish protein, soy protein
and pea protein fertilizer like the video I guide to take care of
so orchids will grow and bloom all year round
Welcome to part 2 of this video
If you have an orchid, make sure you want it to bloom for a long time.
Orchids are known for their ability to keep flowers on their branches for 3 to 6 months.
For that to happen, you need to nurture, water, and feed it well.
Now I will show you what is the best fertilizer for orchids.
If you follow us till the end of this video, you will learn how to make orchids bloom like crazy.
Now let's get started
Take a bowl and put 5 tablespoons of rice in it.
Pour in 500ml of water at room temperature.
Mix the rice well and wash the rice before cooking.
Then filter the water to wash the rice.
Use a cotton ball soaked in water to wash this rice
Then wipe on the top and bottom of the leaves
Will help clean the surface of the leaves
remove disease fungi and insects on orchids
At the same time, it provides the necessary nutrients for the orchid's growth
Repeat after 2 weeks will help the orchid stay green
Or you can also pour the rice water into a spray bottle.
Then spray evenly on the top and bottom of the leaves
This method also has the same effect as the previous method using cotton balls
Note Do not spray rice water on flowers
Now take a deep bowl in which you will place the orchid ready for watering and soaking.
Rice water is a great natural fertilizer for orchids, as it encourages the flowering of this beautiful plant.
You can soak the orchid in this rice water for about 1 hour so that the orchid roots can absorb the most nutrients.
Then, remove and repeat this treatment every 14 days.
You can also freeze rice water to water your orchids.
When needed, you just need to take a few dice.
Wait for them to defrost and reach room temperature, you can feed your orchids again.
Never place frozen blocks directly on the base of the orchid
Because orchids don't like the cold.
After only 2-3 weeks of use, the leaves will be green
New roots will grow
This will help the orchid best absorb nutrients through the roots
With enough nutrition, your orchid will flower all year round
And that will be all we have prepared for you for this video.
Welcome to part 3 of this video
When orchids have enough nutrients and a good soil environment,
The plant will grow strongly and flower more.
In this video, I share a type of fertilizer that few people know about.
Come explore with me now.
When you grow many orchids, it is inevitable that orchids will rot.
If it accidentally rots, you need to immediately cut off the rotten part.
Then isolate the rotten orchid pot from other normal orchid pots.
This helps prevent rot from spreading to normal orchids.
Then cut off all damaged roots.
This is charcoal
and grind into powder.
Then sprinkle activated charcoal powder on the newly cut wound.
Helps cuts heal faster and eliminates fungal diseases.
Because activated carbon has a very good disinfection function.
Then you sprinkle more on the orchid root.
Then place the orchid pot in a cool place and do not water for 1 week and the orchid will recover.
Next way.
Mix 3 tablespoons of activated carbon with 2 liters of water.
Then use this water to water the orchid roots.
Do this periodically every 2 weeks for normal orchids.
Helps prevent disease and improve pH in growing media.
Activated carbon also contains high levels of calcium and natural minerals that are very good for orchids.
Helps stimulate rooting.
Soak the orchid pot in this water for 20 minutes.
After 20 minutes, take out the orchid pot.
Then filter to get clear water.
Next method: Use this water to thoroughly wipe the top and bottom of the leaves
The orchid will be protected from fungi and insects.
The calcium content in activated carbon helps make leaves strong.
Do this regularly every 2 weeks and you will be as healthy as this.
Next method: You can also use this water to spray the entire orchid plant.
Helps eliminate fungi and insects on leaves very well.
and it also provides some nutrients through its leaves and roots very effectively
Now let's see the results.
Many new roots grow.
Helps orchids absorb nutrients best.
The potassium and phosphorus content in activated carbon stimulates plants to root extremely quickly.
Many flower buds grow on the same tree.
The potassium content in charcoal helps prevent flower buds from falling off
The flowers are brighter and stronger.
Surely you will be surprised with this type of fertilizer.
If you find it interesting, please like and share it with many people.
Hey everyone! If you enjoy my content, please consider subscribing to my channel to support me. Your support means the world to me! Thanks for watching