hello everyone welcome back to happiness
Garden the channel that shares
everything about taking care of orchids
and my gardening
[Music]
tips if you're looking for a simple and
natural way to care for your orchids
today I will share with you how to make
a super effective natural fertilizer
from used chamomile tea bags rice and
baking soda this trick will not only
help your plant grow from The Roots
leaves and flowers but is also very safe
and easy to do at
home if you want to know how to combine
them and how effective they are don't
miss today's video Let's explore it
together now don't forget to like And
subscribe so you don't miss my next
[Music]
videos before fertilizing you should
thoroughly water the plant and and soak
the Orchid pot in water for about 20
minutes this helps the plant absorb
water better and reduces the risk of
fertilizer
[Music]
shock uh this method also helps remove
mineral salts from the fertilizer
residues remaining in the potting
[Music]
medium residual mineral salts and
decaying organic matter are the main
causes of root rotting orchids therefore
you should do this once a month for each
Orchid
pot remember to soak for about 20
minutes to allow the roots to absorb
water and clean the
[Music]
Orchid after soaking for 20 minutes
remove the Orchid pot and then proceed
to make the natural fertilizer for
[Music]
them to create a natural fertilizer for
the orchids today I will be utilizing
used chamomile tea bags this is a simple
economical and safe way to provide
natural nutrients and promote healthy
growth for your
plants added to 1 liter of boiling
water next I add three taspo of rice a
natural fertilizer that is excellent for
orchids providing a nutrients to promote
healthy
[Music]
growth and then I cover it with a lid
and wait for the water to cool down for
optimal
use and here is baking soda I take one
teaspoon of baking
soda dissolve 1 teaspoon of baking soda
in 1 ler of water
step one use a soft cotton pad to soak
the baking soda mixture and gently wipe
the top and bottom surfaces of the
leaves uh this method helps remove
residual mineral salts dust and fungi or
bacteria from the leaves thereby
promoting the Healthy Growth of your
orchids and preventing diseases caused
by bacteria or
fungi regular cleaning will also improve
the plant's ability to absorb sunlight
and nutrients effectively
[Music]
as you can see the cotton pad has
changed from white to Brown which
indicates that there's a lot of dust and
mineral salts accumulated on the
[Music]
leaves um which country are you watching
this video from
leave a comment for me it's so wonderful
that we can connect and chat with each
other from all over the world
if you apply this method one to two
times a month for each Orchid pot you'll
protect them from harmful factors and
ensure they grow strong vibrant and
Thrive beautifully through each growth
cycle
step two pour the baking soda mixture
into a spray bottle
then spray it over the entire Orchid
especially the top side Underside and
between the leaf
crevices spraying the baking soda
mixture over the entire Orchid not only
helps remove dust residual mineral salts
and harmful agents such as fungi and
bacteria but also creates a natural
protective layer on the
leaves this enhances the plant's immune
system and promotes strong healthy
growth
and doing this once a month will be very
beneficial for your orchids helping them
stay healthy and effectively prevent
diseases
[Music]
after the water has cooled I strain the
chamomile tea and rice washing water to
create a natural fertilizer for the
orchids
[Music]
then mix the remaining baking soda
solution with this mixture
[Music]
step three water this mixture into each
Orchid pot with about 10
tablespoons watering this mixture into
each Orchid pot provides essential
natural nutrients from chamomile tea
rice washing water and baking soda it
also uh helps improve the plant's
overall health stimulates root growth
and prevents diseases caused by bacteria
and fungi this is an effective way to
maintain vibrant and Healthy Growth for
your orchids
[Music]
among them chamomile tea rich in
antioxidants and natural compounds that
strengthen the plant's immunity it
effectively kills bacteria and fungi
preventing
diseases rice washing water provides
many natural nutrients such as starch
and vitamins supporting the growth of
roots and leaves it adds beneficial
microorganisms to the potting mix
improving the plant's ability to absorb
nutrients baking soda has the ability to
kill harmful fungi and bacteria on the
leaves it reduces the risk of diseases
and improves the pH of the potting
medium allowing the plant to absorb
nutrients more effectively
apply this mixture to each of your
orchid pots one to two times a month to
protect the plants and promote Healthy
Growth step four use a soft cloth to
gently dab the remaining mixture on the
leaves Buds and leaf crevices to reduce
the risk of rot caused by damp
conditions keeping your orchids healthy
and
thriving you should perform this step
after each watering or after applying
the fertilizer mixture to the orchid
leaves to ensure the plant does not rot
and maintains Optimal Health
if you haven't subscribed yet click the
Subscribe button now so you won't miss
the latest videos from happiness Garden
next place the Orchid pot in a spot with
gentle sunlight to allow the plant to
photosynthesize effectively boosting its
metabolic processes and promoting
Healthy
[Music]
Growth uh let's take a look at the
amazing results after caring for orchids
using this natural fertilizer mixture
new roots are growing abundantly and
strong which helps the plant absorb
nutrients more effectively and thrive in
the upcoming season
[Music]
this natural fertilizer mixture not only
promotes strong root growth but also
encourages the Orchid to produce
numerous new flower stems resulting in a
stunning display of blossoms and vibrant
Vitality for every
pot for
[Music]
the flowers nurtured with this natural
fertilizer mixture will remain vibrant
and graceful transforming every Orchid
pot into a mesmerizing radiant
[Music]
Masterpiece I hope this video provides
valuable insights and helps you take
better care of your orchids right at
home thank you for taking the time to
watch this video wishing you Joy and
success in taking care of your orchids
see you in the next videos