Welcome to my channel.
This video is a useful source of information for beginners growing orchids
or having difficulty getting the orchid to bloom.
The curriculum provides the basics of how to care for orchids, including:
Light, temperature, humidity and fertilizer help orchids bloom year-round.
If you are interested in taking care of orchids, watch the video to learn more knowledge and skills.
1. Light
Orchids need enough light to grow.
Make sure they get enough sunlight or good artificial light.
You can place the orchid pot on the windowsill or under a specialized sun filter for orchids.
If left in direct sunlight, orchids can easily die.
2. Water and humidity.
Water appropriately.
Orchids usually need steady humidity, but don't keep the soil wet all the time.
Every month you water and soak the orchid pot in water once.
This helps retain moisture and wash away excess humus and fertilizer in the orchid growing medium.
On weekdays, when you see the substrate is dry, spray mist to keep the orchid pot moist.
Soak in water for about 20 minutes until the roots turn green, then take them out.
Then take out the orchid pot.
3. When orchids rot
Orchids grown in industrial gardens when first purchased are very susceptible to rot.
This orchid pot grows a lot of mold in the growing environment.
If not treated promptly, the entire tree can easily rot.
Take 2 liters of water.
Then add 1 spoon of wood ash.
Wood ash helps kill fungi and adds nutrients to help increase plant resistance
Filter to get clear water.
Then soak the orchid pot in this clear water for 10 minutes.
Wood ash helps balance the PH level in the orchid growing medium.
and stimulates root growth.
After soaking for 10 minutes, take it out.
The mold on the orchid growing medium has disappeared.
Leave for 10 days without watering to let the orchid recover on its own.
10 Days Later
The roots have recovered and grown new roots.
The leaves are green again.
Flower buds grow larger and do not fall off when young.
From now on, start watering so the orchid continues to grow.
Then plant them in pots or put them on a plate like I did.
Hopefully the video will help you take better care of orchids at home.
Thank you for watching the video. Good luck and see you in the next videos.