welcome to my channel
Today I continue to share how to quickly revive a rotten orchid like this.
All the leaves are rotten.
This flower has also dried.
The top of the flower is still fresh so I decided to leave it to propagate from this flower
Next, cut off all the damaged roots.
Although the orchid has rotted, there are still some fresh roots
Rinse with plain water
take 1 aloe leaf
add 2 cloves of germinated garlic,
If you don't have germinated garlic, you can substitute it with regular garlic,
Garlic sprouts contain very rich AUXIN content
AUXIN is a plant growth stimulant
so it will help the orchid respawn very quickly
add about 30g of aloe leaves
add 1 liter of water
puree
filter out residue
Soak orchids in this water for 20 minutes
I recycle plastic bottles as tools to revive orchids
This recycling tool will also contribute to creating a favorable environment for the orchid to revive quickly,
It also helps to reduce environmental pollution
wash
make vents
Use dry pine bark
let dry for 1 week without watering
The dry pine bark will absorb moisture to help protect the orchid from further rot
AFTER 1 WEEK
Now start watering to keep the orchid moist
Every 5 days, spray mist to keep the orchid moist
and put in a cool place to spread recovery
AFTER 3 WEEKS
Sprout has revived
and the roots are also revived
Continue periodically for 5 days misting to keep the orchid moist
Continue to keep in a cool place for the spread to recover
AFTER 2 MONTHS
Lan has revived and grown healthy
With this approach, orchids will have the right environment to grow
Steam from below always evaporates, creating the right moisture for orchids to revive and grow.
Hope this content will help you take care of orchids at home better
After only 3 months they can bloom again
If you find it interesting, please like, share and subscribe to the channel so you don't miss my next videos
Thanks for watching the video
Good luck and see you in the next videos