Hello friends when the new Orchid Withers
all its flowers this is the best time to
cut the flowers to help them Sprout faster
which country are you watching this video
from please comment below it's so great that
we can chat with each other from all around
the [Music] world uh peel off the protective film
so that the buds will germinate faster [Music]
cut back the branch with a sharp
knife so as not to crush the cut
[Music]
pour melted candle solution into the cut
to help the cut heal quickly and not rot
[Music]
sprinkle cinnamon powder on the freshly cut
wound at the base to help protect the Orchid from
rot use one large garlic clove
or two small garlic cloves
[Music]
hash small [Music]
[Music] put the garlic in the [Music]
jar pour in 500 mL of water at
room [Music] temperature wait 30
minutes for the nutrients from the
garlic to dissolve into the water
[Music]
use foam to arrange
flowers e
[Music]
uh after soaking for 30
minutes filter out the [Music]
[Music]
residue soak Orchid branches
in garlic water for 30 minutes
[Music]
30 minutes
later take
out plug in the
[Music]
sucker pour in filtered water
just enough to moist [Music]
[Music]
close the lid and wait for the Orchid Branch to
sprout after the next 3 weeks [Music]
Sprouts have woken up [Music]
[Music]
after one next [Music]
month the Orchid Sprouts have
grown and The Roots have grown
[Music]
after the next 2 months
the small orchid has grown
[Music]
[Music] healthy now let's plant the Orchid in
pots so that it can adapt to the outside [Music]
environment for
[Music]
in my hand is a withered Orchid
[Music] branch and in this video
I will share so you can propagate from any Orchid
Branch we cut off the spots that
have [Music] bloomed just keep
these three segments and the Orchid can [Music]
Sprout applying candle solution to the cut
will help protect the Orchid from rotting
[Music]
peel off the protective film of
the sleeping sprout that's [Music]
use one chopped fresh ginger [Music]
Branch boil 500 M of water
and wait one day [Music]
after one day take it out
and filter to remove [Music]
residue soak orchids in ginger
water for 30 minutes [Music]
soak the moss in ginger water for 30 minutes
[Music]
I use recycled plastic boxes
to make miniature green houses
to help propagate orchids [Music]
faster there's a vent here [Music]
[Music]
place the Orchid in a miniature greenhouse
and spray it with moisture once a [Music] week
place in a bright Place away from
direct [Music] sunlight 21 days later
[Music]
continue misting to keep it moist and keep
it in a cool well-lit place away from direct
[Music] sunlight after next 10 days [Music]
[Music]
continue misting to moisturize and leave
in a well-lit place avoiding direct
[Music]
sunlight after next 2 weeks [Music]
I
[Music]
plant in a pot so the Orchid can adapt and
grow in the outside environment [Music]
[Music]
if you find it interesting please subscribe to the
channel like and share so more people know [Music]
remember to plant the base higher than the
pot to prevent the Orchid from rotting [Music]
[Music]
when the orchid has just
lost all its flowers it is
the best time to propagate from the flower [Music]
stem buttons that have bloomed cannot be
propagated so so I cut off the
nodes that have finished [Music]
blooming uh repair the cut to
avoid crushing the flower stem
[Music]
sprinkle cinnamon powder on the cut
to help it heal quickly and prevent
rot leave for one day for
the cut to dry completely
[Music]
one day
later peel off the protective
film on the flower [Music]
button this helps baby orchids
easily [Music] germinate for
[Music]
now I use tomatoes to revive
young orchids from flower [Music]
stems Tomatoes contain many important
nutrients such as nitrogen n phosphorus
p and potassium K which are essential
factors to promote the growth of orchids
[Music]
then you tie the Tomato core to this position
to awaken the baby Orchid Sprouts to [Music]
revive this helps baby orchids
quickly revive from flower stocks
[Music]
leave for about 30 minutes for the
nutrients to penetrate into the flower stem
[Music]
after 30 minutes remove it
my [Music]
[Music] then insert the flower stem into the
sponge place in a transparent
jar and pour a little water to always have the
right humidity for the baby
orchids to revive [Music]
cover with transparent plastic
and keep in a cool [Music]
place 3 weeks later [Music]
the flower branches have begun
to revive the baby orchids
[Music] continue to put it in the vase and place
it in a cool place for the baby orchids to grow
[Music] after the next one [Music]
month baby orchids have formed from flower stems
[Music] the baby orchids also
take root at the same [Music]
time both the small Orchid and
its roots are healthy [Music]
continue to put it in the vase and place it in
a cool place for the baby orchids to [Music]
grow after the next 2 months
[Music]
uh this simple method helps baby
orchids grow very [Music] healthily
now plant them in pots so they can grow outside
[Music]
uh if you find it interesting please like share
and subscribe to the channel to support [Music]
me I have created subtitles
in many different languages
so you can choose the appropriate language
[Music]
now plant in a pot so the Orchid
can grow in an outdoor environment
if you find it interesting please subscribe
to my channel to support me don't forget to
hit the like button and share this video
so others can Discover it too every bit
of support from you motivates
me to create even better [Music]
videos thank you for watching ing the video
good luck and and see you in the next videos