Welcome to my channel.
This orchid has yellow leaf disease.
The cause is due to insects sucking tree sap and then being infected with fungi and bacteria through insect bites.
This disease leaves the leaves still succulent but falls off very quickly.
Only one healthy leaf remains. The rest are infected.
I cut here to check for disease inside the stem.
All infected leaves need to be removed.
Black spots are where the disease resides so they need to be removed.
then take 5 spoons of cement.
Mix 5 liters of water.
Then wait for the sediment to settle.
10 Minutes later.
Take only the clear water at the top.
Clean orchid branches with cement water.
Soak the orchid pot in cement water for 10 minutes
Soak the moss in cement water for 10 minutes.
Soak 10 eggshells in 2 liters of boiled water.
Wait for the water to cool.
In the meantime, I recycle plastic bottles into orchid nursery equipment.
Take 3 more Vitamin B1 tablets and mix them into eggshell water.
Soak the orchid branches in this water for 20 minutes.
20 minutes later.
Sprinkle cement powder on the cut.
Place the orchid branch in.
Pour some water into the plate.
Place in a cool place, avoid direct sunlight.
After 1 week, spray water every 5 days.
Water from eggshells and B1.
Pour some water into the bowl.
Leave in a cool place, after 1 week spray water every 5 days.
1 MONTH LATER.
Roots grow very strongly.
Now plant it in a pot so it can grow outside
Under the orchid tree, two more small orchids have grown.
Hope the video will help you a lot.
If you find the video meaningful, please share, like and subscribe to my support channel.
and invite you to continue watching part 2 of the video
To help you have many options when caring for orchids at home with organic fertilizer.
Aims to protect the environment but still help orchids grow strongly.
In this video, I continue to share new methods.
Subscribe to videos so you don't miss any Tips on my channel.
To make this compost I recycle chicken bones into fertilizer.
First, wash the chicken bones several times with water
Chicken bones are rich in potassium and calcium.
These are all very benign substances and have very good effects for the growth and development of orchids.
Using chicken bones as fertilizer will help you take care of orchids more effectively.
Wash the chicken bones and dry them crispy at low temperature.
After the chicken bones are dry and crispy, they will be ground into powder.
Take 1 tablespoon of chicken bone powder and put it in a jar.
Then soak with 2 liters of water.
Wait a day before using.
The remainder is stored for use in the next batch.
A DAY LATER.
Filter out residue.
FIRST METHOD.
Water this fertilizer solution on the orchid roots.
Chicken bones contain many minerals and organic substances that help provide nutrition for orchids.
It contains nitrogen, potassium and phosphorus which are important for orchid growth.
Potassium helps flower development and resists drought very well.
Phosphorus helps roots grow quickly. Nitrogen will help develop orchid stems and leaves.
NEXT METHOD
Spray this fertilizer on the entire orchid.
Spray the top and bottom of the leaves thoroughly
Spray seedlings to help them grow faster.
Spraying the roots will stimulate many branches.
RESULT
After 1-2 months of applying this fertilizer, many roots and branches grow.
Potassium in chicken bones helps prevent flower buds from wilting.
The flowers bloom more brightly than usual.
The flowers stay on the branches for a long time before fading.
Thank you for watching the video. Good luck
goodbye and see you again in the next videos.