Welcome to my channel
I am an orchid care specialist
Today I show you how to make organic fertilizer for orchids at home
Subscribe to the channel and watch till the end to see the magic.
5 tablets of vitamin B1
1 liter of water at room temperature
Keep in a cool place, away from direct sunlight for 1 hour
I have 5 eggshells in my hand
Eggshells contain many nutrients needed by plants,
including calcium, potassium and trace elements such as iron,
magnesium, manganese, copper and zinc.
Therefore, it will help provide the necessary nutrients for orchids,
Dry on low heat for 5 minutes
This helps to eliminate fungal diseases before using as fertilizer
When using eggshells as fertilizer,
it also helps to increase the pH of the soil, helping orchids grow better.
I use 100 grams of compost pressed from animal waste
Mix 2 types together
With the orchids that have bloomed all the last flowers
I fertilize each pot with 20-30 grams of this compound fertilizer
Orchid after full bloom is very exhausted
so I need to apply this fertilizer to quickly recover
Pay attention to fertilizing far from the root
With orchids in full bloom
This fertilizer also helps flowers bloom for a long time
If I apply this fertilizer once every 2 months,
I guarantee that the orchid will bloom for 6 months without fading
With orchids with buds
I also apply this fertilizer to help flower buds grow faster
1 HOUR AFTER
Decant the clear water above
Use this absorbent cotton
Clean the top and bottom of the leaves
Helps eliminate fungal diseases and prevent parasitic insects on leaves
At the same time, it supports the supply of nutrients through orchid leaves
Orchids are always green and growing
The rest of the water
Water this water on the orchid growing medium
Vitamin B1 helps strengthen the root system and promote plant health,
while improving the soil's ability to absorb nutrients.
Vitamin B1 has the effect of protecting plants from external agents such as drought,
sunburn, and cold, and enhances resistance to plant diseases.
You should fertilize B1 for orchids once a month in the cool afternoon
Results after 1 week
Flowers are still very fresh and fragrant than usual
These orchids will bloom all year round
This helps me to always enjoy the flowers in bloom
Only a week after using the orchid has grown a lot of new roots
So we can use these organic fertilizers to take care of orchids very well
However, keep in mind that an overdose can also harm plants,
Therefore, it is advisable to adhere to the dosage that I have instructed.
Wish you all success and happiness in life.