welcome to my channel
Rice is a popular and very effective source of organic fertilizer for crops,
and now I will show you 02 ways to make orchid fertilizer from rice.
FIRST WAY
Use 3 spoons to eat rice
puree
add 1 liter of boiled water
Close the lid and wait for it to cool
filter out residue
add 2 liters of water
Now use this water to water the orchid
Rice contains many nutrients such as potassium, fosfor, and protein, which are essential nutrients for the growth of orchids.
Using rice as fertilizer helps provide these nutrients for your orchid garden, helps plants grow healthy, enhances resistance to pests and diseases.
Rice is a food source for beneficial bacteria and microorganisms in orchid growing media
Using rice as fertilizer enhances the activity of this microflora in the orchid growing medium, thereby helping the orchid absorb nutrients better.
do this once a month
Will help orchids grow healthy
And of course it also blooms a lot
The microflora in the orchid growing medium helps to protect the roots from rot
When roots grow, they will absorb nutrients to make flowers more beautiful
so flowers bloom long
regular care in this way,
The leaves are also provided with enough nutrients, so they grow very green
SECOND WAY
When we cook, we usually wash the rice
And every time you cook rice, don't rush to throw away this rice water,
Please filter this rice water
wait for it to settle down
After settling, we filter 100ml of clear water above
add 200ml plain water
Put this rice water in a spray bottle
Use this water to spray evenly on the surface of the orchid leaves
Vitamin B1 in rice water helps stimulate the conversion of nutrients, especially harmful substances such as manganese, iron and copper into a more easily absorbed form.
Vitamin B1 helps strengthen the immune system of orchids
Helps plants resist attack by pests and other environmental agents
For the rice water that settles below
I filter out the scum
then add 2 liters of water
And I use this water to water my orchids
we also do this once a month like the first way i shared at the beginning of the video
In addition, you need to combine the use of other organic fertilizers to help the orchid receive full nutrients.
After using this fertilizer for 1 month, the orchid will produce many new roots
This helps orchids absorb the most nutrients through the roots
When absorbing enough nutrients and enough light, orchids will bloom many flowers
Flower colors are vibrant and long lasting
If you like what type of orchid you like, please comment the name of that orchid species below the video comment
Thank you for watching the video. Wishing you all the best of luck and success.