welcome to my
Channel today I will show you how to
revive a rotten Orchid like
[Music]
this when the orchid has withered all
the leaves and only the stem and Roots
do not rush to throw it away
[Music]
where are you watching the video from
please leave a comment and let me
[Music]
know it's amazing that we can chat
together from all around the
world uh here the branches are still
fresh
my video features voiceovers in six
languages English French German Spanish
Portuguese and Italian additionally I
have subtitles in various other
languages around the world for you to
choose
from I will remove all wilted and rotten
leaves
[Music]
and I remove all the broken
Roots um if you haven't subscribed to
the channel yet please hit the Subscribe
button to support
[Music]
me I keep only the fresh roots that are
left
[Music]
over I cut off the flower stock so that
the Orchid can concentrate nutrients for
the new Sprout to grow
rinse with
[Music]
water apply melted candle solution to
the cut to prevent water from seeping
into the tree
[Music]
use three cloves of garlic and
mince soaked garlic in one L of water at
room
temperature incubate for 1
[Applause]
[Music]
day at the same time spread in a cool
place for one
[Music]
day one day after
filter out
[Music]
residue soak Orchid branches in garlic
water for 20 minutes
[Music]
the rest of the water I will spray on
other orchids to help protect the Orchid
from insects and fungi at the same time
garlic juice also stimulates the
development of roots and Flower sprouts
very well
[Music]
20 minutes after
after soaking for 30 minutes
plant using pine bark or dry pmus Stone
to plant will help absorb moisture in
the roots making the Orchid roots not
[Music]
rot put in a cool place for 1 week
without watering
[Music]
one week
later from now on water the Orchid to
keep it
moist then place it in a place with
light sunlight the best temperature is
20 to 25° C
[Music]
regularly spray moisture to spread life
and revive
faster 2 weeks after
[Music]
use 3 m of GE Ginger water mixed with 1
liter of water
[Music]
um GE ginger juice is considered an
organic fertilizer that helps to
stimulate plant growth very
[Music]
well water this G Ginger every 10 days
continue to place the plant in a place
with light
sunlight uh cover with a clear vented
plastic container and wait for the plant
to
revive 1 month
later the root system is very
welldeveloped
[Music]
when the roots are strong like this you
can fertilize the Orchid with organic
fertilizer like I shared on the channel
uh to help the Orchid grow healthier
hope this sharing content will help you
in resurrecting weak orchids to grow
again hope this sharing content will
help you in resurrecting weak orchids to
grow
[Music]
again um the video I have created many
subtitles you you can choose the
appropriate language to understand my
sharing
[Music]
welcome to part two of the
video today I share with you an amazing
organic fertilizer and anyone can do it
easily
just one to two ripe bananas and the
Orchid Garden will bloom all kinds of
flowers now I will revive this Orchid
with new
[Music]
flowers um you've seen this Orchid lose
all its flowers leaving only withered
branches
and here are the withered orchids that
have been revived with lots of new
flowers step one
[Music]
cut off the
withers apply toothpaste on the cut
apply toothpaste on the cut
[Music]
don't throw away banana peels when
eating bananas
[Music]
don't throw away banana peels when
eating
[Music]
bananas clip the banana peel to to the
place where the buds can
[Music]
grow and no to remove after 6
hours this helps to create the right
moisture provide essential nutrients and
stimulate Flower sprouts
[Music]
do this once a
week step
two use a banana peel to wipe the top
and bottom of the leaves this helps
eliminate insects fungi bacteria hiding
on orchid leaves and at the same time
provides a part of nutrients through the
leaves for orchids
[Music]
this method also helps the orchid plant
to be protected and not be affected by
yellowing or rotten
[Music]
leaves after wiping you will see green
leaves orchids will photosynthesize eyes
better to increase resistance
[Music]
step
three one liter of water
[Music]
leaving a cool and dark place place for
one
[Applause]
[Music]
day after one
day banana juice is darker
[Music]
use this absorbent cotton
clip a cotton ball where the flower buds
can
grow and note to remove after 6
hours uh this helps to to create the
right moisture provide essential
nutrients and stimulate flour
Sprouts do this once a week
step
[Music]
four normally after 3 to 4 weeks flower
buds will be formed and develop like
this um with a flower Sprout this big
there's no need to sandwich banana peels
with cotton balls
[Music]
you will be surprised how amazing this
is
[Music]
don't forget to subscribe to see my next
videos
[Music]
sty add water to make 2 L water this
banana for orchids once every 2 to 3
weeks banana peel is rich in potassium
phosphorus and essential
vitamins will promote the growth of
orchid roots
in particular the potassium and banana
peel stimulates flowering very
[Music]
well in addition you need to combine
using other organic fertilizers for
orchids like manure made from soybeans
peas fish poop as I shared
[Music]
hope this sharing content will help you
in taking better care of orchids at
[Music]
home um if you find the video
interesting don't forget to like share
and subscribe to support my
channel welcome to part three of the
video in part three I share a new way to
help spread more Roots branches and
flower buds
[Music]
join me in discovering this wonderful
way to make organic
[Music]
fertilizer uh to make this type of
fertilizer you need one branch of ginger
[Music]
where are you watching the video from
please leave a comment and let me
[Music]
know it's amazing that we can chat
together from all around the world
[Music]
after slicing put into a glass
jar then add one spoon of yeast
this is the yeast used to make
bread and add one teaspoon of honey
[Music]
and 1 liter of warm
water incubate in a dark place for 1
week
[Music]
one week
later take three tblsp oons of fermented
Ginger
[Music]
solution add 1 liter of water
first
[Music]
method use cotton balls dipped in
organic fertilizer solution from
fermented Ginger
[Music]
uh then place it in the places where you
want to take root and
[Music]
Sprout after 6 hours take the cotton
out do it once a week
[Music]
method
two if you want this Branch to continue
[Music]
blooming then add cotton and clip it
after 6 hours take the cotton
[Music]
out do it once a week
method
[Music]
three um if you want this button to
continue growing flower buds
[Music]
um if you want this button to continue
growing flower
[Music]
buds this helps the buds grow faster
apply toothpaste to the
[Music]
cut this helps the cut heal quickly
then stuff cotton into the button with
this sleeping
[Music]
Bud after 6 hours take the cotton
out method four
[Music]
use a fertilizer solution from fermented
Ginger after the
[Music]
leaves helps Kelps kill fungi and
insects very well
[Music]
cleaning the stamata helps orchids
photosynthesize
[Music]
well method five
apply this liquid fertilizer to the base
of the
[Music]
Orchid this type of fertilizer helps
stimulate the growth of roots branches
and buds very
[Music]
well method
six spray the fertilizer solution from
fermented ginger on the entire orchid
[Music]
supports nutritional supplementation
through leaves very
well let's check the results
[Music]
together after 2 months the sprouts and
Roots developed very well
[Music]
the flower buds have also developed and
are ready to bloom
[Music]
the buds at the tips of the branches
continue to grow and
[Music]
Bloom Sprouts also grow in leaf axles
many branches grow on the same
tree the flowers bloom on the branches
for up to 6 months before falling
[Music]
the roots are likened to the sole of the
Orchid orchids grow healthy thanks to
healthy
Roots um if the roots are healthy the
Orchid will also grow many flower
buds in this video I will show you how
to make orchids grow roots and flower
buds
[Music]
quickly you need one fresh ginger about
g you need one fresh ginger about 50 g
[Music]
put in a jar recommended plastic
jar add three tablespoons of sugar any
sugar will
do add in 100 m of filtered
water add in 100 m of beer any beer is
fine
[Music]
cover and keep in a dark place for 1
month open the lid once every 3 days to
let the gas
[Music]
out 1 month
later uh the smell of GE Ginger is
fermented so it's very
[Music]
fragrant the ratio of mixing is 3 m of G
ginger for 1 liter of water
[Music]
first way
soak cotton balls in water mixed with
Ginger
[Music]
G Place cotton balls soaked in GE Ginger
between the leaves
helps keep moisture and GE Ginger
stimulates rooting and flow Sprout
differentiation very
quickly change this cotton once every 3
[Music]
days on normal days when the cotton is
dry you just need to mist it with water
to keep it moist
[Music]
use this water to wash the top and
bottom of the leaves helps provide
nutrients through leaves clean stamata
eliminate harmful insects and fungi and
help help Orchid photosynthesis the best
[Music]
wipe the orchid leaves with GE Ginger
once a month so that orchids are best
protected and developed
[Music]
way
three use GE Ginger water to water
[Music]
orchids uh yeast brewed from fresh
ginger has the effect of stimulating
sprouting strong rooting repelling
insects killing fungi stimulating Buds
and stimulating growth
GE Ginger also helps orchids increase
their ability to absorb nutrients from
the fertilizer you fertilize
them only do this one to two times a
month do not use too much as it will
affect the growth of
[Music]
orchids see the
results after one week of use New Roots
grow very quickly
[Music]
these roots will help the Orchid absorb
nutrients more easily and
more orchids grow well or not thanks to
the photosynthesis of roots and leaves
[Music]
when the Orchid is healthy after the
Orchid Branch blooms the last flowers
then there will be new flowers that
flowers that will continue to
[Music]
grow my video features voiceovers in six
languages English French German Spanish
Portuguese and Italian additionally I
have subtitles in various other
languages around the world for you to
choose from
[Music]
with this simple way you can do it
yourself to take care of orchids at home
at very low cost and
[Music]
convenience uh hope the video content
will help you take better care of
orchids at
home thank you for watching the video
wishing everyone good luck and an
abundance of love