Welcome to my channel
Today I share how to propagate orchids from flower stems using a new, extremely easy method
so that you have many different ways to choose from for propagating orchids.
Pry off the membrane so the sprouts can grow easily
Use about 10g of onion
Squeeze the onion juice
Wait 5 minutes for the onion juice to penetrate the orchid
AFTER 5 MINUTES
Wait for the cut to dry
Use tree bark glue (TREE SEAS)
Apply it on the cut to keep it from drying out
and helps prevent orchids from rotting.
WAIT FOR THE GLUE TO DRY
Use 1 teaspoon of cinnamon bark powder
Add 60ml boiled water
Wait for the water to cool
Soak the moss in this cinnamon water for about 20 minutes
Cinnamon juice has very good antiseptic properties
After 20 minutes soak in cinnamon water
I use recycled plastic bottles to make orchid care tools
Insert the branch and point the sprout upward
and spray regularly with moisturizing water
PUT IN A COOL LOCATION
and spray water to moisturize
AFTER 3 WEEKS
Sprouts have grown
Regularly mist to moisturize
CONTINUE INSTALLATION IN A COOL PLACE
AFTER 3 MONTHS
The small orchid has grown very well
Roots develop very well
Reuse recycled plastic bottles to grow orchids
With this planting method, orchids will grow very quickly
Because orchids always have appropriate humidity