Welcome to my channel
Surely when planting orchids, everyone wants to grow and bloom a lot of flowers
In this video I will show you how to make fertilizer for orchids at home very easily
help orchids grow and bloom non-stop
like my orchids here
especially for newbies
If you haven't subscribed to the channel yet,
please subscribe now so you don't miss any of my videos
And don't fall from the video without getting any value
Now let's get started
How to make fertilizer
This is garlic powder that has been dried and crushed
use 1 teaspoon of garlic powder
Add 1 liter of boiling water
then wait for the water to cool
After the water cools
Filter the water in the upper part
The scum below we remove
1. Clean the leaves
Use a cotton ball soaked in garlic juice to wipe the upper and lower eyes of the leaves
Garlic juice has antiseptic properties that will help get rid of the fungus
and get rid of insects like aphids, red spiders, insects
This also causes the stomata in the leaves to open
help orchids photosynthesize well
Regularly wipe, the orchid leaves will be green like this
2. Mist moisturizing
Spray on front, back and base of orchids
This is like using foliar fertilizer
Helps orchids grow and increase resistance to fungal diseases
3. Irrigate this liquid fertilizer for orchids
Water each orchid 5-6 tablespoons of this garlic-based fertilizer
Just 2 times a month combined with other organic fertilizers that I have shared
Will help orchids grow, increase disease resistance
Because orchids contain many natural vitamins and minerals such as nitrogen,
phosphorus, and potassium
When irrigated with fertilizer from garlic,
it will help orchids absorb nutrients more easily
Fertilizer from garlic is very good but should not be overused
should only be used as my guide
Now look at the orchids after being cared for with garlic water
The roots are protected, so they grow very well
a lot of new roots grow after 2 weeks of use
Many flower buds grow on the same branch
Thank you for watching the video
If you find it interesting, please click like and share so more people know
And subscribe to the channel to help my channel reach 10,000,000 subscriptions soon