welcome to my
[Music]
channel when the flowers bloom nutrition
will focus on the
bloom so after the flowers bloom the
Orchid will weaken if you don't know how
to take care of
it so in this video I continue to share
how to make organic fertilizer to help
orchids
[Music]
thrive let's get
started this is the Orchid after
[Music]
blooming the Orchid becomes weak and its
leaves
[Music]
Wilt first remove yellow leaves and
damaged roots
[Music]
this helps prevent the Orchid from
rotting further
[Music]
removing damaged Roots will help prevent
rot from spreading to healthy roots
[Music]
then cut off the wilted flower stems
then take one aloe vera
[Music]
leaf aloe vera is rich in vitamins a c e
and minerals such as calcium potassium
and magnesium which help improve plant
health and enhance photosynthesis
[Music]
apply aloe vera gel to the cut so it
doesn't rot and heals quickly because
aloe vera gel has antibacterial and
antifungal properties it helps protect
plants from diseases
[Music]
aloe vera gel helps provide moisture to
the plant helping it recover quickly
when the leaves
[Music]
wither wipe the top and bottom of the
leaf evenly
[Music]
using aloe vera gel also helps plants
reduce stress caused by changes in the
environment or care conditions uh
especially good for orchids with wil Ed
leaves like this
[Music]
plant which country are you watching
videos from please comment for me
it's great that we can chat together
from all over the
[Music]
world don't forget to subscribe and hit
like if you found the video helpful this
will help the channel grow and you won't
miss any orchid care tips
[Music]
applying this gel to the tree trunk will
help stimulate root growth in the in
this
[Music]
location doing this one to two times a
month will be very good for weak
orchids then leave it for 1 day without
watering to help the cut heal completely
[Music]
cut the remaining aloe vera leaves into
thin slices
[Music]
then put it in a
jar add 1 liter of water at room
temperature
[Music]
add 3 tasps of
rice rice especially rice water has many
effects in restoring wilted and weak
[Music]
orchids then incubate in place in a cool
place for one day to help the nutrients
completely
[Music]
dissolved one day later
stir well so that the nutrients
dissolved into the
[Music]
water then filter this water
add 1 liter of water
[Music]
add some sterilized moss on top of the
Orchid
[Music]
pot this helps Orchid pots retain
moisture better
[Music]
now water and soak the Orchid pot in
this
[Music]
water enzymes and vitamins in aloe vera
gel stimulate root growth helping the
plant absorb water and nutrients better
[Music]
aloe vera gel provides necessary
nutrients helping plants Sprout and
flour quickly
[Music]
do it twice a
month soak the Orchid pot in this water
for 20 minutes to help the Orchid Roots
absorb the best nutrients
um and when soaked like this the insects
in the Orchid growing medium will also
die or run
[Music]
away next pour this water into the spray
bottle
[Music]
then spray this water on the entire
Orchid this method is similar to fure
fertilization for ORS
[Music]
uh at the same time it also helps wash
away dirt mold and insects on the leaf
surface from there orchid leaves will
photosynthesize light better
[Music]
do it twice a
month after soaking for 20 minutes take
out the Orchid
[Music]
pot place it in a place with lots of
scattered sunlight so the Orchid can
photosynthesize and the plant can grow
[Music]
results after 50
days after only 50 days many new Roots
Grew From a weak Orchid with withered
leaves and withered roots
orchid leaves are glossier and
[Music]
Greener when the roots develop the
Orchid can easily absorb water and
nutrients
we help orchids quickly recover withered
[Music]
leaves harder and glossier your leaves
will help with better photosynthesis and
metabolism
[Music]
when healthy orchids will continue to
grow and Bloom in the next
[Music]
cycle hopefully the video will help you
a lot in taking care of orchids at home
[Music]
uh if you find it interesting please
like and share so more people know this
Orchid growing
[Music]
tip and if you haven't subscribed yet
please subscribe to my channel for
[Music]
support I always pray for blessings for
everyone on this
[Music]
Earth thank you for watching the video I
wish you a wonderful day and look
forward to seeing you in the next video