Welcome to my channel.
When the orchid has finished blooming or the plant is stunted, slow to grow and has not yet bloomed
Cut all dry branches, roots and leaves
then take 3 teaspoons
Add 2 liters of boiled water
then brew until the water cools
After the water cools, filter to remove residue
Then add water to get 5 liters of liquid organic fertilizer solution from coffee
First, use this water to thoroughly wipe the top and bottom of the leaves.
This clears dirt and removes fungus, disease and insects that damage the leaves.
Apply this method once a month
Helps leaves stay green, strong and resistant to pests
Then you use this water to water the orchid roots
This helps roots grow healthily and prevents root rot
Coffee contains many minerals necessary for the growth of orchids
Organic phosphorus and potassium found in coffee help roots and flowers develop outstandingly
Do this twice a month for your orchids so they grow and bloom profusely
Or you can also use this water to spray the entire orchid
Thoroughly spray the top and bottom of the leaves to remove dirt and insects from the leaf surface
Do this every 2 weeks.
Coffee water helps repel orchid pests very effectively
After spraying and soaking in this water for about 5 minutes, the insects will run away from the orchid pot.
Then take the orchid pot out and place it in a cool place with enough light for the orchid to grow
2 Months later
Orchids will begin to sprout and bloom profusely
Blooming flowers have bright colors
Shoe petals will stay fresh longer
The flowers bloom for up to 6 months before fading
Hopefully the video will help you a lot in taking better care of orchids at home
If you find it useful, don't forget to subscribe to the channel so you don't miss any orchid growing tips on your channel
And please like and share so more people know this orchid growing tip
My videos have subtitles in many different languages
Please choose the appropriate language to clearly understand my shared content
Thank you for watching the video. Good luck and see you in the next videos.