Welcome to my channel.
To help you have many choices when caring for orchids at home with organic fertilizer.
In this video, I continue to share new methods.
Subscribe to the video so you don't miss any tips on my channel.
No.1
To make this fertilizer you need apples.
Apples contain potassium, an important mineral for orchid growth.
Potassium helps orchids develop stronger leaves, roots and flowers.
I took the apple peel and put it in a bottle.
Soak in boiled water and leave overnight.
No. 2
To make this type of fertilizer you need more eggshells.
Soak the eggshells in boiled water and leave overnight.
After 1 night, filter the water.
So we have fertilizer from apples and eggshells.
FIRST METHOD.
Water this fertilizer solution on the orchid roots.
Eggshells provide natural calcium which is very good for orchids.
Helps orchids stay healthy and increase resistance.
Apple peels contain a lot of Phosphorus, which is also an important nutrient for orchid growth.
especially during the flowering and flower development stage.
Do this 1-2 times/month to supplement nutrition and increase the orchid's resistance.
SECOND METHOD.
Spray this fertilizer on the entire orchid.
This method is similar to using foliar fertilizer.
Calcium in eggshells helps orchids stay healthy and increases their resistance to pests.
Apples contain nitrogen, an important nutrient.
Helps orchids develop green parts and increase photosynthesis ability.
Do not spray on flowers.
Because wet flowers will easily fall off.
THIRD METHOD
Clean the leaf surface with this liquid fertilizer.
The leaf surface will always be clean and airy.
Orchids will photosynthesize better.
Fertilizing regularly 1-2 times/month will help keep the leaves healthy.
No. 3
You can reuse eggshells and apple peels to make fertilizer again.
RESULT.
This type of fertilizer stimulates rooting very quickly.
After 1 month of use you will see great results.
Many flower buds develop and do not fall.
Blooming flowers stay on the branches for a long time before fading.
Flowers can remain on branches for up to 6 months before falling.
Thank you for watching the video. Good luck and see you in the next videos!