Hello friends!
So glad you've come to my channel!
What natural methods do you usually take care of orchids?
Please share your experiences with flower lovers in the comments!
Today I continue to introduce to you a new type of organic fertilizer.
Let's start.
When orchids are damaged by insects, they cause diseases to spread from insect bites.
And insect bites damage beautiful orchids
Now I will show you how to make a fertilizer that combines insect repellent with a very easy natural method.
In my hand is an orange
I will scrape its shell
Orange peel contains very high levels of vitamin C and essential oils
This gives it excellent antibacterial properties
Will help protect orchids from pests, fungi and bacteria.
You put orange peel in the cup
Next, add 1 teaspoon of baking soda to help eliminate insects and equal the PH level in the orchid growing medium
Next you need Rice
Add 5 spoons of rice to the cup
Then add 2 liters of water
Cover and leave for 1 hour before using.
1 Hour Later
Method 1: Clean the leaves with this water.
This helps remove dust and insects from the leaves
Helps clean stomata and helps orchids photosynthesize and synthesize chlorophyll better.
Apply 1-2 times per month.
Method 2: Water this water on the orchid root.
This type of liquid fertilizer not only provides nutrients but also helps balance the PH level in the orchid growing medium
and also protects orchid roots from attacks by harmful insects and fungi.
The essential oil in orange peel is very hot, so after watering, take the orchid pot out immediately.
Fertilize your orchid twice a month with this liquid fertilizer.
Then pour this water into a spray bottle
Method 3: spray this water on the entire orchid.
Vitamin C content and essential oils in orange peel
Will help protect plants from fungus, bacteria or harmful insects.
You do not need to use chemical pesticides.
Helps protect a clean, green living environment.
Orange peel also contains a lot of calcium, potassium and some biological compounds
Necessary for growth and stimulation of orchids flowering.
You can also spray this fertilizer on your flowers to help protect them from harmful insects.
Fertilize your orchids 1-2 times a month.
Result
Orchids are protected from pests and are provided with enough nutrients so their leaves are always green.
The nutrient content in this fertilizer is abundant so the buds grow very large and strong.
Flowers bloom brightly and stay fresh for a long time
When orchids are provided with enough nutrition, the flowers will stick on the branches for a long time before fading
These orchids of mine can be kept on branches for up to 6 months before blooming.
If you want Phalaenopsis orchids to bloom for a long time, you need to place the plant in a place with a temperature of 15 - 20 degrees Celsius.
Where the temperature is 30 degrees Celsius or higher, Phalaenopsis orchids will quickly wilt
My videos have subtitles in many different languages! Please choose appropriate subtitles to clearly understand your shared content
Thank you for watching the video. Good luck and see you in the next videos!