Welcome to my channel.
These are orchids that have finished blooming. The tree becomes stunted.
If you want it to continue to grow and bloom, do as I do.
Cut off all dry and rotten branches.
This flower branch was still fresh but had fully bloomed so it was cut off.
Same with this branch.
This helps the orchid concentrate nutrients on the nodes so it can continue to bloom.
Then use toothpaste to apply to the cut.
This helps the cut heal quickly.
Next, use eggshells that are rich in calcium, potassium and organic phosphorus.
Very good for root development, flower buds and increasing pest resistance for orchids.
Then dry at low temperature for 10 minutes, helping to eliminate fungal diseases that harm orchids.
After 10 minutes, take it out and wait for the eggshell to cool.
then grind into powder.
Take 2 spoons of eggshell powder.
Add 1 liter of boiled water.
then brew until the water cools.
2 hours later, decant the clear water above.
Add 4 liters of water to get 5 liters of eggshell liquid fertilizer solution.
Step 1
Use this water to thoroughly wipe the top and bottom of the leaves.
Helps clean dirt and eliminate fungi, bacteria, and insects that are harmful to orchid leaves.
Helps leaves photosynthesize better and increase disease resistance.
Step 2
Water this liquid fertilizer for orchids 1-2 times a month.
Egg shells contain many important minerals such as calcium, potassium and magnesium,
along with other nutrients such as nitrogen, phosphorus and potassium.
These substances are necessary for the growth and health of orchids.
Adding fertilizer from eggshells helps stimulate the growth of orchids, helping them grow strong and healthy.
Step 3
Spray this liquid fertilizer on the orchid 1-2 times a month.
Minerals and nutrients from eggshells help orchids prevent attacks from harmful bacteria, fungi and insects.
This type of fertilizer stimulates flower development very well.
Result
After 2 months of fertilization, the orchid finished blooming and continued its growth cycle and grew many new flower buds.
From the cut nodes, many new flower branches grow.
Newly bloomed flowers are very healthy.
My videos have subtitles in many different languages. Please select the appropriate language.
Hopefully the video will help you a lot in taking better care of orchids at home.
If you find it interesting, click Like and share with as many people as possible.
And don't forget to subscribe to the channel so you don't miss any orchid growing tips on my channel.
Thank you for watching the video. Good luck and see you in the next videos!