welcome to my channel!
If you have an orchid with yellow leaves and weak roots, don't miss this video
First, remove all yellow leaves and damaged roots
Tell me where you come from
Let me create subtitles for your country's language so we can communicate easily
Then use small pieces of pine bark to replant this orchid.
If you haven't subscribed to the channel yet, please click the subscribe button to support me
Spread a layer of moss on the surface of the orchid pot to help retain moisture better
Take 2 tablespoons of vinegar.
Mix 4 liters of water with the vinegar.
Step 1: Clean orchid leaves with this water
Vinegar water helps remove lime deposits and dirt from the leaves,
allowing them to photosynthesize better under sunlight.
At the same time, it eliminates harmful insects that often hide on the underside of leaves,
such as red spiders, leafhoppers, aphids, and thrips.
If you don't understand, don't hesitate to comment so we can help you
Doing this 1–2 times a month will keep orchid leaves green and prevent leaf diseases.
Then take 1 teaspoon of sugar and mix it with the vinegar water.
Step 2: Water this water on the orchid roots.
Vinegar combined with sugar helps stimulate root growth very quickly and effectively.
Vinegar helps eliminate pests harmful to orchid roots, while sugar provides nutrients
and creates an environment for beneficial microorganisms to thrive around the roots.
Soak in this water for 30 minutes.
Then take it out and place it in a spot with gentle sunlight so the orchid can photosynthesize and grow well.
Use the remaining mixture to water other healthy orchids to promote their growth
and improve their resistance to pests and diseases.
Use this solution on your orchids twice a month.
1 MONTH LATER
After only 1 month, the orchid has developed many new roots
These new roots will absorb the best water and nutrients, helping the orchid grow quickly
Hopefully the video content will help you how to care for orchids at home
Thank you for watching! Wishing you good health and good luck in taking care of your orchids at home.
Welcome to part 2 of this video
Rice is a common and very effective organic fertilizer for plants.
So in this video, I will show you 2 methods to make orchid fertilizer using rice.
FIRST WAY
ake 3 tablespoons of rice.
Grind it into a fine powder..
Add 1 liter of boiling water.
Close the lid and wait for it to cool.
filter out residue.
Dilute it with 2 liters of water.
Now use this water to water the orchid
Rice contains many nutrients such as potassium, fosfor, and protein, which are essential nutrients for the growth of orchids.
Therefore, rice washing water helps the plants grow healthily and enhances their resistance to pests and diseases.
Rice washing water helps boost the activity of beneficial microorganisms in the orchid's growing medium,
thereby protecting the roots and making it easier for them to absorb nutrients.
Doing this once a month will help your orchids grow strong and healthy.
And of course, it will also bloom a lot.
The microflora in the orchid growing medium helps to protect the roots from rot
When the roots grow, they absorb nutrients that make the flowers more beautiful,
so the flowers stay in bloom for a long time before their petals wither.
Regular care in this way will ensure the leaves receive enough nutrients, allowing them to grow very green.
SECOND WAY.
When cooking rice, we usually rinse the rice. From now on, don't rush to pour this rice water down the drain.
Filter this rice washing water and let it settle.
wait for it to settle down
After it has settled, filter 100ml of the water from the top.
Dilute it with 200ml of regular water.
Put this rice water in a spray bottle
Use this water to spray evenly on the surface of the orchid leaves
Vitamin B1 in rice water helps stimulate the conversion of nutrients, especially harmful substances such as manganese, iron and copper into a more easily absorbed form.
Vitamin B1 helps strengthen the orchid's immune system,
allowing the plant to fight off pests and other environmental stressors.
For the rice water that has settled at the bottom, I filter out the residue.
then add 2 liters of water
And I use this water to water my orchids
we also do this once a month like the first way i shared at the beginning of the video
Additionally, you can combine other organic fertilizers to ensure your orchids receive all the necessary nutrients.
Thank you for watching the video. Wishing you all the best of luck and success.