Welcome to my channel.
To help you have many choices when caring for orchids at home with organic fertilizer.
In this video, I continue to share new methods.
Subscribe to the video so you don't miss any tips on my channel.
To make this compost you need 1 lemon.
Squeeze 1 teaspoon of lemon juice.
Add 3 liters of water.
Lemon juice contains citric acid which enhances the plant's absorption of certain minerals from fertilizers.
Water the orchid with organic lemon fertilizer 1-2 times a month.
Lemon juice is acidic, which helps kill fungi and insects in the orchid root system.
Lemon also contains a lot of vitamins C, E and minerals such as.
Natural nitrogen, phosphorus and potassium are good for orchid growth.
Helps balance the pH in orchid soil.
When watered with organic fertilizer from lemon, it helps increase nutrition.
Use cotton to soak lemon juice.
Then thoroughly wipe the top and bottom of the leaf.
Lemon juice is highly acidic, helping to kill fungi on orchids
At the same time, it helps eliminate insects such as aphids, aphids, and red spiders that damage orchids.
Thoroughly wipe the underside of the leaves because this is where insects and fungi often infest.
Do it every 2 weeks to protect orchids.
If you do this method regularly, the orchid will always be green like this.
Orchids will not be affected by mold and insects.
And you can also spray lemon juice on the leaves 1-2 times a month.
This method is similar to the way we fertilize orchids through the leaves.
Helps the stomata to be clear and the orchid will photosynthesize better.
Result.
After 1 month of fertilizing, you will see many new roots growing.
Roots grow very strongly.
when the roots absorb enough water and nutrients.
Then both leaves and flowers grow.
You see your orchid has many flower branches growing from one tree.
When the flowers bloom, they will stay on the branches for a long time before fading.
The flowers can bloom for up to 6 months before fading.