Welcome to Happiness Garden channel
There are different ways to revive old, wilted, rootless orchids
This video will add a new way for you to have more choices
Cut off all damaged roots
Rinse with water
Use 1 clove of garlic
300ml of water at room temperature
Puree
Filter out residue
add 700ml of water
Soak orchid branches in garlic water for 30 minutes
After soaking for 30 minutes, take it out and dry it
Sprinkle cinnamon powder on the cut and orchid root
This helps the cut to heal quickly and is highly resistant to rot
Use bricks with holes like this
then you recycle 5 liter plastic bottles like i do here
Add water like I do
Plug the orchid branch into the hole of the building brick
2 days misting 1 time
Place it next to a window or a place with light
but avoid direct sunlight
45 Days Later
Orchids have developed very healthy roots
In this way,
bricks do the job of absorbing water and keeping moisture very well
Therefore,
it will create a favorable environment for orchids to recover
and grow very well
From now on, spray organic foliar fertilizer once a week like I shared on the channel.
AFTER THE NEXT 3 MONTHS
With a very good orchid growing environment, the orchids recovered and grew quickly.
From leaves to roots and flower buds grow wonderfully.
Many flower buds grow at the same time.
Only healthy orchids produce so many flower buds at the same time.
Hopefully the video will help you a lot in taking better care of orchids at home.
If you find it interesting, please click like and share so more people know this trick.
And don't forget to subscribe to the channel so you don't miss any videos on my channel.
Thank you for watching the video. Wish you luck and see you in the next videos