Hello friends
In this video, I share how to take care of orchids to help them grow and flower
You see my orchids
New flowers always grow after the old ones fall
so my orchids bloom all year round
bloom from branch to branch
flowers bloom on long branches
Flowers can be kept on branches for up to 6 months
Many flowers grow on the same tree
New roots grow a lot to help absorb nutrients best
chubby flower buds
Help flowers bloom long on branches
brilliant flowers
How to make fertilizer as follows:
Use 1 small carrot weighing about 30g
Cut into small pieces
Add 1 liter of filtered water
Puree
filter out residue
Add 1 liter of filtered water
How to use
Use a cotton ball to soak up carrot juice
Wipe both the top and bottom of the leaves
help get rid of insects
and open stomata
Orchid will have better photosynthesis and metabolism
At the same time, orchids also absorb some nutrients through the leaves
Help keep the leaves green
It is recommended to do this 1-2 times per month
2nd way
Water this carrot for orchids
Carrot juice is a good source of nutrients for orchids,
including vitamins and minerals like beta-carotene, potassium, magnesium, and phosphorus.
When the carrot juice is poured into the orchid pot,
it provides nutrients to the orchids and helps to promote their health.
In addition, carrot juice is also acidic, which helps regulate the pH of the potted soil
and enhances the orchid's ability to absorb nutrients.
You can soak the orchid pot in this carrot juice for 20 minutes
Do this 1-2 times a month
3rd way
mist moisturizing carrot juice for orchids
Spray both the top and bottom of the leaves
help wash away dirt, wash away insects on orchids
Nutrients in carrot juice help orchids thrive and bloom
However, be careful not to over-water the carrot juice as it can clog the water lines in the orchid.
Do not water the flowers because the flowers fall off quickly
Hope the video content will help you in caring for orchids at home to bloom easily
If you find it interesting, please like, share and subscribe to my support channel