Welcome to my channel.
After the orchids have withered away
Cut off all flower stems and take care of them so that they continue to revive and bloom.
At this time, it is necessary to take care of the roots so that they can develop and absorb nutrients best.
Use 2 thin slices of onion.
Helps stimulate root and flower development very effectively.
Add 2 liters of water at room temperature.
Add 5 tablespoons of rice.
Leave for 1 day before using
1 Day Later
Method one: Clean the leaves with this water
This water helps stimulate growth and eliminate fungal diseases and leaf-damaging insects
Helps leaves synthesize and create more chlorophyll.
The leaves will always be green and sturdy, increasing their resistance to pests.
Method 2: This water net for plant roots
Doing this once a week helps stimulate root and flower growth.
Rice water creates beneficial microorganisms that help protect roots from fungal diseases very effectively
Method 3: Spray this water on the entire orchid
Doing this once a week helps eliminate fungus and insects that harm orchids.
At the same time, supplement nutrients through leaves and roots for orchids
After only 1 month the roots have grown a lot
Roots help orchids absorb the most nutrients.
Old orchids will recover quickly and synthesize nutrients for the next blooming season.
and after 2 months the orchid begins to produce buds for the next flower crop.
and after 3 months the orchids began to bloom
With this simple method, orchids will bloom continuously from season to season.
and your garden will always bloom with colorful flowers
Hello friends.
Orchids thrive in the right light and humidity conditions.
You should not put the orchid in a place where there is direct sunlight, it will make the orchid yellow.
Mist once every 7 days to create moisture for orchids to grow
There are many different ways to care for orchids to grow
Today I share a liquid natural fertilizer made from garlic
I use 3 cloves of garlic
Pour 1 liter of water in
I left it in a place without light for a day
After 1 day, I take this garlic water to water my orchids
I water each orchid 10 tablespoons
Garlic juice has the effect of repelling insects and protecting the roots of orchids
And provides nutrients for orchids such as: Vitamins
Minerals, calcium, potassium, phosphorus and magnesium
Help orchids to be protected and developed
Do this once a week to protect and grow the orchid
When fully provided with nutrients: Calcium, magnesium, potassium, phosphorus, orchids will bloom and last long.
To protect the leaves, I use 1 tablespoon of water mixed with 2 tablespoons of filtered water.
Fresh milk helps protect orchid leaves from fungi and bacteria
And clean the dirt on the leaves
You see this leaf clinging to a lot of dust
When there is a lot of dust, the surface of orchid leaves is not ventilated.
stomata blocked by dust
Orchid will have difficulty in photosynthesis
After wiping, the stomata are ventilated
Orchids will photosynthesize well, the leaves will be green again.
Do this every 2 weeks to protect and promote orchid growth
Hope my sharing content will help you to take better care of orchids
Please subscribe to the channel and press the notification to receive my latest shared videos
I wish you success and good luck
Now goodbye and see you in the next videos.