Welcome to my channel.
In this video, I share how to fertilize to help rot-affected orchids continue to revive and bloom strongly.
Please subscribe to the channel so you don't miss any orchid growing tips on my channel.
When growing many orchids, orchid rot cannot be avoided.
When orchids rot like this, cut off all rotten leaves as soon as possible.
This will help prevent rot from spreading into the stem, killing the orchid.
Then sprinkle cinnamon powder on the cut to help the wound heal quickly.
and sprinkle on the surface of orchid pots to help limit the spread of rot to the roots.
Then leave it for 1 day without watering to let the cut heal completely.
While waiting for the cut to heal, I took a thinly sliced ​​green banana.
Green bananas contain many minerals and nutrients such as potassium, phosphorus,
and nitrogen, which helps provide nutrition for orchids.
Add 1 liter of water.
Then add 3 tablespoons of rice.
Rice helps absorb some pollutants and improves environmental quality for orchids.
and add 1 teaspoon of trichoderma and Bacillus spores.
It will produce many beneficial microorganisms that help protect orchids very well.
Wait 1 day before using.
1 DAY LATER.
Decant the clear water above for use.
I add water to this residue to reuse after 1 week.
I add water in a 1/1 ratio.
From now on, water your orchids with this mixture once a week.
Green bananas help provide organic matter and increase water retention.
Rice helps provide organic matter and improve environmental quality for orchids very well.
Then spray this water on the leaves to supplement nutrients through the leaves for the orchid.
Helps leaves stay green and increases resistance to pests
Then place it on the windowsill or under a sun filter.
1 MONTH LATER.
The rotten orchid is now healthy and has many buds.
Leaves are stronger than before.
Continue watering this once a week.
and continue to spray this water once a week on the leaves.
AFTER NEXT 1 MONTH.
The rotten orchid has recovered and many flower branches have grown.
Leaves are greener and healthier.
Up to 6 flower stems develop at the same time.
Hopefully the video will help you a lot in taking better care of orchids at home.
If you find the video interesting, don't forget to like and share so more people know.
Thank you for watching the video. Good luck and see you in the next videos!