Welcome to my channel.
To help you have many choices when caring for orchids at home with organic fertilizer.
In this video, I continue to share new methods.
Subscribe to the video so you don't miss any tips on my channel.
To make this organic fertilizer you need garlic.
Use 1 clove of garlic like this.
Soak garlic in warm water for 2 hours.
After soaking for 2 hours, filter to remove residue.
Add water to make 3 liters of solution.
Add 2 tablespoons of milk.
FIRST METHOD
Clean the leaf surface with this liquid fertilizer.
The leaf surface will always be clean and airy with stomata.
Orchids will photosynthesize better.
Fertilizing regularly 1-2 times/month will help keep the leaves healthy.
SECOND METHOD
Spray this fertilizer on the entire orchid.
This method is similar to using foliar fertilizer.
Garlic contains essential oils that help kill fungi and insects very well.
Spraying aerial roots helps aerial roots develop.
THIRD METHOD
Water this fertilizer solution on the orchid roots.
Milk-based fertilizer provides natural calcium which is very good for orchids.
Helps orchids stay healthy and resistant to pests.
And milk contains a lot of nutrients for orchids.
Do this 1-2 times a month to supplement nutrition and increase the orchid's resistance.
RESULT
After 3 times of applying this fertilizer method, the root system has developed very strongly.
Roots help orchids absorb and transport nutrients to nourish plants and flowers.
Flowers bloom in more vibrant colors.
The orchid blooms many flowers at the same time but is still healthy.
Flowers bloom for a long time before fading.
Welcome to part 2 of the video
When the orchid is sick and rotten like this,
Don't rush to throw it away,
Let me guide you on how to help it recover quickly.
Remove all rotten leaves so they do not spread to the stem.
The roots are still very healthy.
Use about 1/4 small lemon.
Add 500ml of water.
Soak in this water for about 5 minutes
AFTER 5 MINUTES OF WAIT.
Keep in a cool place to dry.
Use dry paper to absorb water.
Sprinkle some cinnamon powder here to dry and prevent rot.
Keep in a cool place and do not water for 1 week.
AFTER 1 NEXT WEEK
Use about 10g of aloe vera leaves.
Add 500ml of water.
Take a portion into a spray bottle
Watering aloe vera for orchids.
AFTER 3 NEXT WEEKS.
Has sprouted small.
Periodic 7 to 10 days watering and moisturizing 1 time.
AFTER THE NEXT 2 MONTHS.
From now on, fertilize once every 2 weeks and keep the orchid moist to grow stronger.
Thank you for watching the video.
Good luck and see you in the next video.