Hello
friends nice to meet you on my
channel you see here a withered Orchid
maybe it's because you didn't water it
or due to direct sunlight shining on the
Orchid
[Music]
um if you want orchids to be nourished
and grow quickly please watch this video
[Music]
carefully now I will share this amazing
trick with
you you need one aloe vera leaf
[Music]
which country are you watching the video
from please comment
below it's wonderful that we can chat
together from all around the
world this aloe vera gel is great for
Reviving
[Music]
orchids now apply aloe vera gel on on
the top and bottom of the
[Music]
leaf aloe vera gel has a very good
moisturizing
[Music]
effect in addition aloe vera also
contains vitamins a b and c and minerals
such as nitrogen phosphorus and
potassium
[Music]
uh do this every 5 days and leave the
Orchid pot in a cool place for 3 weeks
[Music]
next take 1 liter of warm water and put
it in the
[Music]
bottle then take one spoon of rice and
soak it in this water for about 30
minutes let the nutrients in the rice
completely dissolve into the water
[Music]
chop the remaining aloe vera leaves into
small pieces
[Music]
then puree with 300 mm of water
filter out residue then add 2 L of water
at room temperature
[Music]
after soaking for 30 minutes filter this
rice water
[Music]
mix rice water with aloe vera
juice so I ended up with about 3 l of
this wonderful liquid manure solution
[Music]
cover the pot with moss to retain
moisture
[Music]
better now you use this solution to
water the Orchid every 5 days
[Music]
soak the Orchid pot in this water for 2
hours
after soaking for 2 hours remember to
lift the Orchid pot and place it in a
cool place to let the Orchid
[Music]
recover 2 weeks
later for flize after 2 weeks for
fresher orchid
[Music]
leaves new Roots develop very
well many new roots are growing
[Music]
new Roots will help transport water and
nutrients from the roots to the
stem if the leaves are provided with
enough water and nutrients from the
roots the leaves will gradually become
Lush again
[Music]
1 month
later you see the leaves are very fresh
[Music]
and the Orchid grows a new Leaf
after the next 2
[Music]
months the orchid has grown two branches
two
[Music]
buds but the leaves at the base have
turned yellow so I will cut off these
yellow leaves
[Music]
uh instinctively when an orchid buds if
the plant lacks nutrients that the base
leaves will turn yellow and fall off to
provide nutrients for the buds to
develop
now I need to supplement the orchid's
nutrition by taking three spoons of
[Music]
rice uh then soak in 2 L of water at
room
[Music]
temperature and wait 30 minutes for the
nutrients to completely dissolve in
water before
[Music]
using 30 minutes
later add 3 tbsp of milk
[Music]
rice water and milk are excellent
sources of nutrients for orchids to
[Music]
grow now you water the Orchid with this
solution once a week to help the Orchid
recover quickly
[Music]
after the next 1
month after three to four times s of
applying liquid fertilizer from milk and
rice water the Orchid had many
[Music]
roots hope the video will help you a
lot if you like the video remember to
hit like share and subscribe to support
[Music]
me uh thank you for watching the video
wish you luck and see you in the next
videos