welcome to my channel
Today I show you how to propagate orchids at home from flower branches
Peel off the cover to make sprouts easy to grow
Apply molten candle solution to the cut
Doing so will not allow water to seep into the branches.
At the same time, it helps the orchid not to lose water.
Helps protect orchid branches from rot
Use 2 small cloves of garlic
add 1 liter of water at room temperature
puree
filter out residue
Soak orchid branches in garlic water for 20 minutes
Garlic contains a number of natural hormones that stimulate the growth of sprouts and roots
Soak moss in garlic water for 20 minutes
Garlic contains sulfur compounds and natural antibiotics, which help prevent the growth of harmful bacteria and pests that exist in orchid media.
AFTER 20 MINUTES
I recycle plastic boxes as orchid propagating tools
Put the orchid branch here and remember to put the sprout facing up
Put in a cool place for the orchid to revive
AFTER 2 WEEKS
Sprouts have grown a bit
Keep misting to keep moisture regularly
Continue to put it in a shady place to wait for the tree to revive
AFTER 3 MONTHS
WOW
The orchid has grown into a very healthy seedling
The roots are very big and strong
So with only garlic bulbs, we can propagate orchids at home very easily
We don't need to use chemical drugs
In order for the plant to be perennial and not have root rot, I will replant it later
I planted with pine bark and pumice stone so that the roots of the orchid can be ventilated
Just put the orchid on and water to keep it moist
From now on you can take care of it like any other orchid
There are many different ways to revive old, wilted, or rootless orchids like this
This video will add a new way for you to have more choices
Cut off all damaged roots
Rinse with water
Use 1 clove of garlic
300ml of water at room temperature
Puree
Filter out residue
add 700ml of water
Soak orchid branches in garlic water for 30 minutes
After soaking for 30 minutes, take it out and dry it
Sprinkle cinnamon powder on the cut and orchid root
This helps the cut to heal quickly and is highly resistant to rot
Use bricks with holes like this
then you recycle 5 liter plastic bottles like i do here
Add water like I do
Plug the orchid branch into the hole of the building brick
2 days misting 1 time
Place it next to a window or a place with light
but avoid direct sunlight
45 Days Later
Orchids have developed very healthy roots
In this way,
bricks do the job of absorbing water and keeping moisture very well
Therefore,
it will create a favorable environment for orchids to recover
and grow very well
From now on, spray organic foliar fertilizer once a week like I shared on the channel.
AFTER THE NEXT 3 MONTHS
With a very good orchid growing environment, the orchids recovered and grew quickly.
From leaves to roots and flower buds grow wonderfully.
Many flower buds grow at the same time.
Only healthy orchids produce so many flower buds at the same time.
Hopefully the video will help you a lot in taking better care of orchids at home.
If you find it interesting, please click like and share so more people know this trick.
And don't forget to subscribe to the channel so you don't miss any videos on my channel.
Welcome to part 3 of this video
When orchids are old and have poor resistance, we need to rejuvenate them.
First you need to cut off all damaged leaves and roots.
Keep only fresh roots.
Onions have very good antiseptic and growth stimulating effects
Take about 20 grams of thinly sliced ​​onion.
Take 1 teaspoon of baking soda.
Helps balance PH levels and eliminate fungal diseases harmful to orchids
Add 2 liters of water at room temperature.
Wait 30 minutes before using
After 30 minutes, filter to remove residue
Then water the orchid with onion water and baking soda
Soak in this water for 30 minutes
Cover the pot with a layer of dry moss
Place the dried moss in this transparent plastic box
Leave in a cool place for 1 day without watering
1 Day later
From now on, water your orchids once a week
Or water when the moss is dry
Be careful to keep the moss moist. If the moss is waterlogged, the orchid will easily rot.
Then place it in a cool place with enough light for the orchid to grow
3 Weeks Later
Many baby orchids have sprouted
Take 2 liters of water at room temperature
Then add 5 spoons of rice
Water the orchid with rice water once a week
Helps stimulate baby orchids to grow and take root quickly
Continue to place in a cool, well-lit place for the orchid to grow
After the next 1 month
The baby orchids grow very healthy.
Newly growing roots will help the orchid absorb the most nutrients
From now on, you can add other organic fertilizers to your orchids such as fish protein or soybean fertilizer to help your orchids grow faster
After 4 months orchids will bloom throughout the garden
If you find it interesting, please click like and share so more people know
And don't forget to subscribe to the channel to help your channel reach 1 million subscriptions soon.