Welcome to my channel.
When orchids have enough nutrients and a good soil environment,
The plant will grow strongly and flower more.
In this video, I share a type of fertilizer that few people know about.
Come explore with me now.
When you grow many orchids, it is inevitable that orchids will rot.
If it accidentally rots, you need to immediately cut off the rotten part.
Then isolate the rotten orchid pot from other normal orchid pots.
This helps prevent rot from spreading to normal orchids.
Then cut off all damaged roots.
This is charcoal
and grind into powder.
Then sprinkle activated charcoal powder on the newly cut wound.
Helps cuts heal faster and eliminates fungal diseases.
Because activated carbon has a very good disinfection function.
Then you sprinkle more on the orchid root.
Then place the orchid pot in a cool place and do not water for 1 week and the orchid will recover.
Next way.
Mix 3 tablespoons of activated carbon with 2 liters of water.
Then use this water to water the orchid roots.
Do this periodically every 2 weeks for normal orchids.
Helps prevent disease and improve pH in growing media.
Activated carbon also contains high levels of calcium and natural minerals that are very good for orchids.
Helps stimulate rooting.
Soak the orchid pot in this water for 20 minutes.
After 20 minutes, take out the orchid pot.
Then filter to get clear water.
Next method: Use this water to thoroughly wipe the top and bottom of the leaves
The orchid will be protected from fungi and insects.
The calcium content in activated carbon helps make leaves strong.
Do this regularly every 2 weeks and you will be as healthy as this.
Next method: You can also use this water to spray the entire orchid plant.
Helps eliminate fungi and insects on leaves very well.
and it also provides some nutrients through its leaves and roots very effectively
Now let's see the results.
Many new roots grow.
Helps orchids absorb nutrients best.
The potassium and phosphorus content in activated carbon stimulates plants to root extremely quickly.
Many flower buds grow on the same tree.
The potassium content in charcoal helps prevent flower buds from falling off
The flowers are brighter and stronger.
Surely you will be surprised with this type of fertilizer.
If you find it interesting, please like and share it with many people.
Hey everyone! If you enjoy my content, please consider subscribing to my channel to support me. Your support means the world to me! Thanks for watching