welcome to my channel uh in this video
I'm sharing how to revive a weakened
Orchid so it can grow normally and Bloom
beautifully if you haven't subscribed
yet make sure to hit that subscribe
button so you don't miss any orchid care
tips on my
[Music]
channel let's get
started this is an orchid that has
rotted it was disc started but I brought
it home to revive
[Music]
it after the Orchid blooms the plant
often becomes a bit weak because it has
used a lot of energy to
flour um if not properly cared for the
Orchid May struggle to recover and it
will be difficult for it to bloom again
next
[Music]
time need to remove all the damaged
leaves roots and old stems
[Music]
removing the infected Parts helps
prevent the growth of bacteria and
[Music]
mold uh the plant doesn't have to
nourish the weak Parts allowing it to
focus on the healthy
sections removing the old Parts helps
the plant grow new stronger choots and
roots
[Music]
now I'm cutting through the Orchid stem
to check if there's any rot
[Music]
inside luckily the inside of the Orchid
stem hasn't rotted yet
[Music]
cut off all the damaged leaves to
prevent the rot from spreading to other
[Music]
areas then wash it thoroughly with water
for the Orchid stem we need to make a
clean cut to avoid crushing it which
will reduce the risk of rot from the cut
these rotting leaves should be removed
and kept far from the garden to prevent
spreading the rot to other
[Music]
orchids do you have cinnamon
powder take one spoonful of cinnamon
powder and put it into a jar
then add it to 1 liter of boiling
[Music]
water stir well to prevent the cinnamon
powder from clumping
[Music]
then let it Steep and wait for the water
to cool
[Music]
down once the water cools down stir well
to ensure the nutrients are fully
dissolved in the water
[Music]
that's my helper do you have any
pets now strain out the
residue cinnamon has natural
antibacterial and antifungal properties
helping to eliminate bacteria and fungi
that cause rot especially root and stem
rot
step one use a soft cotton ball to soak
up the water and gently wipe the top and
bottom of the
leaves wiping the leaves clean helps
remove fungi bacteria or mold that may
develop on the surface reducing the risk
of the plant getting infected
when the leaves are cleaned light can
easily reach the surface helping the
plant photosynthesize more effectively
especially during the recovery
process then place it here
and soak the leaf stem in the cinnamon
water for 10
minutes cinnamon water has antibacterial
and anti-fungal properties helping to
prevent infection at the cut cinnamon
helps stimulate the growth of new Roots
supporting the orchid's quick recovery
[Music]
then water the Orchid pot with the
cinnamon
water it helps prevent diseases caused
by bacteria and fungi in The
Roots it helps the Orchid Roots grow
strong and
healthy it it enhances the plant's
ability to resist harmful factors
after watering soak the Orchid roots in
this water for about 10 minutes for the
best effect on the
[Music]
roots then remove the roots and dry off
the cinnamon water
[Music]
and take the Orchid pot
out next take one aloe vera leaf
aloe vera contains oxin a natural plant
hormone that helps stimulate root
development from the leaf
stem it helps protect the leaf stem from
bacteria and fungi preventing infection
and supporting the rooting
process then take aloe vera gel and
apply it to the leaf stem
[Music]
then apply the aloe vera gel to the cut
on the Orchid stem and roots to
stimulate root growth and protect
against rot from the cut
[Music]
aloe vera gel contains natural hormones
that stimulate the growth of new roots
and chots
[Music]
I use Moss to plant orchids as it helps
retain moisture well and stimulates fast
root growth
[Music]
soak the moss in cinnamon water for
about 5 minutes to eliminate bacteria
and fungi that may be present in the
[Music]
Moss then take the Moss Out and ring out
any excess water
[Music]
place the moss in here that
then place the Orchid leaf in
[Music]
here then you should spray water to
maintain moisture once every 3 days
use plastic wrap to cover the mouth of
the
bottle create ventilation holes at the
top like
this then place it in a location with
enough light but avoid direct sunlight
on the Orchid
now I'm adding more Moss to the surface
of this Orchid pot to help retain
moisture
[Music]
better this method also helps stimulate
the rapid growth of new roots
then spray water maintain moisture for
the Orchid pot whenever you notice the
growing medum is
dry then spray water to maintain
moisture for the Orchid pot whenever you
notice the growing medium is
dry the results after 50 days
[Music]
wow as you can see many new Roots have
grown from the leaf
[Music]
stem and and the new leaves have also
grown bigger than before the recovery
[Music]
the new Roots help the plant absorb
water and nutrients more
effectively healthy Roots help the plant
resist diseases and adverse
environmental
factors this in turn helps the plant
grow stronger and healthier
[Music]
you can see that the base of the orchid
has also revived very
[Music]
well the Orchid stem has grown a new
very healthy
shoot many new roots are growing under
the layer of moss
[Music]
these new Roots help the plant grow
strong recover quickly and prepare to
bloom
[Music]
now I'm planting the Orchid Leaf in a
new pot so it can grow better in the
[Music]
outside um I'm planting it with pine
bark chips uh which maintain uh moderate
moisture moisture and provide good
drainage for the roots to
grow with this simple method you can
quickly and effectively revive a
weakened Orchid on your
own I hope you enjoyed the video don't
forget to support the channel and leave
a comment
now you just need to care for it like
any other regular orchid
plant uh take care of your Orchids with
all the love for plants and you'll get
to enjoy beautiful vibrant blooms
uh thank you for watching I wish you
success in caring for your orchids and
many wonderful moments with your plants
goodbye and see you again soon