Hello friends!
When your orchids have finished blooming or your orchids have never bloomed
First you need to cut off all wilted flower branches, leaves, and damaged roots.
This helps eliminate pathogens and stimulates the growth of new flowers, leaves and roots
Next I use eggshells as fertilizer to stimulate flowering
Crush about 5 eggshells
Then add 50ml of vinegar water to help ferment and dissolve the organic calcium
The reaction between vinegar water and eggshell creates organic calcium that dissolves very quickly
Leave for 1 day to completely dissolve the calcium and minerals in the eggshell
1 Day Later
Step 1: Water the roots every 2 weeks
Eggshells contain a lot of calcium to help plants stay healthy and increase their resistance to pests
Eggshells also contain a lot of potassium which helps stimulate flower growth
Nitrogen and phosphorus in eggshells help leaves and roots grow very well
Step 2: Spray this water on the leaves every 2 weeks
Vinegar helps remove dirt, insects, and fungal diseases on orchids
Helps orchids photosynthesize light and grow better
2 Months Later
The orchid has continued to bloom many buds
If you find it interesting, don't forget to like, share and subscribe to my support channel
Next, I share how to quickly restore rotten orchids
If you have an orchid that has rot causing it to lose all its leaves.
So don't rush to throw it away. I'll share how to revive it quickly and easily.
This orchid has a bacterial disease that causes it to rot.
First, cut off and clean the rotten areas.
Then completely cut off the damaged roots.
And this is hydrogen peroxide.
Place pure hydrogen peroxide on the rotten area.
Helps eliminate pathogens and prevent rot from spreading.
and you pour it on the cut to help disinfect it.
Then leave it for 1 day without irrigation to let the wound heal completely.
Take 3 liters of water.
Take 1 teaspoon of baking soda and mix it with water.
Baking soda helps eliminate pathogens and needs to balance pH levels.
Soak the entire orchid in this water for 10 minutes.
will eliminate pathogens and need to balance the PH level in the orchid growing environment.
Then take it out.
Pour water into the plate.
helps the substrate always have the right moisture for orchids to germinate.
Place in a cool, well-lit place.
Spray moisturizer regularly when the substrate feels dry.
Take 2 spoons of rice.
Rice water contains many nutrients that are very good for the growth of orchids.
Soak orchid roots in rice water for 20 minutes.
Helps stimulate the growth of sprouts and roots
Do it once a week.
After soaking for 20 minutes, take it out.
1 MONTH LATER.
From the rotten orchid root, a small healthy orchid is revived.
Continue watering the orchid with rice water once a week.
Soak for 20 minutes then take out.
After the next 1 month.
Baby orchids are getting healthier and stronger.
Orchid roots also grow very healthily.
Hopefully the video will help you a lot in recovering rotten orchids.
If you find the video interesting, please like and share so more people know.
and subscribe to my channel to support me.
Thank you for watching the video, good luck and see you in the next videos on this channel.