welcome to my channel.
In this video, I share how to fertilize to help flower branches continue to revive and bloom after the flowers wither.
Please subscribe to the channel so you don't miss any orchid growing tips on my channel.
When eating bananas, don't throw away the peel.
Because banana peels contain a lot of potassium and important nutrients that are very good for plant growth.
I took a banana peel and cut it into thin slices.
then put it in a jar.
Then take 3 tablespoons of soybeans and put them in a jar.
Add 1 teaspoon of sugar.
and add 1 teaspoon yeast.
Then pour in 500ml of warm water.
Leave in a cool place for 1 month before using.
This is an orchid after blooming and fading.
I cut off all the dry branches.
These nodes may continue to bloom.
The top of the orchid has rotted.
The leaves also rot.
Cut off rotten leaves
Then sprinkle cinnamon powder on top to help the cut heal quickly and prevent rot.
and sprinkle it on the rotting tops.
Leave for 1 day without watering until the cut heals
1 DAY LATER.
Watering keeps the roots green.
This will help the roots absorb nutrients better when we fertilize the orchids.
Soak the orchid pot in water for about 20 minutes then take it out.
This is soybean water and banana peel fermented after 1 month.
Take 50ml.
Mix with 2 liters of water.
Cleaning leaves helps protect them from disease.
The pH of this water helps eliminate fungi and insects, so it protects orchids very well.
Spray this water on the leaves once a week.
will supplement nutrients through the leaves to help the leaves stay green.
And spray this water on the branches once a week to help stimulate flowering.
And I water this once a week to stimulate the growth of roots, stems, leaves and flowers.
Because the roots are the best part of the plant that absorbs nutrients.
and can be soaked for about 20 minutes and then taken out.
1 Month Later.
Many flower buds have sprouted from withered orchid branches.
This simple method will help your orchids bloom many times a year.
Even rotten orchids like mine still bloom several times a year.
If you find it interesting, please share this orchid growing tip with as many people as possible
Thank you for watching the video. Good luck and see you in the next videos.