Welcome to my channel
If you have a rotten orchid like this, don't rush to throw it away
For this video I will share how to restore rotten orchids that grow very quickly
First, remove all damaged leaves and roots.
Then rinse with water to help eliminate fungi and bacteria that cause orchid rot
Use a small aloe vera leaf to have antiseptic properties
In addition, aloe vera leaves also contain many important amino acids and nutrients.
Promotes rapid growth of orchids
Add 1 liter of water
Add 1 teaspoon of honey which has antiseptic properties and provides nutrients and vitamins
Leave for 2 hours before using
2 Haurs later
Soak orchid roots in aloe vera and honey for 20 minutes
Use aloe vera juice and honey to thoroughly wipe the top and bottom of the leaves
Helps eliminate fungal diseases and insects that harm orchids
Cleaning stomata helps photosynthetic light spread better
Therefore, the leaves will always be sturdy and naturally shiny green
Then use this aloe vera and honey water to water the orchid roots
Doing this twice a month helps stimulate the orchid to grow new roots
and protect orchid roots from root rot
Use dry pine bark as a growing medium for orchids
Plant the orchid in a new pot
Leave for 3 days without watering to help the wound heal quickly
3 Days Later
Adding a layer of moss on the surface helps keep the orchid moist
From now on, water once a week or when the surface of the orchid pot is dry, you need to water the orchid pot.
Utilize recycled plastic bottles to create miniature greenhouses to grow orchids
1 MONTH LATER
The small orchid has grown very healthy
Take 3 spoons of rice
1 Liter of water
Water the orchid with rice water every 2 weeks
Rice water helps stimulate growth and adds many nutrients to help baby orchids grow quickly
Spray a moisturizing mist with water when the surface feels dry
2 MONTHS LATER
The small orchid has developed healthy roots, stems and leaves
Hopefully the video will help you a lot in taking better care of orchids at home.
Thank you for watching the video. Good luck and see you in the next videos