Welcome to my channel.
If you have a wilted orchid with wrinkled leaves and you are looking for a way to revive it.
Watch this video until the end. I'll show you how to recover instantly.
First, cut off all the yellow leaves.
Because these yellow leaves cannot be revived.
With these wrinkled and withered leaves, I will show you how to restore them now.
Wash the roots with water to remove any excess organic matter.
Helps reduce root clogging and remove excess fertilizer.
then take 3 liters of water.
Then take 3 tablespoons of cement to help disinfect and remove excess acid.
Wait for the water to clear before using.
After the water clears.
Scoop out the clear water.
Then wipe the leaves clean with this water.
Helps remove dirt and harmful fungi and insects on leaves.
Then water the roots with this water.
Helps disinfect planting media and orchid roots from orchid pests.
Soak the orchid pot in this water for 10 minutes.
I use this water to water this orchid with top rot.
Helps prevent diseases and balance the PH level in orchid pots.
After 10 minutes, take it out and leave it in a cool place for 3 days without watering.
After 3 days, take 2 liters of water into the jar.
Add 3 tablespoons of rice.
From now on, use this rice water for watering every 2 weeks.
Rice water is rich in polyphenols, calcium, magnesium, vitamins, etc.
This helps wilted orchids recover and grow very quickly.
Then spray this water on the orchid as a foliar fertilizer every 2 weeks.
Nutrients in rice water restore wilted leaves very quickly.
Place the plant in a cool place to avoid direct sunlight on the orchid.
3 Months Later.
With this simple method, after 3 months the orchid recovered and grew strongly.
Green leaves, no longer wrinkled.
and produce many flower buds at the same time.
The tree is very sturdy and healthy.
Hopefully the video will help you a lot in taking better care of orchids at home.
This tree also recovers and grows very well.
My videos have subtitles in many different languages ​​so you can easily choose the appropriate language.
Don't forget to Like, share and subscribe to the channel.
Thank you for watching the video. Good luck and see you in the next videos.