Hello friends
Nice to meet you on my channel
For orchids to grow healthily, they need a strong root system,
Thanks to that, the orchid will grow sustainably and bloom many flowers
Big, beautiful, bright flowers.
When blooming, the flowers can stay on the branches for up to 6 months before fading
Leaves that absorb enough fertilizer and light will always be green
Leaves are sturdy and disease-free
In this video, I share a new type of organic fertilizer with ingredients available in every kitchen.
What I need is an apple.
I cut this apple into small slices.
Natural fertilizers should not be underestimated; they are just as effective as ready-made mineral complexes but are safer.
You can see many types of homemade natural fertilizers on my channel
If you are new, please subscribe to the channel so you don't miss any tips on how to grow and care for orchids!
This method of making fertilizer is very simple and anyone can do it.
Put it in the jar
I poured boiling water over the sliced ​​apples.
Then cover tightly and set aside
I use oatmeal as fertilizer
Take 2 tablespoons of oatmeal and put it in a jar
and add 500ml of room temperature water
Incubate until the water cools
1 Hour later
Filter residue
If you are new, please subscribe to the channel so you don't miss any tips on how to grow and care for orchids!
Filter and mix apple juice with oatmeal
Add 1 liter of water
METHOD 1
Take a cotton ball and wipe the leaves with this water
Wipe both the top and bottom of the leaves thoroughly 1-2 times a month
Helps remove dirt and residue on leaves
This method also kills fungal diseases and insects that reside on leaves and harm orchids.
Carefully wipe the underside of the leaf as well
Because the underside of leaves is often wet, insects and fungal diseases often hide there.
They just wait for an opportunity and when they encounter favorable conditions, they will cause diseases that destroy orchids.
This will help keep the leaf stomata open
and your orchid will photosynthesize the light better
Helps increase resistance for orchids
METHOD 2
You water this fertilizer solution for the orchid. each orchid root.
This type of fertilizer helps stimulate the spread of new roots very well
At the same time, it has the ability to keep the orchid growing environment moist.
Helps improve absorption
and nutrient exchange of the orchid growing environment.
This helps orchids grow stronger.
Do this regularly 1-2 times a month for sustainable orchid growth.
Promotes better rooting, budding and photosynthesis.
Stimulates blooming and produces more beautiful flowers.
Soak the roots in this water for 20 minutes
will help orchids absorb nutrients best through their roots
After soaking for 20 minutes, take out the orchid pot
METHOD 3
You pour this fertilizer solution into a spray bottle
Then water and mist the orchid leaves and roots.
Apples are rich in carbohydrates, protein, calcium, phosphorus,
potassium, zinc, iron and many other trace elements.
Same amount of Vitamin A and C in abundance.
These are essential minerals for the growth and flowering of orchids.
Watering orchids regularly every 2 weeks with this fertilizer will give very good results.
You can also combine other types of organic fertilizers to care for the plant.
Regular fertilization of orchids is very important, especially in the fall.
In this season, orchids grow many new flower branches
Result
After 2-3 times of applying this fertilizer, the orchid begins to grow new roots
This fertilizer is good.
But remember, no amount of fertilizer will help your orchids if they don't get enough diffused light,
at least 12 hours a day.
If there is too much light or too much direct sunlight, the orchid will become stressed, wilt and fail to grow.
Thank you for watching the watering video here
May God always bless you
goodbye and see you again