Nice to meet you on my channel
Orchid is a tropical plant with very strong vitality
With an orchid like this, many people probably throw it away because they think it's dead
When you see this orchid, don't rush to throw it away
Today I will show you how to revive orchids like this quickly
First, cut off all damaged roots
Remember to subscribe to the channel so you don't miss any videos
Rinse with water
Dry the cut
Drop the molten candle solution on the freshly cut wound
Will help orchids not lose water and also work against fungal diseases
Use 1 teaspoon of cinnamon powder
1 Liter of boiled water
Close the lid and wait for the water to cool
Now the water has cooled
Filter out the residue
Soak orchids in cinnamon water for 30 minutes
Water the cinnamon evenly on the top and bottom of the leaves
Cinnamon has antiseptic properties, so it helps to eliminate fungi and insects that are harmful to orchids very well
Cinnamon also contains many minerals, vitamins and amino acids that are very beneficial for the revival of orchids
Do this once a month to keep your orchid protected and healthy
30 minutes after soaking in cinnamon water
Use dry pine bark to grow orchids
Spread 1 turn of dry moss on top of the pot
Leave in a cool place and do not water for 1 week so that the fungus does not grow harmful
1 week later, start watering to keep the orchid moist
Pour water into the dish at the bottom of the pot to create the right humidity for the orchid to revive quickly
Recycling plastic bottles into miniature greenhouses makes it easier for orchids to revive
1 month later
Since the tree has grown roots, I use organic fertilizer made from fish waste to fertilize the orchid
The baby orchid is still very small, so I only apply it on the outside edge of the pot to avoid causing the baby orchid to be shocked with feces
Watering and moisturizing once a week
2 months later
From now on take care like other mature orchids
See you in the next videos