Hello friends, today I share one way
Restore orchids, when the leaves have turned yellow and dried like this
with these orchids, when the leaves above are still green
and be healthy, don't give up
and these roots were damaged
So the plant cannot metabolize
Let's cut in here
Remove these yellow and rotten leaves from the plant
Cut more to remove crushed stems and prevent the orchid from rotting further
and this part of the roots is completely damaged
so it cannot be restored
Rinse thoroughly with water
This helps the tree recover faster
helps orchids, even though they only have one leaf, can revive faster and easier
Wipe this leaf again until it is completely dry
And this method will remove dirt and insects still attached to this leaf
Just use 3 tablespoons of rice
Contains many B vitamins
Add 500ml of water and wait 30 minutes before using
After 30 minutes Take this rice water
Rice will be very good and help orchids grow very quickly
Use soft cotton pads
Wipe the leaves again and add nutrients through the leaves
Helps orchid leaves recover
Will not be infected by insects and fungus
put the leaf here and let's add this rice water
Leave it for 30 minutes to help the plant regenerate its roots very quickly
and use the remaining rice water
Spray directly on orchids, it will help orchids
grows very quickly and remember to spray under the leaves
to prevent the growth of insects
You should apply this method every 2 weeks
Rice water helps beneficial microorganisms grow, stimulates root growth and protects roots
Orchids will always be green and bloom many flowers
Orchids will always be green and very healthy
Orchids blooming on branches can last 6 months before fading
After 30 minutes, take the leaves out and wipe off all the water
Use 1 clove of garlic, garlic has very good antibacterial and antiseptic properties
Apply to this root
Helps this root part become antibacterial
Place the leaf like this and leave it in a cool, dry place for 1 day
After 1 day, the cut will dry and the orchid will recover quickly
Take advantage of plastic boxes and create ventilation holes like this to grow orchids
Take sterilized dry moss and soak it in water
Then use this moss to grow orchids
Helps create appropriate humidity for flax plants to quickly root
will put it here
Then spray moisturizer with water every 3 days
Take advantage of plastic boxes and create ventilation holes
Then cover and place the orchid pot in a cool and well-lit place
1 Month later
The orchids began to grow
The roots were very healthy
With this method it is very easy to restore orchids
Root development is faster
to this stage when the tree is already there
If you have strong roots, you will feel secure when replanting
helps this orchid plant grow faster in the outside environment
Use aquaponic plastic beads or pine bark placed underneath
Helps roots grow strongly and not rot
Spread a layer of moss on top to help retain moisture better
Then plant the orchid and care for it until the roots attach to the substrate before fertilizing
I always share many methods for you to see
and choose which methods are most suitable
I always share many subtitles for you to watch and choose from
Which subtitle is suitable?
Hope it will always help you a lot,
Don't forget to like, share and subscribe to the Channel
and press the bell to conveniently follow.
Goodbye and see you again. Wish you always success