Welcome to my channel
When growing orchids, everyone wants the orchid to grow healthy and flower a lot,
And if that's what you want, watch to the end of the video.
Today I will show you how to make a new organic fertilizer, it is made from bell peppers,
It's great because it helps the orchid grow and bloom a lot of flowers for you
You see this orchid of mine,
Thanks to the fertilizer I made myself from bell peppers
so its leaves are always green and sturdy,
The roots are very large, growing healthy,
grow many buds and do not fall,
Flowers bloom brilliantly and long.
Let's start doing it
Use 20 grams of bell pepper
Add 600ml of water
filter out residue
Add water to make 1 liter
Bell peppers contain many vitamins A, C, amino acids and minerals: Calcium, magnesium, zinc.
In particular, bell peppers are very high in sugar and phosphorus and potassium
Those are the organic substances necessary for the growth of orchids
Water this once a month
The nutrients in bell peppers will stimulate orchid growth,
The phosphorus content in bell peppers will stimulate the roots to grow very quickly,
The potassium and sugar content will help the orchid transport water and sugar from the roots to the leaves, to the flower branches,
When there is potassium and sugar, the leaves will never wilt,
Flower buds will also not fall when given enough sugar and potassium in bell peppers
This is milk
milk without sugar
Mix 30ml milk with 70ml water
Clean the surface of orchid leaves with milk
The stomata on the leaves will be ventilated
Insects on leaves are also removed
Disease fungi and bacteria on leaves are also eliminated
At the same time, milk is also a very good source of nutrients for plants
Orchids are also provided with nutrients through their leaves
so the orchid will always be green and sturdy
Note: it is necessary to thoroughly wipe both the top and bottom of the leaves
The underside of the leaf is a humid place, so fungi and bacteria hide and work
Orchids are very susceptible to leaf rot caused by fungi and bacteria
The underside of the leaves is also a shelter for insects,
They will destroy the orchid leaves starting here,
It will then spread causing the entire leaf to turn yellow
you see
After wiping the green orchid leaves
Orchids will photosynthesize well
Orchid's metabolism will also be better
Lan will increase resistance
when the orchid is healthy
and enough nutrition
with good care
When blooming, it will be very fresh and long-lasting.
Healthy roots contribute to good nutrient absorption for orchids
Hope the video content will help you in taking better care of orchids at home
Welcome to my channel
Today I continue to share a new organic fertilizer to help stimulate flowering for orchids.
It is made from part of the red beetroot.
It is really a great fertilizer for flower growth
Using this fertilizer will always have beautiful orchids,
Your garden always blooms,
Each orchid will bloom again and again many times a year
STEP 1
This is red beetroot
Eat beets, do not rush to throw away the skin
Beetroot contains many minerals
vitamins like B1, B6, B12
They are essential nutrients important for orchid growth
Use the peel of 1 red beetroot
This young shoot will contain many plant stimulants called AUXIN
will stimulate the budding of plants and flower buds.
Add 1 liter of water
Closed
Leave in a cool and dark place for 6 hours
AFTER 6 HOURS
Add water to get 4 liters
Now water the orchid with this water
Red radish is rich in natural potassium,
so orchids are easier to absorb than chemical potassium and safe
Potassium helps balance water and ions,
Potassium also controls stomatal activity,
prevent excessive water loss in dry conditions,
Therefore, potassium is one of the essential macronutrients provided to plants during the maturation and flowering stages,
Same goes for orchids,
So, if you want orchids to have flowers, pay attention to fertilizing with high potassium content,
Do this once a month for your orchid to bloom
Note that you should not apply too much potassium because if you apply too much potassium, the orchid will have atrophy of its roots, small and bad leaves.
Applying this fertilizer once a month is enough.
STEP 2
Use 1/3 teaspoon of baking soda
add 1 liter of water
use cotton balls
Wipe the top and bottom of the orchid leaves with baking soda salt water,
Baking soda is a very good disinfectant,
Please clean the orchid leaves once a month,
it helps to remove dirt on the leaves,
and kill fungi and bacteria on orchids,
and also kill insects such as aphids, aphids, mosquitoes... clinging to orchids,
Helps protect orchid leaves always beautiful shine,
Orchid leaves photosynthesize better,
When the orchid is healthy, it will always bloom with many beautiful and long-lasting flowers
Thank you for watching the video. good luck and happy