welcome to my
[Music]
channel um when the last phenopsis
orchids are about to fall this is the
right time to cut branches to propagate
phenopsis orchids from flower stems
[Music]
these nodes still contain dormant buds
so they can be used to propagate orchids
from flower
[Music]
spikes and these nodes have already
bloomed so cut them off as they can no
longer be used for propagation
[Music]
after that I use a potato to create a
substance that helps propagate orchids
quickly
[Music]
potatoes contain many substances
necessary for the growth of
[Music]
orchids I will recycle potato peels into
organic fertilizer
[Music]
pour one liter of hot water into the
jar then Brew until the water cools
need to peel off the protective film of
the sleeping
Sprout this will help the sprouts grow
faster
[Music]
apply potato gel to the sleeping sprouts
this helps stimulate Sprout
[Music]
growth next apply toothpaste on the
cut helps cut seal fast
[Music]
faster wrap with thinly sliced potatoes
this helps moisturize and awaken dormant
sprouts
[Music]
uh leave for 6 hours to let the
nutrients from the potatoes penetrate
inside take one teaspoon of cinnamon
[Music]
powder add one liter of hot water
after the water cools filter to remove
sediment
[Music]
soak terracotta beads and aquaponic
resin beads in cinnamon water solution
for 30 minutes
[Music]
[Applause]
soak the moss in the cinnamon solution
for 30 minutes
[Music]
recycle used boxes into Orchid sprouting
tools
[Music]
conduct orchid nursery
spray moisturizer every 3
[Music]
days place in a cool
place when cool filtered remove residue
[Music]
um watering this liquid fertilizer for
orchids one to two times a month will be
very
[Music]
good 3 weeks later
the sleeping Sprouts have awakened
[Music]
continue spraying water and leave in a
cool place for the Sprouts to grow
[Music]
after next 1
month the Sprout has grown leaves
[Music]
continue spraying water and leave in a
cool place for the Sprouts to grow
[Music]
after the next 2
month small orchids grow very quickly
[Music]
with this simple way you can propagate
orchids at home easily
[Music]
hope the video will help you a lot
now I will plant it in a pot so the
Orchid can grow in the outside
[Music]
environment uh if you find the video
meaningful please like share and
subscribe to support me so my channel
can reach 10 million subscribers soon
[Music]
then nurture the Orchid with water and
organic fertilizer as I shared on the
happiness Garden Channel and take care
of it with all the love you have for the
plant in return it will bring you beauty
and growth
[Music]
wishing you success and happiness in
life goodbye and see you in the next
video