Welcome to my channel.
In this video, I share how to fertilize to help flower branches continue to revive and bloom after the flowers wither.
Please subscribe to the channel so you don't miss any orchid growing tips on my channel.
These are the branches after the flowers have faded.
All the flowers have fallen.
I cut off all the dry branches.
Then sprinkle cinnamon powder on the cut and leave for 1 day without watering.
This helps the cut heal quickly.
then take 2 liters of water.
and take 20ml of milk.
Nitrogen is a major component of proteins and other compounds important in plant biological processes.
Step 1: Clean the leaves with this water.
Milk has the ability to shine and clean leaves.
When you wipe orchid leaves with milk, it will help remove dirt and sebum.
and other pollutants on the leaves, helping orchids become cleaner and more active.
Then take 2 cloves of garlic.
This type of sprout will have a lot of Auxin to help stimulate plant growth.
Garlic has antibacterial and anti-fungal properties, helping to prevent the growth of pathogens harmful to orchids.
then mix it into this water.
Step 2: Water the orchid once a week.
Milk and garlic also provide phosphorus, an important nutrient that enhances root growth and cell division.
Phosphorus is an important part of a plant's reproductive and energy processes.
Milk and garlic also contain potassium, which helps improve plant health and increase resistance against diseases.
Step 3: Spray this water on the orchid once a week.
Milk also contains beneficial organic matter that helps improve soil structure and enhance plants' ability to absorb nutrients.
Spray evenly on branches to stimulate flower bud growth.
Then leave it on the windowsill or under a sun filter.
1 MONTH LATER.
From the dry branches, many flower buds continue to grow.
And this method will help orchids bloom many times a year.
Continue watering the orchid once a week with this water.
and continue to spray the orchid with this water once a week.
AFTER NEXT 1 MONTH.
Orchids have bloomed a lot.
Flower colors are vibrant and last long.
Hope the video will help you a lot
If you find the video interesting, don't forget to like and share so more people know.
Thank you for watching the video. Good luck and see you in the next videos!