Welcome to the happiness garden where we
explore the wonderful beauty of orchids
together and learn how to care for them
with lots of
[Music]
love. Today I will continue to share
with you a new method for uh making
natural fertilizer that is both simple
and effective, suitable for orchids and
many other types of plants using
familiar ingredients that almost every
household already has in the kitchen.
[Music]
This type of fertilizer will help your
orchid grow quickly, stay healthy, and
remain vibrant with beautiful clusters
of flowers that bloom evenly and last a
long
time. The flowers will stay fresh longer
right on the plant and may even bloom
year round, bringing lasting and vibrant
beauty to your garden.
[Music]
Let's get
started. To make today's natural
fertilizer, I will use eggshells. A
simple, easy to find ingredient that is
very rich in essential nutrients for
plants, helping to strengthen the health
of orchids and other plants in the
garden.
[Applause]
Take about 10 eggshells and wash them
thoroughly with water to remove all dirt
and impurities, preparing for the next
step in making natural
[Music]
fertilizer. Um, please comment and let
me know which country you are watching
the video from. Um, it's wonderful that
we can chat together from all around the
world.
[Music]
If you haven't subscribed to the channel
yet, please hit the subscribe button to
support me and not miss any orchid
growing tips. It's wonderful to have you
along for the journey.
[Music]
Then dry or with the eggshells on the
stove over low heat for about 5 minutes.
This step helps completely eliminate
fungi and bacteria, ensuring safety for
the plants when using the
[Music]
fertilizer. After roasting the eggshells
on the stove for five minutes, take them
out and let them cool naturally,
preparing for the next step in the
fertilizer making
process. Next, use a mortar and pestle
to crush the eggshells into small
pieces, making the fertilizer easier to
dissolve and allowing the plants to
absorb the nutrients in the eggshells
better.
[Music]
After crushing, put the crushed
eggshells into a clean glass jar for
fermentation, helping the nutrients from
the eggshells blend and work best when
applied to the plants.
[Music]
Then pour about 100 mm of white vinegar
into the jar to help dissolve the
minerals in the crushed eggshells and
stimulate the decomposition process,
creating a natural fertilizer rich in
nutrients for the plants.
You close the jar lid and observe the
reaction process between the eggshells
and the
vinegar. When you see bubbling and foam
appear, that is a sign that the the
minerals are dissolving and breaking
down, ready to nourish your plants.
[Music]
Then let the mixture ferment overnight
at room temperature, allowing the
nutrients from the eggshells and vinegar
uh to fully blend before using it to
fertilize the
[Music]
plants. After fermenting overnight,
prepare some clean water to dilute the
fertilizer before use. This helps reduce
the acidity and ensures it's safe for
the plant roots when
watering. Prepare two cups, each
containing one liter of clean water.
[Music]
Then mix 2 milll of the fermented
eggshell and white vinegar solution into
each liter of water. This ratio provides
just the right amount of nutrients for
the plants without harming the roots or
soil.
[Music]
Then I proceed to treat the pine bark
before planting to eliminate fungi and
impurities while also making the bark
safer and more suitable as a growing
medium for orchids.
[Music]
Pour the diluted fertilizer mixture over
the pine bark and moss to soak them for
about 20 minutes before planting. This
helps with light sterilization, adds
initial nutrients, and softens the
materials, creating an ideal environment
for orchid roots to attach and grow
healthily.
Now I prepare a healthy small orchid to
repot into a new pot.
You need to remove the old moss or
orchid growing foam before planting
because these mediums retain water very
well, but can easily cause root rot when
transferring to a larger pot, negatively
affecting the plant's
[Music]
growth. After removing the old growing
medium, we need to cut off any rotten
and weak roots.
This helps remove parts that can no
longer absorb nutrients while also
stimulating the plant to focus on
growing new, healthier roots, ensuring
good growth in the new pot.
[Music]
Then soak the orchid roots in the
diluted fertilizer mixture for about 20
minutes. This helps with light
sterilization, stimulates the roots to
absorb nutrients and promotes quick
recovery after pruning, creating the
best conditions for the plant to grow
vigorously.
Next, take a soft cloth, soak it evenly
with the diluted fertilizer mixture.
Then, gently and thoroughly wipe both
the top and underside of the orchid
leaves.
This method helps remove dust and pests
while also directly supplying nutrients
to the leaves, helping the plants stay
healthy and more vibrant.
[Music]
After soaking the pine bark and moss in
the diluted fertilizer mixture for about
20 minutes, uh, take out the pine bark
and
[Music]
moss. and let them drain before using
them as a growing medium, helping to
maintain good irration and cleanliness
for healthy root
development. Then we proceed to plant
the orchid in a new pot. Make sure to
choose a pot with drainage holes at the
bottom to allow excess moisture to
escape, preventing water logging and
root rot and creating ideal conditions
for healthy plant growth.
[Music]
Okay. I have to
After planting, place the orchid pot in
a spot with gentle sunlight, good
ventilation, and away from drafts.
Uh, and during the first week, avoid
watering to allow the plant time to
stabilize, prevent damage to young
roots, and help it adapt well to the new
[Music]
environment. Uh, you can pour the
leftover fertilizer into a spray bottle
to use on other orchid plants.
[Music]
You can use a spray bottle to mist the
orchids that are blooming. This is very
beneficial as it directly supplies
nutrients through the leaves, helping
the flowers stay fresh longer and
keeping the plants healthier throughout
the blooming season.
[Music]
The fertilizer will provide ample
calcium and essential minerals, helping
to strengthen the cellular structure of
the orchid flowers. This makes the
petals firmer, more vibrant, and extends
the blooming period, allowing you to
enjoy their brilliant beauty for longer.
Um, when sprayed directly onto the
leaves, the fertilizer quickly
supplements nutrients, enhances the
plant's photosynthesis capacity and
resistance, helping the orchid better
withstand changing weather conditions
and
pests. After spraying the fertilizer,
remember to gently wipe off any water
droplets on the surface and crevices of
the leaves with a soft cloth.
This helps prevent uh prolonged moisture
buildup, reduces the risk of fungal
infections, and keeps the orchid leaves
dry and
[Music]
healthy. After a week without watering
to allow the plant to stabilize, we
begin fertilizing the orchid.
[Music]
I use rice water to care for
orchids. Use a soft cloth soaked in the
rice water mixture to gently wipe the
surface of the orchid leaves clean.
This method helps remove dust, provides
nutrients, and keeps the leaves shiny
and healthy, contributing to enhancing
the plant's photosynthesis
[Music]
capacity. Then use the diluted rice
water to water directly onto the roots
and growing medium of the orchid.
Uh, it's best to alternate between
different types of natural fertilizers
for your orchids every 2
weeks. This method helps provide the
plant with a full range of diverse
nutrients, avoiding nutrient excess or
deficiency while maintaining balanced
and sustainable
growth. After that, remember to place
the orchid pot in a spot with gentle
sunlight so the orchid can
photosynthesize optimally.
[Music]
And here is the result after 3 months of
care. Um, you can see the orchid leaves
have become noticeably larger, shinier,
and
[Music]
firmer. How do you find the way to
restore your weak orchid? Please write
your feedback and share your thoughts
with me.
[Music]
Besides that, the plant has grown two
new flower spikes. A clear sign that
this natural fertilizing method has
helped the orchids stay healthy, grow
well, and get ready for a promising next
blooming season.
If you care for your orchid with all the
love and patience, just like we do,
using this natural fertilizer, your
garden will always reward you with
vibrant beauty and strong vitality. A
beautiful reminder of nature's power and
the deep connection between humans and
plants. Orchids in full bloom bring you
a deep sense of tranquility, like a
gentle breeze soothing your soul.
They bring gentle, delicate joy and
brighten your living space with vibrant
natural beauty, making each day more
radiant and full of
[Music]
life. I hope you will like this video.
If you find it useful, don't forget to
like and subscribe to the channel so you
won't miss the next shares about how to
care for orchids naturally and simply.
[Music]
If you face any difficulties during the
orchid growing process, don't hesitate
to leave a comment for me. I'm always
ready to support you so you can grow
healthy orchids that bloom
[Music]
beautifully. Thank you for watching the
video. I always pray that God blesses
you all with health, happiness, and joy
on your journey of caring for plants and
in life.
[Music]