welcome to happiness Garden Channel um
happiness Garden Channel specializes in
Sharing tips for caring for orchids
using natural fertilizers promoting
sustainable growth abundant blooms and
Environmental Protection if you love
orchids as much as I do subscribe to my
channel to support me and never miss any
tips today I'm sharing how to make a
natural fertilizer from garlic that's
both simple and effective for your
orchids
I just need a clove of
[Music]
garlic garlic promotes harmonious growth
and Lush long- lasting flowering of
orchids it repels most pests and kills
spores of fungi viruses and bacteria
[Music]
substances in garlic water strengthen
the immune system of
[Music]
orchids I pour crushed garlic with 1
liter of hot water
[Music]
and this is turmeric powder was rich in
vitamins and minerals potassium calcium
magnesium sodium phosphorus iron
manganese copper selenium and zinc
increases plant resistance to fungi and
diseases while stimulating growth and
flowering
[Music]
uh incubate until the water cools so
that the nutrients from the garlic and
turmeric starch are completely dissolved
in the water
[Music]
after the water cools we filter it to
remove sediment
[Music]
fertilizer for orchids must be carefully
filtered so that organic fragments do
not rot in the
substrate guys please write a comment
letting me know which country you're
watching my video from the of
fence it's great to know that we can
communicate worldwide
[Music]
uh to know if it's time to water orchids
I look at the color of the
roots when the Orchid Roots have a light
silver color it's time to water the
Orchid
if the roots are bright green you should
wait until the roots turn pale silver
before
watering if you water when the roots are
still green The Roots will easily become
water logged and cause root rot
My Maids are tired and
sleeping and the cat seems to be hunting
down the mice that are destroying my
orchids orchids grown in pots with
drainage
holes I water this one to two times a
month soak the roots in the this water
for about 20 minutes to help the roots
absorb nutrients
[Music]
best um the finished infusion for
orchids helps strengthen the immune
system promotes the development of the
root system
this water is also very good when
sprayed on
Orchids spraying your Orchids with
garlic and turmeric water will protect
them from
diseases pests and boost their immune
system
spray the entire Orchid from leaves to
Roots but you should not water the
flowers because wet flowers will quickly
fall off
do it one to two times a
month if you have a very humid climate
orchids are susceptible to Leaf base
rot to prevent orchids from rotting at
the base of the leaves you can use
cotton balls to protect them
now spray the cotton with garlic and
turmeric
water and spray it on your orchids to
protect them from diseases pests and
boost the immune system
leave the cotton there for 20 minutes
then remove it
then you take the Clear Water above
if you don't have access to spraying
orchids you can wipe the leaves with a
cotton pad soaked in this
[Music]
water will help remove mineral salts
still attached to the leaf
surface helps orchid leaves avoid
burning when exposed to sunlight
uh this not only clears the dust but
also provides them with nutrients and
protects them from diseases and
[Music]
pests thoroughly wipe both the top and
bottom of the leaf
do this one or two times a
month uh it is enough to keep the Orchid
in this water for 20 minutes
soaked in this water The Roots will
change from Silver to purple blue like
this
[Music]
then place the Orchid pot in a warm
place with lots of diffused light so the
Orchid will grow quickly
[Music]
after 20 minutes remove the cotton ball
and place the Orchid pot in a warm place
with lots of diffused
[Music]
light
result um the leaves are always green
and shiny like this
the roots are green large and
healthy thanks to the clean Leaf surface
orchid leaves photosynthesize
better when orchids have enough light
for photosynthesis they will always be
healthier than
usual thanks to this care the Orchid
produces many
[Music]
flowers vibrant flower colors
orchids bloom all year round flowering
very long and
boldly hope you like this video
thank you for viewing good luck and
success in life
[Music]