Welcome to the happiness garden, where
every leaf and every flower tells you a
gentle story of love and life.
In this video, I continue sharing with
you how to make natural fertilizer,
gentle yet highly effective to help
revive your orchid after it has finished
blooming so it can keep growing strong
and bloom again like a radiant gift from
nature.
[Music]
Let's get started. This is an orchid
that people once thought was dead and
thrown away, but I picked it up because
I believe that with just a little hope
and gentle care, it could come back to
life and bloom once again.
First, you need to gently remove the
yellow and damaged leaves because they
no longer contribute to the plant's life
and only hinder its natural recovery
process.
[Music]
Next, trim off the withered flower
spikes because once they've lost their
original beauty, they should be removed
so the plant can focus on nourishing its
roots and leaves, preparing for a
vibrant new blooming season.
Leave a comment and let me know which
country you're watching from. It's
wonderful that we can connect and share
with each other from all around the
world.
The damaged roots, the hollow ones that
can no longer absorb water and nutrients
need to be cut off.
This is like helping the plant let go of
its burdens so it can focus its energy
on nurturing the healthy parts.
Cutting off the damaged roots also helps
the plant avoid the risk of rot
spreading to healthy roots while
creating the right conditions for new
roots to grow stronger from within.
[Music]
Then take a small lemon, squeeze out the
juice, and dilute it with clean water to
create a natural disinfecting solution.
Either yellow lemon or green lime works
just fine.
If you haven't subscribed yet, please
hit the subscribe button to support me
and never miss any orchid growing tips.
It's truly wonderful to have you along
on this journey.
Dilute it with about one liter of clean
water to create a natural disinfecting
solution.
[Music]
After mixing, use the solution to
disinfect the entire orchid from the
root. roots and stems to any cuts or
rotting spots.
[Music]
The natural lemon solution will gently
disinfect, prevent bacteria and fungi
from spreading and protect the plant
during its recovery phase.
Additionally, lemon juice contains many
beneficial minerals and vitamins that
offer natural antibacterial properties
and stimulate cell recovery. As a
result, the orchid is not only cleansed
but also energized to revive and grow
stronger.
[Music]
You can also use this mixture to soak
the entire root system and growing
medium. This helps deeply cleanse from
within, eliminate hidden pathogens in
the old medium, and protect the roots
from infection during the recovery
process.
[Music]
After watering the roots and growing
medium thoroughly, soak the entire
orchid pot in the solution for about 20
to 30 minutes.
This amount of time is enough for the
mixture to penetrate deeply and cleanse
effectively, helping to eliminate any
remaining bacteria, mold, and harmful
agents.
While waiting for the orchid to soak,
you can you can prepare another natural
ingredient, a small aloe vera leaf.
Simply
slice the aloe vera leaf into thin
pieces so that its nutrients can easily
dissolve during soaking.
This simple method helps retain the
maximum amount of gel in the leaf,
providing gentle yet highly effective
recovery benefits for the plant's roots.
Uh this succulent leaf will be used to
make a natural fertilizer helping to soo
the roots, promote cell regeneration and
support faster recovery after pruning.
[Music]
After slicing the aloe vera thinly,
place the pieces into a clean jar.
[Music]
Then pour about one liter of clean water
into the jar to soak the aloe vera
slices. As they soak, the nutrients from
the aloe will gradually dissolve,
creating a natural solution that soothes
the roots and stimulates the plant's
growth.
[Music]
Close the jar and let it sit for about 1
hour. This resting time allows the
nutrients from the aloe to gradually
infuse into the water, creating a gentle
yet revitalizing mixture, ready to
nourish the recovering roots of your
orchid.
Uh after soaking for about 30 minutes,
gently remove the orchid pot from the
solution.
At this point, the roots have been
thoroughly cleansed and disinfected,
ready for the next step in the recovery
journey.
[Music]
Next, gently apply aloe vera gel to both
the upper and lower surfaces of the
leaves.
[Music]
Um, this thin layer of gel will help
soothe the leaf surface, enhance
moisture, and create a natural
protective barrier against bacteria and
pests during the recovery period.
[Music]
After applying, let the plant rest for
about 30 minutes to allow the aloe vera
gel to fully absorb and for the cut
areas to dry out.
[Music]
After soaking for about 1 hour, strain
out the aloe vera residue and keep only
the clear liquid.
[Music]
This is a natural, nutrient-rich
solution full of minerals and moisture,
perfect for caring for the freshly
cleaned roots and leaves of the orchid.
[Music]
Next, pour the filtered aloe vera
solution into a clean spray bottle.
Then, spray it evenly over the entire
orchid from the roots and stem to both
the upper and lower sides of the leaves.
Uh this fine mist will help provide
moisture, soothe the plant and support a
gentle natural recovery.
[Music]
You can also use this solution to water
the roots directly. The nutrients in
aloe vera will penetrate deeply,
soothing the cut areas, stimulating new
root growth, and boosting the plant's
resistance during the recovery phase.
After watering, continue soaking the
orchid pot in this solution for about 20
minutes. This method allows the roots to
fully absorb the nutrients from the aloe
vera, supporting the recovery process
and encouraging the healthy growth of
new roots.
After that, gently take the orchid pot
out and place it in a spot with gentle
sunlight and good air circulation. The
soft light will help the plant recover
naturally and stimulate the
photosynthesis process.
[Music]
And here is the result after 3 weeks of
patient care.
[Music]
You can see a new chute has awakened,
emerging from the leaf axle and getting
ready to grow. Like a gentle response
from nature to the steadfast love and
care you've given the plant.
I continue caring for the plant by
applying natural fertilizer made from
aloe vera once every 2 weeks.
[Music]
I water this aloe vera mixture directly
onto the roots, helping to provide
moisture and essential nutrients to
stimulate the growth of new, stronger
roots day by day.
[Music]
I use a soft cloth, gently soak it with
the aloe vera mixture and wipe it evenly
over the leaf surfaces.
This simple method helps clean off dust,
provide natural moisture to the leaves,
and create a gentle protective barrier
against pests and diseases.
[Music]
After that, don't forget to place the
orchid pot in a spot with gentle
sunlight and fresh air. The soft light
will help the plant continue
photosynthesizing, recover more
effectively, and soon reveal the first
signs of new life.
[Music]
And here is the result after another
month.
You can see many new roots have grown
healthy, white, and full of vitality.
[Music]
From the tiny initial chute, a young
orchid has now emerged from the mother
plant. A beautiful testament to the
miraculous recovery journey made
possible by the simple wonders of
nature.
[Music]
These new roots will help the plant
absorb water and nutrients more
efficiently, providing a strong
foundation for long-term growth. With a
healthy root system, the orchid will
continue to thrive, grow lushly, and be
ready for a vibrant blooming season
ahead.
Um the leaves of the mature orchid are
gradually turning greener, thicker, and
sturdier. This is a sign that the plant
is recovering well and beginning to
store energy for continued growth uh
from the roots and stem to each
individual leaf. Subsc
[Music]
I continue to care for the orchid using
natural fertilizer made from aloe vera.
[Music]
Once the root system has grown strong
and stable, you can also alternate with
other natural fertilizers such as rice
water or oat soaking water.
These gentle nutrients will boost the
orchid's overall growth and help it get
ready for the next blooming season.
Don't forget to wipe the leaves
regularly to keep them free from dust,
well ventilated, and better able to
photosynthesize.
This is a small but very important step
to keep the plant healthy and full of
vitality.
[Music]
After that, place the orchid pot in a
spot with gentle sunlight and good air
flow. A calm, well-lit environment will
help the plant continue its recovery,
maintain energy, and get ready for new
shoots and flower buds in the near
future.
[Music]
And here is the result after 11 weeks
since the beginning of the recovery.
You can see the young orchid has grown
noticeably larger with leaves that are
firm and vibrantly green.
This shows that the plant is growing
strong from within thanks to your
patient care and the natural nutrients
you've lovingly provided.
[Music]
And here is the result after 25 weeks
since the beginning of the recovery.
As you can see, the orchid is now in
full bloom. These beautiful flowers are
not only a gift from nature, but also a
sweet reward for the gentle and
persistent care you've given throughout
the recovery journey.
[Music]
From a pot of orchid that once seemed
discarded, it has now become a beautiful
testament to resilient life and the
patient love you've given to nature.
[Music]
As long as you stay patient and care
with all your heart, the plant will
always find a way to revive and bloom
beautifully, like a gentle gift from
nature to a heart that knows how to
love.
[Music]
I hope you enjoyed this video. If you
found it helpful, don't forget to like
and subscribe so you won't miss the next
tips on how to care for orchids
naturally and simply.
[Music]
What do you think about the way I
revived this little orchid? Uh, don't
hesitate to leave a comment and share
your thoughts. I'd love to hear your
feedback and experiences.
If you face any difficulties while
growing orchids, don't hesitate to leave
a comment. I'm always here to support
you so you can grow healthy orchids that
bloom beautifully.
In addition to the English voiceover, we
have now created versions in French,
German, Italian, Spanish, Portuguese,
Japanese, Hindi, Dutch, Polish, Korean,
and Indonesian to help you listen and
understand the content more easily.
To listen to the language, open the
video and click on settings, the gear
icon to select the appropriate audio
language.
[Music]
Thank you so much for watching. I hope
this little story brings you more
inspiration and confidence to keep
nurturing the beautiful gifts of nature.
See you in the next video.
Hello everyone. Today I'm going to share
with you a simple way to make natural
fertilizer at home which will help your
orchids grow healthy, lush, and bloom
beautifully throughout the garden.
[Music]
Thanks to this natural fertilizer, the
roots and leaves of the plant will stay
healthy, which in turn helps the orchid
produce not only more flowers, but also
longerlasting blooms that retain their
color and stay on the stem for a long
time before fading.
The method is very simple. Anyone can do
it using familiar ingredients found
right in the kitchen.
Let's get started.
You can easily notice that this orchid
is having a pro problem as many of its
leaves have turned yellow and show signs
of rot.
We need to remove the damaged leaves
from the orchid immediately as this will
help the plant recover and grow better.
After removing the damaged leaves, we
need to carefully check the roots and
the orchid's growing medium to ensure
the plant is not infected and has a good
environment for for growth.
Cut off the damaged roots to help the
orchid regenerate and grow healthier.
[Music]
Um, this orchid pot I bought from an
industrial orchid garden is entirely
planted with moss which helps retain
moisture very well. However, if um if
the watering is not carefully
controlled, the plant is very prone to
root rot.
Therefore, I will remove about 2/3 of
the old moss and replace it with new
growing medium, which is pine bark. uh
to help the roots stay more airrated and
prevent water logging.
You should not completely remove the old
growing medium because the orchid still
has flowers. Keeping it will help to
maintain moisture and grow steadily.
Then remove the wilted flowers to help
the orchid focus its energy on
developing new buds and extend the
freshness of the remaining flowers on
the stem.
Next, we will prepare natural fertilizer
to help the orchid recover quickly
without affecting the beautiful flowers
remaining on the stem.
The first ingredient I need to make
natural fertilizer is coffee.
Take three teaspoons of coffee and put
them into the bottle.
[Music]
Next, pour one liter of boiling water
into the coffee bottle.
Close
the lid and let it sit overnight so the
nutrients from the coffee can fully
dissolve into the water.
[Music]
The next ingredient I will use to make
natural fertilizer is oat flour.
Take three teaspoons of oat flour and
put them into the bottle.
Then add one liter of room temperature
water to the bottle.
Um, close the lid and let it sit
overnight so the nutrients from the oat
flour can fully dissolve into the water.
[Music]
After one night, strain out the coffee
grounds and oat flour, keeping only the
liquid to use as fertilizer for the
orchid.
[Music]
After one night, strain out the coffee
grounds and oat flour, keeping only the
liquid to use as fertilizer for the
orchid.
[Music]
Step one, use a soft cotton ball to soak
up the coffee mixture and gently wipe
the top and bottom of the orchid leaves.
[Music]
Wiping the leaves with the coffee
solution helps remove dust and residue
from the leaf surface, especially the
top side where most of the
photosynthesis takes place.
Clean leaves help the plant absorb light
more effectively, thereby boosting
energy production for the orchid's
growth.
[Music]
Coffee contains natural compounds that
can gently polish the leaves, making the
orchid leaves look healthier and more
vibrant.
A glossy leaf surface not only looks
attractive, but also reflects that the
plant is in good health and thriving.
This is sy mold on the orchid. Orchids
that lack sunlight and are in humid
environments are often affected by sy
mold.
The coffee solution also helps eliminate
fungi, especially sy mold on orchid
leaves.
Diluted coffee solution can provide a
small amount of nutrients such as
potassium and antioxidants directly
supporting the nutrition of the leaves.
Um, absorption through the leaf
epidermis helps increase resistance and
improve the overall vitality of the
plant.
[Music]
The scent and natural compounds in
coffee can help reduce the presence of
small insects like aphids or fungusnats,
which are common pests that harm
orchids.
Regularly wiping the leaves helps keep
the plant clean and less prone to pest
attacks.
Coffee has mild antibacterial
properties, helping to limit the growth
of harmful mold and bacteria on the
leaves. At the same time, it creates
conditions for beneficial microorganisms
to thrive, promoting healthy orchid
leaves and reducing the risk of rot or
leaf spots.
Wiping the orchid leaves with coffee
solution one to two times a month helps
keep the plant clean, provides gentle
nutrients, and reduces insects without
overloading the plant.
Step two, pour the coffee solution into
a spray bottle and spray it evenly over
the entire orchid plant.
[Music]
Coffee has mild antibacterial
properties, helping to prevent the
growth of mold and harmful bacteria on
the leaves and stem.
[Music]
When sprayed, the coffee solution helps
wash away dirt and mold, keeping the
orchid leaves clean and healthier.
[Music]
Diluted coffee solution helps provide a
small amount of nutrients such as
potassium and antioxidants, supporting
the orchid's healthy growth and boosting
its resistance.
The natural scent of coffee helps repel
some small insects, protecting the
orchid from pest attacks.
Um, you should spray the diluted coffee
solution on the orchid about once a
month. This helps the plant absorb
nutrients effectively without
overloading it.
[Music]
Then mix the oat solution with the
coffee solution to create a natural
fertilizer rich in nutrients, helping
the orchid recover quickly and grow
healthily.
[Music]
Before mixing, we need to strain out the
oat residue to ensure that the
fertilizer solution doesn't get clogged
when used and can easily be absorbed
evenly by the orchid.
[Music]
Then soak the orchid roots in this
mixture for 20 minutes to provide direct
nutrients to the roots, stimulating
growth and rapid recovery of the plant.
[Music]
Soaking the roots in this mixture helps
with antibacterial action, disinfecting
and stimulates the growth of new roots
for the orchid.
[Music]
Um, after soaking for 20 minutes, remove
the orchid and plant it in a new pot,
providing the orchid with a better
growing environment with well-airrated
growing medium and sufficient nutrients.
[Music]
I use broken pine bark as the growing
medium for orchids to enhance root
irerration, prevent water logging, and
create an ideal environment for orchid
growth.
Please leave a comment letting me know
which country you're watching this video
from. It's amazing that we can chat
together from all around the world.
[Music]
If you haven't subscribed to the channel
yet, click the subscribe button to to
support me and never miss any orchid
care tips. It's wonderful to have you as
a companion on this journey.
[Music]
Next, spread a little moss on top of the
pot to help retain moisture for the
plant while providing a gentle
protective layer for the orchid roots,
promoting healthy growth.
[Music]
After planting, water the orchid with
this mixture once a week to provide
regular nutrients, support the plant's
strong growth, and help maintain its
overall health.
[Music]
Um, after each watering, soak the orchid
pot in this mixture for about 20 minutes
to help the plant absorb the maximum
nutrients.
Then take the orchid pot out and place
it in a spot with gentle sunlight or
diffused light to allow effective
photosynthesis, boost metabolism, and
support healthy plant growth.
[Music]
To protect the new roots as they grow,
we need to secure the orchid with a
support stick to stabilize its position,
prevent movement that could break tender
roots, and create favorable conditions
for the plant to anchor itself to the
growing medium.
[Music]
Remember, no matter how good the
fertilizer is, if the orchid lacks
sunlight, it will grow slowly, be prone
to rot, and will not be able to bloom.
Therefore, always place the orchid pot
in a spot with gentle sunlight so the
plant can photosynthesize, absorb
nutrients efficiently, and grow
healthily.
[Music]
Now, let's take a look at the results
after 3 weeks of recovery with natural
fertilizer.
[Music]
You will see new roots have grown which
shows that the orchid is recovering and
growing healthily.
These new roots help the orchid absorb
nutrients and water better, supporting
strong growth in the next blooming
cycle.
[Music]
The leaves have become plump and
greener, and the orchid looks healthy
and vibrant, which shows that the plant
has received enough nutrients and has
recovered well from the natural
fertilizer, improving its health and
promoting its growth.
[Music]
The leaves have become plump and
greener, and the orchid ID looks healthy
and vibrant, which shows that the plant
has received enough nutrients and has
recovered well from the natural
fertilizer, improving its health and
promoting its growth.
[Music]
Not only that, the orchid has also
started growing new buds, which proves
that the natural fertilizer recovery
process not only helps the plant become
healthier, but also stimulates
flowering, promising a vibrant bloom for
the next season.
[Music]
Take care of your orchid with all the
love for plants and you will see
wonderful results.
Um, each time you care for a healthy
orchid, you will gradually have a
beautiful and vibrant orchid garden like
a gift from nature to you.
[Music]
What do you think of the way I revived
my weak orchid? Please leave a comment
with your thoughts and suggestions.
I hope you enjoyed this video. If you
find it helpful, don't forget to like
and subscribe so you don't miss out on
future tips on how to care for orchids
naturally and simply.
Thank you for watching the video. I
always pray for blessings for all of
you, wishing you a healthy orchid garden
full of beautiful blooms.