welcome to happiness
Garden today we will explore how to care
for weak orchids helping them recover
strongly from Roots to leaves and Bloom
beautifully don't forget to like And
subscribe so you won't miss any great
tips you can see that this Orchid hasn't
grown for 6 months its leaves are
gradually wilting the roots are rotting
and the plant is on the brink of dying
have you ever encountered a similar
situation and didn't know what to do to
save your beloved
Orchid uh first I'll carefully remove
all the wilted and damaged leaves this
is important because unhealthy leaves
can drain the plant's energy hindering
its recovery and growth
next I'll cut off all the damaged Roots
this is essential because rotten Roots
can spread Decay to healthy parts of the
plant preventing it from from absorbing
nutrients properly
[Music]
uh finally I'll cut off any old flower
stems if present this helps the plant
Focus its energy on New Growth rather
than wasting resources on Fading flowers
[Music]
then I'll rinse the Orchid thoroughly
with water to remove any remaining dirt
or contaminants that could harm the
plant uh which country are you watching
this video from leave a comment and let
me know
it's it's amazing that we can connect
with each other from all around the
[Music]
world then I'll place the Orchid into an
empty jar
[Music]
now I'll add 1 liter of water into the
jar now next I'll add 1 teaspoon of
baking soda to the water and mix it
well baking soda helps prevent mold and
bacterial diseases on
[Music]
Orchids then I'll pour the baking soda
mixture into the jar and soak the Orchid
in it for 10 minutes to disinfect The
Roots and eliminate harmful mold and
bacteria this helps the Orchid recover
quickly prevent the recurrence of
diseases and promote the plant's
[Music]
growth next I'll take three teaspoons of
rice to make natural fertilizer for the
Orchid
add it to 1 liter of
[Music]
water rice water contains vitamins and
minerals that stimulate root development
and improve the health of wilted
orchids after rinsing the rice you can
let the rice water ferment overnight to
create beneficial bacteria for the
Orchid
[Music]
after soaking the Orchid in the baking
soda solution for 10 minutes gently
remove the plant and Pat it dry with a
soft cloth this helps remove any
residual solution prevents mold and
bacteria growth and allows the Orchid to
recover quickly and healthily
[Music]
then let it sit to allow the cut to heal
completely
this is moss for planting orchids I put
it into the
jar then pour the baking soda mixture
into the jar to soak the Moss
soaking the Moss before planting orchids
helps eliminate harmful bacteria and
mold while providing a clean and safe
environment for the orchid's roots to
thrive I soak it overnight before using
it to plant the
orchids um after one night I take the
Orchid and place the roots into the cup
like
[Music]
this then strain out the residue and
keep the rice water to make a liquid
fertilizer which is very beneficial for
orchids
[Music]
then soak the Orchid roots in the rice
water for 20 minutes this helps
stimulate rapid root growth because the
rice water is rich in nutrients and
beneficial microorg organisms that
promote root development
[Music]
while waiting I take a soft cotton pad
soak it in the rice water and gently
wipe the leaves to help revive wilted
leaves because the rice water nourishes
and moisturizes the leaves promoting
recovery and Healthy Growth
[Music]
if you haven't subscribed yet please
subscribe to support me
after soaking for 20 minutes take the
Orchid out and plant it immediately into
the new pot
[Music]
take the Moss that has been soaked in
the baking soda solution ring out the
excess water and then use it to plant
the Orchid
[Music]
planting orchids with soaked Moss helps
the wilted Orchid quickly grow roots
because Moss has good moisture retention
providing an ideal environment for
strong root development additionally
Moss retains nutrients from the soaking
solution aiding the plant in recovery
and rapid growth
[Music]
after that water the Orchid with rice
water once every 10 days to help it
recover quickly
[Music]
on regular days if the Orchid is dry you
only need to mist it with water to
maintain
moisture after watering remember to
place the Orchid pot in a spot with with
gentle sunlight so the plant can
photosynthesize and improve its
metabolic
processes the results after 3
weeks as you can see the wilted leaves
have become Greener shinier and a bit
[Music]
sturdier the orchid has also grown a new
healthy leaf that looks very
[Music]
strong the orchid has developed numerous
new Roots which efficiently absor absorb
water and
nutrients um this helps speed up the
recovery process and helps the wilted
plant recover faster
uh if you find the video helpful don't
forget to like share and subscribe to
the channel to support
me uh after that I continue taking care
of the Orchid with natural natural
fertilizer made from rice water once
every 10 days
[Music]
if you encounter any difficulties in
caring for your orchids don't hesitate
to comment below the video and I'll be
ready to advise you
the result after the next
month you can see that the orchid has
grown two new very healthy leaves which
proves that the Orchid is growing very
well showing that the care method
applied is effective
you can see that the orchid has grown
two new very healthy leaves which proves
that the Orchid is growing very well
showing that the care method applied is
effective
you can see that the orchid has grown
two new very healthy leaves which proves
that the Orchid is growing very well
showing that the care method applied is
[Music]
effective the result after the next 3
months
you can see that the orchid has almost
fully recovered with the leaves becoming
healthy and
strong and the orchid has even grown a
new flower Spike that's very healthy
with this simple care routine the orchid
has quickly recovered and bloomed
beautifully just like any other healthy
[Music]
Orchid this natural fertilizer not only
supports the recovery process of your
beloved Orchid but also helps the
flowers bloom more vibrantly
uh last longer and stay in bloom for up
to 6 months before
[Music]
wilting I hope this video will be
helpful to you in caring for orchids at
home if you find it useful please like
share and subscribe to the channel
[Music]
thank you all for watching I always pray
that blessings will come to
you wishing everyone good health goodbye
and see you next
time welcome to my
channel today's video I share how to
easily make your own fertilizer but its
effects are
miraculous it's amazing how we connect
from all around the
world where are you watching from let me
know in the
comments if you haven't subscribed to
the channel yet please subscribe to my
channel to support me and not miss any
orchid care tips on my channel thank you
very much for always accompanying me
let's explore this wonderful way to make
natural
fertilizer to make this magical
fertilizer you need
[Music]
flour I took 3 tbsp of
flour and take another spoon full of
yeast the type of yeast used to make
bread
[Music]
add a little warm water
then incubate for 2 hours for The
Beneficial microorganisms in the yeast
to take
[Music]
effect after 2 hours
currently the beneficial microorganisms
in yeast have multiplied many times over
[Music]
mix with 5 liters of water
first
[Music]
method water the Orchid roots with this
microbial fertilizer solution beneficial
beneficial microorganisms will grow in
the Orchid pot helps protect Orchid
roots from rot caused by fungi and
bacteria
you
[Music]
this type of fertilizer also balances
the pH level in Orchid pots helps
stimulate Orchid roots to grow and not
be damaged by acid
[Music]
this type of fertilizer also provides
many necessary nutrients for orchids
such as potassium phosphorus nitrogen
magnesium calcium iron zinc and vitamins
[Music]
it would be better to soak the Orchid
pot for 20 minutes
[Music]
this type of fertilizer is especially
good for weak stunted orchids uh with
underdeveloped root systems because it
does not Shock weak orchids like
chemical fertilizers
[Music]
second
method wipe the leaves clean with this
microbial fertilizer solution helps
eliminate insects and leaf damaging
fungi
[Music]
this work also improves photosynthesis
helping plants grow
[Music]
better third method
method spray this fertilizer solution
over the entire
Orchid this method helps provide
nutrients directly to both roots and
leaves
this not only cleans but also helps the
plant absorb beneficial microorganisms
thereby improving overall
health especially for weak orchids it
will help them recover quickly by
providing necessary nutrients and
fostering a healthier environment for
root and leaf
growth uh let's see the results with
proper care and the use of a natural
fertilizer solution your orchid will
hopefully grow strong and healthy
if you do this every 2 weeks after only
1 to two months the Orchid will have
many new
[Music]
Roots this helps the Orchid absorb
maximum nutrients through its
[Music]
roots if you find the video interesting
remember to like share and subscribe to
my channel for support thank you for
watching and supporting the channel
um flowers bloom brightly and colorfully
filling your space with vibrant Beauty
and
life this careful care and natural
fertilizer helps orchids Thrive
producing beautiful blooms that are a
true reward for your
dedication many flowers bloom on the
same Branch creating a beautiful display
of color and
vitality this abundant flowering shows
that the Orchid is receiving proper care
and that nutrients from natural
fertilizers are are supporting its
growth and
flowering it is a great sign of a
healthy and thriving
[Music]
tree thank you for watching the video
good
[Music]
luck goodbye and see you again in the
next video