Welcome to Happiness Garden, where every
leaf and every petal tells us a gentle
story of love for nature and care from
the
[Music]
heart. Let's discover together the
wonders that come from the smallest
things in this
garden. After buying an orchid and
enjoying its blooms, the plant often
starts to decline. Yellowing leaves,
weak roots, and a tired look.
Sadly, many people throw it away too
soon, not knowing there's still a strong
life force inside waiting to be
revived. Many orchids here have been
discarded
[Music]
wastefully. This orchid, although
weakened, still has fresh green leaves,
a sign that it's alive. So, I decided to
take it home to care for and revive it,
hoping to bring it back to full
strength. We need to gently remove the
old growing medium, which may hold dust
and bacteria, and repot the orchid into
a new container to give it a better
environment to grow.
This helps the roots breathe and absorb
nutrients and water more effectively,
supporting the recovery process.
[Music]
After removing all the old growing
medium, we trim away all the damaged
roots, those that are rotten or no
longer able to absorb water and
nutrients.
[Music]
This helps the plant focus its energy on
growing new healthy roots, increasing
its chances of recovery and healthy
growth.
[Music]
Next, we cut off the dry flower spikes
and old weak
[Music]
stems. This helps the plant save energy
and focus nutrients on its healthy
leaves and roots, promoting new growth
and preparing for more vibrant blooms in
the future.
Next, we remove the wilted and yellow
leaves as they no longer perform
photosynthesis well and may harbor
harmful
bacteria. This keeps the plant clean and
allows it to focus nutrients on healthy
leaves, supporting recovery and growth.
Next, we rinse the entire orchid
thoroughly with clean water to remove
dust, bacteria, and impurities from the
leaves, roots, and
stem. This step creates a clean
environment, reduces the risk of
infection, and helps the plant absorb
nutrients more effectively during
recovery.
[Music]
Next, I sterilize the moss used as the
orchid growing
medium. This step is crucial to
eliminate bacteria, mold, and harmful
agents that might exist in the moss,
creating a clean and safe environment
for the orchid roots to grow strong.
I soak the moss in hot water to
sterilize it, effectively removing
bacteria, mold, and insects that may be
hidden inside.
[Music]
I soak the moss in hot water to
sterilize it, effectively removing
bacteria, mold, and insects that may be
hidden inside.
Next, we prepare a natural fertilizer to
restore the orchid's
health. Take one liter of clean water as
the base to dissolve the fertilizer
ingredients.
[Music]
Here is the banana extract, GE banana
that I made 3 weeks
ago. It is a natural fertilizer rich in
nutrients, helping stimulate strong
growth from roots to leaves while also
promoting recovery after the plant has
[Music]
weakened. Take 50 ml of banana extract
and mix it into one liter of clean
water. This ratio creates a balanced
fertilizer solution, providing enough
nutrients for the orchid to absorb
effectively without causing irritation
or damage during
recovery. You can refer to the video
tutorial on how to make banana extract
GE banana via the link in the
description of this video.
[Music]
Next, soak the entire orchid in the
banana extract fertilizer solution for
about 20
[Music]
minutes. This allows the plant to absorb
nutrients directly and deeply,
supporting faster recovery and boosting
its resilience.
[Music]
While waiting, I recycle old plastic
cups to make recovery pots for the
orchids. This is an economical and
eco-friendly way also providing good
erration and drainage for the roots to
grow strong.
[Music]
after soaking the orchid for about 20
minutes. Remember to gently remove the
plant.
Use a soft cloth to gently pat dry the
water droplets on the leaves and between
the leaf
folds. This helps prevent prolonged
moisture, reducing the risk of mold and
leaf diseases while keeping the plant
clean and healthy.
[Music]
Once the water has fully cooled, take
out the moss and prepare it for
repotting the orchid.
[Music]
The clean sterilized moss provides an
ideal environment helping the orchid
roots grow strong and the plant recover
faster.
[Music]
Next, plant the orchid in the pot using
the sterilized moss as the growing
medium.
[Music]
Gently place the roots into the moss,
making sure they have good contact with
the medium without being too tightly
packed to allow proper air flow and
encourage healthy root growth.
[Music]
after planting from Now on, water the
orchid once every 10 days with the
diluted banana GE
solution. This regular watering helps
provide nutrients to the plant
regularly, supporting healthy root
growth and green leaves during
recovery. Just about 5 tablespoons of
the diluted banana GE solution is enough
for each watering.
This moderate amount allows the plant to
absorb nutrients effectively without
causing overwatering or wasting
fertilizer. Then place the orchid pot in
a spot with gentle sunlight, good air
circulation, and protection from heavy
rain. Soft morning or late afternoon
light helps the plant photosynthesize
better, supporting recovery and growth
without burning the leaves.
[Music]
Um, put put the remaining fertilizer
mixture into a spray bottle and mist it
onto the orchids that are currently
blooming.
[Music]
This method delivers nutrients directly
to the leaves and flowers, promoting
healthy growth and enhancing the
longevity and vibrancy of the
[Music]
blooms. The natural potassium content in
the banana extract, GE, helps the orchid
petals last longer, potentially keeping
the flowers fresh for up to 6 months.
Now, I invite you to join me in seeing
the results after 3 weeks of orchid
recovery. Oh, can you see the new white
root growing inside the orchid
pot? Let's check the roots inside the
orchid pot together.
[Music]
Wow. You can see the orchid has grown
many new roots which shows the plant is
recovering very well and ready for the
next strong growth phase.
These new roots increase its ability to
absorb water and nutrients, bringing
vibrant life to the
[Music]
plant. How do you find the way to
restore your weak orchid? Please write a
comment to let me know your
[Music]
opinion. If you find the content
interesting and meaningful, don't forget
to like, share. so that many people know
and subscribe to the channel to support
me. Thank you for always accompanying
[Music]
me. Once the orchid has developed many
new roots, I transplanted into a new pot
filled with pine bark as the growing
medium.
Pine bark improves irerration and
drainage, creating an ideal environment
for the roots to grow stronger, helping
the plant become healthier and ready for
vibrant blooming cycles ahead.
[Music]
If you haven't subscribed to the channel
yet, please hit the subscribe button to
support me and not miss any orchid
growing tips. Um, it's great to have you
along. After planting, we prepare
natural fertilizer to care for the
orchid.
To make natural fertilizer, I take I
take one tablespoon of wheat flour
diluted in one liter of
water. This mixture provides gentle
nutrients and helps stimulate beneficial
microorganisms in the growing medium,
contributing to the orchid's health
naturally and
[Music]
effectively. After mixing, strain out
the sediment so the solution becomes
clear and can penetrate the growing
medium and roots more
[Music]
easily. This helps the natural
fertilizer work most effectively without
clogging or harming the
orchid. Then apply this fertilizer twice
a month to provide consistent nut
nutrients for the orchid.
Regular feeding helps the plant grow
steadily, boosts its resistance, and
prepares it well for future blooming
[Music]
cycles. Then place the orchid pot in a
spot with gentle sunlight so the plant
can photosynthesize. Only with good
photosynthesis can the orchid absorb
nutrients effectively.
[Music]
And here is the result after 5 months of
recovery.
Like you can see that the orchid has
grown vigorously with many new roots
growing and the leaves are greener and
shinier than
[Music]
before. Especially the orchid has
bloomed with new flowers. A wonderful
achievement after a journey of patient
and loving
[Music]
care. This moment brings not only joy
but also motivation to keep nurturing
our love for orchids.
[Music]
Uh, thank you for joining me on this
orchid recovery
[Music]
journey. I hope these tips help you care
for and cherish your orchids even more.
[Music]
Don't forget to like, share, and
subscribe so you won't miss upcoming
helpful videos. See you next time.