welcome to my
channel if you have a wilted Orchid like
this don't rush to throw it
[Music]
away um now I share how to recover
quickly with natural
[Music]
fertilizers please remove inor organic
fertilizers and damaged
[Music]
Roots because the roots do not rot I
keep the old planting material to help
the Orchid recover
[Music]
quickly and remove all yellow and rotten
leaves
[Music]
which country are you watching videos
from please comment for
[Music]
me uh it's great that we can chat
together from all over the world
[Music]
if you haven't subscribed yet please
subscribe to support me and to not miss
any Orchid growing tips
[Music]
now you need to soak the entire orchid
in water at room temperature for 1
hour this helps to quickly restore
wilted roots and
leaves awaken the ability of fresh roots
and leaves to absorb
[Music]
water place in a cool place for 1 hour
now you take 1/3 teaspoon of sugar
[Music]
mix with 500 mm of water at room
temperature then take 500 milon of warm
water
[Music]
add 1 teaspoon of dry yeast yeast used
to make bread
[Music]
wait 1 hour for the yeast to develop
before using it as
fertilizer after soaking for 1 hour take
the Orchid out
[Music]
then soak the leaves in sugar water for
30 minutes
[Music]
no
after soaking for 30 minutes take the
Orchid
[Music]
out nutrients and sugar penetrate the
leaves helping wilted leaves recover
quickly
[Music]
now mix the sugar water with the dry
yeast
[Music]
solution uh this will create a natural
fertilizer that will stimulate strong
rooting and plant recovery
[Music]
soak the Orchid root in this water for
30 minutes will help stimulate rooting
extremely quickly
[Music]
the remaining liquid fertilizer is used
to water Orchid
[Music]
pots water each Orchid pot with 10
tablespoons
[Music]
this fertilizer helps stimulate root
growth a strong root system will help
the Orchid absorb nutrients
[Music]
best doing this one to two times a month
will be very good for the Orchid
[Music]
wa
water the Orchid roots with this
microbial fertilizer solution beneficial
microorganisms will grow in the Orchid
pot helps protect Orchid roots from rot
caused by fungi and bacteria
[Music]
this type of ferer also helps balance
the pH level in Orchid pots help
stimulate Orchid roots to grow and not
be damaged by
[Music]
acid after soaking for 30 minutes take
the Orchid out
[Music]
The Roots have become juicier and
Greener I use pine bark to grow orchids
[Music]
cover the surface of the Orchid pot with
a little Moss helps retain moisture
better
[Music]
then apply this microbial fertilizer to
the orchids every 2
weeks uh will create beneficial
organisms in the growing environment and
stimulate Orchid roots
uh on weekday you just need to spray
mist to keep it moist and water when the
substrate is
[Music]
dry then place the Orchid pot in a cool
place with enough light for the orcan to
recover
[Music]
results after 1
month after only one month Orchid Roots
have grown a lot and are
[Music]
healthy um these new Roots will help the
Orchid absorb nutrients and water best
[Music]
and gradually the leaves will become
fresh again
[Music]
take 1/5 teaspoon of sugar
[Applause]
[Music]
and take 1/5 teaspoon of dry
yeast mix with 300 mm warm water
[Music]
and wait until the water cools to room
temperature then use this microbial
fertilizer to water every 2
[Music]
weeks this type of fertilizer is
especially good for weak stunted Orchids
with underdeveloped Roots because it
does not Shock weak orchids like
chemical
[Music]
fertilizers um placing it in a place
with light sunlight will be best for
[Music]
orchids after the next 1 month
um the orchid has completely recovered
[Music]
the leaves are normal green and
thick the roots are very fat and have
many new roots
[Music]
hope the video will help you a
lot if you find it interesting please
like share and subscribe to my support
Channel thank you for
watching good luck and see you in the
next videos