welcome to my
channel in this video I continue to
share a new way to make organic
fertilizer for orchids helps orchids
grow healthily and Bloom continuously
all year
round if you haven't subscribed to the
channel yet please click the Subscribe
button to support me and not miss any
Orchid growing
tips it's great to have
company let's get
started after buying the Orchid the
orchid has finished blooming and entered
the withering stage of the Flower Branch
don't rush to throw it
away um let me share how they can grow
and continue to
bloom first you need to remove all
wilted petals
[Music]
then throw away this old plastic Orchid
pot then cut off all damag
[Music]
Roots this helps the roots Branch
quickly and not rot
in addition to the English dub we've now
created dubs in French German Italian
Spanish Portuguese Japanese Hindi and
Indonesian to help you hear and
understand the content videos are
easier when transplanted to a new pot
these branched roots will grow very
[Music]
strongly but if we don't replant it in a
new pot The Roots will rot very quickly
so cut off damaged
leaves please comment to me which
country you are watching the video from
it's great that we can chat together
from all over the world
if you encounter any difficulties during
the Orchid growing process don't
hesitate to comment I am always ready to
support you so you can grow healthy
orchids and Bloom lots of
flowers then take one
onion and take its
[Music]
shell onion peels contain many
antioxidants and antibacterial compounds
which help strengthen orchid's
resistance and protect them from
diseases when onion peels decompose they
provide nutrients such as potassium
calcium and magnesium helping plants
grow
healthily put all the onion skins in the
jar
[Music]
add 1 liter of boiled water about 4 cups
of
water then take 3 tablespoons of oatmeal
[Music]
oats contain many nutrients including
vitamins minerals and proteins which
help provide nutrition for work
kids oats have good moisture retention
ability ability helping to maintain
moisture in Orchid soil especially on
hot
days incubate and wait until the water
[Music]
cools now take one teaspoon of baking
soda
[Music]
add 1 liter of water about 4
cups baking soda has anti-fungal
properties helping to prevent common
fungal diseases in orchids such as mold
then pour the baking soda solution in to
soak use a soft cotton pad to thoroughly
wipe the top and bottom of the leaves
with baking soda solution
baking soda solution has antifungal
properties helping to prevent the
development of fungal diseases on orchid
leaves wiping leaves helps remove dirt
and impurities helping leaves absorb
light better thereby promoting photo
[Music]
synthesis soak Orchid roots in this
water for 20
minutes 30 minutes
later after soaking for 20 minutes take
the Orchid out and plant it in a new
pot planted with deep pine bark helps
moisturize better
is
after the water cools
[Music]
filter out residue
add 1 liter of
[Music]
water add 1 liter of water
the nutrients in the onion skin will
penetrate the leaves helping the plant
absorb more necessary
[Music]
minerals wiping leaves with onion peel
water helps remove dirt and impurities
cleaning the leaf surface for more
effective photosynthesis
[Music]
from now on do this once a month to
protect orchid
[Music]
leaves then use this water to water the
orchids
[Music]
as onion skin decomposes it provides
nutrients such as potassium calcium and
magnesium which help the plant grow
[Music]
healthily onion peels have the ability
to retain moisture helping to maintain
moisture in Orchid soil which is
essential for root growth
[Music]
soak in this water for 20
minutes or you can also put this water
in a spray bottle
[Music]
then spray the entire
Orchid this method is similar to folar
fertilization for orchids
[Music]
after soaking for 20 minutes take the
Orchid pot out and place it in a place
with light sunlight for the Orchid to
photosynthesize
[Music]
results after 1
month Orchid branches continue to
[Music]
flower the petals are very thick and
beautiful
[Music]
brilliant colors
The Roots grow
healthily um healthy Roots help plants
absorb water and essential nutrients
from the environment ensuring good
growth Roots play an important role in
regulating the plant's humidity
preventing orchids from drying out or
root
[Music]
R Roots also produce hormones that help
promote plant growth including flowering
and new
[Music]
leaves the leaves also become Greener
and glossier
[Music]
um this proves proves that the Orchid is
in a very healthy
period take care of your Orchids with
all the love you have for
plants and you'll be rewarded with
beautiful flowers that you you take care
of
yourself I hope this video will be an
inspiration and helpful for you in
taking care of your beloved orchids at
home if you find this content
interesting don't forget to hit the
Subscribe button so you won't miss out
on more helpful
tips thank you for watching the video I
ask God to bless you