welcome to my
channel uh there are different ways to
restore wilted and rootless
orchids today I share a new way to
orchids hope it will help you in
choosing a method to restore your
orchid if you haven't subscribed to the
channel yet please click the Subscribe
button to support me and not miss any
Orchid growing tips it's great to have
company if you have a wilted Orchid like
this don't throw it away just do as I
[Music]
instruct first we need to check the
roots then cut off all damage
Roots please comment to me which country
you are watching the video from it's
great that we can chat together from all
over the
[Music]
world uh create a layer of molten candle
wax on the freshly cut wound it will
help prevent the Orchid from
[Music]
dehydrating use one clove of
garlic add 2 cups of room temperature
water about5 l
[Music]
then puree in
water filter out
residue pour a portion into this jar
[Music]
uh the remaining garlic juice is used to
clean orchid
[Music]
leaves garlic has an antiseptic effect
at the same time garlic also contains
many nutrients necessary for plant
growth and will help the Orchid recover
very quickly
[Music]
next I soaked the Orchid root in garlic
water for 30
[Music]
minutes 30 minutes later
in addition to the English dub we've now
created dubs in French German Italian
Spanish Portuguese Japanese Hindi and
Indonesian to help you hear and
understand the content more easily
[Music]
growing upside down orchids in jars
we just need to pour some water in the
bottom of the
jar only refill When the Water Runs
[Music]
Out clip cotton soaked in garlic juice
to the base of the Orchid and repeat
every 7
[Music]
Days place in a cool place
clip cotton soaked in garlic juice to
the base of the Orchid and repeat every
days then leave it in a cool place to
[Music]
recover 2 months
wow you can see amazing results
[Music]
right the orchid has given birth to a
lot of new
Roots um orchid leaves also recover
quickly because the humidity in the vase
is very
[Music]
high um The Roots have grown very
strongly if you find it interesting
don't forget to like share and subscribe
to the channel to support
[Music]
me um we plant orchids in new pots to
adapt to the outside environment
[Music]
I spread gravel underneath to give the
Orchid Roots ventilation and limit root
[Music]
Rod add a little moss on top to keep it
moist from now on you water and care for
orchids like any other plant
nurture your orchid with all your love
and care and in return it will Bloom
with radiant flowers spreading a gentle
fragrance in the breeze bringing you
peace freshness and relieving all
stress thank you for taking the time to
watch the video I always pray that God
blesses you with joy happiness and peace
in
life goodbye and see you in the next
videos
Hello
friends I am an expert in organic
fertilizers and orchid care
techniques in this video I show you how
to rejuvenate an old Orchid and the
secret to Reviving The Orchid to take
root and produce young
leaves uh if you haven't subscribed to
the channel yet please click the
Subscribe button to support me and not
miss any Orchid growing tips it's great
to have company
[Music]
now remove all damaged leaves to help
the Orchid concentrate nutrients on
healthy Parts stimulating the growth of
new roots and leaves
[Music]
then cut off damaged roots to create
conditions for healthy roots to grow
better
[Music]
rinse with
water uh this helps eliminate fungal and
bacterial diseases that cause root
rot use one clove of
garlic garlic has antiseptic properties
that help prevent rot and stimulate root
growth and development for orchids
[Music]
use one sprig of fresh
ginger add 300 M of filtered water about
[Music]
cup garlic and ginger have a very good
effect on stimulating germination and
root growth
puree the garlic and ginger to extract
their beneficial compounds for the
[Music]
orchids filter out the residue to obtain
a clear solution for easy absorption by
the Orchid roots
[Music]
soak Orchid branches in garlic and
ginger juice for 20 minutes to disinfect
stimulate root growth and enhance
resistance to
[Music]
diseases after soaking for 20 minutes
take out the Orchid stem and let it dry
naturally before planting
[Music]
wipe the Orchid stem gently and wait for
the cut to dry completely before
planting to prevent
[Music]
infection then drop melted wax onto the
cut to help it heal quickly and prevent
[Music]
infection recycle plastic boxes into
many green houses to help weak orchids
grow faster by maintaining humidity and
warmth
[Music]
place the Orchid branches inside the the
miniature Greenhouse to create a warm
humid environment that promotes faster
root growth and
Recovery add water to the miniature
Greenhouse ensuring that it creates
humidity but does not touch the Orchid
branches this helps maintain moisture
while preventing
rot place the Orchid in a cool area with
a temperature between 20 to 30° C
ensuring it gets light but avoiding
direct sunlight this creates the ideal
environment for Healthy
Growth now I will rejuvenate this old
Orchid to help it grow strong and Bloom
beautifully again
[Music]
water once every 2 weeks and keep it in
a cool place as mentioned earlier to
support Healthy
Growth results after 5
[Music]
weeks the old Orchid stem has been
rejuvenated grown new healthy roots and
grown two healthy baby orchids
[Music]
the Orchid branch has grown many roots
and is very
[Music]
healthy and developed one more Young
Leaf
[Music]
now I plant in pots to grow orchids in
the outside
[Music]
environment after planting you take care
of them like any other normal plant
[Music]
if you find the video meaningful please
subscribe to help the channel reach 10
million subscribers
[Music]
soon and don't rush to leave the video
because in part two I share how to grow
orchids
welcome to happiness Garden
channel in this video I share how to
grow it to grow
[Music]
fast when I just bought orchids we
remove all this
Moss uh because these Orchid pots are
grown in an industrial environment
controlled by temperature humidity and
uh ideal for orchid
but when brought back the environment
has changed making these roots
susceptible to rot therefore you should
cut off damaged
Roots please comment to
me which country you are watching the
video from it's great that we can chat
together from all over the
world then wash the roots
[Music]
taking advantage of used plastic bottles
I recycled them into hydroponic Orchid
[Music]
pots this method of planting will not
require watering but will still help
orchids grow very healthily and produce
more beautiful and vibrant flowers
[Music]
recycling plastic bottles to make Orchid
pots is not only a great way to
repurpose used materials uh but also
helps protect the environment this way
we reduce plastic waste while creating
unique and sustainable Orchid pots
[Music]
if you haven't subscribed to the channel
yet please click the Subscribe button to
support me and not miss any Orchid
growing tips it's great to have
company I need to wash the plastic
bottle to make sure it's clean from
fungi and bacteria that are harmful to
the Orchid
[Music]
using the drill bit will cut out the
positions here
[Music]
this part will be used as an orchid
pot the rest is for water storage
[Music]
using a glass jar on the bottom will
help the roots not absorb too much water
[Music]
put the Orchid
in put terracotta seeds around the
pot grown in a semi-hydroponic
environment often in contact with water
so we use breathable terracotta beads as
the best
[Music]
if it's breathable it's very rarely
rotten and after planting The Roots will
grow very
[Music]
fast so I've finished planting
you water the potted
plants we only water once next time you
don't need to water
[Music]
anymore with this simple planting method
you save a lot of time to take care
[Music]
of with this planting method you will
let the water level cover part of the
bottom of the
[Music]
pot the water will absorb itself helping
to maintain the moisture in the growing
medium we will not need to water
[Music]
anymore when the water in the container
is empty remember to add more water to
keep the growing medium in a moist state
[Music]
and this is the Orchid I planted it
using this method you can see it grows
very
quickly the flowers are durable and have
many flower stems on the same
[Music]
branch and I also grow this Orchid using
the semi hydroponic method using pine
bark when it flowers it has vibrant
colors and stays fresh
[Music]
longer uh growing semih hydroponic
orchids the moisture is always
wellmaintained the roots will grow very
quickly a strong root system will help
the plant perform metabolism and absorb
organic fertilizer and water very well
uh with this simple planting method we
will get orchids that grow
faster I hope this video provides useful
information to help you take great care
of your orchids at home if you found it
helpful don't forget to like share it so
more people can learn too and subscribe
to the channel to stay connected with me
thank you for watching wishing you a
wonderful day and see you in the next
videos
[Music]