Welcome to my channel. Today I want to
continue sharing with you a simple but
effective care method that helps your
orchid maintain continuous blooming
cycles while still keeping its natural
health. Orchids will always respond to
the love and patience you give them.
This orchid of mine has just gone
through a blooming cycle, so it has
become quite weak and needs time to
recover. When all the flowers fall off,
the plant's energy has been focused on
nourishing the blooms. So, it doesn't
have much strength left. Therefore, we
need to care for and restore the plant
in a timely manner so it can regain its
vitality and prepare for the next
blooming cycle.
First, we need to cut off the damaged
roots. These root parts can no longer
absorb water or nutrients and can even
cause rot to spread to the healthy
roots. By removing them, you are helping
the plant lighten its load and creating
conditions for new, stronger roots to
grow.
[Music]
Let me know in the comments which
country you're watching from. It's
wonderful that we can chat with each
other from all around the world.
[Music]
If you haven't subscribed yet, please
click the subscribe button to support me
and not miss any orchid growing tips.
It's wonderful to have you with me.
[Music]
Next, cut off the damaged or yellowing
leaves. These leaves can no longer
perform photosynthesis effectively and
may drain the plant's energy, even
becoming spots where diseases can easily
develop.
[Music]
Now, we will cut off the old and dry
flower stems. These stems no longer have
aesthetic or nutritional value for the
plant. And if left, they can reduce the
plant's overall vitality.
After finishing the pruning, you should
let the plant rest for a few days to
allow the cuts to heal. This is an
important step to help the plant avoid
infection or rot.
After a few days of rest, we will start
making a natural fertilizer to restore
the plant's health. This time, the
ingredient I chose is wheat flour, a
nutrientrich source of energy that helps
the plant quickly recover its roots and
leaves while creating favorable
conditions for new flower shoots to grow
vigorously.
You only need one full teaspoon of wheat
flour, enough to provide the necessary
nutrients without overdoing it.
[Music]
The next ingredient is aloe vera, and
you only need a small leaf.
Aloe vera not only provides water, but
also contains many vitamins and
minerals, helping the plant recover
quickly with greener, shinier, and
smoother leaves.
Then add 500 ml of water to the wheat
flour and aloe vera leaf and grind
thoroughly so that all the nutrients are
completely dissolved.
[Music]
Next, strain out the solids from the
mixture. This helps make the solution
smooth.
[Music]
Next, dilute the solution with an
additional 500 ml of clean water. This
step helps thin the mixture just enough
for the plant to absorb easily without
being too thick while ensuring the
nutrients spread evenly to the roots,
leaves, and flower shoots, helping the
plant recover more healthily.
[Music]
Step one, water this natural fertilizer
mixture directly onto the roots and the
growing medium.
As the solution soaks in, the roots will
quickly absorb the necessary nutrients,
helping the plant regain vitality, grow
vigorously, and prepare for new flower
shoots.
When applying this fertilizer, the
nutrients from the wheat flour and aloe
vera will penetrate deeply into the
growing medium and the roots.
The orchid roots are provided with full
energy and minerals, helping them grow
strong, anchor firmly in the medium, and
enhance their ability to absorb water
and nutrients for the plant.
The vitamins and minerals from aloe vera
combined with the energy from wheat
flour help the leaves become green,
shiny, smooth, and full of vitality.
Healthy leaves are an important
foundation for good photosynthesis,
providing a solid energy source for
flower shoots and the overall
development of the plant.
Step two, pour the natural fertilizer
mixture into a spray bottle. This allows
you to evenly mist the solution over the
entire plant from the roots and growing
medium to the leaves and flower shoots,
ensuring that every part receives
nutrients effectively.
[Music]
When spraying, make sure to cover both
the top and underside of the leaves. The
fine mist will evenly coat them,
allowing the nutrients to penetrate
deeply and be better absorbed while also
enhancing pest prevention and
stimulating the orchid to grow
healthily.
[Music]
When sprayed directly onto the leaves
and stems, the nutrients penetrate
straight into the leaf tissue, providing
essential vitamins and minerals. The
leaves become green, firm, and
healthier, enhancing photosynthesis and
energy storage for the plant.
[Music]
The solution sprayed on the stems and
leaves also helps the plant receive
signals to develop flower shoots. When
the leaves and stems are healthy, the
plant has enough stored energy to
produce new buds, preparing for a more
vibrant next blooming cycle.
Besides the leaves and stems, you should
also spray directly onto the plant's
roots. Uh, as the nutrients penetrate
the roots, they are quickly absorbed,
helping the roots grow strong, anchor
firmly in the medium, and support the
plant in restoring energy while
preparing well for new flower shoots.
After watering, you can soak the roots
and growing medium in this natural
fertilizer mixture for about 20 minutes.
[Music]
After soaking the roots and growing
medium for about 20 minutes, remember to
gently remove the orchid pot. This step
helps prevent prolonged water logging
and ensures the roots do not rot.
Step three. After soaking, if the leaves
are still wet, gently use a soft cloth
to blot all the water from the leaves.
[Music]
This helps prevent prolonged water
accumulation that can cause mold or leaf
rot while keeping the plant dry,
healthy, and ready to absorb nutrients
from its surroundings.
[Music]
After drying the leaves, place the
orchid pot in a spot with gentle
sunlight. Adequate light will help the
plant photosynthesize effectively,
promote shiny green leaves, strong
roots, and vigorous flower shoots, while
preventing the leaves from burning or
wilting.
[Music]
And here are the results after 1 month
of restorative care using natural
fertilizer made from wheat flour and
aloe vera for the plant.
You can see that the roots have firmly
anchored into the medium and the leaves
have become green, shiny, firm and full
of vitality. This shows that the plant
has recovered well after the blooming
cycle and is ready for new flower shoots
to develop.
[Music]
And the special thing is that you can
see new flower shoots beginning to
emerge, signaling that a vibrant
blooming cycle is approaching. The
orchid is now healthier, full of energy
to bloom and showcase its beauty in the
coming period.
The roots grow strong and anchor firmly
into the medium, creating a solid
foundation for the plant to to absorb
water and nutrients effectively.
This is an important factor that helps
the orchid recover quickly, maintain
healthy leaves, and prepare for new
flower shoots to emerge.
[Music]
The aerial roots are also growing
healthily, indicating that the orchid's
growing environment in the garden is
very suitable. When the aerial roots are
strong, the plant can absorb more oxygen
and nutrients from the air, helping the
orchid increase its vitality, develop
smooth green leaves, and produce flower
shoots more consistently.
[Music]
When you care for your orchid with all
the love and patience you give to
plants, you will be rewarded
accordingly. Shiny green leaves, strong
roots, and fresh flower shoots will be
proof of the love and effort you have
invested in the plant.
[Music]
and believe that with dedicated and
patient care, flowers will bloom all
over the garden, vibrant with a variety
of colors. Each flower is the result of
your love, effort, and perseverance,
turning the garden into a lively,
vibrant painting full of life.
I hope you enjoy this video. If you find
it helpful, don't forget to hit like and
subscribe to the channel so you won't
miss future tips on caring for orchids
in a natural and simple way.
[Music]
Um, thank you so much for watching. I
truly appreciate your time and support.
Don't forget to like, subscribe, and
share if you enjoyed this video. Wishing
you a wonderful day filled with joy and
blooming orchids. See you in the next
video.