Welcome to the happiness garden where we
explore simple yet effective orchid care
tips together so each passing day is
filled with blooming flowers and joy.
In today's video, I will share with you
a very simple way to propagate orchids
at home using the very flower spikes
that have already bloomed. Gentle,
natural, yet highly effective.
Please leave a comment letting me know
which country you're watching from. Um,
it's wonderful that we can connect and
share from all around the world.
[Music]
Do you have eggs?
Every time you eat eggs, don't be quick
to throw away the shells. Keep them as
they are a wonderful natural fertilizer
that helps your orchids grow healthier
and more vibrant each day.
[Music]
You just need to take about two
eggshells, then rinse them under running
water to remove any remaining egg white.
This small step helps reduce odor and
keeps your fertilizer safe for the
plant.
[Music]
After rinsing, crush the eggshells into
small pieces and put them into a clean
bottle.
[Music]
Um, the next ingredient I need is
banana, a familiar fruit that contains
many nutrients beneficial for the growth
of orchid roots and leaves.
[Music]
When eating bananas, don't throw away
the peels as they contain plenty of
potassium and natural minerals that help
orchids grow strong, root quickly,
and increase their blooming potential.
Uh, set aside a small portion of the
banana peel for later use and cut the
remaining peel into small pieces to put
into the bottle along with the
eggshells. This natural combination will
create a wonderful nutrient mix for your
orchid.
[Music]
Then pour about one liter of boiling
water into the bottle. The hot water
will help release the nutrients from the
eggshells and banana peels, creating a
natural nutrient tea for your orchid.
Close
[Music]
the lid and let the mixture cool down.
During this time, the nutrients will
gradually dissolve into the water, ready
to nourish your orchid in a natural and
effective way.
[Music]
Now take the inner side of the remaining
banana peel and gently rub it on the top
surface of the orchid leaves.
This soft inner layer not only helps
clean off dust but also provides extra
nutrients making the leaves shiny,
healthy, and better at absorbing light.
[Music]
Wiping the leaves with banana peel also
helps remove dust and some harmful
bacteria while providing a thin layer of
natural nutrients on the leaf surface.
This allows the plant to photosynthesize
better and grow stronger each day.
[Music]
Please comment and let me know which
country you are watching this video
from. It's wonderful that we can connect
and chat together from all around the
world.
If you persist in doing this once a
month, the orchid leaves will gradually
become glossy, healthy, and full of
vitality. A clear sign of a well-ared
for and thriving orchid.
[Music]
When the last flowers have just fallen,
that is the golden time to propagate
from the flower spikes. Because at this
time, the plant still holds a lot of
stored energy, helping the flower spikes
easily grow new roots and develop into
healthier young plants.
The flower buds that have already
bloomed cannot sprout in into new
plants. So, you should cut off this part
to allow the nutrients to focus fully on
root and new chute development, helping
the young plant grow stronger.
[Music]
These three unopened flower buds I keep
because they are potential sprouts that
can develop into healthy young orchids
if properly cared for and stimulated in
time.
Then gently peel off the protective
outer layer of the orchid spike. This
step exposes the young tissues inside
creating favorable conditions for new
root growth and rapid development of the
young plant.
[Music]
If you haven't subscribed to the to the
channel yet, please hit the subscribe
button to support me and don't miss any
orchid care tips. It's wonderful to have
you along on this journey.
[Music]
You can also use the inner side of the
banana peel to gently rub the flower
spike and the young tissue. This method
not only helps clean the surface, but
also provides a natural layer of
nutrients, supporting root stimulation
and helping the young plant grow
stronger.
Then gently wrap the inner side of the
banana peel around the freshly exposed
young tissue. This layer will help
retain natural moisture and provide
nutrients, thereby stimulating the
sprout to grow and develop into a young
orchid more easily.
[Music]
Then sprinkle a little cinnamon powder
on the cut. Cinnamon has natural
antibacterial properties that help
prevent infection and promote faster
healing while also stimulating the
flower spike to root quickly.
[Music]
Once the water has cooled, stir it well
to ensure all the nutrients are fully
dissolved.
[Music]
Then strain out the solids through a
sieve to obtain a clear, nutrient-rich
solution ready to water your orchids or
use in the propagation process.
Dilute the filtered liquid with one more
liter of clean water to make a total of
2 L of solution. Uh this ratio makes the
mixture gentle and safe for orchid roots
while still providing all the essential
nutrients.
Use a soft cloth. Gently soak it in the
diluted solution and slowly wipe it over
the surface of the leaves.
[Music]
Wiping the leaves with a mixture of
banana peel and eggshell helps remove
the layer of dust and harmful bacteria
on the leaf surface. Clean leaves help
the plant breathe better, reduce the
risk of disease, and create favorable
conditions for the overall development
of the orchid.
[Music]
This mixture contains many natural
minerals such as potassium from banana
peel and calcium from eggshells. When
applied to the leaves, these nutrients
can be absorbed through the surface
directly supplementing the plant.
Especially useful during recovery or
when new leaves are developing.
[Music]
Next, pour the remaining solution into a
spray bottle. This allows you to easily
mist the entire orchid, especially the
roots and flower spikes being propagated
to provide moisture and nutrients evenly
and effectively.
You should spray the solution on both
the upper and lower sides of the leaves.
This not only helps clean the leaves,
but also delivers nutrients directly to
the absorbing tissues, improving
nutrient uptake and boosting the plant's
resistance.
[Music]
Spraying the mixture of banana peel and
eggshell on both sides of the leaves
helps the plant quickly absorb minerals
such as potassium, calcium, and
magnesium thanks to the stamata and soft
tissues on the leaves. As a result, the
leaves become glossy, healthy, and the
photosynthesis process becomes more
efficient.
[Music]
After keeping it moist for a while,
gently remove the banana peel from the
soft tissues at the three nodes. At this
point, the tissue is well moistened and
lightly stimulated, ready for the
rooting stage and sprouting into a young
plant.
Um, then gently spray the mixture onto
the three nodes to wash away any
remaining organic residue and at the
same time provide additional nutrients
directly to the young tissues. This
helps keep the area around the nodes
clean, moist, and nutrientrich, creating
an ideal environment for the young plant
to grow.
[Music]
Finally, use the remaining solution to
water the base of the orchid directly.
This natural fertilizer mixture will
soak deep into the roots, providing
essential nutrients such as potassium,
calcium, and other trace elements,
helping the plant recover quickly,
strengthen its roots, and prepare for
the growth of young orchids on the
flower spike.
[Music]
After each time you spray the
fertilizer, remember to use a soft cloth
or clean paper to absorb any remaining
water on the leaf surface and in the
leaf crevices. This helps prevent water
buildup, reduces the risk of fungal
diseases, and keeps your orchid dry,
airy, and healthy.
[Music]
Then place the orchid pot in a cool
shaded area. Under these conditions, the
nodes on the spike will more easily
develop into cakey baby plants thanks to
the stable environment, high humidity,
and limited direct sunlight.
[Music]
On the other hand, if you place the
orchid pot in a spot with a lot of
sunlight, the nodes tend to form new
flower buds. Strong light stimulates the
plant to switch into blooming mode
instead of developing baby plants.
Therefore, choose the location based on
your specific care goal.
[Music]
And this is the result after 7 weeks of
consistent care.
The orchid leaves are now glossier and
sturdier than before. A clear sign that
the plant is absorbing nutrients well,
healthy from root to tip, and ready for
its next stage of growth.
[Music]
>> Many new roots have begun to grow
vigorously. This indicates that the
nutrient and moisture conditions you've
provided are just right, helping the
plant recover quickly, anchor firmly to
the growing medium, and absorb nutrients
more effectively.
[Music]
Uh, these healthy roots will continue to
grow longer, firmly attached to the
growing medium. Um, and and and play an
essential role in absorbing water and
nutrients, creating a solid foundation
for the orchid to grow vigorously,
produce green leaves, and store
nutrients to nourish the developing baby
plants on the flower spike.
[Music]
And most importantly, you can see that
from the small nodes on the spike, kei
have begun to form with ivory white
young roots and leaf shoots reaching out
with vitality. It's a wonderful sign
marking the beginning of a new cycle
full of hope and promise for your orchid
pot.
[Music]
>> I continue to nourish the orchid with
natural fertilizer made from banana peel
and eggshells. A simple yet
nutrient-rich formula that helps roots
grow strong, leaves become glossier, and
especially supports the baby plant's
rapid growth, preparing for a beautiful
blooming season ahead.
[Music]
Water your orchid with this fertilizer
mixture twice a month. This consistent
routine will help the plant absorb
nutrients steadily, maintain ideal
moisture levels, and promote overall
development from roots to leaves and
young shoots.
[Music]
You can also alternate with other
natural fertilizers to provide a variety
of nutrients for your orchid. This
approach helps prevent micronutrient
deficiencies, boosts the plant's
resistance, and promotes more balanced
growth throughout its life cycle.
[Music]
Once the baby plant has started forming
on the spike, you should place the
orchid pot in a spot with gentle
sunlight. This will help the young plant
absorb soft light, stimulate
photosynthesis, and grow faster, while
also avoiding the risk of leaf burn from
harsh sun.
[Music]
And here is the result after 14 weeks of
care.
[Music]
[Laughter]
You can see that the baby orchid growing
on the spike has developed very well
with sturdy, lush green leaves and long
ivory white roots. A promising start for
a new vibrant orchid full of life.
When the baby orchid has grown strong
with stable roots and leaves, this is
the right time to separate it from the
mother plant. Planting it independently
gives the young orchid space to grow on
its own, absorb nutrients more easily,
and continue developing into a vibrant
new orchid pot.
[Music]
What happened?
After separating the baby plant from the
mother plant, apply a little cinnamon
powder to the cut. Cinnamon has natural
antibacterial properties that help the
wound dry quickly, prevent fungal
infections, and create a safe condition
for the plant to recover and continue
growing.
[Music]
Choose a transparent pot with drainage
holes to plant the baby orchid. The
clear pot allows you to easily monitor
root development, while the drainage
holes ensure good air circulation and
prevent water logging that could cause
root rot, creating ideal conditions for
healthy orchid growth.
[Music]
I chose moss as the growing medium for
the baby orchid. Moss retains moisture
well, is soft and breathable, creating
an ideal environment for the young roots
to anchor and grow. It also helps the
plant adapt more easily after being
separated from the mother plant.
[Music]
Then, gently place the baby orchid on
top of the moss, being careful not to
bury the roots too deeply. Let the young
roots stay exposed to the air and
gradually grow down into the medium
naturally. This helps the plant
stabilize and develop more healthily.
And you should mist the plant to
maintain moisture whenever the growing
medium starts to dry. This gently keeps
the young roots hydrated. Only after the
roots have firmly attached to the medium
should you begin fertilizing to avoid
damaging the tender roots and support
the baby orchid's steady development.
[Music]
I hope you'll enjoy this video. If you
find it helpful, don't forget to hit the
like button and subscribe to the channel
so you won't miss upcoming tips on how
to care for orchids in a natural and
simple way.
Thank you for watching until the end of
the video. Wishing you joy, good health,
and happy orchid growing. See you again
in the next sharing.