Hello everyone. It's great to see you on
my
[Music]
channel. Today I will share how to
restore an orchid suffering from leaf
rot so that it can recover and grow
quickly. If you haven't subscribed to my
channel yet, please subscribe to support
me and and uh not miss any orchid tips
on my
channel. So, let's get started.
You can see that this orchid which was
growing healthily suddenly has some
rotting leaves in the middle of its
stem. When you encounter an orchid with
with this type of rot, the first thing
you need to do is isolate it from the
garden to prevent the disease from
spreading to other
plants. The cause of this leaf rot in
the orchid is bacteria which leads to
orchid soft rot disease.
In just a few hours, they can make the
orchid leaves become soft, mushy, and
[Music]
necrotic. If not treated quickly, the
rot will spread to other leaves, down
the stem, and to the roots, causing the
orchid to die
rapidly. After isolating it from the
garden, we proceed to clean up and
remove the rotten parts from the orchid.
[Music]
At the same time, I trim off all dry
branches and roots. Um, this helps the
orchid focus its nutrients on the
healthy parts and stimulates stronger
new root
growth. At the same time, removing the
withered parts also helps the plant stay
well ventilated, reducing the risk of
fungal infections and pests.
[Music]
Please comment and let me know which
country you are watching the video from.
It's amazing that we can chat together
from all over the world.
[Music]
In addition to the English dub, we've
now created dubs in French, German,
Italian, Spanish, Portuguese, Japanese,
Hindi, and Indonesian to help you hear
and understand the content more easily.
[Music]
This is cinnamon powder. Cinnamon has
strong antibacterial and antifungal
properties, helping to prevent the
spread of rot in
[Music]
orchids. I take one spoonful of cinnamon
powder and mix it with four cups of
boiled water, about one liter.
[Music]
Then we stir it well, cover it, and wait
until the water cools down before using
it.
[Music]
After the water cools down, we filter
out the residue to obtain the clear
liquid. Squid.
[Music]
If not filtered properly, cinnamon
powder can stick to the leaves and
roots, hindering the plant's respiration
or creating a humid environment that
promotes fungal growth.
Additionally, well-filtered cinnamon
water allows the solution to penetrate
wounds more effectively, enhancing its
antibacterial properties and aiding the
plant's
recovery. Step one, soak a cotton pad in
the cinnamon water mixture and gently
wipe both the upper and lower surfaces
of the leaves.
Cinnamon water helps eliminate bacteria
and fungi on the leaf surface,
preventing diseases such as leaf spots
and soft
rot. The scent of cinnamon repels
harmful insects such as aphids and
thris, helping to protect orchid leaves
from attacks.
[Music]
Removing dirt helps the leaves absorb
light better, enhancing photosynthesis
and promoting healthy plant
[Music]
growth. Thanks to its natural
antibacterial properties, cinnamon water
helps orchids become stronger and more
resistant to unfavorable environmental
conditions. If the plant is healthy,
wipe the leaves once a month to prevent
diseases and improve light absorption.
[Music]
Uh if the plant shows signs of disease,
increase to twice a month to help
eliminate bacteria and speed up
recovery.
[Music]
Note, wipe in the morning or late
afternoon using a soft cloth to avoid
scratching the leaves, allowing the
plant to absorb the natural nutrients
from cinnamon
[Music]
effectively. Step two, pour the cinnamon
water into a spray bottle.
If you encounter any difficulties while
growing orchids, don't hesitate to leave
a comment. I'm always ready to help you
grow healthy orchids with plenty of
beautiful
blooms. Then I spray this cinnamon water
onto the rotting area to clean it. This
helps the wound dry faster and reduces
the humid environment where bacteria and
fungi can
thrive. When the rotting area is cleaned
and dried, the plant will recover more
easily, develop healthy new tissue, and
stimulate tissue
regeneration. Then spray it on the
orchid leaves. This helps clean them and
support photosynthesis by removing dust,
allowing the plant to absorb light
better and promoting
growth. The antibacterial and antifungal
properties of cinnamon water help
prevent the growth of harmful bacteria
and fungi on the leaf surface, reducing
the risk of diseases such as leaf spots
and soft rot.
If the plant is healthy, spray once a
month to prevent diseases and boost its
resistance. Uh, if the plant shows signs
of fungal disease or pests, spray twice
a month to help eliminate bacteria,
fight fungi, and provide better
protection for the plant.
[Music]
Step three, dry the water on the leaf
joints and surfaces to prevent water
accumulation, reducing the risk of
fungal diseases and soft
[Music]
rot. Use a soft cloth or cotton pad to
gently absorb the moisture, especially
in the leaf joints where water tends to
accumulate.
[Music]
Keep the plant in a well ventilated area
to allow the leaves to dry quickly and
prevent prolonged
[Music]
humidity. Carefully check the base of
the leaves as this is where bacteria and
fungi can easily develop if if water
remains.
[Music]
This step helps keep the orchid dry,
healthy, and better able to absorb
[Music]
nutrients. Then take two cups of
cinnamon water, about 0.5 L.
[Music]
Dilute it with two cups of filtered
water, about 0.5 L.
[Music]
This is beer. Some microorganisms in
beer can help balance the substrate
environment, supporting the plant's
better
[Music]
recovery. Mix in 5 tablespoons of beer.
When using beer for orchids, it should
be diluted with water as I've instructed
to avoid overloading the plant with
nutrients or causing excessive
fermentation.
[Music]
Step four, water the orchid pot with the
cinnamon and beer mixture to help the
orchid recover faster and grow
[Music]
healthier. When watering, slowly pour
the mixture around the base of the
plant, avoiding direct contact with the
leaves and crown to prevent water
accumulation.
[Music]
Water in the morning or late afternoon
to help the plant absorb nutrients
better and prevent fermentation due to
high
[Music]
temperatures. This mixture provides
nutrients from beer, stimulating root
growth and aiding in faster recovery.
This mixture also improves the growing
medium by introducing beneficial
microorganisms from beer, helping the
plant absorb nutrients more
effectively. After watering, let the
roots soak in this mixture for about 20
minutes to enhance the recovery
[Music]
effect. After soaking, take the orchid
pot out and place it in a well
ventilated area with gentle sunlight to
enhance photosynthesis and boost
recovery.
[Music]
Now, let's take a look at the results
after 3 weeks of caring for and
restoring the rotting
orchid. You can see that new roots have
started to grow from the previously
rotting area. This is a wonderful sign
that the orchid has recovered and is
continuing to thrive.
You can also see that the leaves are
greener and firmer, which proves that
the plant has absorbed enough nutrients
and regained its vitality.
[Music]
And here is another orchid that I also
restored using this method. As you can
see, from the roots to the leaves, it is
thriving after the recovery phase.
[Music]
The growing medium is dry and well
ventilated with no unusual odors. This
indicates that the environment has
improved, reducing the risk of fungal
diseases.
[Music]
And here is the orchid I cared for and
restored using this method 3 months ago.
Now look at its roots. So strong and
healthy,
right? With this simple method, you can
easily restore rotten orchids at home.
Right. With a little patience and the
right approach, your orchid will quickly
recover, grow new roots, turn lush green
again, and may even bloom
soon. Keep caring for and loving your
orchids, and you will be rewarded with
wonderful results. Wishing you success.
What do you think about my method for
reviving weak orchids? Leave a comment
and share your thoughts with
me. If you find this content helpful and
meaningful, don't forget to like, share
so more people can benefit and subscribe
to support my channel. Thank you for
always being with
[Music]
me. I always pray for God's blessings
upon all of you. For now, goodbye and
see you in the next videos.
[Music]