welcome to my channel have a good
[Music]
day to help you have many choices when
caring for orchids at home using natural
methods in this video I continue to
share new methods helps orchids bloom
continuously all year round with large
beautiful
flowers the Orchid grows many new plump
and healthy roots
[Music]
let's get
started do you have
coffee put one teaspoon in the
jar coffee contains a lot of organic
matter rich in nitrogen n helps plants
grow green leaves and supports
[Music]
photosynthesis add 2 cups boiling water
about .5 l
um if you haven't subscribed to the
channel yet please hit the Subscribe
button to support me and not miss any
Orchid growing tips it's great to have
you
along close the
[Music]
lid wait 2 hours for the water to
cool next I need
flour take one spoon of
flour wheat flour contains carbohydrates
proteins and minerals such as iron zinc
and magnesium to help plants absorb
nutrients
[Music]
better then mix in 2 cups of warm water
about 0.5 l
[Music]
please comment to me which country you
are watching the video from it's great
that we can chat together from all over
the world
wait 2
hours 2 hours
later filter out residue
[Music]
add 2 cups of water about 0.5
l in addition to the English dub we've
now created dubs in French German
Italian Spanish Portuguese Japanese
Hindi and Indonesian to help you hear
and understand the content more
easily step
one use a soft cotton soaked in coffee
water to gently wipe the top and bottom
of the leaves thoroughly
coffee can help remove stains and dust
from the orchid leaves making them
cleaner and better at absorbing
[Music]
light um a diluted coffee solution can
provide small amounts of nutrition for
the plant especially helping it develop
healthy leaves and
Roots if you encounter any difficulties
in the process of growing orchids do not
hesitate to comment for me I am always
ready to support you so that you can
grow healthy orchids and Bloom a lot of
flowers
step
two then add the brw coffee solution
into the spray bottle
then spray the entire
Orchid spraying diluted coffee Solution
on orchid leaves helps remove dirt
provides some nutrients such as nitrogen
phosphorus and potassium and improves
the plant's antibacterial and antifungal
abilities
[Music]
however it is important to use it in
moderation to avoid harming the plant
[Music]
step
three standing water on the leaves can
create a moist environment ideal for
fungal and bacterial growth leading to
diseases like rot Leaf spots or white
mold
gently wipe off water droplets from the
leaves with a soft cloth or lint-free
fabric to avoid damaging the
leaves uh water in the early morning or
late afternoon so the leaves have time
to dry before night time
dry the leaves so that the tears on the
leaves do not become infected with
fungal
diseases then you place the plant in a
place with good light and good air
circulation to help the leaves dry
quickly and avoid moisture accumulation
mix flour solution and coffee solution
to create a complete nutritional mixture
for orchids
[Music]
step four
you water each Orchid pot with about 10
tblspoon of this
[Music]
solution um the combination of coffee
solution and flour May stimulate the
growth of the root system due to the
nutrients in both components
[Music]
coffee has mild antibacterial and
antifungal properties which help protect
orchids from certain types of fungi and
bacteria
[Music]
wheat flour provides a good environment
for beneficial microorganisms to thrive
supporting a healthy soil
[Music]
ecosystem the combination of coffee
solution and flour May stimulate the
growth of the root system due to the
nutrients in both components
[Music]
then you soak the Orchid pot in this
solution for about 20 minutes so that
the plant roots can best absorb water
and nutrients
[Music]
after 20 minutes take out the Orchid pot
and and place it in a place with plenty
of
light this solution is very good for
orchids however if the Orchid lacks
light and cannot photosynthesize the
plant will still be stunted and slow to
grow
[Music]
results after 3
weeks after only 3 weeks many new Roots
have
[Music]
grown new Roots help the plant absorb
water and necessary nutrients from the
[Music]
environment uh this is very important
for plant growth especially during the
flowering stage
Roots help the tree stand firmly
creating stability and reducing the risk
of
falling especially in strong wind
environments or when trees are
tall the growth of new Roots often
stimulates the growth of other parts of
the plant including leaves and
flowers uh the plant will have enough
energy to grow and
[Music]
flower newly developed Roots often
signal that the tree is in healthy
condition
[Music]
create favorable conditions for
flowering Roots also participate in the
plants respiration process helping to
provide oxygen to
[Music]
cells this is very important for the
life of the tree
[Music]
Orchids with strong roots will produce
many
[Music]
buds this Orchid of mine produces a lot
of buds
when the flowers bloom they are bright
and
[Music]
plump the flowers stay on the branches
for a long time before
[Music]
fading hope you like this
video um please comment to let me know
if you like this
video thank you for watching the video
good luck and success in life