welcome to my
channel today's video I share how to
easily make your own fertilizer but its
effects are
miraculous it's amazing how we connect
from all around the
world where are you watching from let me
know in the
comments if you haven't subscribed to
the channel yet please subscribe to my
channel to support me and not miss any
orchid care tips on my channel thank you
very much for always accompanying
me let's explore this wonderful way to
make natural
fertilizer to make this magical
fertilizer you need
[Music]
flour I took 3 tbsp of flour
and take another spoonful of yeast the
type of yeast used to make bread
[Music]
add a little warm water
then incubate for 2 hours for The
Beneficial microorganisms in the yeast
to take effect
[Music]
after 2
hours currently the beneficial
microorganisms in yeast have multiplied
many times over
[Music]
mix with 5 L of water
first
[Music]
method water the Orchid roots with this
microbial fertilizer solution beneficial
beneficial microorganisms will grow in
the Orchid pot helps protect Orchid
roots from rot caused by fungi and
bacteria
[Music]
this type of fertilizer also balances
the pH level in Orchid pots helps
stimulate Orchid roots to grow and not
be damaged by acid
[Music]
this type of fertilizer also provides
many necessary nutrients for orchids
such as potassium phosphorus nitrogen
magnesium calcium iron zinc and vitamins
[Music]
it would be better to soak the Orchid
pot for 20
[Music]
minutes this type of fertilizer is
especially good for weak stunted orchids
uh with underdeveloped root systems
because it does not Shock weak orchids
like chemical fertilizers
[Music]
second
method wipe the leaves clean with this
microbial fertilizer solution helps
eliminate insects and leaf damaging
[Music]
fungi this work also improves
photosynthesis helping plants grow
better
[Music]
third
method spray this fertilizer solution
over the entire orchid
this method helps provide nutrients
directly to both roots and
leaves this not only cleans but also
helps the plant absorb beneficial
microorganisms thereby improving overall
health especially for weak orchids it
will help them recover quickly by
providing necessary nutrients and
fostering a healthier environment for
root and leaf growth
uh let's see the results with proper
care and the use of a natural fertilizer
solution your orchid will hopefully grow
strong and
healthy if you do this every 2 weeks
after only 1 to two months the Orchid
will have many new
[Music]
Roots this helps the Orchid absorb
maximum nutrients through its
[Music]
roots if you find find the video
interesting remember to like share and
subscribe to my channel for support
thank you for watching and supporting
the
[Music]
channel um flowers bloom brightly and
colorfully filling your space with
vibrant Beauty and
life this careful care and natural
fertilizer helps orchids Thrive
producing beautiful blooms that are a
true reward for your
dedication many flowers bloom on the
same Branch creating a beautiful display
of color and
Vitality this abundant flowering shows
that the Orchid is receiving proper care
and that nutrients from natural
fertilizers are supporting its growth
and
flowering it is a great sign of a
healthy and thriving
[Music]
tree thank you for watching the video
good
[Music]
luck goodbye and see you again in the
next video
Hello
friends in my hand is a withered
dendrobium Orchid and in this video I
will share how you can propagate any
dendrobium
Orchid we cut off the spots that have
bloomed
[Music]
only keep these three parts for
propagation because they still have
dormant buds at the
nodes drip melted wax onto the cut to
protect it from absorbing water
preventing the cut from
rotting which country are you watching
this video from please leave a comment
for me
it's amazing that we can chat with each
other from all around the
[Music]
world peel off the protective film of
the sleeping sprout
[Music]
h
use one sprig of chopped fresh
[Music]
ginger if you haven't subscribed to the
channel yet click the Subscribe button
to support
[Music]
me 500 M of boiled water
wait one
[Music]
day soak orchids in ginger water for 30
minutes
[Music]
soak moss in ginger water for 30 minutes
I use recycled plastic boxes to make
miniature green houses to help propagate
orchids
[Music]
faster there's a vent here
put the Orchid in a miniature greenhouse
and spray it with moisture once a
[Music]
week uh place in a bright place and
avoid direct
sunlight 21 days after
[Music]
continue missing to keep moisture and
keep in a light place of void direct
[Music]
sunlight after 10 next day
continue misting to keep moisture and
keep in a light place avoid direct
sunlight after two next weeks
[Music]
I hope this video will be very helpful
for you in taking care of orchids at
home
[Music]
plant in pots to let the Orchid adapt
and grow in the outside environment
[Music]
if you find it interesting please
subscribe to the channel like share to
let more people know
[Music]
my videos have subtitles in different
languages please select the appropriate
language to understand the video content
[Music]
clearly remember to plant the root
higher than the pot so that the Orchid
does not have root
rot that's all I want to share with you
in this
video now goodbye and see you in the
next videos