Welcome to the Happiness Garden channel.
When the rainy season combines with hot
and humid weather, does your orchid
start to rot and gradually weaken day by
day?
Don't worry, because in this video, I
will show you how to revive your orchid
at home. Simple, easy to do, and
surprisingly effective with just a few
simple steps and natural ingredients
readily available right in your kitchen.
No chemicals, no need for expensive
products. Just a little patience and the
love you give to your plant and you will
see a true miracle happen.
If you haven't subscribed to the channel
yet, please hit the subscribe button to
support me and not miss any orchid
growing tips. It's wonderful to have you
along on this journey.
Now, let's get started.
[Music]
When the weather becomes hot and humid,
the moisture in the air also increases.
This is when orchids become very
vulnerable, and it's also the time when
fungal diseases become active, putting
your orchid at risk of root or leaf rot
if not cared for properly.
[Music]
If you're facing this situation, quickly
remove the damaged leaves to prevent the
disease from spreading to the rest of
the plant. Timely action will give your
orchid a better chance to recover
faster.
[Music]
Leave a comment and let me know which
country you're watching from. It's
wonderful that we can connect and chat
from all around the world.
[Music]
Um, the main cause of orchid rot during
the rainy season is prolonged water
logging of the roots without timely
drainage.
You'll notice the growing medium is
excessively wet, preventing the roots
from breathing. Grenang
moss medium retains moisture very well
and is especially suitable for
industrial orchid gardens with full
humidity control systems.
But when grown at home, the conditions
are not the same. If humidity cannot be
controlled, orchid roots are very likely
to become water logged and rot, causing
the plant to weaken quickly.
After removing all the old growing
medium, gently trim off the damaged
roots. This helps eliminate the source
of rot from spreading to the healthy
roots while also allowing the plant to
focus on nurturing and developing
stronger new roots.
[Music]
After trimming the damaged roots, you
should rinse the entire orchid with
clean water. This not only helps remove
dirt, but also gets rid of any remaining
bacteria and fungi on the stems, leaves,
and roots. A clean environment will help
the plant recover quickly and be better
prepared for the next stage of growth.
[Music]
In addition to the English voiceover, we
have also created versions in French,
German, Italian, Spanish, speeggies,
Japanese, Hindi, Dutch, Polish, Korean,
and Indonesian to help you listen and
understand the content more easily.
To listen in your preferred language,
open the video and click on settings,
the gear icon to select the appropriate
audio language.
[Music]
After rinsing, place the orchid in a
well ventilated area to let it dry
completely.
Now it's time to prepare natural
fertilizer to help your orchid recover.
The first ingredient you need is ground
coffee, a familiar material rich in
minerals and capable of stimulating root
growth. Be sure to choose pure coffee
without added sugar or flavorings to
ensure it's safe for your plant.
Take one teaspoon of ground coffee. Add
it to 500 ml of boiling water. Then stir
well to let the nutrients in the coffee
dissolve into the water.
After stirring well, cover the container
and let the mixture steep until the
water has completely cooled.
[Music]
The next ingredient you need to prepare
is rice. uh a natural component rich in
starch and minerals.
Take three teaspoons of rice and put
them into a cup.
Rice not only nourishes beneficial
bacteria, but also provides easily
absorbable nutrients, supporting the
orchid roots recovery in a natural and
sustainable way.
[Music]
Next, add the prepared rice to 500 ml of
room temperature water.
[Music]
After stirring well, cover the container
and let it sit for about 2 hours.
This amount of time is enough for the
nutrients in the rice to seep into the
water, creating a lightly fermented rice
water that is very beneficial for
orchids during their recovery stage.
[Music]
Once the coffee water has completely
cooled, use a strainer to remove the
grounds, keeping only the clear liquid.
[Music]
Removing the grounds helps prevent
residue buildup. up in the growing
medium while also allowing the solution
to penetrate more easily and be absorbed
more effectively by the orchid roots.
[Music]
Next, strain the soaked rice water and
mix it with the filtered coffee water to
create a natural fertilizer solution.
The gentle combination of these two
ingredients will provide a natural
source of energy. helping orchid roots
recover quickly while also supporting
the healthy and sustainable growth of
leaves and new shoots.
[Music]
Step one, use a soft cloth to soak up
the natural fertilizer solution. Then
gently wipe both the top and bottom
surfaces of the leaves.
[Music]
Wiping the leaves removes dust and dirt
buildup. And the solution also has mild
antibacterial properties, helping reduce
the risk of fungal infections on tender
new leaves.
[Music]
The nutrients in coffee and rice water
are absorbed through the leaf surface,
boosting vitality and making the leaves
naturally greener and glossier.
[Music]
When the leaves are clean, their
surfaces become more breathable,
allowing the plant to absorb light more
efficiently. As a result, photosynthesis
becomes more active, promoting the
overall healthy growth of the orchid.
After wiping the leaves, gently place
the orchid into a clean cup.
Step two, pour the natural fertilizer
mixture in and soak the orchid roots for
about 20 minutes.
[Music]
During this time, the nutrients from the
coffee and rice water will be absorbed
into the roots, stimulating new root
formation and supporting the plant's
recovery after pruning.
[Music]
You can use the remaining mixture to
water other orchid pots in your garden.
[Music]
This is a simple yet effective way to
provide extra natural nutrients to your
entire orchid garden, helping the plants
grow evenly, stay healthy, and get ready
for the next blooming season.
You can apply this natural fertilizer to
each orchid pot about twice a month.
Regular feeding helps maintain a steady
supply of nutrients supporting the
growth of roots, leaves, and flower
buds.
As you can see with this orchid, new
roots have started to grow along with a
flower spike that is continuing to
develop. All happening after the plant
completed its previous blooming cycle.
This is a clear sign that the plant is
recovering well and is ready to enter a
new growth phase.
[Music]
This orchid is the same. You can easily
notice its root system growing strong,
plump, and full of vitality.
[Music]
This is the solid foundation that allows
the plant to absorb nutrients more
effectively, enabling it to keep growing
healthy leaves and strong shoots and to
prepare for the next vibrant blooming
cycles.
[Music]
New flower spikes from the old flower
stem have begun to emerge, signaling
that a new blooming cycle is
approaching. This is a very positive
sign, showing that the orchid is not
only recovering well after flowering,
but also accumulating enough energy to
continue producing vibrant blooms.
[Music]
While waiting for the roots to soak, I
used the time to recycle a used plastic
cup, turning it into a recovery
container for a rotting orchid.
[Music]
Uh, this recycling not only helps save
costs, but also contributes to
protecting the environment while
creating a simple yet effective orchid
care setup right at home.
[Music]
After soaking the roots for about 20
minutes, gently take the orchid out and
plant it in a new pot that has been
prepared in advance.
[Music]
The growing medium I chose to help the
orchid recover is sand. A simple yet
very effective material,
[Music]
sand has high irerration, retains just
the right amount of moisture and helps
helps prevent root rot during the
sensitive stage. At the same time, its
clean environment limits bacteria and
fungi, creating ideal conditions for new
roots to grow strong and healthy.
[Music]
Since the orchid is in a very weak
state, I decided to cut off this flower
spike so the plant doesn't have to use
too much energy. Removing the flower
spike allows the plant to focus its
nutrients on nurturing the roots and
leaves, helping the recovery process
happen faster and more effectively.
[Music]
After cutting off the flower spike,
sprinkle a little cinnamon powder on the
cut. Cinnamon has natural antibacterial
and antifungal properties, helping to
prevent infection and promote faster
healing. This is a simple yet highly
effective method to protect the plant
during this sensitive stage.
After planting in the new pot, place the
orchid in a well ventilated area with
gentle light and away from drafts.
During the first week, avoid watering to
allow the cut to dry and give the roots
time to adjust to the new environment.
[Music]
Uh after 1 week once the plant has
stabilized and the cuts have dried you
can start lightly misting the leaves and
roots.
This watering method provides the
necessary humidity without water logging
the roots while also helping the plant
absorb moisture through the leaves
during recovery. Do it in the early
morning or late afternoon so the plant
can absorb it effectively and avoid
water sitting overnight.
[Music]
After misting, use a soft cloth to
gently wipe off any remaining water
droplets on the leaves, especially in
the leaf joints.
[Music]
Place the orchid pot in a cool,
wellventilated area with gentle light.
When you notice the growing medium
starting to dry, you can lightly mist to
provide just enough moisture for the
roots and leaves.
[Music]
And here's the result after 2 months.
You can see that from an orchid with
only one remaining leaf, it has now made
an impressive recovery. A new orchid
chute has grown from the side of the
mother stem. This is a wonderful
testament to the orchid's strong
vitality when cared for properly with
natural methods and patience.
[Music]
You just need to pour water into the pot
while it's slightly tilted. The water
will easily wash away all the sand from
the roots. This simple method doesn't
damage the roots and helps you clean the
plant quickly before moving on to the
next care step.
[Laughter]
[Music]
As you can see, many new roots have
grown, white, healthy, and full of
vitality. This is a clear sign that the
plant is recovering well and absorbing
nutrients effectively.
Um, these new roots will be the strong
foundation that helps the plant continue
to grow vigorously in the coming days.
[Music]
Now we need to plant the orchid in a new
pot to create more favorable conditions
for its growth.
A clean pot with a well-airrated growing
medium will give the new roots space to
grow strongly while also reducing the
risk of prolonged moisture that can harm
the plant. This is an important step for
the orchid to enter a stable growth
phase and prepare for the next blooming
season.
[Music]
What do you think about the way I
revived this little orchid? Uh, feel
free to leave a comment and share your
thoughts. I'd love to hear your feedback
and experiences.
[Music]
If you face any difficulties during the
orchid planting process, don't hesitate
to leave a comment. I'm always here to
help you grow healthy orchids that bloom
beautifully.
[Music]
After planting, I continued to care for
the orchid using the natural fertilizer
made from coffee and rice.
This mixture provides gentle yet
complete nutrients, helping new roots
grow strong, leaves stay lush, and the
plant recover quickly. It's a simple,
safe, and eco-friendly method for orchid
care that you can use regularly.
[Music]
With this simple method, we can
completely revive weak orchids at home
effectively. With just a little
patience, love, and the use of natural,
readily available ingredients, your
orchid will gradually come back to life,
grow new roots, green leaves, and get
ready to bloom again.
Each plant is a new journey, a small
revival of life. And step by step,
you'll begin to witness miracles
unfolding in your garden. The once weak
orchids now stretch out with strength,
grow roots, and bloom beautifully.
Gradually, your garden will be filled
with the vibrant colors of orchids. Not
just as a gift from nature, but as a
result of your love, patience, and
gentle care.
I hope you'll enjoy this video. If you
find it helpful, don't forget to hit
like and subscribe to the channel so you
won't miss upcoming tips on how to care
for orchids in a natural and simple way.