hello everyone welcome to happiness
Garden today I will share with you an
amazing tip to help your orchids not
only grow vigorously but also Bloom
beautifully all year
[Music]
round this is a method to make natural
safe and effective fertilizer using
simple ingredients from your
kitchen if you love orchids and want to
care for them properly
let's get started
together uh to make this natural
fertilizer I first used oranges because
they contain many nutrients that are
very good for
[Music]
orchids peel the skin off one orange
orange peels are rich in nutrients like
vitamin C citric acid and natural
essential oils which help stimulate
Orchid root growth boost resistance and
create a favorable environment for
better nutrient
absorption put the orange peel into a
[Music]
blender next I need bananas to make the
natural fertilizer
[Music]
banana peels are rich in potassium
phosphorus and other essential minerals
which help orchids grow robustly
stimulate root development and enhance
[Music]
flowering put the banana peel into a
blender
add 300 mL of water to the
blender which country are you watching
this video from leave a comment below to
let me know
blend the mixture until smooth and
blender
pour the mixture into a
jar add 700 M of water to the mixture
[Music]
next add one teaspoon of baker's yeast
to promote fermentation creating a
fermented GE mixture that is very
beneficial for
[Music]
orchids if you haven't subscribed yet
please hit subscribe to support me and
stay updated with all the new videos
from happiness Garden
then leave it in a cool well ventilated
place for 3 weeks to create a wonderful
fermented GE mixture for your orchids
[Music]
after 3 weeks the GE mixture is
ready the mixture has a mild Pleasant
beer-like Aroma and a white frothy layer
on top which indicates that it is good
and ready to
use Take 2 tablespoons about 50 mL of
the mixture
for this mixture after opening the lid
you can store it in the refrigerator for
up to 3
months then dilute it with 1 liter of
water to create a natural fertilizer
that is very beneficial for your orchids
[Music]
this is a young orchid plant you can
propagate it from seeds by using flower
stems or purchase it from e-commerce
platforms uh before transplanting it
into a larger pot you need to check and
remove any rotten roots and damaged
leaves
step one soak the Orchid roots in this
mixture for about 10 to 20
minutes this helps stimulate the growth
of new roots and allows the Orchid to
absorb additional nutrients more
effectively
[Music]
step two use a soft cotton ball to soak
the mixture and gently wipe both the top
and bottom sides of the leaves
thoroughly
uh this helps remove dust harmful fungi
and pests from orchids while also
providing nutrition through the
leaves step three transplant it into a
larger pot to allow the Orchid to grow
better and faster
I plant using pine bark to help retain
moisture and provide better irration for
the Orchid roots to grow well
on top of the Orchid pot I sprinkle a
little Moss to help retain moisture and
create a natural environment conducive
to Healthy Growth
[Music]
step four from now on water this mixture
for your orchid once every 10 days to
provide nutrients through the
roots if you haven't subscribed yet
please hit subscribe to support me and
stay updated with all the new videos
from happiness
Garden step five wipe off any excess
mixture or water that has collected in
the crevices of the leaves to prevent
the Orchid from rotting due to
overwatering
[Music]
then place the Orchid pot in a spot with
gentle sunlight to allow photosynthesis
which will help the Orchid grow well
[Music]
results after 10
days the orchid has developed many new
Young Roots indicating that it is
growing healthily and effectively
absorbing nutrients from the mixture
[Music]
uh when the Orchid absorbs sufficient
nutrients and undergos photosynthesis
with adequate sunlight its leaves will
become Greener shinier and stronger than
before then I continue to water this
fertilizer mixture at the base of the
Orchid to help the plant absorb
additional nutrients and grow
healthily remember to apply this mixture
once every 10 days on regular days if
the growing medium is dry you only need
to water with plain water
and then soak this mixture and continue
wiping both the top and bottom sides of
the leaves to remove dust fungi pests
and provide nutrition through the
leaves then I place the Orchid pot in a
in a spot with gentle sunlight
this allows the Orchid to
photosynthesize effectively synthesize
nutrients and promote the plant's growth
from Roots to
[Music]
leaves results after the next 2
months the root system has developed
stronger and healthier
the orchid has developed larger thicker
and sturdier
leaves this demonstrates the incredible
effectiveness of the natural fertilizer
promoting the orchid's robust and
Healthy Growth from Roots to leaves
I continue to water this natural
fertilizer mixture on the Orchid every
10 days to support its growth and
prepare it for the next stage of Bud
development
I need to clean the leaves by thoroughly
wiping this mixture on both the top and
bottom surfaces to remove dust insects
and fungi ensuring the orchid's health
and
protection after after cleaning the
leaves I will water this mixture onto
the roots to provide essential nutrients
and boost the orchid's overall health
from the
base after watering the roots with the
mixture I continue to place the Orchid
pot in a spot with gentle sunlight to
allow allow the plant to photosynthesize
effectively and absorb nutrients
[Music]
optimally um results after the next 3
months the orchid has produced three new
flower spikes which proves that the care
and nutrients have been effective
helping the plant to thrive and prepare
for a promising new blooming
season as you can see the leaves are
growing very well with large thick
leaves which indicates that the Orchid
is absorbing adequate nutrients and is
in its healthiest state to continue
growing and Bloom
with this simple method you can easily
care for your orchids at home
effectively and Achieve amazing results
[Music]
uh I will continue to care for my
orchids using this natural fertilizer
mixture to keep them healthy and
thriving uh I hope this video provides
valuable information and helps you
succeed in caring for your
orchids uh I hope this video provides
valuable information and helps you
succeed in caring for your orchids
uh if you find this video enjoyable and
helpful don't forget to hit like share
and subscribe to support me and stay
tuned for more videos on happiness
Garden wishing you all success in caring
for your orchids and having many joyful
days
ahead goodbye and see you in the next
video