Welcome to the Happiness Garden
channel. This is where I share my
passion and experience in orchid
care. In today's video, I'll introduce
you to a new natural fertilizer, which
not only helps orchids grow strong, but
also bloom beautifully all year round.
[Music]
If you love orchids and want to discover
tips to care for
them, let's get
started. This is an orchid that has
finished
[Music]
blooming. The petals have withered.
cut off damage
leaves. Please comment to me which
country you are watching the video from.
It's great that we can chat together
from all over the
world. Uh as soon as the flowers wilt,
repot your orchid and the plant will
recover and grow quickly.
Uh, you cut off old flower branches so
that the orchid can focus on nutrition
for new flower branches
[Music]
later. Then use coffee powder to
sprinkle on the cut to help the wound
heal quickly.
[Music]
Then wait overnight for the cut to heal
completely before proceeding with the
with the next care
[Music]
step. To make this fertilizer, I use
okra.
Okra is an excellent natural ingredient
for making fertilizer for orchids due to
its rich
[Music]
nutrients. Next, I use potatoes as
natural fertilizer to restore the
orchid.
Potatoes are rich in starch providing
essential energy for orchid
growth. Uh potatoes are packed with
minerals like potassium, phosphorus and
vitamin B6 which stimulate root
development and promote healthy orchid
growth.
Put the okra and chopped potatoes in the
jar.
Add one liter of
water.
Close the
lid. Wait overnight for the nutrients to
dissolve into the
water. Next, I use oatmeal as a natural
fertilizer. Take 3 tablesp of oatmeal.
Add one liter of water.
[Music]
Wait overnight.
After one
night, stir well so that the flour
nutrients dissolve into the
[Music]
water. Filter out residue.
Step
one, use a soft cloth to gently wipe the
top and bottom of the orchid leaves with
the okra and potato soaked water
solution.
removes dust and residue, improving the
plant's ability to
photosynthesize. The okra and potato
solution supplies natural nutrients
through the leaves.
Leaves become shinier, softer, and
healthier. The solution may form a
protective layer, reducing the risk of
pest infestations on orchid leaves.
Gently wipe each leaf, both the upper
and lower surfaces, ensuring the
solution is evenly
applied. Do it one or two times per
month for best results.
This method keeps orchids clean,
healthy, and
thriving. Step
two, put this solution in a spray bottle
and mist the entire orchid plant.
Spraying adds moisture especially in dry
conditions. Spraying ensures the
solution covers the entire plant from
roots to stems and leaves.
Spraying ensures the solution covers the
entire plant from roots to stems and
leaves. Forms a natural protective layer
reducing the risk of pest
infestations. Do it one to two times per
month for best results.
Step three, after spraying, use a soft
cloth to blot excess water from orchid
leaves. Water pooling on leaves,
especially in crevices, can cause rot if
left too long.
A damp environment can attract fungi and
bacteria harmful to
orchids. Protects orchid leaves. Keeps
leaves dry, glossy, and healthy.
This habit keeps your orchids clean,
healthy, and minimizes potential pest or
disease issues.
Step
four. Now I mix the oatmeal solution
with the okra and potato solution.
This mix provides amino acids,
polysaccharides, and natural starches to
encourage longer, stronger
roots. Then you water the orchid roots
with this mix solution.
The solution stabilizes moisture levels,
enhancing nutrient
[Music]
absorption. Made from natural
ingredients, it's safe for orchids and
the environment.
This mixture is a fantastic natural
nutrient source, helping orchids grow
robustly and bloom
beautifully. Do it one to two times per
month for best
results. And I soaked the orchid root in
this mix solution for 20 minutes.
[Music]
Soaking softens the roots, increasing
their ability to absorb water and
nutrients
[Music]
afterward. After 20 minutes, take it out
and place the orchid pot in a place with
plenty of light.
[Music]
Placing the orchid in a well-lit area
helps it dry properly, reducing the risk
of mold or
pests. Light aids the orchid in
photosynthesis, converting nutrients to
promote strong growth.
[Music]
results. After 50
days, the orchid grows two new flower
branches. Orchid leaves become glossier,
thicker, and healthier with a vibrant
green color.
[Music]
Now we'll check the roots.
Wow. Orchid roots grow very strongly.
This clearly improves and enhances the
ability to absorb nutrients and water.
With strong root and leaf growth, the
orchid will absorb nutrients more
efficiently from the surrounding
environment.
Now I'm repotting the orchid into a new
pot for better growth.
I plant with pine bark to help retain
moisture and
ventilation. When planted in a new pot,
the orchid will grow faster.
Goodbye.
After planting, you take care of orchids
like other normal plants.
Take care of your orchids with all the
love you have for plants, and you will
be rewarded with beautiful blooms, a
healthy orchid, and the satisfaction of
nurturing your plant.
Thank you for watching and see you in
the next
videos. Wishing you success in caring
for your orchids and having beautiful
flowers.