Welcome to Happiness Garden, where we
take care of and explore the beauty of
orchids together. From the lush green
roots to the vibrant, lively petals.
When your orchid is rotting like this,
don't rush to throw it away. Rest
assured, I will share how to revive it
immediately so the plant returns to
being lush and healthy as before.
[Music]
I guess this orchid is rotting and the
cause may be due to the plant being
shocked by inorganic fertilizer. When
the plant receives too many chemicals at
once, the roots and leaves weaken,
leading to rot.
[Music]
Cut off all the dry branches and damaged
roots. This not only prevents the rot
from spreading but also stimulates new
root growth, helping the plant revive
quickly.
[Music]
Leave me a comment letting me know which
country you're watching from. It's
wonderful that we can connect and and
chat with each other from from all
around the world.
If you haven't subscribed yet, hit the
subscribe button to support me and never
miss any orchid growing tips. It's
wonderful to have you along.
and cut off all the rotten parts. This
helps prevent the rot from spreading and
creates conditions for the plant to
recover healthily.
Then rinse the plant with water. This
helps remove any remaining bacteria and
impurities, creating a clean environment
for the plant to recover faster.
[Music]
after rinsing. Let the plant drain
completely before proceeding with the
next care steps.
[Music]
Then take two aloe vera leaves to
prepare fertilizer, helping to quickly
restore the orchid's health.
Cut the aloe vera into short pieces to
make it easier to extract nutrients from
the leaves.
[Music]
Take four cups of soy sauce, about one
liter, to soak the aloe vera.
[Music]
The next ingredient is ginger. You only
need about 10 g of ginger, enough to
enhance the recovery of the orchid.
[Music]
Slice the ginger thinly to extract the
nutrients most effectively.
[Music]
Ginger has antibacterial properties and
stimulates orchid root growth, helping
the plant recover faster.
[Music]
Then add the ginger to soak together
with the aloe vera, allowing the
nutrients to blend and be ready to make
recovery fertilizer for the orchid.
Soak the mixture for one day, allowing
the nutrients from the aloe vera and
ginger to fully dissolve in the water.
[Music]
One day after soaking, strain out the
residue, keeping only the nutrient-rich
solution to fertilize the orchid.
[Music]
Then soak the orchid in this mixture for
20 minutes, allowing the plant to absorb
maximum nutrients. and recover quickly.
[Music]
While waiting, I prepare dry moss in a
new pot, creating an ideal environment
to replant the orchid and help the roots
grow strong.
Then gently place the orchid into the
pot and tuck dry moss around it.
Dry moss needs to be sterilized before
planting orchids to protect the roots
from fungal infections and help the
plant grow healthily.
[Music]
Then leave the plant undisturbed for one
week without watering.
The dry moss will absorb excess moisture
and help the cuts heal quickly, creating
conditions for new roots to grow.
After one week, you can start watering
the plant, helping to stimulate new root
growth.
[Music]
After watering, you can let the orchid
pot soak in water for about 10 minutes,
helping the roots fully absorb water and
nutrients.
[Music]
Next, take a transparent box to cover
the orchid pot. This creates a mini
greenhouse effect, helping maintain
stable humidity and temperature for the
plant to grow.
And remember to place the orchid pot in
a cool, airy spot with gentle sunlight
so the plant recovers quickly and grows
healthily.
When the growing medium is dry, you
should water or lightly mist the orchid,
helping retain moisture and maintain an
ideal environment for the plant to grow.
[Music]
And here is the result after more than
one month of recovery care.
You can see that from the old stem of
the mother plant, a healthy baby orchid
has grown with well-developed roots and
ready to continue growing strong.
[Music]
If you face any difficulties during the
orchid growing process, don't hesitate
to leave a comment. I'm always ready to
support you so you can grow healthy
orchids that bloom abundantly.
If you want the orchid to grow quickly,
we need to fertilize it. Take one liter
of water in a bottle, preparing to make
nutrient-rich natural fertilizer.
[Music]
Um then take 3 teaspoon of rice
preparing to mix it into the water to
make natural fertilizer for the orchid.
[Music]
Uh rice contains many important
nutrients helping the orchid develop
strong roots, green leaves, and prepare
for new blooming cycles.
[Music]
And from now on, water the orchid with
rice water once every 1 2 weeks, helping
the plant stay healthy and grow faster.
[Music]
Rice water also helps beneficial
microorganisms in the growing medium
thrive, creating a natural environment
that allows the orchid to absorb
nutrients better.
[Music]
Remember to place the orchid pot in a
spot with gentle sunlight so the plant
can photosynthesize.
When photosynthesis is good, the plant
can absorb nutrients most effectively.
[Music]
And here is the result after 2 months.
You can see that the baby orchid growing
from the mother plant stem has developed
very healthily. The leaves have become
sturdy. New roots have grown abundantly
and are very strong, signaling that the
plant is thriving.
[Music]
What do you think about the way I
revived this little orchid? Don't
hesitate to leave a comment and share
your thoughts. I'm really looking
forward to hearing your feedback and
experiences.
[Music]
continue caring for the plant with
natural fertilizer, helping the orchid
stay healthy.
[Music]
And here's the result after 3 months.
You can see that the leaves have become
firmer and shinier. This proves that the
orchid is healthy and absorbing
nutrients very well.
The roots have grown long and dense,
showing that the orchid is in a strong
growth phase and completely healthy.
In addition to English dubbing, we have
now created French, German, Italian,
Spanish, Portuguese, Japanese, Hindi,
Dutch, Polish, Korean, and Indonesian
versions to help you listen and
understand the content easily.
To hear the language, open the video and
click on settings, the gear icon to
select the appropriate audio language.
[Music]
Continue caring for the plant with
natural fertilizer so the orchid grows
healthy and quickly blooms with vibrant
flowers.
[Music]
And here is the result after 6 months of
recovery.
You can see that the leaves are now
shiny and firm from an orchid that once
had root rot and lost all its leaves.
Thanks to consistent care, it has
revived and sprouted a baby plant from
the mother stem. Now, the baby orchid
has grown strong and is blooming
beautifully. A truly proud achievement
and a great source of motivation for
orchid lovers.
[Music]
This shows that as long as you are
patient and care for it properly, even a
weakened orchid can revive and bloom
beautifully again. Keep loving and
caring for them everyday and soon you
will enjoy clusters of fresh, vibrant
flowers right at home.
[Music]
So, don't be discouraged when your
orchid has problems. Just care for it
with natural methods and patiently wait,
and you will be rewarded with vibrant,
healthy blooms. Each time it flowers is
a joy and a well-deserved reward for the
effort you've put in.
[Music]
I hope you will enjoy this video. If you
find it helpful, don't forget to like
and subscribe so you won't miss the next
tips on caring for orchids in a natural
and simple way.
[Music]
Thank you for watching until the end of
the video. Wishing you joy, happiness,
and thriving orchids that grow greener
and bloom more beautifully. See you in
the next video.