Welcome to the Happiness Garden channel.
If you have an orchid that is rotting
like this, don't rush to throw it away.
In this video, I'll guide you on how to
treat rot and restore it so it can can
quickly bloom again.
Prune off the dry stems, damaged roots,
and withered leaves to give your plant a
fresh burst of energy, helping it grow
healthier and more vibrant.
[Music]
Which country are you watching this
video from? Please leave a comment and
let me know.
[Music]
It's amazing that we can chat together
from all around the world.
[Music]
Damaged roots, leaves, and stems, if not
removed, can create conditions for rot
to spread, worsening the plant's
condition. Remove these parts
immediately to protect the plant's
health. Health health.
[Music]
Only leave the fresh roots like this.
Then wash the plant thoroughly with
water to remove dirt, mold, and
bacteria, helping to keep the plant
clean and prevent disease more
effectively.
[Music]
Then place the plant in a dry area
overnight to allow the cuts to heal.
helping the plant recover better and
prevent infection.
[Music]
Then I take a teaspoon of cinnamon as
cinnamon has excellent properties in
helping orchids recover from rot while
also preventing bacteria and mold from
entering.
[Music]
Add it to one liter of boiling water to
allow the cinnamon essence to dissolve
into the water.
And I cut an aloe vera leaf as it
contains many valuable nutrients that
help weak orchids recover quickly and
grow stronger. Aloe vera also has
anti-inflammatory properties helping to
protect the plant from infection.
Uh, cover the lid and leave it
overnight, allowing the nutrients from
aloe vera and cinnamon powder to fully
dissolve into the water, creating a
nutrient-rich solution that helps the
orchid recover effectively.
After one night, strain the mixture to
remove the residue, leaving only the
pure nutrient solution ready to be used
for the orchid.
[Music]
Then soak the orchid roots in this
mixture for 20 minutes to disin infect
them while also stimulating the roots to
grow quickly and healthily.
Next, I use a cotton pad to soak up the
mixture and gently wipe the top and
bottom of the leaves, helping the plant
absorb nutrients better and preventing
diseases caused by bacteria and mold.
[Music]
After soaking for 20 minutes, remove the
orchid and plant it in a new pot to help
it recover better.
I plant the orchid using pine bark mulch
because it helps with good drainage,
maintains stable moisture, and provides
an ideal environment for the orchid
roots to grow healthily.
[Music]
If you haven't subscribe to the channel
yet, don't forget to hit the subscribe
button so you won't miss any helpful
videos on orchid care. Join the
Happiness Garden family today.
[Music]
Spread a little moss on top of the
orchid pot to help retain moisture for
the roots, create a cool environment,
and protect the plant from drying out.
It also helps prevent weeds and keeps
the orchid pot clean.
[Music]
After planting, water the orchid with
this mixture every 10 days to provide
continuous nutrients and support the
plant in growing strong and healthy.
[Music]
This mixture works wonderfully in
helping the orchid recover and grow
strong. Cinnamon powder has
antibacterial properties, helping to
prevent mold and bacteria from entering
the cut while also aiding the healing
process.
Aloe vera provides essential nutrients
such as vitamins, minerals, and amino
acids, stimulating the growth of roots
and leaves and boosting the plant's
immune system.
[Music]
Remember
to place the orchid pot under gentle
sunlight, avoiding direct and strong
sunlight as this helps the orchid grow
healthily without the risk of leaf burn.
[Music]
After one month of recovery, you can see
that the orchid has become fresher.
The new leaves have grown taller,
indicating that the plant is growing
strong, strong, and healthy. The the
appearance of new leaves shows that the
plant is absorbing nutrients and energy
well, ready for its next phase of
growth.
[Music]
Wow, the new roots have grown a lot,
showing that the orchid is recovering
quickly and healthfully. Strong root
growth helps the plant absorb water and
nutrients better, ensuring sustainable
growth for the plant in the future.
[Music]
When replanting the orchid into the pot,
be sure to handle it gently to avoid
damaging the new roots.
[Music]
After planting, continue to care for the
orchid with this nutrient mixture every
10 days. This will provide continuous
nutrients to the plant, promote strong
root and leaf growth, protect the plant
from diseases, and enhance its
resistance.
[Music]
On regular days, if you notice the
growing medium is dry or the roots turn
silvery white, simply water or mist
gently to keep the orchid hydrated.
Remember
to always place the orchid pot in a
location with gentle sunlight, allowing
the plant to absorb enough light for
photosynthesis without stressing the
plant.
After the next 2 weeks, you'll notice
that the new leaves have grown larger,
uh, indicating that this fertilizer is
helping the orchid recover effectively.
[Music]
The growth of new leaves shows that the
plant is absorbing nutrients well and
gradually becoming healthier, ready for
the next stages of development.
[Music]
Continue
to care for the orchid with this
nutrient mixture every 10 days, helping
to maintain steady growth and provide
the necessary nutrients to keep the
orchid healthy and thriving.
[Music]
If you encounter any difficulties in
caring for and restoring your orchid,
don't hesitate to leave a comment for
me. I'll be happy to assist you.
[Music]
After the next 2 months, you'll see that
the orchid has grown very healthily with
vibrant green leaves and strong roots.
Just like other healthy orchids, the
plant has fully recovered and is ready
for the next growth cycle, prepared to
bloom if cared for properly.
Heat.
[Music]
Hey, Heat.
With this simple method, you can easily
care for and restore weak orchids at
home. This approach helps the orchid
continue to grow strong, produce new
leaves, and eventually bloom
beautifully, bringing a fresh and
vibrant beauty to your living space.
[Music]
I hope you enjoyed this video. Don't
forget to like, share the video so more
people can learn how to care for
orchids. And if you haven't subscribed
to the channel yet, make sure to
subscribe so you won't miss the next
videos. Thank you for watching and see
you in the next video.
[Music]
Hello everyone.
To give you more options for making
natural fertilizers to care for orchids
at home, helping your plants grow
healthy and bloom beautifully, today
I'll continue sharing a new fertilizer
making method that's super simple and
effective.
[Music]
Let's explore together.
This is the orchid I bought which was
grown in an industrial orchid garden and
it has now finished blooming.
[Music]
If you don't know how to care for it,
the orchid after blooming may become
weak. Its leaves could turn yellow.
Roots may dry out or rot. And it will be
very difficult for the plant to bloom
again.
Remove all the damaged leaves
[Music]
because damaged orchid leaves can harbor
pests, mold, and bacteria, negatively
affecting the plant's health and
hindering its new growth.
[Music]
and remove all the damaged roots.
Um because damaged orchid roots can
cause rot to spread to healthy roots
making it difficult for the plant to
absorb water and nutrients which weakens
the plant and hinders its growth.
[Music]
If you haven't subscribed to the channel
yet, please click the subscribe button
to support me and not miss any orchid
growing tips.
[Music]
Um, in this spot there's still a dormant
flower bud that hasn't grown into a
bloom yet. So, I'll keep it so it can
continue to develop and flower.
Uh, at the spots where the flower spikes
have finished blooming, they won't bloom
again. So, they should be discarded.
[Music]
This is cinnamon powder which has
antibacterial and antiseptic effects.
[Music]
Then take cinnamon powder and sprinkle
it on the cut to help it heal faster.
Please comment to me which country you
are watching the video from.
It's great that we can chat together
from all over the world.
[Music]
Then leave it overnight without watering
to let the cut heal completely.
[Music]
Then I use potatoes as natural
fertilizer for orchids.
Take about 10 g.
[Music]
Then add about five dry eggshells.
Eggshells when used as natural
fertilizer for orchids provide calcium,
improve soil structure, enhance root
health, and help the orchid grow strong
and resist diseases.
[Music]
Add 300 mm of water and puree the whole
thing.
[Music]
Which country are you watching videos
from? Please comment for me.
Um, it's nice that we can chat together
from all over the world.
[Music]
Then leave overnight.
After one night,
stir to dissolve the nutrients in the
water.
[Music]
Then strain to get this water.
Add one liter of water.
[Music]
Add one liter of water. Step one, use a
soft cloth to soak up this liquid
fertilizer solution and gently wipe the
leaves.
[Music]
Clean both the top and bottom sides of
the leaves thoroughly.
[Music]
Wiping orchid leaves with a liquid
fertilizer solution made from potatoes
and eggshells helps provide direct
nutrients to the leaves, strengthen the
orchid's health, stimulate
photosynthesis, and make the leaves
greener and healthier.
[Music]
And it also helps remove dirt, mold, and
impurities on the surface of the leaves,
allowing the plant to easily absorb
light and perform photosynthesis.
[Music]
In addition to the English voice over,
we have now created voiceovers in
French, German, Italian, Spanish, and
Portuguese to help you listen to and
understand the video content more
easily.
How to select the audio language on
YouTube. One, uh, open the video and
click on settings, the gear icon. Two,
select subtitles CC. Three, click on
audio and choose the language you want.
English, France, Deutsch, italiano,
espanol or Portuguese.
[Music]
Then use a soft cloth to wrap the
dormant flower bud.
[Music]
Step two, put this solution into a spray
bottle and spray it on the orchid.
[Music]
Use
spray skills above and below the leaves.
[Music]
This provides additional nutrients to
the plant, enhances leaf growth,
stimulates flowering, and helps the
orchid grow healthy, resist pests, and
improve its overall resistance.
[Music]
Then spray this water here to awaken the
dormant flower bud, helping it bloom
faster.
[Music]
Step three, water the solution onto the
roots and the orchid growing medium.
[Music]
Watering with a liquid fertilizer made
from potatoes and eggshells can help
stimulate plant growth, including both
root and flower development.
[Music]
Soaking in this solution for about 20
minutes helps plant roots absorb water
and nutrients best.
[Music]
After 20 minutes, take the orchid pot
out.
[Music]
Step four, use a clean, soft cloth to
gently wipe off the water droplets from
the leaf axles.
Avoid using rough cloths or materials
with stiff fibers that might damage the
leaves.
[Music]
Wiping off excess water from the leaf
axles of orchids is an important step in
orchid care because stagnant water on
the leaves can lead to issues like rot
or mold.
[Music]
Remove the wrapper from the sleeping
bud.
Do all four steps once a week with this
liquid fertilizer for your orchids.
Place it in a well-lit area so the
orchid can photosynthesize and
metabolize properly.
Results after 1 month.
[Music]
The leaves will be greener and
healthier.
[Music]
The roots grow very quickly and many new
root tips grow.
[Music]
New roots help the plant absorb water
and essential nutrients from the soil or
growing medium, which is vital for
healthy plant development and blooming.
[Music]
If the new roots are not strong and
healthy, the plant will struggle to
supply nutrition and moisture to the
flowering tissues.
[Music]
When new roots are welldeveloped, the
plant can adequately supply the
necessary nutrients and moisture to
trigger the blooming process, resulting
in larger, more beautiful, and
longerlasting flowers.
[Music]
You can see that the sleeping bud has
awakened and grown into a new flower
spike. And if
[Music]
now I'm planting it into a larger pot so
the orchid can thrive better in the
outdoor environment.
[Music]
Planting with pine bark chips helps
retain moisture well while also draining
quickly, preventing the orchid's roots
from rotting.
[Music]
Then you take care of the orchid like
other normal orchids.
I hope you enjoy this video. Don't
forget to like, share, and subscribe to
the channel so you don't miss out on
helpful videos about orchid care.
[Music]
Take care of your orchids with all the
love and attention you have for nature,
and you will be rewarded with stunning,
vibrant flowers that light up your
world. dispelling all worries and
stress, bringing you peace and endless
joy.
[Music]
Thank you for supporting the channel and
I wish you peaceful moments and joy with
your beautiful orchids.