Welcome to the little garden called
Happiness, where flowers are cared for
with love and passion.
[Music]
Today, I want to share with you a simple
but very effective method using natural
fertilizer that helps orchids develop
strong roots and exceptionally healthy
green leaves.
Your orchid will produce many flower
spikes, and when blooming, the flowers
will be vibrant in color, lasting long
on the stem before gently wilting.
[Music]
The first ingredient I use to make
natural fertilizer is pure coffee
powder, a nutrient-rich source that is
very good for the healthy development of
orchids.
Take one spoon of pure coffee powder
into a bottle, then mix it with half a
liter of boiling water to create a
nutrient solution for orchids.
[Music]
Stir the mixture well. Cover it with a
lid and let the water cool completely
before using.
[Music]
Next, take half a liter of room
temperature water and put it into
another glass.
[Music]
Then add one spoon of baking yeast into
that glass of water.
[Music]
The last ingredient I use is oatmeal
powder, a rich source of important
nutrients that helps orchids grow
stronger and healthier every day.
[Music]
Add one spoon of oatmeal powder together
with the baking yeast into the glass.
[Music]
Stir the mixture well and then let it
sit for a few hours to allow the
fermentation process to take place.
[Music]
After 2 hours, when the water has
cooled, stir well and then strain out
the coffee grounds to collect The
solution.
[Music]
Dilute the solution with water at a 1:1
ratio to safely use it for orchids.
Step one, use a soft cloth to soak the
diluted coffee solution. Then gently
wipe both the upper and lower surfaces
of the leaves.
This method helps clean dust off the
leaves while also providing nutrients to
make the leaves healthier and greener.
[Music]
Be sure to wipe the underside of the
leaves thoroughly as this is where dust
often accumulates and pests are more
likely to attack.
[Music]
When the leaf surfaces are cleaned
regularly, harmful mold and bacteria
will have little chance to develop,
thereby helping protect the plant from
unwanted diseases.
If you see leaves that are wilted,
yellow, or damaged, you need to remove
them immediately to help the plant
maintain its health and prevent the
disease from spreading to other leaves.
Properly wiping the leaves also helps
stimulate gas exchange on the leaf
surface, supporting better respiration
and enhancing the overall vitality of
the plant.
Clean leaves help the plant absorb light
better, thereby promoting efficient
photosynthesis, which helps the plant
grow strong and healthier every day.
Uh please comment and let me know which
country you are watching the video from.
It's wonderful that we can chat together
from all around the world.
If you haven't subscribed to the channel
yet, please click the subscribe button
to support me and never miss any orchid
care tips. It's wonderful to have you
along for the journey.
When caring for orchids, if you see the
leaves at the base and the leaf tips
turning yellow, it is often a sign that
the plant is lacking water or has
damaged roots, causing it to to not
absorb enough water and lack nutrients,
especially nitrogen.
When caring for orchids, if you see the
leaves at the base and the leaf tips
turning yellow, it is often a sign that
the plant is lacking water or has
damaged roots, causing it to not absorb
enough water and lack nutrients,
especially nitrogen.
[Music]
Step two, pour the diluted coffee
solution into a spray bottle.
Then spray the solution evenly onto the
upper and lower surfaces of the leaves
as well as the root area.
Spraying the coffee solution helps
provide many natural nutrients to the
plant, thereby stimulating orchids to
grow strong and healthier every day.
The compounds in coffee also help
enhance the plant's ability to resist
pests, naturally protecting it from
harmful agents.
When sprayed on the leaves, coffee helps
clean the surface, creating favorable
conditions for more efficient
photosynthesis, allowing the plant to
absorb energy better from light.
The coffee solution also helps improve
moisture for both roots and leaves,
keeping the plant fresh and preventing
it from drying out.
Step three, strain the liquid from the
fermented oatmeal solution, then mix it
with the coffee solution to create a
natural nutrient mixture for orchids.
Then use this mixture to water each
orchid pot directly, helping the plant
absorb nutrients easily and effectively.
The coffee oatmeal mixture provides a
rich source of natural nutrients helping
orchid roots grow stronger and absorb
nutrients more effectively.
Uh the lightly fermented mixture gently
stimulates the growth of beneficial
microorganisms in the growing medium
creating a healthy living environment
for the roots.
Regularly watering with this mixture
helps boost the plant's resistance,
effectively preventing common orchid
diseases.
When properly nourished from root to
tip, the plant will have enough energy
to prepare for a new blooming season,
full, vibrant, and long-lasting.
The nutrients in oatmeal and coffee help
the leaves stay lush, shiny, and healthy
while also supporting the growth of new
shoots and leaves.
After each time of applying liquid
fertilizer, you should soak the orchid
pot in this mixture for about 20 minutes
to allow nutrients to deeply penetrate
the roots, helping the plant absorb more
effectively.
Step four, use a soft cloth to gently
soak up the remaining liquid fertilizer
on the leaves and leaf axles, helping
keep the leaves clean and preventing
damage.
[Music]
Wiping the leaves also helps keep the
leaf surfaces dry and ventilated,
preventing water accumulation that can
cause leaf rot or damage.
Wiping off water droplets on the leaves
helps prevent the growth of mold and
bacteria, protecting orchid leaves from
harmful diseases.
Cleaned leaves help the plant breathe
better, creating favorable conditions
for efficient gas exchange and
photosynthesis.
Uh, perform these four care steps for
your orchid two to three times each
month to ensure your orchid stays
healthy and grows well.
[Music]
After soaking for 20 minutes, take the
orchid pot out and place it in a spot
with gentle sunlight to allow the plant
to photosynthesize, helping it absorb
nutrients more effectively.
[Music]
Now, let's take a look at the results
after 2 weeks of caring for the orchids.
You can see the orchid has developed
very large and healthy new roots, a sign
of recovery and good growth.
[Music]
Healthy new roots will help the orchid
absorb nutrients and water more
effectively, thereby promoting the
plant's overall development.
[Music]
Uh strong roots also help the plant
anchor firmly to the growing medium,
maintaining stability for the orchid to
grow vigorously over time.
[Music]
In addition, well-developed roots help
the plant increase its reproductive
capacity, creating favorable conditions
for flowering and producing new shoots
more effectively.
[Music]
When cared for with this fertilizer,
flower buds become healthier, develop
evenly, and have the potential to bloom
more brilliantly.
When cared for with this fertilizer, the
petals will be smooth and firm with
vibrant colors that stay fresh longer.
I hope you will like this video. If you
find it useful, don't forget to hit like
and subscribe to the channel so you
won't miss future shares on how to care
for orchids naturally and simply.
[Music]
Thank you for watching the video. I
always pray that God blesses all of you.
Hello friends.
Nice to meet you on my channel.
You see here a withered orchid. Maybe
it's because you didn't water it or due
to direct sunlight shining on the
orchid.
[Music]
Um, if you want orchids to be nourished
and grow quickly, please watch this
video carefully.
[Music]
Now, I will share this amazing trick
with you.
You need one aloe vera leaf.
[Music]
Which country are you watching the video
from? Please comment below.
It's wonderful that we can chat together
from all around the world.
This aloe vera gel is great for reviving
orchids.
Now apply aloe vera gel on the top and
bottom of the leaf.
[Music]
Aloe vera gel has a very good
moisturizing effect.
[Music]
In addition, aloe vera also contains
vitamins's A, B, and C and minerals such
as nitrogen, phosphorus, and potassium.
[Music]
Uh do this every 5 days and leave the
orchid pot in a cool place for 3 weeks.
[Music]
Next, take one liter of warm water and
put it in the bottle.
[Music]
Then take one spoon of rice and soak it
in this water for about 30 minutes. Let
the nutrients in the rice completely
dissolve into the water.
[Music]
Chop the remaining aloe vera leaves into
small pieces.
[Music]
Then puree with 300 mm of water.
filter out residue. Then add 2 L of
water at room temperature.
[Music]
After soaking for 30 minutes, filter
this rice water.
[Music]
Mix rice water with aloe vera juice.
So I ended up with about 3 L of this
wonderful liquid manure solution.
[Music]
Cover the pot with moss to retain
moisture better.
[Music]
Now you use the solution to water the
orchid every 5 days.
[Music]
Soak the orchid pot in this water for 2
hours.
After soaking for 2 hours, remember to
lift the orchid pot and place it in a
cool place to let the orchid recover.
[Music]
Two weeks later,
Fertilize after two weeks for fresher
orchid leaves.
[Music]
New roots develop very well.
Many new roots are growing.
[Music]
new roots will help transport water and
nutrients from the roots to the stem.
If the leaves are provided with enough
water and nutrients from the roots, the
leaves will gradually become lush again.
[Music]
One month later,
you see the leaves are very fresh.
[Music]
And the orchid grows a new leaf.
after the next two months,
the orchid has grown two branches, two
buds.
But the leaves at the base have turned
yellow. So I will cut off these yellow
leaves.
[Music]
uh instinctively when an orchid buds, if
the plant lacks nutrients, the the base
leaves will turn yellow and fall off to
provide nutrients for the buds to
develop.
Now I need to supplement the orchid's
nutrition by taking three spoons of
rice.
[Music]
Uh then soak in 2 L of water at room
temperature
[Music]
and wait 30 minutes for the nutrients to
completely dissolve in water before
using.
[Music]
30 minutes later,
add 3 tablesp of milk.
[Music]
Rice water and milk are excellent
sources of nutrients for orchids to
grow.
[Music]
Now you water the orchid with this
solution once a week to help the orchid
recover quickly.
[Music]
after the next one month.
After three to four times of applying
liquid fertilizer from milk and rice
water, the orchid had many roots.
[Music]
Hope the video will help you a lot.
If you like the video, remember to hit
like, share, and subscribe to support
me.
Uh, thank you for watching the video.
Wish you luck and see you in the next
videos.
Hello orchid enthusiasts.
Today I'm excited to share with you how
to make homemade organic fertilizer that
helps orchids thrive from their roots,
stems, leaves to flowers. With easy to
find ingredients and a simple process,
this fertilizer not only provides
essential nutrients, but also protects
the environment.
Let's get started.
To fertilize orchids, I use green tea.
Green tea is not only rich in
antioxidants, but also provides
essential nutrients for plants.
Amino acids and minerals in green tea
help plants grow strongly, increase
resistance, and enhance leaf color.
[Music]
In addition, green tea also improves
soil structure and effectively retains
moisture.
Uh, take 10 g of green tea and put it in
a jar.
[Music]
Uh, take 10 g of green tea and put it in
a jar.
[Music]
Cover and wait for it to cool.
1 hour later.
[Music]
Uh, if you haven't subscribed to the
channel yet, please click the subscribe
button to support me and not miss any
orchid growing tips. It's great to have
company.
[Music]
Filter out residue.
Add one liter of water about four cups.
Step one.
Use a soft cotton soaked in tea water to
gently wipe the top and bottom of the
leaves thoroughly.
Compounds in tea have antibacterial
properties helping to prevent mold and
disease.
[Music]
Tea water contains many minerals and
amino acids helping to provide
additional nutrients to plants.
In addition to the English dub, we've
now created dubs in French, German,
Italian, Spanish, Portuguese, Japanese,
Hindi, and Indonesian to help you hear
and understand the content more easily.
Do you have pets? That's my maid.
[Music]
Cleaning dirt from leaves helps leaves
absorb light better, thereby improving
photosynthesis.
Uh tea water helps maintain moisture in
leaves supporting the growth process.
[Music]
Using diluted tea helps plants increase
resistance and fight against harmful
agents.
Which country are you watching videos
from? Please comment for me.
Uh, it's great that we can chat together
from all over the world.
[Music]
In short, this not only helps the plant
stay healthy but also beautifies the
orchid leaves.
Step two,
[Music]
put diluted tea into a spray bottle.
Then spray the substrate, roots, stems,
and leaves of the orchid.
Spraying green tea water also provides
moisture, helping the leaves stay fresh
and reducing stress on the plant.
Green tea spray helps plants increase
their resistance to harmful agents,
making them healthier.
Tea water helps clean leaves, allowing
them to absorb light better and improve
photosynthesis.
Be careful not to spray on flowers.
Water standing on flower petals can
cause rot, especially in humid
conditions, leading to premature flower
deterioration.
[Music]
Standing water on flowers creates
conditions for fungi and bacteria to
grow, causing disease in the plant.
[Music]
When an orchid rots like this flower,
you need to cut it off immediately to
avoid spreading the rot to other
orchids.
[Music]
to make fertilizer for the roots. I need
more grapes.
Just take two grapes and put them in a
blender.
[Music]
Add 300 mls of water, about one cup.
Grapes contain many vitamins, minerals,
and natural sugars which help provide
essential nutrients to the roots.
Puree
Then mix with green tea.
[Music]
Three,
grapes can promote the growth of
beneficial microorganisms in the soil.
support the decomposition process and
improve soil structure.
Green tea provides minerals and amino
acids while grapes provide vitamins and
natural sugars helping the plant receive
adequate nutrition.
Both green tea and grapes have
antibacterial properties which help
prevent diseases and protect plants from
mold.
[Music]
Natural sugars in grapes help enhance
the roots ability to absorb nutrients.
[Music]
Grapes contain antioxidants which help
increase the plant's resistance to
harmful factors.
[Music]
Compounds in green tea and grapes help
increase the plant's resistance to
harmful agents.
[Music]
This combination helps promote the
growth of beneficial microorganisms in
the soil, improving soil structure and
moisture retention.
[Music]
After watering, soak the orchid pot in
this water for about 20 minutes.
[Music]
20 minutes later.
Take the orchid pot out and place it in
a place with lots of scattered light so
the orchid can photosynthesize more.
[Music]
Now let's see the results.
Healthy orchid roots play an important
role in absorbing nutrients and helping
the plant bloom.
[Music]
Well-developed roots help plants become
more stable, facilitating the growth of
stems, leaves, and flowers.
[Music]
Strong roots help plants retain moisture
better, which is important in
maintaining the health and growth of
orchids.
[Music]
Roots absorb nutrients necessary for
photosynthesis, helping plants have
enough energy to grow and flower.
[Music]
Strong roots also help plants resist
diseases and adverse environmental
factors, thereby supporting stable
flowering.
When absorbing enough nutrients and
light, the leaves are healthy and shiny
green.
[Music]
When the roots absorb enough nutrients
and water, the plant is able to focus
its energy on flower development,
creating beautiful and healthy flowers.
[Music]
Thus, the healthy growth of orchid roots
not only helps the plant survive but
also promotes brilliant blooming.
[Music]
Finally, dedicate your love and care to
your plant companions.
Nurture your orchids with all your heart
and you will be rewarded with their
stunning beauty.
[Music]
Goodbye for now and I look forward to
seeing you in the next videos.
[Music]
Wishing you all the luck and success in
your plant care journey.