welcome to happiness Garden
channel are you looking for an easy way
to propagate the most beautiful orchid
in the
world let me show you the simple yet
effective
[Music]
secret this is a dendrobium orchid and I
will breed them from an old pseudo bulb
[Music]
um with old pseudo bulbs if not
separated they will not grow into
seedlings by
[Music]
themselves from these nodes orchids can
grow
[Music]
if you haven't subscribed to the channel
yet please click the Subscribe button to
support me and not miss any Orchid
growing tips it's great to have
[Music]
company apply toothpaste to the cut to
help it heal quickly and prevent the rot
from spreading
[Music]
then wait for it to
dry take two cups of room temperature
water about half
[Music]
liter and add two vitamin B1 tablets
soak old Orchid branches in water mixed
with vitamin B1 for 30
[Music]
minutes this is a sponge
in addition to the English dub we've now
created dubs in French German Italian
Spanish Spanish Portuguese Japanese
Hindi and Indonesian to help you hear
and understand the content videos are
easier
[Music]
uh please comment to me which country
you are watching the video from
it's great that we can chat together
from all over the world
[Music]
spe
clip old Orchid branches fixed to the
[Music]
sponge then you fill the Basin with
water
[Music]
now put it in and it will always float
on
[Music]
water 1 month later
with this simple method after only 1
month there were many small orchids
growing from old Orchid
[Music]
branches I continue to put the Orchid
branch in the water so that the small
Orchid continues to grow
[Music]
after one next
month the little orchid has grown very
well
[Music]
with this simple method after only 2
months I have obtained a lot of
dendrobium
[Music]
orchids uh this way you can also
propagate any other dendrobium Market on
your own
[Music]
if you find it interesting don't forget
to like share and subscribe to support
the
[Music]
channel now you cut the piece and plant
it in a pot for the plant to grow in the
outside
[Music]
environment thank you for watching the
video
[Music]
wish you always success and happiness in
life
[Music]
hello
everyone in today's video I'll share a
new organic fertilizer that will help
help your orchids Thrive and Bloom
[Music]
continuously if you want your plants to
be vibrant and stunning stay tuned for
some great
tips let's get
[Music]
started this pot of orchids has finished
blooming and has yellow leaves
these yellow leaves rot due to bacteria
if not treated promptly rot will spread
very
quickly so remove all damaged
leaves then cut off the dry branches
[Music]
and cut off damaged
Roots that's my maid do you have pets
[Music]
which country are you watching videos
from it's great that we can chat
together from all over the world
do you have
[Music]
apples I took an apple to make natural
fertilizer for
[Music]
orchids cut apples into small pieces
apples are rich in vitamins minerals and
enzymes providing essential nutrients
for plant
growth the compounds and apples can
stimulate the flowering process helping
orchids bloom beautifully
natural compounds and apples help
strengthen the trees resistance to
[Music]
disease use apples helps maintain
moisture in the substrate creating
favorable conditions for root
growth as apples decompose they create a
conducive environment for beneficial
microorganisms improving soil health and
plant
Vitality next I took one aloe vera leaf
and cut it into thin
slices aloe vera leaves contain many
vitamins and minerals that provide
essential nutrients for the
plants aloe vera has antibacterial and
antifungal properties helping plants
resist
diseases then you put aloe vera and
chopped apples into the jar
add 100 m of beer for fermentation
[Music]
and add 3 tblsp of brown sugar to help
ferment quickly and not rot
[Music]
take one liter of
[Laughter]
[Music]
water put water in the pot
Now cover the pot and place in a cool
place for 3
weeks after 3 weeks you will have a
great fertilizer for orchids
this is the bottle I fermented 3 weeks
ago after fermentation for 3 weeks it
will form a GE product that is very good
for
orchids take 50 mm of G apple and aloe
vera
[Music]
then mix with 2 L of water
step one
[Music]
you use this GE water to water and soak
Orchid
Roots GE is rich in vitamins minerals
and beneficial enzymes that support
plant
[Music]
growth the compounds in GE can stimulate
flower development helping orchids bloom
more
vibrantly G promotes the growth of
beneficial microorganisms in the
soil after watering soak the Orchid pot
in this water for about 20 minutes to
help the Orchid Roots absorb nutrients
water and balance the pH level in the
substrate
step
two use cotton soaked in GE water to
gently wipe the top and bottom of the
leaf thoroughly
GE water is rich in vitamins and
minerals aiding orchid leaves in
nutrient
absorption uh the enzymes in GE can
promote Leaf growth making them
healthier and greener
using GE enhances the leaves resistance
to diseases and
pests the antibacterial and antifungal
properties of GE help prevent mold
growth on the
leaves step three
you put GE water in a spray
bottle then spray GE Solution on the
entire orchid
GE spraying promotes the comprehensive
development of plants from Roots to
leaves and
flowers spraying GE on the leaves helps
retain moisture for the plant a
favorable environment for growth
step
four water droplets on leaves can create
conditions for mold and diseases to
thrive wiping them dry helps reduce this
risk when leaves are dry photosynthesis
occurs more efficiently
as light can directly contact the leaf
surface when leaves are dry they can
better absorb nutrients from sprayed
[Music]
Solutions after soaking for about 20
minutes take the Orchid pot out and
place it in a place with lots of light
so the Orchid can photosynthesize
[Music]
better results after 45 days of
treatment with GE solution every 10
[Music]
days the orchid has developed many young
roots
[Music]
young roots are highly sensitive and can
absorb nutrients from the soil or or
watering solution providing essential
substances for the plant
young Roots enhance the plant's ability
to absorb water especially in dry
[Music]
conditions and orchids also develop new
flower buds
leaves also become
stronger the growth of young Roots
stimulates stronger development in
orchids leading to new leaves and
flowers
hours young Roots contribute to forming
a sturdy root system helping the plants
stabilize and grow better
when the orchid's strong roots absorb
enough nutrients the flowers bloom
larger and more brilliantly than
[Music]
usual that's all I want to share with
you thank you for watching the video I
wish you good luck and success in life
goodbye and see you in the next video