Welcome to my happiness
garden. Today I'm going to continue
sharing with you a special way to make
natural fertilizer that helps care for
orchids at
home. By following some simple steps,
you'll see your orchids thrive and bloom
all year round.
Let's get
started. To make this fertilizer, I need
coffee or you can also use coffee
[Music]
grounds. Take one teaspoon of coffee
powder into the pot and add one liter of
hot water.
[Music]
That's my maid. How do you like it?
Uh, incubate and wait for the water to
[Music]
cool. 2 hours later.
Stir until the nutrients are completely
dissolved into the
water. Filter out residue.
[Music]
Then add one liter of water at room
temperature.
Step
[Music]
one, use a soft cloth soaked in coffee
water to gently wipe the top and bottom
of the leaves
thoroughly. Wiping the leaves helps
remove dust and impurities, allowing the
plant to photosynthesize more
effectively.
Coffee can also help increase humidity
for the leaves which is beneficial for
the development of orchids.
Coffee contains many nutrients such as
nitrogen which helps promote plant
growth.
[Music]
The compounds in coffee can enhance the
plant's ability to resist
diseases. Coffee can provide a pleasant
aroma to the surrounding space.
These combined benefits help your
orchids stay healthy and thrive
better. Do this step one to two times a
month.
Step
two, put the ground coffee solution into
a spray bottle.
[Music]
Oh, and then you spray your entire
orchid.
The coffee solution contains nitrogen
and other minerals promoting plant
growth. Nitrogen is crucial for protein
synthesis and chlorophyll production
necessary for photosynthesis.
Compounds in coffee can help orchids
resist certain diseases and pests,
potentially reducing the need for
chemical pesticides.
Uh spraying coffee solution increases
humidity for the leaves and the
surrounding
environment. After spraying, wiping off
the excess water on orchid leaves is
crucial for several reasons.
Um, water accumulation on leaves can
create a favorable environment for the
growth of fungi and
bacteria. If water is not dried off, the
plant is more susceptible to diseases
like leaf rot or mold.
When water sits on the leaves, sunlight
may be reflected, reducing the plant's
ability to
photosynthesize. Wiping the leaves dry
optimizes the photosynthesis process.
Step
three. When orchid roots appear silvery
white and the growing medium is dry,
this usually indicates that the plant is
lacking water and needs to be watered
[Music]
immediately. Coffee solution contains
nitrogen, phosphorus, and potassium,
essential nutrients for plant growth.
[Music]
Nitrogen supports leaf and stem
development, stimulating
[Music]
photosynthesis. Phosphorus strengthens
roots, enhancing water and nutrient
absorption.
[Music]
Potassium boosts plant resilience
against harsh environmental conditions.
[Music]
The natural compounds in coffee can
fight fungi and bacteria, help orchids
fight common diseases such as mold and
root rot due to the antibacterial
properties of coffee.
[Music]
You can soak in this water for about 20
minutes to help kill bacteria in the
growing medium and help the roots absorb
enough water and nutrients.
[Music]
After soaking the orchid pot for 20
minutes, take it out and place the
orchid pot in a place with natural light
but not exposed to direct
[Music]
sunlight. Light that is too strong can
cause leaf burn.
[Music]
Now, let's see the results of caring for
the orchids with natural
fertilizer. Do this one to two times a
month and you will get great
results. After only 2 weeks of care with
this natural fertilizer, the orchid
leaves became healthier and greener than
before.
New roots develop and the root system
remains healthy and
rot-free. Strong roots help the plant
efficiently take up water and nutrients
from the growing
medium. A robust root system helps the
plant resist diseases and harsh
environmental conditions.
Roots also store energy, supporting the
plant through various growth
stages. Well-developed roots facilitate
effective gas exchange, enhancing the
plant's respiration.
When an orchid absorbs sufficient
nutrients and is healthy overall from
its roots, stems, and
leaves. If you haven't subscribed to the
channel yet, please hit the subscribe
button to support me and not miss any
orchid growing tips. It's great to have
you as a companion.
In addition to the English dub, we've
now created dubs in French, German,
Italian, Spanish, Portuguese, Japanese,
Hindi, and Indonesian to help you hear
and understand the content. Videos are
easier. Um, if you encounter any
difficulties in the process of growing
orchids, do not hesitate to comment for
me. I am always ready to support you so
that you can grow healthy orchids and
bloom a lot of
flowers. Now, let me see the results
after 2
months. You can see the orchid has grown
healthier than before and has produced
two new very healthy flower branches.
The tough glossy leaves indicate that
this organic fertilizer is very
effective in promoting the healthy
growth of the orchid and aiding nutrient
absorption. The large thick flower spike
branching into many fishboneike stems
shows that the orchid is getting ready
for a promising blooming season with
many flowers.
This proves that the natural fertilizer
is excellent for blooming, helping the
plant not only grow vigorously, but also
stimulate the formation of many healthy
flower spikes.
[Music]
After blooming, the flowers not only
retain their fresh appearance, but also
display more vibrant and richer colors
than usual, making the orchid pot stand
out and look even more captivating.
Remarkably, the flowers stay on the
spike for a long time before wilting,
showing the plant's strong vitality and
the excellent nutritional support
provided by the natural
fertilizer. With this method of care,
the orchid will bloom repeatedly
throughout the year, bringing fresh and
vibrant beauty all year round.
Uh, the flowers stay on the spike for an
extended period lasting up to 6 months,
allowing the orchid to showcase its
beauty for an extended time, filling the
space with fresh and magnificent charm.
With this simple natural fertilizer care
routine, anyone can effectively take
care of orchids at home without spending
much, allowing the plant to thrive and
bloom beautifully without the need for
expensive
products. Uh, I hope this video provides
helpful information and helps you take
better care of your
orchids. If you found it useful and
enjoyable, don't forget to like, share,
and subscribe to the channel so you
won't miss any future
videos. Uh, I hope this video provides
helpful information and helps you take
better care of your
orchids. If you found it useful and
enjoyable, don't forget to like, share,
and subscribe to the channel so you
won't miss any future videos.