hello everyone welcome to the happiness
Garden
Channel today I'll share an amazing tip
for taking care of orchids after their
flowers have faded this method is
especially effective for helping wilted
or weak orchids recover and grow
[Music]
quickly this is an orchid that has
already bloomed but became wilted and
stunted so it was
discarded I picked it up with the hope
of Reviving it and helping it grow
strong again let's see how I do
it first trim off the old flower Spike
that has long
withered this helps the plant redirect
nutrients to root and leaf growth
instead of sustaining the dried flower
[Music]
stem next upon checking the roots I
found many inorganic fertilizer pellets
in green and gray
[Music]
um this Orchid may have wilted because
the inorganic fertilizer damaged its
roots preventing it from absorbing water
and nutrients which caused the leaves to
wilt therefore we need to remove these
fertilizer pellets and treat the roots
to help the plant recover
[Music]
the roots are severely damaged and dry
uh this prevents the plant from
absorbing water and nutrients
[Music]
uh the next step is to trim off the
damaged Roots so the plant can focus on
growing new healthier ones
next rinse the roots thoroughly with
water this removes any remaining dirt
old fertilizer and damaged Parts
preparing the plant for
Recovery which country are you watching
this video from leave a comment below
and let me
know I'd love to connect and chat with
all of you from around the
[Music]
world to make natural fertilizer I first
take one teaspoon of honey honey
provides natural nutrients and supports
the plant's growth in a safe and
effective
way dilute the honey in 1 liter of
water this makes the solution lighter
allowing it to easily penetrate the
leaves and roots without causing harm
while effectively providing nutrients
[Music]
next I take one aloe vera leaf as it is
excellent for helping wilted or stunted
orchids recover aloe vera provides
moisture and natural nutrients to help
the plant recover quickly and grow
strong add the aloe vera leaf to about
300 M of water
then blend the aloe vera with a blender
until smooth this ensures the aloe vera
is fully mixed into the water creating a
fine smooth solution that can easily
absorb into the roots and leaves of the
Orchid
strain out any pulp or residue from the
aloe vera
mixture this makes the solution smooth
ensuring it can easily penetrate the
plant without clogging or causing damage
to the roots and leaves
[Music]
place the aloe vera leaf in a cup and
pour the aloe vera water over it letting
it soak for about 20
minutes this method helps provide
moisture and essential nutrients
speeding up the recovery process for
wilted orchids
[Music]
after soaking for 20 minutes remove the
Orchid and wipe off any excess mixture
on the
leaves this helps prevent overwatering
or excess mixture reducing the risk of
leaf or root rot
place the Orchid Roots into the
cup this makes it easier to observe and
proceed with the next steps in the
recovery
process now mix the honey with the aloe
vera
mixture and here is vitamin B1 which is
great for recovering wilted leaves and
encouraging new root growth
growth vitamin B1 helps strengthen the
plant's resistance and supports its
quick recovery after stress or
weakness then pour this mixture and soak
the Orchid roots for about 20 minutes
this helps provide all the necessary
nutrients and vitamins accelerating the
plant's recovery
[Music]
process after soaking for 20 minutes we
take the orch it out and plant it into a
new
pot planting it into a new pot provides
the plant with the best conditions to
grow and absorb nutrients from fresh
soil I plant the Orchid using moss to
help retain
moisture Moss is a fantastic natural
material that maintains humidity and
supports the plants quick recovery
[Music]
from now on water the Orchid with the
honey Aloe Vera and Vitamin B1 mixture
once every 10 days this will provide
essential nutrients and moisture
promoting quick recovery and Healthy
Growth
[Music]
on regular days if you notice the
growing medium is dry simply water or
Mist the Orchid to maintain
moisture this helps the plant maintain
proper hydration and grow steadily
without needing the special mixture
[Music]
then place the Orchid pot in a spot with
gentle
sunlight gentle sunlight allows the
plant to absorb enough energy for growth
without burning its leaves or causing
damage from excessive
[Music]
Sun you can use any leftover mixture to
water other regular orchids
this will help stimulate root growth and
promote the development of new chots
improving the overall health and growth
of the
[Music]
plants uh you can see this Orchid of
mine which was cared for using this
method has developed many new shoots and
roots and is now healthy the natural
method using honey Aloe Vera and Vitamin
B1 is truly effective and helps the
plant recover quickly
[Music]
the result after 3 weeks is that the
orchid has developed many new emerging
Roots this is a clear sign that the
plant has recovered strongly and is now
in a healthy growth
[Music]
phase if you haven't subscribed yet
please hit the Subscribe button and
support my
channel your support is a great
motivation for me to keep creating more
interesting and helpful videos
[Music]
the orchid has sprouted a new Leaf
bud this is a great sign that the plant
is recovering well and ready to continue
growing in the future
[Music]
the wilted leaves are much fresher
compared to before the recovery
process this is a clear sign that the
plant has absorbed sufficient nutrients
and is on the path to Healthy Growth
[Music]
I will continue to water this Orchid
with the natural fertilizer mixture of
Honey Aloe Vera and Vitamin B1 once
every 10
days this will help the plant maintain
its health and continue to develop
strong root fruits and leaves in the
future
[Music]
next use a soft cotton pad to soak up
the mixture and gently wipe both the top
and bottom sides of the leaves
this helps provide nutrients directly to
the leaves and remove dirt promoting
better plant health and
[Music]
growth then place the Orchid pot in a
spot with gentle
sunlight remember while fertilizer is
beneficial without sufficient sunlight
the Orchid won't synthesize nutrients
proper ly leading to stunted
[Music]
growth the result after the next 2
months is that the orchid has grown very
well with many new roots and healthy
leaves the Natural Care method with
honey Aloe Vera and Vitamin B1 has
proven to be highly effective
[Music]
you can see the orchid has grown many
new healthy leaves
and it has also sprouted a new flower
Chute which proves that the orchid has
fully
recovered this is a wonderful sign that
the plant is thriving and ready to bloom
soon care for your Orchids with all the
love and tenderness in your heart and
nature will always reward your
efforts every drop of water every moment
of care is a gift that brings life
vibrant blooms and endless
Joy thank you for watching wishing you a
joyful and energetic day goodbye and see
you next time