Hello everyone. Welcome to the Happiness
Garden channel.
Today I'll share an amazing tip for
taking care of orchids after their
flowers have faded. This method is
especially effective for helping wilted
or weak orchids recover and grow
quickly.
Um, these are orchid pots that once
bloomed brilliantly but later withered,
became stunted, and were discarded by
people.
I am quietly observing, trying to see if
any plant still has life so I can save
it.
Even if it's just a bit of green at the
base or a small root reaching out, I
believe that with gentle care, they can
still recover and bloom again.
And as you can see among the discarded
orchid pots, one plant still remains.
The leaves at the base have turned
yellow and wilted, but there are still
two green leaves at the top.
Uh, I picked it up with the hope that it
will come back to life and help it grow
strong again. Let's see how I do it.
First, you need to gently cut off all
the damaged yellow or wilted leaves.
[Music]
You can see that the leaves of this
orchid have been infected with white
fungus.
[Music]
It is these white mold spots that have
silently attacked, causing the orchid to
weaken rapidly. As you can see,
[Music]
this wilted leaf needs to be removed.
Removing the weakened parts helps the
plant avoid wasting energy on sections
that cannot recover, allowing it to
focus its energy on nourishing the
healthier parts and increasing its
chance of recovery.
[Music]
Leave a comment and uh let me know which
country you're watching from. It's it's
wonderful that we can connect and and
chat with each other from all around the
world.
[Music]
If you haven't subscribed to the channel
yet, please hit the subscribe button to
support me and not miss any orchid
growing tips. It's truly wonderful to
have you along on this journey.
Next, you need to cut off the old and
damaged flower spike.
Uh, you can see that the white mold has
spread and attacked even the flower
spike.
When the fungus has reached this stage,
the plant will weaken quickly if not
treated in time. This is when we need to
step in to stop it from spreading.
[Music]
Next, we will check the growing medium
and the plant's roots. This is a very
important step to determine whether the
plant is still healthy and if we need to
replace the medium to help it recover
better.
Uh you can see that there are still many
gray and organic fertilizer pellets in
the growing medium. This type of
fertilizer may not be suitable for
orchid growth as orchids prefer a well
ventilated environment with gentle more
natural nutrients.
[Music]
We need to remove the entire old growing
medium. Replacing it will help create a
clean and well ventilated environment
for the roots to recover.
[Music]
After that, we will cut off all the
damaged roots.
[Music]
Rotten, brittle, or mushy roots can no
longer absorb water and nutrients, and
keeping them may harm the plant.
Removing them helps keep the plant
healthy and ready to grow stronger new
roots.
[Music]
After cutting off the damaged roots, we
can see that there are still quite a few
healthy roots remaining.
This will make the plant's recovery
process easier and more effective. When
the roots are still healthy, the plant
can absorb water and nutrients better,
helping it regain its vitality more
quickly.
[Music]
You can see that the old leaf stem is
also infected with fungus. Therefore, we
need to remove this part to prevent the
fungus from spreading to other parts of
the plant while also keeping the plant
disease-free and providing a better
environment for recovery.
[Music]
After that, we rinse the entire plant
thoroughly under running water.
Uh, this cleaning process helps remove
all the old soil, mold, and remaining
bacteria, creating the best conditions
for the plant to recover.
[Music]
After rinsing, we let the plant drain.
The first ingredient I use to make a
recovery fertilizer for orchids is aloe
vera leaf.
I cut the aloe vera leaf into small
slices and put them into a jar.
Cutting it into smaller pieces helps the
aloe release its nutrients more
effectively and dissolve more easily
when mixed with other ingredients.
The next ingredient I use is tobacco.
With its natural antibacterial
properties, tobacco helps eliminate
harmful fungi and bacteria, supporting
root protection during the orchids
recovery process.
[Music]
In addition, tobacco also helps repel
insects, protecting the orchid from
pests during the recovery phase. It's a
simple yet highly effective ingredient
in plant care.
I add all the ingredients into about one
liter of boiling water.
The high temperature will help the
nutrients in the aloe vera and tobacco
release more quickly, forming a natural
solution that supports orchid recovery.
After that, we wait until the water has
completely cooled down.
After the water cools down, we proceed
to strain out the residue. Filtering
carefully will make the solution
clearer, preventing sediment from
sticking to the roots or affecting the
air flow of the growing medium.
[Music]
The Next ingredient I use is vitamin B1.
This vitamin helps stimulate root growth
and allows the plant to recover more
quickly after being damaged.
The main component of vitamin B1 is
thamin monitrate with a concentration of
2.5 mg. This is the key active
ingredient that stimulates the formation
of new roots and supports the plant's
recovery after pruning.
I add three tablets of vitamin B1 and
stir well until fully dissolved.
[Music]
After that, I soak the plant's roots in
this mixture for about 20 minutes.
The soaking time is just enough for the
roots to absorb nutrients while also
disinfecting and stimulating the
regeneration of new roots.
While waiting for the soaking time, you
can use a soft cloth to absorb the
mixture and gently wipe both the top and
underside of the leaves.
[Music]
This method helps remove any remaining
fungal or bacterial spores and provides
nutrients directly to the leaves.
[Music]
After soaking for about 20 minutes,
gently remove the orchid from the
solution. At this point, the roots have
been cleaned and have absorbed enough
nutrients to begin the recovery process.
[Music]
Since the orchid stem is quite long, I
cut the plant into two parts to
separately recover the top and the base.
This helps each part focus its energy
more effectively and increases the
chance of developing new roots.
I use a clean cloth to gently clean the
cut. Cleaning helps prevent bacteria and
fungi from entering, allowing the cut to
dry quickly and heal better.
[Music]
After that, I apply a thin layer of
melted wax solution to the cut.
[Music]
This layer of wax helps protect the
wound, preventing water and bacteria
from entering and also supports faster
healing of the cut.
[Music]
To replant the orchid, I use moss as the
growing medium.
Uh, but before planting, pour the
prepared solution in to soak the moss.
Uh but before planting, pour the
Soak the moss in the solution for about
10 minutes.
[Music]
While waiting for the moss to soak, I
repurpose a used plastic cup to recycle
it into a seedling pot for the orchid
top. This is a simple, cost-effective
and environmentally friendly method.
[Music]
After that, I take the moss out of the
solution. At this point, the moss is
clean and full of nutrients, ready to be
used as a growing medium for the orchid.
Then I plant the top part of the orchid
into the prepared pot with moss.
The stem will be gently nestled into the
moist moss, creating favorable
conditions for growth and the formation
of new roots.
[Music]
For the lower stem with roots, I planted
into a larger pot that has drainage
holes at the bottom. This design helps
the roots get enough air, prevents water
logging, and reduces the risk of root
rot during the recovery process.
The roots will be gently nestled into
the moist moss, creating favorable
conditions for growth and the formation
of new roots.
[Music]
After planting, place the orchid pot in
a spot with gentle sunlight. Water to
maintain moisture when the growing
medium feels dry, helping the plant
absorb nutrients better and stimulating
the growth of new roots.
[Music]
And here's the result after 5 weeks.
You can see that the lower stem with
roots has revived into a healthy baby
orchid or kei. A wonderful testament to
patience and proper care.
The baby orchid is growing very well
with thick, plump, and healthy roots.
This is a sign that the plant is
absorbing nutrients effectively and is
ready for a new growth cycle.
[Music]
As for the top stem part, you can see
the leaves look fresher and greener than
before. This is a positive sign that the
plant is gradually recovering.
[Music]
I need to carefully check the roots to
ensure they are healthy before
transplanting into a larger pot.
[Music]
Wow. You can see that many new roots
have grown.
[Music]
This is a wonderful sign that the plant
is recovering strongly and is ready to
grow even better in its new pot.
[Music]
These new roots will help the plant
absorb water and nutrients more
effectively, providing a solid
foundation for it to continue growing
healthily and blooming in the future.
To help the orchid grow and bloom, I
planted in a larger pot using pine bark
as the growing medium.
Pine bark provides good drainage,
retains moderate moisture, and creates
an airy environment for the roots to
grow.
[Music]
After planting, you should place the
orchid pot in a cool, well ventilated
area for about 1 to 2 days to let the
roots settle. Then then begin watering
to avoid damaging the newly transplanted
young roots.
When you see that the roots have started
to cling firmly to the growing medium,
you can begin fertilizing. This helps
avoid damaging the young roots and
ensures as the plant uh absorbs
nutrients effectively.
Care for your orchids with all the love
and tenderness in your heart and nature
will always reward your efforts.
[Music]
Every drop of water, every moment of
care is a gift that brings life, vibrant
blooms, and endless joy.
Thank you for watching. Wishing you a
joyful and energetic day. Goodbye and
see you next time.
[Music]