Welcome to the happiness garden. Today I
will continue sharing a simple yet
effective method to help all types of
orchids grow healthily, develop strong
roots, and bloom more brilliantly than
ever before.
This is an orchid that was once thrown
into the trash, but today I will bring
it back and begin the recovery journey
to give it a new chance at life.
[Music]
Although the orchid has withered,
orchids are incredibly resilient plants.
Therefore, as long as they are properly
cared for, they can fully revive and
continue to shine.
[Music]
First, gently cut off all the damaged
roots to prevent the spread of disease
and prepare the plant for the recovery
process.
[Music]
In addition to the English voiceover, we
have now created voiceovers in French,
German, Italian, Spanish, Portuguese,
Japanese, Hindi, Dutch, Polish, Korean,
and Indonesian to help you listen to and
understand the content more easily.
[Music]
To listen in your preferred language,
open the video and click on settings,
the gear icon to select the appropriate
audio language.
Uh, leave a comment and let me know
which country you're watching from. It's
wonderful that we can connect and chat
with each other from all around the
world.
[Music]
After cutting the roots, rinse the
entire plant with water to remove any
remaining dirt and pathogens.
[Music]
Washing not only helps remove dirt and
bacteria, but also allows the plant to
to absorb nutrients more effectively
during the recovery stage.
[Music]
After washing, let the orchid dry
completely. This is an important step to
prevent root rot and create ideal
conditions for the plant to recover.
[Music]
Um, to revive the orchid, I will use
rice, a familiar ingredient, but very
rich in nutrients to make a natural
fertilizer that helps the plant recover
quickly.
[Music]
Take about 3 teaspoon of rice and mix
them with 600 ml of hot water. This will
help effectively extract the natural
nutrients found in the rice.
[Music]
After mixing, cover the container and
let the mixture steep until the water
has completely cooled. This process
allows the nutrients in the rice to
fully infuse into the water.
[Music]
After the water has cooled, stir well to
dissolve all the nutrients from the
rice.
[Music]
Next, strain out the rice residue to
obtain a clear solution, which helps the
plant absorb nutrients more easily and
prevents leftover particles from harming
the roots.
[Music]
Next, strain out the rice residue to
obtain a clear solution, which helps the
plant absorb nutrients more easily and
prevents leftover particles from harming
the roots.
[Music]
I will add three tablets of vitamin B1,
each containing 2.5 mg to the solution
to boost the plant's resistance, support
better orchid recovery.
Step one, place the orchid in a clean
glass. Then pour in the prepared
mixture, soaking the stem for about 20
minutes to allow the plant to absorb the
nutrients.
[Music]
We only need to pour enough water to
cover the stem and base roots without
submerging the entire plant to avoid
leaf rot and crown rot.
Step two, use a soft cloth soaked in the
mixture. Then gently wipe both the top
and underside of the leaves to clean
them and directly provide nutrients to
the plant.
[Music]
Wiping the leaves with the rice and
vitamin B1 mixture provides direct
nutrients to the foliage, especially the
wilted ones, helping them recover faster
and regain a healthy green color.
At the same time, cleaning the leaf
surface helps remove dirt and bacteria,
allowing photosynthesis to occur more
efficiently, thereby boosting the
overall vitality of the orchid.
[Music]
Moreover, regularly wiping the leaves
allows you to detect early signs of
abnormalities such as disease spots or
pests, enabling timely treatment and
effective protection of the orchid.
[Music]
After soaking for about 20 minutes,
gently take the orchid out and let it
dry completely before moving on to the
next step.
[Music]
And now we need to prepare a piece of
floral foam to create a simple
propagation tool that supports a more
effective recovery process.
Please observe carefully and follow each
step exactly as I do so we can help the
orchid revive easily together.
[Music]
In addition to the English voiceover, we
have now created voiceovers in French,
German, Italian, Spanish, Portuguese,
Japanese, Hindi, Dutch, Polish, Korean,
and Indonesian to help you listen and
understand and the content more easily.
To listen in your language, open the
video and click on settings, the gear
icon to select your preferred audio
language.
[Music]
Please leave a comment and let me know
which country you're watching the video
from. It's wonderful that we can connect
and chat from all around the world.
Add just enough clean water so that the
floral foam retains moisture without
being water logged to prevent the roots
from rotting during the propagation
process.
[Music]
If you haven't subscribe to the channel
yet, please hit the subscribe button to
support me and never miss any orchid
care tips. It's wonderful to have you
along on this journey.
[Music]
Place the orchid in the cup for
propagation and keep it in a cool, airy
place. Remember to change the water once
a week to maintain clean moisture and
help the plant recover better.
[Music]
Place the orchid in a cool, well
ventilated spot with soft, natural light
to support the development of roots and
leaves, helping the plant recover
quickly.
[Music]
And here is the result after one month
of recovery.
[Music]
Wow. You can see that the orchid has
grown many new roots around the old
stem. If this shows that the plant is
recovering well and starting a healthy
growth cycle,
[Music]
with a simple method and easy to find
materials, we can completely revive
orchids that once seemed beyond saving,
bringing them back strong and ready for
a new blooming season.
Um, what do you think about the way I
revived this little orchid? Don't
hesitate to leave a comment and share
your thoughts. I'd love to hear your
feedback and experiences.
If you find the content helpful and
meaningful, don't forget to like, share
so more people can see it and subscribe
to support me. Thank you for always
being with me.
Although the leaves are still wilted,
once the roots grow strong and dense,
the plant will gradually recover fully
and fresh green leaves will soon appear
as the roots are the lifeline that
nourishes the entire orchid.
When the roots are healthy, plant the
orchid in a pot with a suitable growing
medium to help it grow and get ready to
bloom.
I chose a pot with drainage holes at the
bottom to ensure the roots stay well
ventilated and to prevent water
accumulation uh that could cause root
rot during care.
At the bottom of the pot, I placed a few
pieces of foam to improve drainage and
keep the roots from getting water logged
when watering.
And the main growing medium I use is
dried moss that has been treated to
remove any fungi or diseases. It retains
moisture well and is safe for the young
roots during the recovery process.
[Music]
However, when planting with moss, make
sure not to pack it too tightly so the
roots have enough space to grow and to
avoid excessive moisture that that can
cause root rot.
During care, you should only water just
enough to keep the medium moist, as the
roots are still young and fragile after
recovery and can easily rot if the
environment is too wet.
[Music]
After planting, I will care for the
orchid using diluted rice water,
watering it twice a month to provide
natural nutrients and support healthy
growth.
[Music]
Diluted rice water contains many natural
vitamins and minerals such as vitamin B,
potassium, and phosphorus. When used
regularly, it helps stimulate healthy
root growth and supports more efficient
nutrient absorption.
In addition, rice water also helps
improve the plant's resistance, making
the leaves greener, thicker, and
healthier, while reducing fungal
diseases in humid conditions, which is
especially important during the recovery
phase.
After that, place the plant in a spot
with gentle sunlight in the morning or
late afternoon to support better
photosynthesis and continued strong
growth.
[Music]
And here is the result after the next 3
months. The healthy orchid roots
spreading throughout the growing medium
show that the plant is absorbing well
and ready to grow.
And especially the orchid has also grown
two new flower buds looking plump and
healthy like a sweet reward in return
for the loving and patient care.
[Music]
The once soft and weak leaves are now
completely firm, showing that the plant
has recovered well and is growing
steadily.
[Music]
Uh the two flower buds are growing
strong, which shows that the plant has
not only revived but is also ready to
enter a promising new blooming season.
With just a few simple steps, we can
completely care for and revive weak
orchids at home, allowing them to come
back strong and once again bloom
beautifully.
Uh, from a withered flower that seemed
close to dying, it has now recovered and
is even getting ready to bloom in the
near future. What do you think about my
method of orchid recovery? Please leave
a comment or suggestion below. I'd
really love to hear your thoughts.
Um, if you run into any difficulties
during the orchid planting process,
don't hesitate to leave a comment. I'm
always here to support you so you can
grow healthy orchids that bloom
beautifully.
[Music]
Um, I hope you'll enjoy this video. If
you find it helpful, don't forget to hit
like and subscribe. so you won't miss
the upcoming tips on how to care for
orchids naturally and simply.
Thank you for joining me on this orchid
revival journey. See you in the next
videos with many more easy and helpful
tips for caring for orchids at home.