Welcome to Happiness Garden.
This is where I share how to care for
and revive orchids using natural methods
and organic fertilizers.
Uh let's make your orchids healthy and
bloom more beautifully than ever.
If you have a wilted orchid like this
one, don't throw it away just yet.
In this video, I'll share how to revive
it and help it grow strong again.
This orchid wasn't cared for properly
after blooming, causing it to weaken and
become stunted. Without timely recovery,
the orchid might die.
First, cut off all the damaged roots to
help the orchid recover better.
[Music]
Um, in addition to the English
voiceover, we have now created
voiceovers in French, German, Italian,
Spanish, and Portuguese to help you
listen to and understand the video
content more easily.
How to select the audio language on
YouTube. One, open the video and click
on settings, the gear icon. Two, select
subtitles CC. Three, click on audio and
choose the language you want. English,
Franc, Deutsch, italiano, espanol or
Portuguese.
[Music]
Next, trim off the damaged leaves so the
orchid can focus on growing.
[Music]
This node hasn't bloomed yet, so we can
stimulate it to grow into a baby cake.
[Music]
For nodes that have already bloomed and
branches that are wilted, trim them off
so the plant can focus on growth.
[Music]
Next, rinse the orchid thoroughly with
water to remove dirt and bacteria.
Which country are you watching this
video from? Leave a comment and let me
know.
[Music]
It's amazing that we can chat together
from all around the world.
[Music]
Next, take an aloe vera leaf to make a
natural fertilizer that helps retain
moisture and quickly revive wilted
orchids.
Then add about 10 g of ginger to the
mixture to boost the orchid's recovery.
[Music]
Add 400 ml of water.
Then blend mix.
[Music]
Finally, strain the mixture to ensure
there are no organic residues left in
the solution.
[Music]
Add one more liter of water to create a
very effective natural fertilizer mix
for orchids.
[Music]
Then pour this mixture over the wilted
orchid to help it recover quickly.
This mixture helps revive wilted leaves
by providing essential nutrients and
moisture. It also stimulates new root
growth and cakey development thanks to
the natural compounds in aloe vera and
ginger, making the orchid healthier and
stronger.
Next, use a soft cotton pad to soak up
the mixture and place it on the unopened
flower node to stimulate cakey growth.
Then soak the orchid in this mixture for
about 20 minutes to allow the plant to
absorb the nutrients effectively.
After soaking for 20 minutes, take the
orchid out.
[Music]
Remove the cotton pad from the node to
allow the orchid to continue growing
without staying too wet for too long.
Sprinkle cinnamon powder on the cut to
help with antibacterial protection and
prevent infection.
[Music]
Then wipe off any remaining mixture on
the leaves to prevent them from rotting.
[Music]
If you haven't subscribed yet, please
hit the subscribe button to support me.
Thank you so much.
[Music]
Then I plant the orchid in a larger pot
to give it more space for better growth.
I plant the orchid using pine bark chips
to ensure good drainage and provide an
ideal environment for root growth.
[Music]
If you haven't subscribed to the channel
yet, please subscribe to support me and
not miss any orchid care tips.
Uh, add a layer of moss on top to help
retain moisture better for the orchid.
[Music]
After planting, water the orchid with
this mixture once every 2 weeks to help
it grow healthy.
[Music]
On regular days, if the growing medium
feels dry, simply water or mist the
orchid to maintain moisture.
[Music]
Then place the orchid pot in a spot with
gentle light, avoiding direct sunlight
to help the plant grow well.
Make sure the area is well ventilated as
well.
[Music]
After one month, your orchid will begin
to recover. The leaves will become
greener. New roots will begin to grow.
And even the kei will have developed.
[Music]
After 1 month, the orchid has grown a
new chute at the tip, showing that the
recovery and growth process is going
very well.
[Music]
The cakey on the stem is growing very
plump and healthy, showing that the
orchid is recovering well and growing
strong.
[Music]
Continue
watering the orchid with the aloe vera
and ginger mixture once every 2 weeks to
maintain healthy growth.
[Music]
Then place the orchid pot in a spot with
gentle light, avoiding direct sunlight
to help the plant grow well.
[Music]
After the next 3 months, the orchid has
grown strong with many new roots, fresh
green leaves, and the kei is starting to
grow bigger.
The orchid now looks very healthy and is
preparing to bloom.
[Music]
I'm going to die.
These two leaves have turned yellow and
wilted and cannot be revived. So, I will
remove them from the orchid to allow the
plant to focus on developing new healthy
leaves.
[Applause]
[Music]
The cakey growing on this flower stem
has strong roots. So, I will cut it and
plant it in a new pot to continue
growing.
[Music]
Separating the kei and planting it
allows the mother orchid to focus its
nutrients on developing healthier leaves
and roots while reducing the furk and
the kei.
[Music]
I plant the kei in a new pot using pine
bark to ensure the plant has good air
flow and drainage.
[Music]
Continue
watering the orchid with the aloe vera
and ginger mixture once every 2 weeks to
maintain healthy growth.
[Music]
Then place the orchid pot in a spot with
gentle light, avoiding direct sunlight
to help the plant grow well. Make sure
the area is well ventilated as well.
Results after 1 month.
Healthy roots and many new flower
branches.
The mother orchid grew strongly with
many fresh green leaves. Healthy roots
and many new flower branches.
[Music]
The baby Kiki has taken root in It's
thriving in its new pot, ready to
continue growing and blooming.
[Music]
Take care of your orchids with all the
love you have for plants, and you will
be rewarded with beautiful, vibrant
flowers and fresh, healthy leaves.
[Music]
Your orchid will grow strong and bring
joy to you everyday.
Thank you for watching.
Uh, take good care of your orchids and
don't forget to subscribe to the channel
to not miss the next videos.
[Music]
Wishing you a wonderful day and see you
in the next videos.
Welcome to my channel.
Rice is a popular and very effective
source of organic fertilizer for plants.
So today I will show you two ways to
make orchid fertilizer from rice.
[Music]
First way,
use three spoons to eat rice.
[Music]
Grind rice into powder.
Please comment to me which country
you're watching the video from. It's
great that we can chat together from all
over the world.
Uh if you haven't subscribed to the
channel yet, please click the subs uh
the subscribe button to support me and
not miss any orchid growing tips.
[Music]
Add one liter of boiled water.
Close
[Music]
the lid and wait for it to cool.
filter out residue.
[Music]
Add 2 L of water.
Now use this water to water the orchid.
Rice contains many nutrients such as
potassium, phosphor, and protein uh
which are essential nutrients for the
growth of orchids.
Using rice as fertilizer helps provide
these nutrients for your orchid garden,
helps plants grow healthy, enhances
resistance to pests and diseases.
[Music]
Rice is a food source for beneficial
bacteria and microorganisms in orchid
growing media.
Using rice as fertilizer enhances the
activity of this micrllora in the orchid
growing medium, thereby helping the
orchid absorb nutrients better.
Do this once a month will help orchids
grow healthy.
[Music]
And of course, it also blooms a lot.
The microfllora in the orchid growing
medium helps to protect the roots from
rot.
When roots grow, they will absorb
nutrients to make flowers more
beautiful. So flowers bloom long.
[Music]
regular care in this way. The leaves are
also provided with enough nutrients so
they grow very green.
[Music]
second Okay.
When we cook, we usually wash the rice.
And every time you cook rice, don't rush
to throw away this rice water.
Please filter this rice water.
[Music]
Wait for it to settle down.
After settling, we filter 100 mm of
clear water above.
[Music]
Add 200 mm plain water.
Put this rice water in a spray bottle.
[Music]
I use this water to spray evenly on the
surface of the orchid leaves.
Vitamin B1 in rice water helps stimulate
the conversion of nutrients, especially
harmful substances such as manganese,
iron, and copper, into a more easily
absorbed form.
[Music]
Vitamin B1 helps strengthen the immune
system of orchids, helps plants resist
attack by pests and other environmental
agents.
[Music]
For the rice water that settles below, I
filter out the scum, then add 2 L of
water.
[Music]
And I use this water to water my orchids
to help stimulate rooting and provide
good nutrition for all types of plants.
Do this once a month for your orchid.
In addition, you need to combine the use
of other organic fertilizers to help the
orchid receive full nutrients.
[Music]
With this care method, you can see that
my orchid has a very strong and healthy
root system.
[Music]
This helps the orchid absorb nutrients
and water more efficiently, promoting
vigorous growth and beautiful blooms in
the next flowering cycle.
The flowers will bloom more vibrantly
with larger petals and richer colors
lasting longer and displaying their full
beauty.
[Music]
Thank you for watching the video.
Goodbye and see you in the next ones.