welcome to my garden in this video I
continue to share how to make natural
fertilizer to care for and restore
orchids after blooming so they can keep
growing and Bloom vigorously in the next
seasons if you haven't subscribed to the
channel yet hit the Subscribe button to
support me and never miss any orchid
care tips it's wonderful to have you
along now let's get
started this is the Orchid after
blooming that I bought from an orchid
shop at a clearance price of just $1 per
plant like
[Music]
this the Orchid is in a state where the
flower spike is withered and the petals
have faded and dried
[Music]
first we need to trim off the withered
flower Spike this helps the plant Focus
its nutrients on the leaves roots and
new CHS instead of sustaining The Faded
flowers
[Music]
then remove any damaged or rotting
leaves this helps protect the plant from
fungal infections as decaying or damaged
leaves can Harbor fungi bacteria and
pests next trim off any damaged or
rotting Roots as decaying or damaged
Roots create an ideal environment for
fungi and bacteria to grow removing them
helps prevent the spread of disease to
other parts of the
[Music]
plant as you can see this Orchid still
has a fairly healthy root system but
because it hasn't been watered for a
long time the plant has become weak
causing the leaves to wilt
significantly do you have lemons we can
use either yellow lemons or green
ones take half a lemon and squeeze the
juice into a
cup lemon has natural antibacterial
properties helping to prevent the growth
of bacteria and fungi in the growing
medium supporting the Orchid and
avoiding issues like root or Leaf
rot then dilute it with 1 lit of room
temperature water
make sure to strain out the pulp and
only keep the diluted lemon
juice please comment and let me know
which country you're watching the video
from it's wonderful that we can chat
together from all around the world
then dip the leaves into the diluted
lemon juice for about 1 minute this
helps disinfect and recover the wilted
Orchid more
effectively lemon juice is acidic and
leaving it on for too long can damage or
burn the leaves therefore it should only
be dip gently and
quickly then wait for 1 minute before
removing it this will help eliminate
fungi and bacteria more
effectively after gently dipping for
about 1 minute immediately remove the
leaves from the diluted lemon juice to
avoid prolonged exposure to the acid
which could harm the
leaves use a clean soft cloth or paper
towel to gently wipe and blot dry any
remaining moisture on the leaves this
helps prevent mold or bacteria from
developing due to prolonged
dampness this method helps protect the
Orchid from the negative effects of
lemon juice while also providing the
benefits of antibacterial properties and
stimulating the plant's growth
[Music]
next we dip The Roots into the diluted
lemon
juice lemon juice has natural acidic
properties that help disinfect The Roots
preventing the growth of mold and
harmful bacteria especially in cases
where the roots are rotting or diseased
diluted lemon juice helps stimulate the
growth of new Roots by creating a
favorable environment for nutrient
absorption which in turn helps the plant
recover more
quickly soak the roots in this mixture
for about 10
minutes for anting orchids I use pine
bark chips as the growing
medium to limit fungi and diseases I
need to treat the growing medium for the
orchids before
planting then I pour the diluted lemon
juice to soak the Orchid growing medium
for about 10 minutes
diluted lemon juice helps reduce the
growth of mold one of the causes of root
and leaf rot in orchids this is
important to keep the growing medium
clean and prevent the development of
fungi once the growing medium is treated
the Orchid will face fewer harmful
environmental factors helping the plant
grow stronger and better resist diseases
then we wait for about 10 minutes before
planting the
Orchid after soaking for about 10
minutes we proceed to plant the Orchid
into the new
pot we take the pine bark out to plant
the Orchid into the pot
as you can see after soaking the roots
in the diluted lemon juice for about 10
minutes The Roots become clean and fresh
again which helps the orchid's recovery
process happen faster
carefully place the Orchid into the pot
making sure the roots are evenly
distributed Not Bent or cramped
[Music]
avoid pressing the plant too tightly
into the pot as this can damage the
roots and affect the plant's growth
simply press the growing medium gently
to ensure the plant stands firm without
being
[Music]
cramped after planting spread a layer of
dry moss over the Orchid pot this helps
protect the roots from direct sunlight
especially when the plant is newly
potted it reduces the risk of root burn
and helps the roots develop
better after planting leave the Orchid
in a cool well ventilated place for a
day and do not water it
uh in the first 24 hours after planting
The Roots need time to adjust to the new
growing medium if you water immediately
the medium could become saturated
creating a favorable environment for
mold and bacteria to grow leading to
root rot not watering helps minimize
this
[Music]
risk since the orchid has a healthy root
system after one day I I proceed to
apply natural fertilizer to stimulate
faster
growth to make natural fertilizer I take
a slice of fresh potato
[Music]
place the potato into a
blender add 0.25 L of water and blend
until
smooth potatoes are rich in vitamins and
minerals especially potassium phosphorus
and some Amino acids these nutrients
help orchids grow stronger stimulate
root growth and assist the plant in
recovering quickly after stress or
weakness
[Applause]
[Music]
then strain out the residue straining
helps make the fertilizer water clearer
reducing the risk of bacteria and fungi
growing in the undissolved particles
this also helps prevent harm to the
Orchid
then dilute it with 1 liter of water
this helps reduce the concentration of
nutrients in the fertilizer preventing
nutrient overload that could damage the
plant's
Roots it's a good way to provide
nutrients without overwatering or
overdosing the
plant after preparing the potato mixture
use a soft cloth to soak up the mixture
and gently wipe both the top and bottom
sides of the orchid's
leaves the potato mixture contains
nutrients like potassium and vitamins
which help directly nourish the orchid's
leav
leaves wiping the leaves helps the plant
absorb these nutrients promoting strong
growth and improving the overall health
of the
[Music]
Orchid then pour the potato mixture into
a spray bottle and Mist the entire
orchid plant
um the nutrients in the potato help
stimulate the growth of new leaves and
strengthen the root
system spraying the potato water on the
entire plant provides the Orchid with
extra energy to recover after periods of
weakness or
stress potatoes have natural
antibacterial properties helping to
protect the plant from mold bacteria and
common
diseases then water the orchid's roots
with the potato
mixture potassium and phosphorus in
potatoes help enhance root growth
particularly by encouraging strong and
widespread root
development when the the roots are
healthy and welldeveloped the plant can
easily absorb enough water and nutrients
which helps it grow more
holistically perform Leaf wiping
spraying and watering the orchid's roots
with the potato mixture twice a
month then place the Orchid pot in a
location with gentle sunlight so that
the plant can photosynthesize allowing
the natural fertilizer to work more
effectively
now let's take a look at the results
after 45 days of care and Recovery using
the natural potato
fertilizer um as you can see the orchid
has grown new leaves and become sturdier
with a shinier healthier green
color not only that but the orchid has
also grown a new flower Spike which
which clearly shows that this natural
fertilizer has a positive effect on the
plant's
growth I continue to care for this
Orchid using the natural potato
fertilizer by following the steps of
watering spraying and wiping the leaves
twice a month
the potato fertilizer helps the Orchid
quickly recover from a weakened state or
nutrient
deficiency the appearance of a new
flower spike is a clear sign that the
plant has received the necessary support
and is returning to a phase of strong
growth remember to place the Orchid pot
in a spot with gentle sunlight so the
plant can photosynthesize allowing the
natural fertilizer to work even
better now let me invite you to see the
results after the next 3 months of care
using the natural
fertilizer as you can see the leaves
have become much Greener sturdier and
healthier than before
and the orchid has even produced
multiple flower spikes at the same time
on the same
plant wow there are as many as six
flower spikes growing at the same time
which proves that the fertilizer is
really effective for recovering and
caring for orchids
[Music]
your orchid blooming with six flower
stems at the same time is a clear sign
that the fertilizer has had a strong
effect in revitalizing and taking care
of the
plant that is a great achievement and
proves that the plant is very healthy
and thriving these are the reasons why
natural fertilizer has had such
wonderful
effects give your orchid all the love
and care you would give to a close
friend don't forget with every bit of
love you give the plant will reward you
with beautiful blooms and vibrant
life um I hope this video brings Great
Value to you if you found it helpful
don't hesitate to share it with those
around you and don't forget to hit the
like button to support me in continuing
to share interesting and useful
content thank you all for taking the
time to watch the video wishing you a
wonderful day and see you in the next
videos