Welcome to the garden, where each flower
tells its own story, where you can
pause, breathe, and feel the natural
beauty around you.
Today, I will continue to guide you on
how to repot and care for orchids,
helping the plant grow strongly from
roots to leaves, ready to bloom all year
round.
[Music]
When growing orchids, if you notice the
roots growing strongly, but the pot is
too small, this is a sign that the plant
needs more space to grow fully and
healthily.
[Music]
Repot immediately so the plant has more
space to grow well. The roots are well
ventilated and absorb nutrients
effectively, helping the orchids stay
healthy and bloom more beautifully.
[Music]
You can see many new roots growing. If
you don't repot in time, these roots can
easily rot because the pot is too tight,
limiting the plant's growth.
[Music]
Uh before planting the orchid in a new
pot, we need to cut off the damaged
roots. But first, sterilize the scissors
with 90% alcohol to ensure safety and
prevent infection for the plant.
[Music]
Cutting off the damaged roots helps the
plant focus nutrients on the healthy
roots, prevents fungal diseases, and
creates conditions for the orchid to
grow more strongly.
[Music]
Remove all the old growing medium
because it may have lost nutrients,
retain too much moisture, or contain
pathogens affecting the healthy growth
of the orchid.
[Music]
Then rinse thoroughly with water to
ensure there is no dirt or impurities on
the roots, helping the orchid be ready
to adapt to the new growing medium.
[Music]
Then let the roots air dry naturally for
a while.
[Music]
Take one liter of clean water into a
container ready to prepare the
disinfecting solution, ensuring safety
and preventing harmful bacteria for the
orchid.
Here
is iodine alcohol used to disinfect the
roots and tools, helping prevent fungal
diseases and protect the orchid's
health.
Add six drops of iodine alcohol into the
water container. Stir well to create a
mild disinfecting solution safe for the
orchid roots.
[Music]
Then pour this solution into a container
and soak the orchid roots for about 20
minutes.
[Music]
Soaking the roots helps remove bacteria
and fungal pathogens, cleanse the roots,
and creates conditions for the orchid to
absorb nutrients more effectively after
repotting.
[Music]
Then use a soft cloth to soak up the
solution and gently wipe both the top
and bottom surfaces of the leaves.
[Music]
Wiping the leaves helps remove dirt,
bacteria, and fungal pathogens on the
leaf surface, preventing harmful issues
for the plant, and keeping the orchid
leaves clean.
Clean leaves absorb light better,
helping the plant perform photosynthesis
effectively, thereby supporting growth
and flowering.
Shiny and clean leaves not only make the
plant more beautiful but also indicate
good health, helping the orchid develop
fully from leaves to roots and flowers.
Then we choose a pot of appropriate size
with drainage holes, ensuring the orchid
roots have space to grow and preventing
water logging.
After soaking for about 20 minutes,
gently take out the roots and plant the
orchid in the new pot, helping the plant
adapt to a clean environment and absorb
nutrients better.
Insert a few pieces of foam around the
roots and at the bottom of the pot to
increase irerration, preventing the
roots from water logging and creating a
good growing environment for the orchid.
If you haven't subscribed to the
channel, press the subscribe button to
support me and not miss any orchid
growing tips. It's wonderful to have you
along.
Um, please comment and tell me which
country you are watching the video from.
It's wonderful that we can chat together
from all around the world.
[Music]
Regarding the main growing medium for
orchids, I always prioritize choosing
sterilized pine bark, which helps the
roots stay airrated, absorb nutrients
well, and reduces the risk of fungal
diseases.
In addition to the English voiceover, we
have now created French, German,
Italian, Spanish, Portuguese, Japanese,
Hindi, Dutch, Polish, Korean, and
Indonesian versions to help you listen
and understand the content easily.
[Music]
To listen in your preferred language,
open the video and click on settings,
the gear icon, to select the appropriate
audio language.
Spread a little moss over the surface of
the growing medium to retain moisture,
create a natural environment, and help
the orchid grow healthily.
Then place the orchid pot in a cool,
airy spot for about 1 day without
watering, allowing the plant to adapt to
the new pot and the roots to stabilize
before absorbing nutrients.
For orchids with leaf rot caused by
fungi, the main reason is usually that
the roots are cramped and do not drain
well, allowing fungi to grow and attack
the leaves.
Rotten leaves contain many fungal
pathogens, so they need to be removed
immediately and the orchid pot isolated
from other plants in the garden to
prevent spreading.
[Music]
Then remove the old pot to completely
get rid of the old growing medium and
any environment that may contain fungal
pathogens. Preparing for repotting the
orchid in a new pot.
[Music]
You can see that the roots have started
to show black spots, which are signs of
damaged or diseased roots that need to
be treated promptly to prevent
spreading.
Old growing medium often loses
nutrients, becomes compacted, and
retains too much moisture, causing
orchid roots to rot easily and limiting
growth.
[Music]
Cut off the damaged roots to remove the
rotten or weak parts, helping the plant
focus nutrients on the healthy roots and
grow better.
[Music]
Then rinse the roots with water to
remove dirt and any remaining pieces of
old growing medium, helping the orchid
roots stay clean before repotting.
[Music]
Next, use a dry cloth to soak up all the
water on the leaves and roots, helping
reduce excess moisture and minimize the
risk of root rot before repotting.
[Music]
Then place the orchid in a cool, airy
spot to prepare for um for treating
wounds on the leaves, helping them
recover and preventing infection.
[Music]
Next, I use iodine alcohol to treat
wounds on the orchid by mixing one
teaspoon of iodine alcohol with one
teaspoon of clean water, creating a
diluted solution safe for the leaves and
roots.
[Music]
Then use this mixture to apply directly
to the wounds on the orchid, helping
disinfect, prevent fungal infections,
and support faster leaf recovery.
[Music]
The solution helps clean and protect the
wounds, creating conditions for the
leaves and plant tissue to recover
quickly, maintaining the overall health
of the orchid.
[Music]
Then place the orchid in a cool, airy
spot for about 1 day to let the cuts dry
naturally, helping prevent fungal
infections and preparing the plant to
adapt to the new environment.
[Music]
Now take about two cups of clean water
into a container ready to prepare the
natural fertilizer to nourish the
orchid. Dot.
[Music]
Then add 1 teaspoon of molasses into the
container, which is a natural source of
nutrients that helps nourish beneficial
microorganisms in the growing medium and
supports healthy growth.
[Music]
Next, add 3 teaspoon of breadcrumbs into
the container, helping to provide
additional organic matter, stimulate
beneficial microorganisms, and supply
nutrients for the orchid.
Close the container and place it in a
cool, airy spot for about 1 day to allow
the mixture to ferment, helping
microorganisms grow and creating a
nutrient-rich natural fertilizer for the
orchid.
[Music]
After one day, open the lid and stir the
fermented mixture well, helping the
natural fertilizer become uniform and
ready to provide nutrients for the
orchid.
Strain out the residue from the
fermented mixture to obtain a smooth
fertilizer solution, easy to absorb and
safe for the orchid roots.
[Music]
Then add 2 cups of clean water to make a
total of about one liter of natural
fertilizer mixture ready to use for
nourishing the orchid.
[Music]
Next, pour the natural fertilizer
mixture into a spray bottle, making it
easy to spray evenly on the orchid's
roots and leaves, ensuring the plant
absorbs nutrients effectively.
[Music]
Spray the natural fertilizer mixture
thoroughly on both the top and bottom
surfaces of the leaves, helping the
leaves absorb nutrients optimally and
stimulating healthy orchid growth.
The mixture contains beneficial
microorganisms in the growing medium and
on the leaves, helping improve soil
health, support strong root growth, and
prevent fungal diseases.
Spraying natural fertilizer helps the
orchid increase resistance, have smooth
green leaves, strong roots, and prepare
the plant to bloom evenly and lastingly.
[Music]
In addition, you can also water the
natural fertilizer mixture directly onto
the roots and growing medium.
[Music]
Watering the mixture onto the roots
helps the plant absorb nutrients quickly
and effectively, promoting healthy root
system growth.
[Music]
The fertilizer mixture helps increase
the activity of beneficial
microorganisms in the growing medium,
improves its structure and paracity,
creating favorable conditions for root
development.
Then use a dry cloth to soak up all the
water on the leaves.
[Music]
Wiping the leaves dry helps remove
excess water, prevents the growth of
fungi and bacteria, and keeps the leaves
clean and healthy, supporting effective
photosynthesis.
[Music]
Then place the orchid pot in a spot with
gentle sunlight. Remember, no matter how
good the fertilizer is, if the plant
lacks light, photosynthesis will be
inefficient, making it difficult for the
orchid to grow and bloom.
[Music]
For orchids with leaf rot, after the
wounds on the leaves have dried
naturally, we proceed to repot into a
new pot, helping the roots stay airrated
and creating a clean environment for the
plant to recover.
[Music]
Choose an orchid pot of appropriate size
with drainage holes, ensuring the roots
have space to grow, preventing water
logging and creating conditions for the
plant to recover quickly.
[Music]
Choose sterilized dry pine bark as the
growing medium, helping the roots stay
airrated, absorb nutrients well, and
reduce the risk of fungal diseases.
Spread a little sterilized dry moss over
the surface of the pot, helping retain
moisture, create a natural environment,
and support healthy orchid growth.
[Music]
Um, after planting, water the natural
fertilizer mixture directly onto the
roots and thoroughly wet the growing
medium, helping the plant absorb
nutrients effectively and stimulating
root growth.
[Music]
After watering, place the orchid pot in
a spot with gentle sunlight to allow
photosynthesis, helping the plant absorb
light, nourish smooth green leaves and
promote healthy growth.
[Music]
And here's the result after 1 month. You
can see strong root growth, smooth green
leaves, and the orchid is on the path to
full recovery and development.
The orchid has grown new leaves, strong
and sturdy, showing good development
from roots to leaves, ready for the
upcoming blooms.
[Music]
The root system has grown strong and
produced many new roots, helping the
plant absorb water and nutrients
effectively while creating a solid
foundation for the long-term growth of
the orchid.
[Music]
If you haven't subscribed to the
channel, press the subscribe button to
support me and not miss any orchid
growing tips. It's wonderful to have you
along.
[Music]
Here
is the orchid with leaf rot. After 1
month of care, you can see that the
plant has recovered and the wounds on
the leaves have dried and fully healed.
Additionally, the plant has grown new
strong and sturdy leaves, demonstrating
the effectiveness of the care method.
The leaves have become much greener and
sturdier than before, showing that the
orchid is growing healthily and
absorbing nutrients effectively.
[Music]
The roots have grown strong, firmly
anchoring into the growing medium and
producing many new roots, helping the
plant absorb water and nutrients better
while creating a solid foundation for
long-term growth.
[Music]
Uh when you care for an orchid with all
your love and dedication to the plant,
it will reward you with vibrant blooms,
brightening your living space and
bringing joy and peace.
Those flowers are not only the result of
meticulous care, but also a testament to
the special bond between humans and
nature. Each blossom unfolds like a
reminder that patience and love for the
plant will always be rewarded.