Welcome to the happiness garden, where
each day we come together to care for
and nurture the gentle beauty of
orchids.
In today's video, I will share with you
the best time to repot your orchid along
with the correct technique to help your
plant avoid diseases, grow strong, and
bloom beautifully all year round.
This is an orchid that needs to be
repotted as the roots inside have grown
too much and completely filled the space
while the aerial roots outside keep
growing longer.
This shows that the plant is searching
for a more spacious and airy environment
to continue growing well and prepare for
a new blooming season.
First, we need to check the potting
medium to see whether it is still airy
and clean or if it's time to replace it.
This is an important step that helps
your orchid live in the best
environment, reduces fungal issues, and
supports stronger root growth.
From a quick inspection, I found that
the potting medium is still fairly airy
and clean. So, I only need to remove
half of the old medium. This method
helps retain beneficial microorganisms
for the plant while creating space to
add new medium, allowing the roots to
continue growing even stronger.
Next, I will cut off the damaged roots
and trim some of the old ones. This
helps remove the weak parts, encourages
new healthy roots to grow, and allows
the plant to adapt better when placed in
the new potting medium.
Um, please comment and let me know which
country you're watching from. It's
wonderful that we can connect and chat
with each other from all around the
world.
After that, I gently remove the damaged
yellow and old leaves. Cleaning away the
unhealthy foliage helps the plant focus
its energy on growing roots and
producing new leaves, keeping your
orchid tidy and full of vitality.
Finally, I will cut off the old flower
spike so the plant no longer wastes
energy on the dried part. When removed
at the right time, the orchid can
recover more easily and prepare for
beautiful new blooms in the future.
If you haven't subscribed yet, uh please
hit the subscribe button to support me
and make sure you don't miss any orchid
growing tips. It's wonderful to have you
along on this journey.
Before
replanting, I will prepare a bit of
natural fertilizer to care for the plant
and help it recover after the trimming
process.
I add one spoon of coffee grounds into a
clean bottle. This simple ingredient
provides gentle minerals that help
stimulate root recovery and boost the
orchid's vitality before is replanted
into a new pot.
Next, I prepare 500 ml of boiled water
to mix with the coffee grounds. The hot
water helps extract the natural
nutrients from the coffee, creating a
gentle yet mineral-rich mixture that is
very beneficial for caring for the roots
after trimming.
After that, I close the lid and wait
until the water cools completely. When
the mixture is allowed to rest like
this, the nutrients in the coffee
dissolve more evenly, creating a gentle
and safe solution for caring for
orchids.
After the water has cooled, I stir the
mixture well so the nutrients in the
coffee grounds can dissolve evenly.
[Music]
Next, I strain out the residue to obtain
a clear solution, making the root care
process safer and more effective. When
there is no sediment left, the roots can
absorb nutrients more easily without the
risk of suffocation or damage.
After that, I add 1.5 L of water to make
a total of 2 L of liquid fertilizer.
This ratio keeps the mixture gentle and
safe, providing enough nutrients without
causing the orchid's roots to become
stressed after trimming.
Step one, I pour this mixture into the
pot to soak the roots and the remaining
potting medium.
This gentle soaking allows the roots to
absorb natural nutrients while also
cleaning and softening the potting
medium, creating ideal conditions for
the orchid to recover before being
replanted.
Soaking for about 20 minutes allows the
roots to slowly absorb nutrients while
soothing the freshly trimmed areas. This
also helps the roots become softer,
making it easier for the plant to adapt
when placed into the new pot.
Step two, use a soft cloth soaked in
this mixture. Then gently wipe both the
top and underside of the leaves.
[Music]
This method helps clean dust, enhances
the leaves natural shine, and supports
better nutrient absorption, keeping the
orchid healthy from root to tip.
When you wipe the leaves with the
diluted coffee solution, the dust on the
surface is gently removed. The leaves
become cleaner and more breathable,
helping the orchid photosynthesize more
easily and absorb light more effectively
during its growth.
The diluted coffee solution helps the
orchid leaves become shiny and healthy
without leaving any grease or residue.
This natural shine not only makes the
plant look more vibrant, but also
reflects the overall good health of the
orchid.
The natural nutrients in coffee help
reduce the growth of some mild fungal
issues on the leaves. When wiped
regularly, the leaves are better
protected and maintain their fresh green
color for a longer time.
When the leaf surface is clean, clear,
and free of dust, the orchid can the
orchid can absorb nutrients from the
care solution more easily. This helps
the leaves stay strong and thick,
supporting balanced growth from roots to
tip.
Step three, I pour the filtered solution
into a clean spray bottle. Using a spray
bottle helps distribute the mixture
evenly and gently over the entire plant,
ensuring both the leaves and roots
receive nutrients naturally and
effectively.
[Music]
When you spray the diluted coffee
mixture over the entire plant, the fine
mist helps remove any remaining dust
that wiping alone cannot completely
clean. As a result, the leaves become
clearer and more breathable, allowing
the plant to absorb light more easily
for effective photosynthesis.
[Music]
The natural minerals in coffee are
absorbed directly through the leaves
when you spray evenly over the surface.
This is a very gentle source of
nutrition, helping the leaves become
stronger, more vibrant, and boosting the
plant's resilience during growth.
[Music]
The fine mist from the spray bottle
helps maintain moderate humidity,
preventing the leaves from drying out
and the roots from losing moisture after
trimming. This allows the orchid to feel
comfortable and recover quickly.
After soaking for about 20 minutes,
gently take the orchid out to let the
potting medium drain. This helps remove
excess solution, prevents root rot, and
prepares the plant to adapt well when
replanted into a new pot.
[Music]
Next, soak the remaining potting medium
to disinfect it and add extra nutrients,
making use of the same diluted coffee
solution that was used for soaking the
orchid.
This method helps the potting medium
stay clean and rich in minerals,
creating a favorable environment for the
orchid roots to anchor firmly and grow
strong when replanted.
Soaking the potting medium for about 20
minutes allows the nutrients from the
coffee solution to penetrate evenly
while also eliminating any remaining
harmful microorganisms.
This is an important step to create a
clean, nutrient-rich foundation, helping
the orchid roots anchor firmly and grow
strong when replanted.
After soaking, remove the potting medium
and let it drain completely before
planting the orchid. This prevents root
rot and ensures the plant is placed into
a medium that is both clean and
nutrient-rich, ready for healthy growth.
When you check and find that the potting
medium no longer sticks to your hands
and maintains a moderately loose
texture, it means it is ready for
planting. In this state, the medium
helps the orchid roots anchor firmly,
provides good irration, and allows
efficient nutrient absorption, creating
optimal conditions for healthy growth.
First, place some large pine bark at the
bottom of the pot. This layer ensures
good drainage, prevents the orchid roots
from becoming water logged, and provides
the necessary erration for healthy root
growth.
Next, place the orchid into the pot and
fill small potting medium around the
roots. This helps stabilize the plant
while ensuring the roots have good
contact with the nutrient-rich medium.
[Applause]
After planting, place the orchid pot in
a cool, airy spot for about a week and
do not water it. This period allows the
roots to adapt to the new medium,
reduces the risk of shock or root rot,
and prepares the plant to recover and
grow vigorously.
After a week without watering, you can
start providing nutrients to the orchid
by watering with the diluted coffee
solution or other natural fertilizers at
a frequency of two to three times per
month.
This helps the plant gradually absorb
the necessary minerals, nourish the
roots and leaves, and prepare for
vibrant blooms in the future.
[Music]
This helps the plant gradually absorb
the necessary minerals, nourish the
roots and leaves, and prepare for
vibrant blooms in the future.
Place the orchid pot in a cool, airy
spot with gentle sunlight. This soft
light allows the plant to
photosynthesize effectively without
scorching the leaves while maintaining
an ideal environment for healthy root
and leaf growth after replanting.
And here are the results 3 weeks after
repotting. You can see that the orchid
leaves have become glossy and firm,
showing that the plant has recovered
well, absorbed nutrients effectively,
and is ready for the next vibrant
blooms.
You can see that even the older leaves
have become glossy and healthy. This
shows that the natural care and
nutrition method we applied is working
effectively, helping the orchid recover
fully from roots to leaves.
[Music]
Additionally, the orchid roots are
firmly anchored in the potting medium
while the aerial roots are also growing
long and strong. This is a clear sign
that the plant is developing in balance,
ready to nourish its leaves and prepare
for the upcoming vibrant blooms.
Especially the dormant buds on the old
flower spike have begun to sprout,
forming new flower buds. This is a
wonderful sign that the orchid is not
only recovering but also preparing for
the next blooming cycle, promising
vibrant flowers in the future.
As long as you follow the steps shown in
the video, your orchid will gradually
recover fully with glossy green leaves,
strong roots, and ready for vibrant
blooms in the upcoming seasons.
And over time, with regular care and
patience, your garden will gradually be
filled with the colors of vibrant orchid
blooms. Each pot thriving and growing
vigorously, bringing joy and happiness
to every plant lover.
Thanks to dedicated and patient care,
each orchid in the garden becomes a
living masterpiece full of vitality and
natural energy.
I hope you enjoy this video. If you find
it helpful, don't forget to like and
subscribe so you won't miss the upcoming
tips on caring for orchids naturally and
easily.
Thank you so much for watching. I truly
appreciate your time and support. Don't
forget to like, subscribe, and share if
you enjoyed this video. Wishing you a
wonderful day filled with joy and
blooming orchids.
See you in the next video.