Welcome to my little
garden. Today I will share with you a
simple and easy method to take care of
orchids that you can do at
home. Help your orchid grow quickly and
keep its leaves green. The root system
stays healthy to absorb nutrients to the
[Music]
maximum. Produce more flower buds and
bloom all year round.
With this method, the flowers not only
bloom, but also stay fresh longer on the
stem, keeping your orchid healthy,
vibrant, and
radiant. Let's get
started. Before preparing the
fertilizer, I always carefully check the
condition of the
[Music]
plant. Please carefully check the roots
of the orchid. If you see any roots that
are soft, darkened, or rotting, you
should use clean scissors to cut them
off immediately. This helps prevent
infection and allows the plant to grow
better.
[Music]
Please comment and let me know which
country you're watching the video from.
It's wonderful that we can chat together
from all around the world.
[Music]
Uh if you haven't subscribed to the
channel yet, please click the subscribe
button to support me and not miss any
orchid growing tips. Uh it's it's
wonderful to have you along for the
[Music]
journey. Uh if you haven't subscribe to
the channel yet, please click the
subscribe button to support me and not
miss any orchid growing tips. Uh it's
it's wonderful to have you along for the
[Music]
journey. Then you water all the orchid
pots once. This helps the plants not to
go into shock when fertilizing and
creates conditions for the roots to
absorb nutrients more effectively during
the subsequent care process.
If you are a beginner and unsure about
how to water your plant, I recommend
observing the color of the roots to
determine the right time to
water. Um, when the roots turn silvery
white or grayish white, that is a sign
that the plant is thirsty and needs
watering.
[Music]
The orchid growing medium needs to stay
moist but not soaked. If the medium is
dry, gently water it to maintain
[Music]
moisture. I water the plants once a
week. This method ensures the plants
absorb water evenly with no risk of
overwatering or drought.
[Music]
If the roots are transparent green or
fresh green, the plant has enough water
and you do not need to water yet.
[Music]
Uh this simple observation will help you
avoid overwatering that can cause root
rot or underwatering that that can dry
out the
[Music]
plant. Do you often eat
bananas? When eating bananas, you often
peel them and throw the peels away.
Don't do that. I'll show you a very
useful orchid care recipe using these
banana peels to make a wonderful natural
fertilizer. Banana peels contain many
natural minerals, vitamins, and
potassium. They are an excellent source
of nutrients that help orchid roots grow
strong and leaves stay lush
green. You can use fresh banana peels or
dry them for storage and long-term use.
Dried banana peels are convenient, easy
to store, and still retain many
nutrients that are good for
orchids. Banana peels can be dried in
the sun or dehydrated. Both methods help
preserve the peels longer while still
retaining nutrients for the
[Music]
plant. After drying, I take three banana
peels and cut them into small slices.
Cutting them into small pieces helps the
nutrients from the banana peels dissolve
easily during
[Music]
soaking. Put the banana peels into a
jar. Then add 0.5 L of boiling water to
soak. Boiling water helps extract
nutrients from the banana peels
[Music]
faster. Cover the lid and soak until the
water cools down.
[Music]
Uh for orchids that have finished
blooming or plants that have grown um
for a long time but do not bloom, this
may be a sign that the roots or growing
medium are struggling. Additionally, the
plant may also be lacking nutrients at
this
[Music]
time. Repotting and replacing the old
growing medium is a necessary step at
this time. This helps the orchid grow
healthy and absorb nutrients better.
[Music]
uh cut off any roots that are rotting,
soft or discolored. This helps prevent
the plant from getting infected and
promotes better
[Music]
growth. After cutting off the damaged
roots, the plant will naturally
stimulate new root growth. This is a
self-repair mechanism that helps the
plant grow
[Music]
healthier. Then cut off the old withered
flower stems. This helps the plant focus
its nutrients on nurturing new flower
[Music]
buds. I remove yellow and wilted leaves
so the plant can focus its nutrients on
growing new leaves.
[Music]
Then rinse the orchid with water to
remove dirt and pests.
[Music]
After the water cools, stir well to
ensure the nutrients dissolve
completely. Straining out the residue
helps make the solution clear and easier
for the plant to absorb.
[Music]
Um, dilute the solution with one liter
of water before use. This helps the
plant absorb nutrients easily without
getting shocked.
[Music]
Then water the orchid with this mixture
once every 1 to two weeks. Regular
watering helps the plant absorb
nutrients consistently and grow
[Music]
well. For healthy orchids, you can water
them with this natural fertilizer once
every 2 weeks. This method helps
maintain steady growth and nourishes the
roots more
effectively. For weak orchids, only
water with a diluted natural fertilizer
once every 3 to 4 weeks. Combine this
with placing the plant in a well
ventilated area with sufficient light
for better recovery.
[Music]
for orchids that are blooming. Apply
banana peel fertilizer only once every 2
to 3 weeks. The potassium in banana
peels helps the plant resist drought and
efficiently transport water from roots
to flowers, helping the flowers last
longer and stay fresh on the stem.
[Music]
Then put the mixture into a spray bottle
for convenient
[Music]
use. Spray evenly over the entire
orchid, especially the unders sides of
the leaves and the leaf axles. This
method helps the plant absorb nutrients
better and effectively prevent pests and
diseases.
[Music]
Regular spraying helps wash away dust
that sticks to the leaves, keeping the
orchid leaves clean and healthy and
enhancing
[Music]
photosynthesis. Additionally, spraying
helps limit the growth of fungal
diseases, keeping the orchid fresh and
promoting steady daily growth.
You should spray the natural fertilizer
in the morning about twice a month. This
frequency helps the orchid absorb
nutrients regularly and grow
[Music]
healthy. Then place the orchid pot in a
spot with gentle sunlight so the plant
can photosynthesize better. Remember, no
matter how good the fertilizer is,
without enough sunlight the plant will
struggle to grow.
You can place the orchid pot on a window
sill or under a specialized shade net
designed for
[Music]
orchids. I dilute the remaining natural
fertilizer mixture with water at a 1:1
ratio before use.
[Music]
Then add two vitamin B1 tablets to the
mixture to stimulate healthier plant
growth.
[Applause]
[Music]
Then soak the orchid roots in the banana
peel and vitamin B1 mixture for about 20
minutes. This method helps stimulate new
root growth and prevent drought stress
when planting into the new pot and
growing
[Music]
medium. While waiting for the roots to
soak, I use a soft cloth soaked in the
mixture to gently wipe the upper and
lower surfaces of the leaves. This helps
clean the leaves and directly provide
nutrients to the plant.
[Music]
Please comment and let me know which
country you are watching the video from.
It's wonderful that we can chat together
from all around the world.
[Music]
I choose pots with drainage holes at the
bottom and around for growing orchids.
This helps prevent water logging and
promotes healthier plant
growth. Um, to help the orchid stabilize
after planting, I make stakes to keep
the plant secure. This method prevents
the plant from leaning, protects new
roots, and helps the plant grow
healthier.
[Music]
Um, the orchid growing medium I choose
is large pine bark. Uh this type keeps
the roots well ventilated while
maintaining appropriate moisture for the
orchid to
[Music]
thrive. With this type of pine bark, you
can water every day without worrying
about orchid roots getting water logged.
[Music]
Growing orchids in large pine bark is
ideal for those who have plenty of time
to care for their
[Music]
plants. On the surface of the orchid
pot, spread a thin layer of moss to help
retain moisture in the soil, reduce
rapid evaporation, and create an ideal
environment for healthy root
development.
If you don't have moss, you can replace
it with pine bark chips. Pine bark chips
also help retain moisture and provide
irerration for the growing
[Music]
medium. Then water the orchid with the
remaining fertilizer
mixture. Place the orchid pot in a
location with gentle sunlight to help
the plant grow faster.
[Music]
Um, thank you all for watching my video
today.
[Music]
As you can see, with simple ingredients
readily available and proper care, we
can help orchids recover quickly, grow
healthy, and bloom again soon.
[Music]
Caring for orchids is a meaningful
journey that helps you maintain patience
and love every
day. No matter what age you are,
spending time caring for plants not only
beautifies your living space, but also
brings joy and peace to your soul.
Believe that every leaf and every flower
you nurture is a testament to your
strength and
resilience. If you face any difficulties
during the orchid growing process, don't
hesitate to leave a comment for me. I'm
always ready to support you so that you
can grow healthy orchids that bloom
beautifully. If you find the content
meaningful and helpful, don't forget to
like, share so many people can know
about it, and subscribe to support my
channel. Thank you for always being with
me.