[Music]
Hello everyone. In today's video, I will
share a simple but very interesting way
to propagate orchids from the flower
spike that has already bloomed.
This is a gentle and easy method that
helps you create new orchid pots right
at home.
[Music]
Let's get started.
When the flowers on the spike begin to
fade, that is the perfect time to cut
the spike and start the propagation
process.
[Music]
Um, at this time, the flower spike still
contains enough nutrients and vitality
to develop into a new plant if handled
correctly.
[Music]
the nodes that have already bloomed will
no longer be able to produce new
plantlets.
[Music]
And here are the nodes that have never
bloomed. They still have the potential
to develop into plantlets if cared for
properly. These dormant eyes are where
uh new life for your orchid is hidden.
[Music]
Gently cut off the nodes that have
already bloomed as they no longer have
the ability to grow.
I choose two nodes that have not bloomed
to propagate using the cutting method.
This is a simple and effective way to
make use of the still healthy flower
spike to create a new orchid plant.
[Music]
I trim the cut area to remove the
damaged part. This helps prevent rot and
creates favorable conditions for the
spike to recover quickly, ready for the
rooting process.
If you haven't subscribed to the channel
yet, please hit the subscribe button to
support me and never miss any orchid
growing tips. It's truly wonderful to
have you along on this journey.
I gently peel off the thin membrane
surrounding the dormant bud at each
node. This helps stimulate the dormant
bud to awaken and develop more quickly
into a plantlet.
[Music]
Uh, leave a comment and let me know
which country you're watching from. It's
amazing that we can connect and chat
from all around the world.
[Music]
I cut the bottom of the spike at an
angle to increase the surface area in
contact with the rooting and sprouting
solution. This allows nutrients to be
absorbed more easily, helping the spike
to root quickly and develop new shoots.
I prepare one to two fresh aloe vera
leaves. This familiar ingredient not
only helps naturally stimulate root
growth but also protects the spike from
harmful bacteria and fungi.
[Music]
I insert the cutting into the middle
along the flesh of the aloe vera leaf so
the gel can be absorbed directly into
the spike.
[Music]
Insert the cutting so that the dormant
bud is submerged in the aloe vera flesh.
This helps the bud absorb maximum
nutrients, thereby stimulating faster
sprouting.
This method allows the nutrients from
the aloe vera to penetrate more deeply,
promoting the rooting process naturally.
After that, I leave it undisturbed for
about 1 hour so the aloe vera gel can be
evenly absorbed into the spike.
Cut the remaining aloe vera leaf into
small pieces and place them in a clean
jar.
We will use this part to continue
supporting the rooting process and keep
the cutting moist.
[Music]
Next, I add the chopped aloe vera into
500 ml of room temperature water. This
mixture will create a moisturizing
environment and effectively stimulate
rooting for the cutting.
[Music]
The next ingredient I use is cinnamon
powder. This natural component helps
with antibacterial protection, prevents
the spike from rotting, and supports the
safe development of the dormant bud.
[Music]
I use 1 teasp of cinnamon powder, add it
to the bottle, then pour in 500 ml of
boiling water.
The steam will help extract the natural
antibacterial compounds from the
cinnamon, creating a more effective
solution for supporting the cutting.
Um, I close the lid and let the mixture
cool naturally.
Uh while waiting for the solution to
cool, I take the opportunity to recycle
two used plastic cups to make seedling
pots for the orchid cutings.
This is a simple yet effective way to
repurpose everyday items, both
cost-saving and environmentally
friendly.
[Music]
After about 1 hour, I take the cutting
out of the aloe vera leaf. At this
point, the gel has deeply absorbed into
the spike, ready for the next step in
the propagation process.
[Music]
Then I filter out the aloe vera residue
to obtain a clear clean solution.
[Music]
When the cinnamon water has cooled, I
mix it with the aloe vera solution to
create a root nourishing mixture. Before
using it for planting, I strain out the
cinnamon residue to keep the mixture
clean and avoid damaging the cutting.
Next, I prepare some vitamin B1.
This familiar ingredient helps stimulate
root growth, supports quick recovery of
the cutting, and promotes healthier
development.
[Music]
I add three tablets of vitamin B1, each
containing 2.5 mg. This moderate amount
will help stimulate root development
without overwhelming the young and
fragile cutting.
[Music]
I use the prepared mixture to soak the
cutting for about 20 minutes.
Uh this is an important step that allows
the cutting to fully absorb nutrients
before planting.
While soaking, I make sure the dormant
bud is completely submerged in the
solution. This helps the nutrients
deeply penetrate the bud, stimulating
the sprouting process and the
development of a new plantlet.
[Music]
Next, I place moss into a bowl and soak
it with the nutrient mixture I just
prepared.
This step prepares the growing medium
before inserting the cutting, helping to
sterilize the moss and infuse it with
nutrients to better support the
cutting's development.
I soak the moss in the mixture for about
20 minutes.
I pour the remaining mixture into a
spray bottle and dilute it further with
500 ml of water.
[Music]
Uh, then I take the spray bottle to the
garden and gently mist it over the
orchid pots I'm caring for.
[Music]
This solution not only supports young
plants but also helps mature orchids
maintain vitality and grow healthier
each day.
You can spray this solution every 2
weeks or alternate it with other natural
fertilizers. This variety and care will
help your orchid receive a full range of
nutrients and develop more completely.
[Music]
Natural ingredients like aloe vera,
cinnamon, and vitamin B1 uh help the
plant fight off fungal diseases and
recover quickly after pruning or
repotting.
[Music]
After soaking for about 20 minutes, I
take the cutting out and gently pat it
dry with a clean cloth.
[Music]
After drying, I apply a small amount of
toothpaste. paste. Make sure to choose a
salt-free type onto the cut area.
[Music]
Toothpaste helps with antibacterial
protection, shields the cut from fungal
infections, and supports faster healing
of the cutting.
[Music]
I let the toothpaste dry naturally on
the cut before planting.
Then I take the moss out of the solution
and gently squeeze out the excess water.
[Music]
The moss is now ready to be used as a
growing medium, providing a moist, airy,
and clean environment for the cutting to
develop.
Once everything is ready, I proceed to
plant the cutting into the pot.
[Music]
Place the cutting so that the dormant
bud faces upward and gently touches the
moss to create the best conditions for
the bud to grow.
[Music]
After planting, I cover the pot with a
transparent plastic lid with ventilation
holes.
This cover helps maintain humidity
inside while still allowing enough air
circulation to prevent mold.
[Music]
After that, I regularly check the
moisture level and lightly mist with
water whenever the growing medium starts
to dry out.
Maintaining stable moisture helps
prevent the cutting from drying out and
promotes more effective root
development.
Place the pot in a cool, airy spot with
gentle light, but away from direct
sunlight. Such an ideal environment will
help the dormant bud develop well and
increase the success rate of forming a
new plant from the cutting.
And here is the result after 45 days of
consistent care.
[Music]
You can see the new shoots beginning to
emerge from the dormant buds, proving
that the cutting is growing healthily
and has great potential to become a
strong new orchid plant.
[Music]
When the orchid begins to grow from the
dormant bud and roots have formed, that
is the time to start preparing natural
fertilizer for care.
Proper fertilization will help the plant
grow healthily, boost its vitality, and
produce beautiful flowers in the next
season.
[Music]
To make the fertilizer, I use one
teaspoon of rice. Since the plant is
still small and young, a moderate amount
of fertilizer will provide gentle
nutrients and avoid shocking the plant
during the early growth stage.
Next, I add 500 ml of water.
[Music]
I stir the mixture well to obtain a
clear, nutrient-rich rice water
solution.
I pour the rice water into a spray
bottle, preparing to mist it evenly over
the orchid. This method helps nutrients
penetrate deeply into the leaves and
roots, supporting effective growth.
[Music]
Uh, I spray this diluted rice water
about every 7 to 10 days. Regular
maintenance helps the orchid
continuously absorb nutrients, promoting
healthy and sustainable growth.
Place the plant in a spot with gentle
sunlight so the orchid can
photosynthesize effectively. Proper
light will help the plant grow faster
with greener leaves and more vibrant
blooms.
[Music]
And here is the result after 3 months.
You can see that the orchid from the
cutting has grown vigorously with strong
roots, lush green leaves, and full of
vitality, ready for its blooming journey
in the near future.
The leaves have become firmer and
thicker, indicating that the plant is
absorbing nutrients well and growing
steadily. This is a positive sign that
the orchid is ready to enter its mature
stage.
The roots, though still short, have
grown densely. This forms a crucial
foundation that helps the plant absorb
water and nutrients more effectively,
preparing it for the flowering process
ahead.
[Music]
When the orchid grown from the cutting
has developed firm leaves and a healthy,
abundant root system, it is the right
time to transfer it to a larger pot.
[Music]
Choose a pot with drainage holes at the
bottom to ensure the roots do not become
water logged.
As for the growing medium, choose one
with good drainage, such as chopped pine
bark, or a mix with charcoal, fern
fiber, or dried moss. These materials
retain just enough moisture while still
providing proper irration for healthy
root development.
[Music]
Then I gently place the orchid into the
new pot, adjusting it so that the roots
fit snugly within the growing medium
without being too tightly compressed.
Careful handling at this step will help
the plant settle quickly and continue to
grow well.
I hope you enjoy this video. If you find
it helpful, don't forget to like and
subscribe to the channel so you won't
miss upcoming tips on natural and simple
orchid care.
Thank you for taking the time to watch
the video. Wishing you good health,
happiness, and lots of beautiful orchids
in your garden. See you in the next
video. Goodbye.