Welcome to the happiness garden where
every flower shines like a little joy
and every lush green leaf reminds us of
the simple beauty of nature. Let's
explore and feel the gentle rhythm of
life here together
uh to give you more options for caring
for orchids at home. Today I will
introduce a completely new natural
fertilizer method. This recipe is both
simple and helps orchids grow healthy
from roots to leaves and flowers.
If you haven't subscribed to the channel
yet, click the subscribe button now so
you won't miss any orchid care tips and
can join us in this happiness garden.
[Music]
To make this fertilizer, we only need to
prepare two cloves of garlic, a simple
but extremely effective ingredient for
orchids.
[Music]
Um, with its natural antibacterial
properties, garlic not only protects the
roots but also helps orchids grow
vigorously.
[Music]
Cut the garlic into small pieces so that
when fermenting, the nutrients in the
garlic can easily dissolve and maximize
their effect on the orchids.
[Music]
Please comment and let me know which
country you are watching this video
from. It's wonderful that we can chat
together from all around the world.
[Music]
>> After chopping the garlic, immediately
put it into a clean jar for
fermentation.
[Music]
The next ingredient that everyone is
familiar with is bread. An everyday
food, but extremely useful when making
fertilizer for orchids.
[Music]
Just a small amount like this is enough
to prepare fertilizer for orchids.
[Music]
Next, uh place the bread into the jar
along with the prepared garlic.
[Music]
Next, we need dry yeast. The type of
yeast you usually use to bake bread at
home.
[Music]
When fermenting, dry yeast produces
beneficial microorganisms, helping the
fermentation process proceed faster and
enriching the nutrients in the natural
fertilizer.
[Music]
With just one teaspoon of dry yeast, the
fermentation process will start quickly.
[Music]
Next, we will use molasses, an
ingredient that not only provides
nutrients for beneficial microorganisms,
but also directly supplies nutrients to
the orchids.
[Music]
After adding the molasses, pour in warm
water to prepare the mixture for the
next fermentation step.
[Music]
When pouring the water, leave some space
at the top to allow the gas produced
during fermentation to escape easily and
safely.
Next, gently stir the mixture, helping
the ingredients dissolve completely and
the microorganisms grow better.
After stirring well, close the jar and
place it in a cool ventilated area for 2
weeks to allow the fermentation process
to complete perfectly.
After 2 weeks of fermentation, the
beneficial microorganisms have fully
developed and the mixture is ready for
the orchids.
[Music]
Take about 50 ml of the fermented
mixture and prepare to dilute it to make
fertilizer for the orchids.
[Music]
Next, mix it with one liter of water and
stir well to create a fertilizer
solution ready for watering the orchids.
[Music]
The first method, water each orchid pot
with this mixture, allowing the solution
to soak evenly into the growing medium
and nourish the roots for healthy
growth.
Gently water the roots in growing
medium, helping the plant absorb
nutrients naturally without shocking the
roots.
[Music]
The fermented solution provides many
beneficial microorganisms, helping the
roots stay healthy and boosting the
plant's natural resistance.
Thanks to the abundant nutrients, the
orchid quickly sprouts new shoots. Its
leaves become lush green and it gets
ready for the next brilliant blooming
season.
[Music]
Do this twice a month, alternating with
regular watering, so the plant always
receives enough nutrients without being
overfed.
[Music]
The second method, you can pour this
mixture into a spray bottle and then
gently mist it to nourish both the
leaves and the aerial roots, helping the
plant absorb nutrients more quickly.
[Music]
When spraying, mist evenly over the
leaves, stems, aerial roots, and even
the roots in the growing medium so the
plant receives complete nutrient
supplementation.
Um, when sprayed evenly on the leaves,
the solution makes them lush and shiny
as the nutrients are absorbed directly
through the leaf surface.
The fermented garlic mixture has natural
antibacterial properties helping to
reduce certain harmful fungi and
diseases that affect the leaves and
roots.
Uh spraying the solution also stimulates
the aerial roots to grow faster uh
helping the plant increase its ability
to absorb moisture and nutrients.
Uh when sprayed regularly, the orchid
will have better resistance, be less
prone to yellowing leaves or root rot,
and maintain a healthy appearance.
[Music]
With gentle and consistent care, the
orchid will soon sprout new shoots, grow
lush and green, and get ready to bloom
with vibrant flowers for the new season.
[Music]
After watering or spraying, you can also
soak the entire orchid pot in the
mixture for about 20 minutes so the
roots can fully absorb the nutrients.
[Music]
The third method, you can use a soft
cloth soaked in this mixture. Then
gently wipe both the top and underside
of the leaves to remove dust and provide
direct nutrients to the leaves.
[Applause]
Uh, wiping the leaves helps remove the
layer of dust that has built up over
time, restoring a clean surface. This
allows the leaves to absorb light
better, photosynthesize more
efficiently, and makes the plant look
fresh and full of life.
[Music]
The fermented garlic mixture has natural
antibacterial properties and when wiped
evenly on the leaves, it helps reduce
the risk of fungal diseases and protects
the leaves from harmful agents.
[Music]
Regularly wiping the leaves is also a
great way to observe the plant's health,
making it easier to spot pests or
unusual signs and take timely action.
[Music]
When the leaves are cleaned and absorb
nutrients directly, the orchid becomes
healthier, its leaves turn glossy green,
and it is ready to burst into brilliant
blooms for the new season.
[Music]
After soaking for about 20 minutes in
the mixture, remember to take the orut
pot out to prevent the roots from
getting water logged and to keep the
plant well ventilated.
If there is still water on the leaves,
gently pat the leaves and stems dry with
a soft cloth.
[Music]
Blotting the excess water helps the
leaves dry faster, preventing prolonged
moisture that could cause leaf rot or
create favorable conditions for fungus
to grow.
[Music]
When the leaves and stems are kept dry,
the plant becomes more ventilated,
reducing the damp environment that
bacteria and pests usually thrive in.
[Music]
Drying the leaf surface also keeps the
leaves clean and shiny, making the plant
look healthy, beautiful, and full of
vitality.
[Music]
By keeping the leaves and stems dry, the
orchid meat maintains stable health and
is ready for a new growth phase with
fresh shoots and vibrant blooms.
[Music]
And here are the results. After just a
few care sessions, you will see the
leaves become thicker, firmer, and
glossy green, full of vitality.
[Music]
Not only do the leaves become firm, but
they also grow larger and shine under
the light, making the plant look
healthier and more vibrant each day.
[Music]
Healthy glossy leaves also help the
plant photosynthesize better, generating
more energy to nourish the roots, new
shoots, and prepare for the upcoming
vibrant blooms.
[Music]
When you regularly care for orchids with
homemade natural fertilizer, the plant
may grow slowly at first, but once the
nutrients penetrate deeply, the roots
will grow thick, strong, and firmly
anchored in the medium, ready to support
healthy growth.
[Music]
Healthy roots help the plant absorb
water and nutrients more efficiently
while also stabilizing it in the pot and
increasing its ability to produce shoots
and bloom regularly.
[Music]
Strongly growing roots also help the
plant accumulate enough energy,
preparing for new shoots to emerge and
paving the way for vibrant flowers about
to bloom.
[Music]
And you can see the flower buds have
appeared plump and healthy, showing that
the plant is receiving enough nutrients
and getting ready for the upcoming
vibrant blooms.
[Music]
Healthy flower buds will quickly bloom
into vibrant, colorful flowers, marking
the results of consistent care and
regular natural fertilization.
[Music]
When you care for them this way, the
blooms will be more vibrant than usual,
bringing bright and lively beauty that
enliven the surrounding space.
[Music]
Uh the vibrant flowers not only make the
surroundings more lively but also serve
as a well-deserved reward for the love
and patience you give the plant. Each
bloom tells the story of dedicated care
and the joy of seeing a healthy,
thriving plant.
[Music]
When the flowers bloom brilliantly, the
fragrance and delicate shape of each
blossom allow you to experience the
magical beauty of nature while inspiring
you to continue caring for and loving
your plants even more.
That's the end of today's video. What do
you think of my orchid care method?
Don't hesitate to leave a comment with
your feedback. I really look forward to
hearing from you.
If you found this video helpful and
meaningful, please like and share it so
more people can learn how to care for
orchids to keep them healthy and
blooming beautifully.
Thank you for watching the video.
Goodbye. And I wish you always have
healthy orchids with lush green leaves
and vibrant blooms.
[Music]