Welcome to my
garden. Uh here I share orchid care tips
to help your plants stay healthy, grow
strong roots, and bloom
beautifully. In the process of growing
orchids over the years, it's inevitable
that plants may suffer from rot,
especially during the summer. This is a
common issue when humidity is high and
temperatures are hot, which can easily
damage your orchids.
You can see that this orchid is severely
affected by rot. If not addressed in
time, the rot can spread quickly
throughout the garden, damaging other
plants. Rot often occurs due to several
factors, primarily overwatering,
especially when the soil doesn't drain
well. This creates an environment for
bacteria and fungi to thrive, damaging
the plant's soft tissues.
Uh when an orchid is affected by rot, we
need to immediately remove it from the
garden to prevent spreading. Then trim
off all the damaged leaves to stop the
disease from
progressing. If you haven't subscribe to
the channel yet, please hit the
subscribe button to support me and not
miss any orchid care tips. It's great to
have you along on this journey.
[Music]
Next, we check the roots and the growing
medium. If the roots are rotten, we need
to trim off the damaged parts and
replace the growing medium to ensure the
plant has a healthy environment to
thrive. Next, we check the roots and the
growing medium. If the roots are rotten,
we need to trim off the damaged parts
and replace the growing medium to ensure
the plant has a healthy environment to
[Music]
thrive. Please comment and let me know
which country you're watching the video
from. It's amazing that we can connect
and chat with each other from all around
the world.
[Music]
I proceed to trim off all the damaged
roots.
The growing medium being too moist is
also a cause of the disease. So I need
to remove it and replace it with a
fresher, more breathable medium. This
will help the orchid roots drain
properly and grow healthily.
[Music]
In addition to the English voiceover, we
have now created voiceovers in French,
German, Italian, Spanish, Portuguese,
Japanese, Hindi, and Indonesian to help
you listen to and understand the content
more
easily. For languages without
voiceovers, we've created subtitles so
you can read and understand the content.
After removing the old growing medium,
We rinse the orchid under running water
to remove any dirt and bacteria,
ensuring the plant is clean before
replanting.
After washing the plant, we continue to
trim off any remaining damaged roots to
prevent the plant from getting infected
and to help it grow healthier.
[Music]
Here you can see that the soft tissue of
the stem has completely rotted making it
very difficult for nutrients to be
transported from the roots upward. If
left as is and replanted, the plant will
gradually weaken and grow more
slowly. So, I decided to cut across here
to separate the base and the upper part
of the stem, giving the plant a chance
to recover and grow back.
Then take about 5 L of
water.
Here is baking soda, which is great for
disinfecting orchids affected by rot. It
helps kill bacteria and prevents the
disease from
recurring. Take 3 tesp of baking soda
and mix it with the 5 L of water from
earlier to create an effective
disinfecting solution for the orchid.
[Music]
Next, soak both the base and the upper
part of the stem in the diluted baking
soda solution for about 10 minutes. This
helps disinfect and prevent bacteria,
allowing the plant to recover quickly.
[Music]
Then take the orchid out and use a soft
cloth to blot off any excess water from
the plant, ensuring it dries thoroughly
and doesn't remain damp.
[Music]
We need to trim the stem once more to
ensure a clean, undamaged
which helps reduce the risk of
infection.
[Music]
We need to trim the stem once more to
ensure a clean, undamaged cut, which
helps reduce the risk of infection.
I sprinkle cinnamon powder on the cuts
to disinfect them and support the
healing process, helping the plant
recover faster.
Next, pour 1.5 L of water into a
container to prepare a fertilizer mix
that will help stimulate the orchid's
growth during its recovery
phase. Next, I use vitamin B1, which
helps stimulate root growth, boost the
plant's resistance, and speed up
recovery after damage.
Take five vitamin B1 tablets and
dissolve them in the water, helping to
boost the plant's health and support
root
development.
Here is honey, which is excellent for
providing nutrients to the plant,
helping to enhance its recovery and
protect it from
bacteria. Take one teaspoon of honey to
mix in, helping to provide nutrients and
stimulate the recovery of the orchid.
[Music]
Then soak the base of the plant in this
mixture for about 20 minutes to allow
the nutrients to penetrate deeply into
the roots and support the recovery
process.
[Music]
We only soak the base, making sure not
to wet the cut areas to avoid excess
moisture, allowing cuta to heal quickly
without the risk of infection.
[Music]
Then take the soft cloth, dip it in the
mixture, and wrap it around the orchid
stem.
This helps provide nutrients directly to
the stem, stimulates root growth, and
supports the plant's quick recovery.
[Music]
Then take the soft cloth, dip it in the
mixture and gently wipe both the top and
bottom of the leaves to remove bacteria
and provide nutrients to the leaves.
[Music]
Next, place the orchid into the glass
cup, but position the leaves facing down
toward the bottom to keep the plant
stable.
[Music]
Next, place the orchid into the glass
cup, but position the leaves facing down
toward the bottom to keep the plant
stable.
[Music]
We only add a little water. And when the
water evaporates, it's important to
replenish it immediately to maintain the
necessary humidity for the plant's
recovery.
[Music]
Then remove the cotton and cover the
glass cup with the
[Music]
lid. This will act like a mini
greenhouse, helping the orchid recover
in an environment with the right
humidity and protecting it from external
factors.
[Music]
Then remove the base and blot off any
excess water.
[Music]
Next, plant the orchid into a new pot
with well- draining growing medium to
give the plant enough space to grow and
prevent rotting.
[Music]
I always choose pine bark chips as the
growing medium for the orchids in my
garden because it drains well, maintains
stable moisture, and provides good air
flow for the roots to grow.
[Music]
I always choose pine bark chips as the
growing medium. for the orchids in my
garden because it drains well, maintains
stable moisture, and provides good air
flow for the roots to
grow. After planting, leave the orchid
overnight without watering to help the
plant settle in and reduce the risk of
root rot.
After one night, water the orchid with
the mixture of vitamin B1 and honey to
stimulate root growth and help the plant
recover
quickly. From now on, water the plant
with this mixture once a week to
maintain nutrients, support healthy
growth, and promote stable root
development.
Normally, if the growing medium looks
dry, just mist it with water to provide
enough humidity without causing root
rot. After that, place the orchid pot in
a spot with gentle sunlight and wait for
the plant to recover under ideal light
and humidity
conditions. Now, let's take a look at
the results after 1 month of the
orchid's recovery.
You can see that the base stem has
developed many roots which proves that
the plant has recovered well and is
starting to grow again.
The new healthy roots show that the
orchid is absorbing enough nutrients and
water from the surrounding environment.
With proper care, the orchid shows
strong signs of regeneration and will
continue to grow well in the future.
With the base, you can see that the
orchid has regenerated a new chute in
indicating that the plant has recovered
and is starting to grow more vigorously.
Now I will plant the upper part of the
stem into a new pot so that the plant
can grow better in the outside
environment with the appropriate space
and growing
[Music]
medium. Use a plasticcoated steel stake
as a support to stabilize the orchid,
preventing the new roots from being
damaged after being planted in the new
growing medium.
[Music]
Then spread a layer of moss on top to
maintain moisture, protect the roots,
and keep the orchid stable during its
growth process.
[Music]
Uh when planting, remember to gently
secure the orchid to keep it stable so
the new roots won't be disturbed or
damaged, providing the best conditions
for the plant to grow vigorously.
[Music]
After planting, water the orchid. to
maintain moisture, creating good
conditions for the new roots to develop
and the orchid to stabilize in its new
environment. With patience and following
the instructions correctly, we can
absolutely revive weak orchids at home.
Careful attention and the right
treatment steps not only help the orchid
revive, but also bring us joy and pride
as we witness the strong growth of our
beloved
[Music]
orchids. With a little patience, love
for plants, and dedication, you will
experience the magic of nature as each
or orchid overcomes challenges and
blooms beautifully.
Again, remember, each step of care is a
journey of learning and experience, and
only you have the power to bring new
life to your
garden. If you find these orchid care
tips helpful, don't forget to like and
share this video with your friends and
family. so we can create beautiful
orchid gardens
together. Uh don't forget to subscribe
to the channel and hit the notification
bell so you won't miss any tutorial
videos on how to care for house
plants. Thank you for your support and
companionship. Together we will continue
the journey of caring for and nurturing
healthy, beautiful orchids.
Wishing you all the best. See you in the
next video.