Welcome to my little orchid garden where
each flower tells a story of life and
the beauty of nature. I'm very happy to
accompany you in caring for these
wonderful orchids.
In today's video, I'll share how to
revive and care for both weak orchids
and those growing normally so they
become healthy, lush, and full of
vibrant blooms right in your garden or
on your small balcony.
Uh, if you haven't subscribed to the
channel yet, please hit the subscribe
button to support me and not miss any
orchid growing tips.
It's truly wonderful to have you with me
on this journey.
[Music]
Let's get started.
First, prepare a container with one
liter of clean water. This will be the
base ingredient for making the natural
fertilizer that helps orchids recover
and grow strong.
[Music]
Next, you'll need some dry yeast used
for baking bread.
[Music]
Uh, just one teaspoon of dry yeast is
enough.
[Music]
The final ingredient you need is a bit
of molasses. Simple as it is, this is a
great source of nutrients that feeds
beneficial microbes and supports your
orchid's healthy growth from roots to
leaves.
[Music]
Just one teaspoon of molasses is enough.
Then stir the mixture well so all the
ingredients dissolve completely in the
water.
[Music]
Cover the container and place the
mixture in a cool, well ventilated spot
for one day to allow natural
fermentation. This step helps activate
the beneficial microorganisms for your
orchids.
After blooming, orchids often enter a
weakened state with reduced resistance
as most of their energy has been used up
during the flowering process. This is
the time when the plant needs proper
recovery to continue growing.
[Music]
You need to remove any yellow leaves
right away as they no longer benefit the
plant. This also helps reduce the risk
of fungal infections and allows the
orchid to recover faster and more
strongly.
Next, trim off any dried or wilted
flower spikes. This prevents the plant
from wasting energy on parts that are no
longer viable, allowing it to focus on
root recovery and new chute growth.
[Music]
At the same time, remove any damaged,
rotting or brittle roots. This helps
prevent the spread of bacteria and
creates the right conditions for healthy
new roots to grow.
[Music]
In addition to the English voiceover,
we've also created versions in French,
German, Italian, Spanish, Portuguese,
Japanese, Hindi, Dutch, Polish, Korean,
and Indonesian to help you listen and
understand the content more easily.
To hear your preferred language, open
the video and click on settings, the
gear icon, to select the appropriate
audio language.
Leave a comment and let me know which
country you're watching from. It's
wonderful that we can connect and chat
from all around the world.
[Music]
After one day of fermentation, we now
have a natural fertilizer full of
beneficial microbes. It's time to use
this mixture to care for orchids that
need recovery and give them a boost of
vitality.
I pour out 500 ml of the fermented
solution to dilute it before use.
The remaining fermented mixture can be
stored in a cool, wellventilated place
for future use. Be sure to keep the lid
tightly closed to preserve the quality
and effectiveness of the fertilizer.
Next, add 500 ml of clean water to the
500 ml of extracted solution. This 1:1
ratio makes the mixture gentler,
suitable for watering orchids without
the risk of shocking their roots.
[Music]
Method one, pour the diluted mixture
into a spray bottle to mist your
orchids.
Then you can spray it directly onto the
leaves, stems, and roots in the early
morning or late afternoon, allowing the
plant to absorb the nutrients easily and
recover quickly.
Wilted yellowing leaves can gradually
regain their green color when gently
nourished with this solution. Spraying
directly onto the leaves allows the
plant to absorb nutrients more quickly
and effectively.
The naturally fermented mixture contains
beneficial microorganisms that improve
the environment around the roots. When
sprayed on the plant, this solution
helps stimulate the growth of new roots,
the most crucial factor in reviving a
weakened orchid.
Uh the solution not only helps the plant
recover after blooming but also
regenerates energy throughout the stem,
roots and leaves. This prepares the
orchid for a new growth phase and the
next blooming cycle.
You only need to do this twice a month.
Regular care like this will help your
orchid gradually recover, grow stronger,
and be well prepared for its next
blooming.
[Music]
Method two, pour the mixture directly
onto the roots and growing medium.
This method allows the nutrients to
penetrate deeply, nourishing the roots
from within and naturally restoring the
surrounding root environment
effectively.
When the solution is poured onto the
roots and growing medium, the
microorganisms and minerals in the
mixture gradually absorb into the root
zone, helping heal damaged areas and
stimulate new root growth. This is a
crucial step in helping the orchid
recover after a weakened phase.
After watering the roots with the
fertilizer, you can also soak the entire
orchid pot in the mixture for about 20
minutes. This helps the roots absorb
nutrients more effectively, softens the
growing medium, and naturally restores
moisture to the plant.
You can put the remaining mixture into a
spray bottle to care for other orchids
in your garden. This method saves
resources and provides consistent
benefits for your entire orchid
collection.
Spraying the mixture provides natural
nutrients, helping your orchids maintain
health and grow steadily everyday.
The fermented mixture stimulates the
microbial system in the soil and growing
medium, creating an ideal environment
for orchid roots to grow sustainably.
Regular care with this solution helps
boost the plant's resistance, enabling
orchids to fight off pests and withstand
unfavorable weather changes.
Spraying this mixture on blooming
orchids gently supplements nutrients,
prolongs the flowers time on the spike,
and keeps the petal colors vibrant. At
the same time, it prevents the plant
from becoming too exhausted during the
blooming process.
After soaking for about 20 minutes, use
a soft cloth to gently blot any
remaining solution from the leaves and
between the leaf joints. This this helps
keep the leaves dry, reduces the risk of
fungal infections, and allows the plant
to breathe more easily.
[Music]
Then gently take the orchid pot out and
place it in a spot with gentle sunlight.
Proper exposure to light will help the
orchid photosynthesize effectively,
absorb nutrients better, and support a
stronger recovery and growth process.
[Music]
And here is the result after one month
of care.
[Music]
You can see many new roots growing,
strong and firmly attached to the
growing medium. A wonderful sign that
the plant is recovering well.
[Music]
New roots help the orchid absorb water
and nutrients more efficiently,
providing the energy it needs to recover
and grow fully.
[Music]
Healthy new roots help the orchid
recover more quickly after a weakened
phase and also boost its resistance to
environmental changes or unfavorable
weather conditions.
[Music]
What do you think about my method for
reviving weak orchids? Feel free to
leave a comment and share your thoughts
with me.
[Music]
Although some leaves are still wilted,
once the roots begin functioning well,
the plant will gradually regain its
vitality. The leaves will absorb enough
water and minerals, slowly turning green
again and no longer appearing wilted.
[Music]
I continue caring for this orchid with
the natural fermented fertilizer made
from molasses, applying it regularly
twice a month.
It's a simple yet effective method that
helps the plant gradually recover and
grow stronger day by day.
Or you can alternate it with other
natural fertilizers.
Rotating nutrient sources helps the
plant absorb a wider range of nutrients,
promoting balanced and sustainable
growth over time.
After that, remember to place the orchid
pot in a spot with gentle sunlight to
help the plant photosynthesize
better during the recovery process.
And here is the result after 3 months.
You can see the orchid has fully
recovered. The the once wilted leaves
are now lush and green again. And the
plant is even beginning to grow a new
flower spike full of hope.
[Music]
Not just one, but three new flower
spikes have grown on the same orchid.
That's a clear sign the plant has made a
strong recovery and is ready to enter a
vibrant new blooming season.
[Music]
Alongside the new flower spikes, the
root system has also grown vigorously
with many healthy new roots. This is the
solid foundation that allows the orchid
to keep growing sustainably and produce
long-lasting blooms.
[Music]
The flower buds have also formed, large,
plump, and firm. That's a sign the plant
is full of vitality and about to bloom
into stunning flowers.
New leaves have also emerged, lush
green, and glossy, a clear sign that the
orchid has truly revived from root to
tip.
Um, the old once wilted leaves have now
fully recovered, becoming firm and full
of life again.
Although the recovered old leaves may
not look as beautiful as the new ones,
they still contain valuable nutrients
inside, helping the plant continue to
grow strong and support other parts.
[Music]
Um, what do you think about the way I
revived this little orchid? Don't
hesitate to leave a comment and share
your thoughts. I'd love to hear your
feedback and experiences.
[Music]
As you can see, with just a few simple
steps, along with patience and a love
for plants, any weak orchid can be
brought back to life with strength.
Start today, care for each little
detail, and you'll witness the magic
created by your own hands.
Just care for one orchid at a time and
over the months and years, you'll have a
garden or balcony filled with radiant
blooming orchids. That journey begins
with patience, love, and the small
actions you take today.
[Music]
Every morning when you wake up, you'll
be greeted by the vibrant blooms of the
orchids you've cared for with your own
hands. A simple yet deeply meaningful
joy that starts your day with peace and
positive energy.
[Music]
I hope you'll enjoy this video. If you
find it helpful, don't forget to like
and subscribe so you won't miss upcoming
tips on natural and simple orchid care.
[Music]
Thank you for watching until the end of
the video. uh wishing you good health,
happiness, and lots of vibrant orchids
blooming all year round. See you in the
next video.