[Music]
Welcome to the garden where every orchid
tells its own story and every moment of
care brings joy and peace.
In this video, I will share a simple way
to help a sick orchid recover quickly
while also stimulating the plant to
produce many keis at the same time.
Thanks to that, in one orchid pot, you
will see many young plants growing
together, bringing a brilliant blooming
season with lots of flowers.
[Music]
Let's get started.
This is an orchid suffering from rot
mainly caused by the attack of fungi and
bacteria which damage and weaken the
leaves.
[Music]
If rot is not treated in time, it will
quickly spread and can cause the entire
orchid to die.
Uh please comment and let me know which
country you are watching the video from.
It's wonderful that we can connect and
chat from all over the world.
The rotten parts after being removed
need to be carefully disinfected or
destroyed far from the garden to avoid
spreading to other plants.
Um, I need to check the roots because
when an orchid rots, it is often due to
water logging in the roots, which causes
root suffocation and gradual weakening
of the plant.
It is necessary to cut off all the
damaged roots, helping the orchid avoid
the spread of pathogens and creating
conditions for new healthy roots to
grow.
If you haven't subscribed to the channel
yet, click the subscribe button to
support me and not miss any orchid
growing tips. It's wonderful to have you
along for the journey.
After that, wash the orchid thoroughly
with water to completely remove any
remaining bacteria and fungi.
[Music]
Next, prepare four cups of water,
approximately one liter, to proceed with
the next care step for the orchid.
[Music]
Then add five tablets of vitamin B1,
each 2.5 mg. Vitamin B1 helps the orchid
recover quickly, stimulates new root
growth, and boosts resistance.
[Music]
Next, take an aloe vera leaf and cut it
into thin slices. Aloe vera is rich in
nutrients, very good for restoring weak
orchids and helping the roots grow
quickly.
Add the aloe vera slices together with
the vitamin B1 to create a nutrient
mixture that helps the orchid recover
quickly and stimulates root growth.
Then wait about 30 minutes for the
nutrients to fully dissolve in the
water, ready for the next care step for
the orchid.
Then strain the water to remove the
residue, keeping only the nutrient-rich
solution for the orchid.
[Music]
Then use this solution to soak the
orchid's roots for about 20 minutes,
helping the roots absorb nutrients,
recover quite quickly, and stimulate
healthy growth.
[Music]
I chose crushed pine bark as the growing
medium because it helps maintain just
the right moisture and ensures good
drainage for the orchid.
Then gently place the orchid into the
growing medium, keeping the roots
comfortable and free from bending or
damage.
The white beads are resin beads used in
hydroponic gardening. When mixed with
crushed pine bark, they help increase
irration for the orchid roots.
Finally, add a thin layer of moss on top
to retain moisture and create a good
environment for the orchid roots to
grow.
[Music]
Then take cotton balls and soak them in
the vitamin B1 and aloe vera mixture.
Then use them to wrap the orchid's
roots, helping retain moisture and
allowing the roots to absorb nutrients
and recover quickly.
[Music]
Wrap for one day and then remove. This
helps stimulate the roots and new shoots
to grow quickly.
[Music]
Then pour the nutrient mixture into a
spray bottle for easy application onto
the orchid.
[Music]
From now on, spray this solution onto
the leaves, roots, and growing medium of
the orchid once a week to help the plant
stay healthy and grow well.
Or you can also pour this mixture
directly onto the roots and growing
medium, helping the orchid absorb
nutrients faster and grow healthily.
Then place the orchid pot in a cool area
with sufficient light, allowing the
plant to stabilize and adapt well to the
new environment.
[Music]
After one day, remove the cotton from
the orchid's roots, allowing the roots
to continue growing normally.
[Music]
Then take a transparent plastic box and
place it over the plant like a mini
greenhouse to retain moisture and
protect the young orchid.
[Music]
Uh place the orchid pot in a cool airy
spot with gentle sunlight, preferably
morning eastacing sun, so the plant can
photosynthesize effectively and
synthesize nutrients well. Continue
spraying the aloe vera and vitamin B1
mixture onto the plant once a week to
help the orchid grow healthily and
recover quickly.
[Music]
Or you can pour this mixture directly
onto the orchid once a week, helping the
plant absorb nutrients and grow
healthily.
Remember
to place the orchid pot in a spot with
gentle sunlight so the plant can
photosynthesize well and absorb plenty
of nutrients, helping the roots and
leaves grow healthily.
And here is the result. After 1 month of
care and recovery using the vitamin B1
and aloe vera mixture, the orchid grows
healthily and blooms beautifully.
You can see that the orchid has grown
two shoots on both sides which shows
that the plant is recovering well and
growing vigorously.
[Music]
Continue spraying the aloe vera and
vitamin B1 mixture onto the plants a
week to maintain healthy growth.
[Music]
Or you can pour this mixture directly
onto the roots and growing medium,
helping the orchid absorb nutrients
quickly and grow healthily.
[Music]
And remember to place the orchid pot in
a spot with gentle sunlight so the plant
can photosynthesize well and absorb
nutrients effectively.
[Music]
And here is the result after another
month.
[Music]
You can see that two young orchids
growing from the mother plant are
developing healthily, but they have not
rooted yet. Therefore, continued care is
needed for the young plants to grow
roots and develop stably.
Continue pouring the aloe vera and
vitamin B1 mixture once a week to help
to help the young orchids grow healthily
and develop roots faster.
[Music]
Or you can spray this mixture onto the
entire orchid once a week, helping the
plant absorb nutrients and grow evenly.
[Music]
And remember to place the orchid pot in
a spot with gentle sunlight. You can use
a specialized orchid sunshade net to
protect the plant and enable effective
photosynthesis.
And here is the result after the next 2
months.
You can see that the orchid has
developed healthy roots, stems, and
leaves, which indicates.
You can also see the orchid is producing
new flower spikes, promising a brilliant
blooming season ahead.
[Music]
The leaves have become green and sturdy,
which shows that the fertilizer and
nutrients are working effectively,
helping the orchid stay healthy.
When you care for an orchid with all the
love you have for plants, it will not
disappoint you. The plant will reward
you with many buds on a single stem.
These buds will not fall off and will
soon bloom, bringing fresh and vibrant
flowers.
Thanks to careful and consistent care,
the orchid will grow vigorously with
lush green leaves, strong roots, and
continuously emerging flower spikes,
promising a brilliant blooming season.
[Music]
And when there is enough sunlight, your
orchids will bloom all at once, creating
a garden full of vibrant colors and
delightful fragrance.
[Music]
Every blooming flower is the result of
the love and patience you give to the
plant, turning your garden into a
vibrant and colorful paradise.
And it is these moments that bring joy,
relaxation, and happiness as you see
your orchids grow, bloom, and shine in
the garden.
I hope you enjoy this video. If you find
it helpful, don't forget to like and
subscribe to the channel so you won't
miss future tips on caring for orchids
naturally and easily.
[Music]
Thank you all for watching. Goodbye. And
I wish you always have healthy orchids
that bloom beautifully and bring lots of
joy to your garden.
[Music]