hello
everyone in today's video I'll share a
new organic fertilizer that will help
help your orchids Thrive and Bloom
[Music]
continuously if you want your plants to
be vibrant and stunning stay tuned for
some great
tips let's get
[Music]
started this pot of orchids has finished
blooming and has yellow leaves
these yellow leaves rot due to bacteria
if not treated promptly rot will spread
very
quickly so remove all damaged
leaves then cut off the dry branches
[Music]
and cut off damaged
Roots that's my maid do you have pets
[Music]
which country are you watching videos
from it's great that we can chat
together from all over the world
do you have
[Music]
apples I took an apple to make natural
fertilizer for
[Music]
orchids cut apples into small pieces
apples are rich in vitamins minerals and
enzymes providing essential nutrients
for plant
growth the compounds and apples can
stimulate the flowering process helping
orchids bloom beautifully
natural compounds and apples help
strengthen the trees resistance to
[Music]
disease using apples helps maintain
moisture in the substrate creating
favorable conditions for root
growth as apples decompose they create a
conducive environment for beneficial
microorganisms improving soil health and
plant
Vitality next I took one aloe vera leaf
and cut it into Into Thin
slices aloe vera leaves contain many
vitamins and minerals that provide
essential nutrients for the
plants aloe vera has antibacterial and
antifungal properties helping plants
resist diseases
then you put aloe vera and chopped
apples into the jar
add 100 mm of beer for fermentation
[Music]
and add 3 tablespoons of brown sugar to
help ferment quickly and not rot
[Music]
take one liter of
[Laughter]
[Music]
water put water in the pot
Now cover the pot and place in a cool
place for 3
weeks after 3 weeks you will have a
great fertilizer for orchids
this is the bottle I fermented 3 weeks
ago after fermentation for 3 weeks it
will form a GE product that is very good
for
orchids take 50 m of G apple and aloe
vera
[Music]
then mix with 2 L of water
step one
[Music]
you use this GE water to water and soak
Orchid
Roots GE is rich in vitamins minerals
and beneficial enzymes that support
plant
[Music]
growth the compounds in GE can stimulate
flower development helping orchids Blom
more
vibrantly G promotes the growth of
beneficial microorganisms in the
soil after watering soak the Orchid pot
in this water for about 20 minutes to
help the Orchid Roots absorb nutrients
water and balance the pH level in the
substrate
step
two use cotton soaked in GE water to
gently wipe the top and bottom of the
leaf thoroughly
GE water is rich in vitamins and
minerals aiding orchid leaves in
nutrient
absorption uh the enzymes in GE can
promote Leaf growth making them
healthier and greener
using GE enhances the leaves resistance
to diseases and
pests the antibacterial and antifungal
properties of GE help prevent mold
growth on the
leaves step three
you put GE water in a spray
bottle then spray GE Solution on the
entire orchid
GE spraying promotes the comprehensive
development of plants from Roots to
leaves and
flowers spraying GE on the leaves helps
retain moisture for the plant a
favorable environment for growth
step
four water droplets on leaves can create
conditions for mold and diseases to
thrive wiping them dry helps reduce this
risk when leaves are dry photosynthesis
occurs more efficiently as light can
directly contact the leaf
surface when leaves are dry they can
better absorb nutrients from sprayed
[Music]
Solutions after soaking for about 20
minutes take the Orchid pot out and
place it in a place with lots of light
so the Orchid can photosynthesize
[Music]
better results after 45 days of
treatment with GE solution every 10
[Music]
days the orchid has developed many young
roots
[Music]
young roots are highly sensitive and can
absorb nutrients from the soil or or
watering solution providing essential
substances for the plant
young Roots enhance the plant's ability
to absorb water especially in dry
[Music]
conditions and orchids also develop new
flower buds
leaves also become
stronger the growth of young Roots
stimulates stronger development in
orchids leading to new leaves and
flowers
young Roots contribute to forming a
sturdy root system helping the plants
stabilize and grow better
when the orchid's strong roots absorb
enough nutrients the flowers bloom
larger and more brilliantly than
[Music]
usual that's all I want to share with
you thank you for watching the video I
wish you good luck and success in life
goodbye and see you in the next video