Welcome to my little charming garden
where simple things become truly
special. In this video, I continue
sharing how to revive orchids that have
finished blooming so they can bloom
again in the next flowering season.
[Music]
The method is very simple using natural
fertilizer available in every
kitchen and your orchid will grow
strong, bloom all year round, decorating
your home more
brilliantly. Now, let's get started. You
can see this is an orchid with many
flower stems growing on the same plant
and they are beginning to enter the
fading flower stage.
Every time the orchid blooms, it focuses
energy on the flowers. Therefore, after
the flowers fade, the plant is usually
very weak. If not carefully cared for,
the orchid will become stunted and may
even die. But don't worry, because with
this simple method, you can help the
plant recover quickly and become healthy
again. The buds that have bloomed will
not bloom again. So, let's cut them off
so the plant can focus on nurturing new
buds.
Uh these are the flower buds that have
bloomed and it need to be cut off.
[Music]
Please comment and let me know which
country you are watching the video from.
It's wonderful that we can chat together
from all around the world.
Then check the roots and growing medium
for signs of damage or
rot. If you haven't subscribe to the
channel yet, please hit the subscribe
button to support me and never miss any
orchid care tips. It's wonderful to have
you along for the journey.
You can see this growing medium squeezes
out a lot of water which makes the
orchid roots prone to water logging.
Therefore, we need to remove this moss
con's growing medium to prevent root rot
and help the plant grow
better. Then cut off all the damaged and
waterlogged roots to prevent the orchid
from getting infected and to encourage
new root growth.
You can see that moss as a growing
medium retains water very well. If the
watering amount is not properly
controlled, the orchid roots will easily
become water logged and rot a lot.
Then we rinse thoroughly, especially the
roots and base of the plant, with wath
water to completely remove the old
growing medium and any remaining
pathogens.
[Music]
For the old pine bark medium, I wash it
thoroughly with water, then treat it for
fungi before reusing it.
This helps eliminate pathogens, save
costs, and protect the
[Applause]
environment. Then let the growing medium
drain before proceeding with
sterilization. Then you take an onion to
make natural fertilizer, which helps
sterilize and stimulate root growth for
the orchid.
use onion skins to make natural
fertilizer because they contain many
nutrients and minerals beneficial for
orchids.
[Music]
Chopping the onion skins helps quickly
release nutrients into the water when
making fertilizer.
Put the onion skins into a jar. Then
pour.5 L of boiling water
in. Cover the jar and wait for the water
to cool before using it.
[Music]
After the water cools, strain the onion
water through a sie to remove the skins
and leftover residue.
[Music]
Dilute the onion water with.5 L of water
so that we have one liter of natural
fertilizer solution made from onions.
[Music]
Now, soak the orchid roots in this
solution for about 20 minutes to help
sterilize and stimulate root
growth. Onions contain natural sulfur
compounds that help sterilize and are
rich in antioxidants that stimulate
faster root growth.
[Music]
While waiting for the roots to soak,
take a soft cloth soaked with this
solution and gently wipe both the top
and underside of the leaves, helping the
orchid stay clean and increasing its
nutrient absorption.
[Music]
Wiping the leaves not only cleans the
leaf surface but also helps remove dust
and some some harmful bacteria making
the orchid leaves
healthier. Um the nutrients in the onion
solution help the orchid leaves become
shinier thereby improving photosynthesis
efficiency and promoting better plant
growth.
While waiting for the roots to soak, we
proceed to treat the old growing medium
for fungi before reusing it for planting
orchids. Pouring boiling water onto the
growing medium helps kill bacteria and
fungi and cleanse the medium before
reuse.
[Music]
Soaking some moss in hot water helps
sterilize the growing medium
effectively, removing bacteria and
fungi.
Soak for about 10 minutes or until the
water cools completely to ensure the
growing medium is effectively
sterilized. Then we take the growing
medium out for orchid planting. Note, if
the medium is still hot, soak it in cold
water before use to avoid damaging the
plant roots.
[Music]
Then plant the orchid into a pot with
drainage holes to prevent root water
logging and ensure good air circulation
for healthy root growth.
[Music]
after planting. ing. Sprinkle a little
moss on top of the pot opening to help
retain moisture in the growing medium
and create a favorable environment for
root development.
[Music]
To prevent the plant from shaking during
root growth, I use a plasticcoated steel
rod as a support for the orchid, helping
keep the plant stable and secure.
To stimulate new flower growth, I use
some grapes because they contain
antioxidants and natural hormones that
help flowers develop quickly and
effectively.
Uh take three grapes and 0.5 L of water.
Then blend them to make natural
fertilizer for the orchid.
After that, make sure to strain out the
residue. So the fertilizer solution is
smooth and easier for the plant to
absorb.
[Music]
Then mix the grape juice with the onion
water to create an excellent natural
fertilizer blend for orchids.
From now on, water your orchid with this
mixture once a
week. Or you can substitute it with
banana or banana peel fertilizer once a
week to help stimulate faster flower
development.
Or you can substitute it with banana or
banana peel fertilizer once a week to
help stimulate faster flower
development. After that, place the
orchid pot in a spot with gentle
sunlight to help the plant recover
quickly, enhance photosynthesis, and
grow
steadily. After 1 month, you can see the
roots growing very healthy. Uh a sign
that the plant is recovering well and
ready for the new flowering
[Music]
period. These new roots will help the
orchid absorb nutrients and water more
effectively, thereby growing strong and
blooming more beautifully.
[Music]
You can also see new flower spikes
budding on the orchid plant.
This proves that the orchid is
recovering well and preparing for a for
a brilliant upcoming flowering season.
[Music]
With this simple method, using
ingredients readily available in the
kitchen, we can completely take care of
orchids at home, helping them bloom all
year round.
[Music]
What do you think about my method for
restoring weak orchids? Please leave
your comments and feedback to let me
know.
[Music]
Just by restoring one orchid at a time,
you will be surprised to have a vibrant
orchid garden full of flowers, bringing
a sense of peace and
happiness. I hope this video will bring
a lot of useful information to
you. If you find the content valuable
and meaningful, don't forget to like,
share, so many people can know and
subscribe to support me. Thank you for
always being with
me. Uh, in addition to English
voiceover, we have now created versions
in French, German, Italian, Spanish,
Portuguese, Japanese, Hindi, and
Indonesian to help you listen to and
understand the content more
easily. Thank you for watching the
video. I always pray that God blesses
all of you.