welcome to the happiness Garden
Channel this is where I share my passion
and experience in orchid
care in today's video I'll introduce you
to a new natural fertilizer which not
only helps orchids grow strong but also
Bloom beautifully all year
round if you love orchids and to
discover tips to care for
them let's get
started this is an orchid that has
finished
[Music]
blooming the petals have
withered cut off damaged leaves
please comment to me which country you
are watching the video from it's great
that we can chat together from all over
the
world uh as soon as the flowers is Wilt
repot your orchid and the plant will
recover and grow
quickly uh you cut off Old Flower
branches so that the Orchid can focus on
nutrition for new flower branches later
[Music]
then use coffee powder to sprinkle on
the cut to help the wound heal
[Music]
quickly then wait overnight for the cut
to heal completely before proceeding
with the with the next care
[Music]
step to make this fertilizer I use
okra okra is an excellent natural
ingredient for making fertilizer for
orchids due to its Rich nutrients
[Music]
next I use potatoes as natural
fertilizer to restore the
Orchid potatoes are rich in starch
providing essential energy for orchid
growth uh potatoes are packed with
minerals like pottassium phosphorus and
vitamin B6 which stimulate root
development and promote healthy Orchid
growth put the okra and Cho potatoes in
the jar
add 1 liter of water
close the
lid wait overnight for the nutrients to
dissolve into the
water next I use oatmeal as a natural
fertilizer take 3 tbsp of oatmeal
add 1 liter of
water wait overnight
[Music]
after one
night stir well so that the flour
nutrients dissolve into the water
[Music]
filter out
residue step
one use a soft cloth to gently wipe the
top and bottom of the orchid leaves with
the okra and potato soaked water
solution
removes dust and residue improving the
plant's ability to
photosynthesize the okra and potato
solution supplies natural nutrients
through the leaves
leaves become shinier softer and
healthier the solution may form a
protective layer reducing the risk of
pest infestations on orchid leaves
gently wipe each Leaf both the upper and
lower surfaces ensuring the solution is
evenly
applied do it one or two times per month
for best
results this method keeps orchids clean
healthy and thriving
step
two put this solution in a spray bottle
and Mist the entire orchid
plant spraying adds moisture especially
in dry conditions
spraying ensures the solution covers the
entire plant from Roots to stems and
leaves spraying ensures the solution
covers the entire plant from Roots to
stems and
leaves forms a natural protective layer
reducing the risk of pest
infestations do it one to two times per
month for best
results step three after spraying use a
soft cloth to blot excess water from
orchid leaves
water pooling on leaves especially in
crevices can cause rot if left too
long a damp environment can attract
fungi and bacteria harmful to
orchids protects orchid leaves keeps
leaves dry glossy and healthy
this habit keeps your orchids clean
healthy and minimizes potential pest or
disease issues
step
four now I mix the oatmeal solution with
the okra and potato solution
this mix provides amino acids
polysaccharides and natural starches to
encourage longer stronger roots
then you water the Orchid roots with
this mixed
solution the solution stabilizes
moisture levels enhancing nutrient
absorption
[Music]
made from natural ingredients it's safe
for orchids and the
environment this mixture is a fantastic
natural nutrient Source helping orchids
grow robustly and Bloom
beautifully do it one to two times per
month for best results
and I soaked the Orchid root in this mix
solution for 20
[Music]
minutes soaking softens The Roots
increasing their ability to absorb water
and nutrients
[Music]
afterward after 20 minutes take it out
and place the Orchid pot in a place with
plenty of light
[Music]
placing the Orchid in a well-lit area
helps it dry properly reducing the risk
of mold or
pests light AIDS the Orchid in
photosynthesis converting nutrients to
promote strong growth
[Music]
results after 50
days the Orchid grows two new flower
branches orchid leaves become glossier
thicker and healthier with a vibrant
green color
[Music]
now we'll check the roots
wow Orchid Roots grow very strongly this
clearly improves and enhances the
ability to absorb nutrients and water
with strong root and leaf growth the
Orchid will absorb nutrients more
efficiently from the surrounding
environment
now I'm repotting the Orchid into a new
pot for better
growth I plant with pine bark to help
retain moisture and ventilation
when planted in a new pot the Orchid
will grow faster
goodbye after planting you take care of
orchids like other normal plants
take care of your Orchids with all the
love you have for plants and you will be
rewarded with beautiful blooms a healthy
Orchid and the satisfaction of nurturing
your
plant thank you for watching and see you
in the next
videos wishing you success in caring for
your orchids and having beautiful
flowers