welcome to my
channel uh to help you have many choices
when caring for orchids at home with
organic fertilizer in this video I
continue to share new
[Music]
methods please subscribe to the video so
you don't miss any tips on my
[Music]
channel now let's get started
to make this organic fertilizer you need
coffee or coffee
[Music]
grounds I use three teaspoons
add 1 liter of boiled water
[Music]
incubate until cool
after the water cools filter to remove
residue
[Music]
add water to make 5 lers of coffee
solution
[Music]
next add one teaspoon of baking soda
first
[Music]
method water this fertilizer Solution on
the Orchid
[Music]
Roots coffee contains many minerals and
organic matter helps provide Orchid
[Music]
nutrition it contains nitrogen
pottassium and phosphorus important
nutritional elements for orchid growth
[Music]
uh baking soda bicarbonate soda has the
ability to increase the pH level in
Orchid pots this is helpful in reducing
acidity if you use too much chemical
fertilizer
[Music]
baking soda has the ability to kill
insects and fun guy that damage plants
[Music]
second
method spray this fertilizer on the
entire orchid
[Music]
this method is similar to using foler
fertilizer
[Music]
[Applause]
you can use it as a natural pesticide to
protect orchids from insects and
diseases
[Music]
third
method clean the leaf surface with this
fertilizer solution
[Music]
the leaf surface will always be clean
and an Airy with stomata orchids will
photosynthesize better
[Music]
please see the
results please see the results
[Music]
uh because of enough nutrition the
flowers bloom more
[Music]
brilliantly many flowers bloom on the
same branch
[Music]
the flowers stay on the branches for a
long time before
[Music]
fading thank you for watching the video
wish you luck and success in
life thank you for watching the video
wish you luck and success in life