hello Orchid
enthusiasts today I'm excited to share
with you how to make homemade organic
fertilizer that helps orchids Thrive
from their roots stems leaves to
flowers with easy to find ingredients
and a simple process this fertilizer not
only provides essential nutrients but
also protects the
environment let's get started
to fertilize orchids I use green
tea green tea is not only rich in
antioxidants but also provides essential
nutrients for
plants amino acids and minerals in green
tea help plants grow strongly increase
resistance and enhance Leaf
color in addition green tea also
improves soil structure and effectively
retains
moisture uh take 10 G of green tea and
put it in a
jar uh take 10 G of green tea and put it
in a jar
cover and wait for it to
[Music]
cool 1 hour
later uh if you haven't subscribed to
Channel yet please click the Subscribe
button to support me and not miss any
Orchid growing tips it's great to have
[Music]
company filter out
residue add 1 liter of water about 4
cups step
one use a soft cotton soaked in tea
water to gently wipe the top and bottom
of the leaves thoroughly
compounds in tea have antibacterial
properties helping to prevent mold and
disease tea water contains many minerals
and amino acids helping to provide
additional nutrients to
plants in addition to the English dub
we've now created dub in French German
Italian Spanish Portuguese Japanese
Hindi and Indonesian to help you hear
and understand the content more
easily do you have pets that's my maid
cleaning dirt from leaves helps leaves
absorb light better thereby improving
photosynthesis uh tea water helps
maintain moisture in leaves supporting
the growth process
using diluted tea helps plants increase
resistance and fight against harmful
agents
which country are you watching videos
from please comment for
me uh it's great that we can chat
together from all over the world
[Music]
in short this not only helps the plant
stay healthy but also beautifies the
orchid
leaves step
two put diluted tea into a spray bottle
then spray the substrate roots stems and
leaves of the Orchid
spraying green tea water also provides
moisture helping the leaves stay fresh
and reducing stress on the
plant green tea spray helps plants
increase their resistance to harmful
agents making them
healthier tea water helps clean leaves
allowing them to absorb light better and
improve
photosynthesis be careful not to spray
on flowers water standing on flower
petals can cause rot especially in humid
conditions leading to premature flower
[Music]
deterioration standing water on flowers
creates conditions for fungi and
bacteria to grow causing disease in the
plant when an orchid rots like this
flower you need to cut it off
immediately to avoid spreading the rot
to other
orchids to make fer ier for the roots I
need more
grapes just take two grapes and put them
in a
blender add 300 M of water about 1
cup grapes contain many vitamins
minerals and natural sugars which help
provide essential nutrients to the roots
puree
[Music]
then mix with green
tea it's three
grapes can promote the growth of
beneficial microorganisms in the soil
support the decomposition process and
improve soil
structure green tea provides minerals
and amino acids while grapes provide
vitamins and natural sugars helping the
plant receive adequate
nutrition both green tea and grapes have
antibacterial properties which help
prevent diseases and protect plants from
mold
natural sugars and grapes help enhance
the roots ability to absorb nutrients
grapes contain antioxidants which help
increase the plant's resistance to
harmful
factors compounds in green tea and
grapes help increase the plant's
resistance to harmful agents
this combination helps promote the
growth of beneficial microorganisms in
the soil improving soil structure and
moisture retention
[Music]
after watering soak the Orchid pot in
this water for about 20
[Music]
minutes 20 minutes
later take the Orchid pot out and place
it in a place with lots of scattered
light so the Orchid can photosynthesize
[Music]
more now let's see the
results hell healthy Orchid Roots play
an important role in absorbing nutrients
and helping the plant
[Music]
Bloom well-developed Roots help plants
become more stable facilitating the
growth of stems leaves and flowers
[Music]
strong roots help plants retain moisture
better which is important in maintaining
the health and growth of
[Music]
orchids Roots absorb nutrients necessary
for photosynthesis helping plants have
enough energy to grow and flower
[Music]
strong roots also help plants resist
diseases and adverse environmental
factors thereby supporting stable
flowering
when absorbing enough nutrients and
light the leaves are healthy and shiny
[Music]
green when the roots absorb enough
nutrients and water the plant is able to
focus its energy on flower development
creating beautiful and healthy flowers
thus the Healthy Growth of orchid roots
not only helps the plants survive but
also promotes brilliant blooming
[Music]
finally dedicate your love and care to
your plant
companions nurture your Orchids with all
your heart and you will be rewarded with
their stunning Beauty
[Music]
goodbye for now and I look forward to
seeing you in the next
[Music]
videos wishing you all the luck and
success in your plant care Journey