hello everyone all of us want to have
orc orchids healthy and has many flower
[Music]
buds the flower buds grow a lot the
flower branches grow very
[Music]
quickly today I share a new
fertilizer with this very simple and
easy method in there will be more flower
buds better green leaves and more flower
[Music]
branches let's start with this simple
method use cinnamon
powder uh it always has antibacterial
properties it helps prevent orchids from
rotting and
fungus use one
[Music]
spoon add 1 liter of boiling
water cinnamon water will help prevent
and control fungi and bacteria that
cause diseases on Orchids very well
[Music]
wait for this water to
cool next I took a ripe banana contains
a lot of minerals helps orchids grow and
quickly produce many flowers
[Music]
and cut into small
pieces put all these banana peels in a
jar add 1 liter of boiling
water wait for this water to cool
before fertilizing water each Orchid pot
this method helps keep the substrate and
plant roots moist and also a way to
remove old fertilizer helps new
fertilizers be more easily absorbed
[Applause]
[Music]
which country are you watching videos
from please comment for me
um it's great that we can chat with
people from all over the world
[Music]
and leave for 20
minutes after 20 minutes take it out
[Music]
this is one of the causes of your orchid
does not grow and has no
[Music]
flowers uh after cooling filter to get
cinnamon juice
[Music]
step
one use it to immediately care for these
leaves applying this method once a week
will add a lot of nutrient through the
leaves helps the leaves stay
Greener remember to wipe both sides of
the leaf evenly because insects often
cling to the surface of leaves helps
remove dirt and insects on Orchids very
effectively when you do this for orchids
it will always work um regain the green
color of leaves and promote plant
photosynthesis
happens faster leaves are always green
and
healthy if the leaves are yellow or
infested with insects this is it one of
the very effective ways
step
two you use this water to spray orchids
[Music]
and we will do this in the morning by
afternoon the leaves will dry and the
tree will always be healthier
[Music]
you should apply this method once a
week weak orchids will develop very
healthy roots
[Music]
um this is one of the very safe and
sustainable organic fertilizers for
orchids to grow
[Music]
quickly it will help eliminate insects
such as spiders aphids
thrips but you should not spray it on
flowers because wet flowers will quickly
rot and lose their petals
[Music]
then we filter the banana peel water and
mix it with cinnamon water
[Music]
step
three water the trees Roots immediately
every 2
weeks it will always protect and promote
sustainable development in
orchids this is one of the very safe and
sustainable fertilizers for
orchids the ability to absorb is slow
but once grown the tree is always
sustainable
you can alternate it with other organic
fertilizers
[Music]
after fertilizing soak the Orchid pot in
this fertilizer solution for about 20
minutes orchids are tropical plants so
don't let the growing medium get too dry
it will be very difficult for plants to
absorb nutrients from fertilizer
[Music]
then you take out and always place the
orchids in places with light during the
day leaves will be greener and plants
will photosynthesize better helps new
flower branches grow very quickly
[Music]
let's see the results of care with this
natural fertilizer your orchids are
cared for this way the roots will grow
very healthy and the leaves will always
be green the green color of the leaves
is very beautiful
[Music]
weak orchids it will gradually become
Greener and The Roots will grow very
healthy
this is one of the simple fertilizers
and very effective so your orchids can
grow quickly and easier
[Music]
flowers will also Bloom longer and last
longer lasting over
time I always share many different ways
to care for orchids so you can see and
choose which method is most suitable
[Music]
there are also many subtitles on the
channel for you to easily choose
from hope it will always help you a lot
don't forget to like share and subscribe
to the channel and press the Bell to
conveniently follow goodbye and see you
again wish you always success