Welcome to the happiness garden. If you
want your orchid pots to always stay
green and bloom all year round, the
secret lies in how you nurture them each
week. Today, I will share with you a
very simple but surprisingly effective
natural fertilizer formula. It helps the
plant stay healthy from the roots with
lush green leaves and long-lasting
flowers.
The first ingredient and also the main
component in today's natural fertilizer
formula is bread. You may be surprised,
but bread contains many wonderful
nutrients for orchids, especially starch
and a small amount of natural yeast that
helps stimulate the growth of beneficial
microorganisms in the growing
environment.
You just need to take a piece of bread
and tear it into small pieces just like
I'm doing.
Uh, leave me a comment and let me know
which country you're watching from. It's
wonderful that we can chat with each
other from all around the world.
If you haven't subscribe to the channel
yet, please hit the subscribe button to
support me and never miss any orchid
growing tips. It's wonderful to have you
with me.
After tearing the bread into small
pieces, put them all into a clean jar.
It's important that the jar is
completely clean so the mixture won't
get contaminated during the fermentation
process.
Next, add about 600 ml of warm water
into the jar to start preparing the
fermentation process.
The next ingredient is dry yeast, the
kind we usually use for making bread.
Dry yeast helps speed up the
fermentation process and creates many
beneficial microorganisms for the
orchid.
[Music]
You only need one teaspoon of dry yeast.
This small amount will naturally
activate the fermentation process. Not
too strong, but enough to create an
ideal environment for microorganisms to
grow.
[Music]
And the final ingredient in today's
formula is molasses. it. It's an
excellent source of energy for the
fermentation process, helping
microorganisms work actively and break
down nutrients more quickly.
Thanks to the molasses, the fertilizer
mixture will become more nutrient-rich,
helping orchids grow strong roots, lush
green leaves, and long-lasting flowers.
[Music]
After stirring all the ingredients well,
close the lid tightly and place the jar
in a cool, airy spot for about 1 week to
let the mixture ferment naturally.
Once a month, before applying this
natural fertilizer, water each orchid
pot.
[Music]
Uh, moistening the growing medium
beforehand will help the orchid roots
absorb nutrients more effectively and
prevent fertilizer shock when the
solution is added afterward. It's just a
small step, but it makes a big
difference, keeping the plant healthy
and helping it bloom more consistently.
[Music]
When the flower spike has finished
blooming, I cut off that part so the
plant can focus on nourishing its roots
and leaves. Pruning at the right time
helps prevent the plant from losing
energy and encourages new flower buds to
form more quickly.
[Music]
When watering, pour as much water as
possible. This method helps wash away
excess fertilizer and residual mineral
salts in the growing medium, creating a
clean and safe environment for the
orchid roots to thrive.
[Music]
Watering before fertilizing not only
cleans the growing medium but also helps
the plant absorb nutrients more
effectively. When the medium is
sufficiently moist, orchid roots can
easily take up the fertilizer, avoiding
overdosing or shock to the roots. This
method allows the natural fertilizer to
work at its maximum, promoting strong
roots, lush green leaves, and
long-lasting blooms all year round.
[Music]
After watering, soak the entire orchid
pot for about 20 minutes. This helps the
growing medium absorb water evenly and
washes away any remaining mineral salts
or fertilizer residues in the pot.
[Music]
After soaking, take the orchid pot out
and let it drain before applying the
fertilizer.
This prevents the fertilizer from
becoming too diluted or washing away too
quickly while ensuring the orchid roots
absorb the nutrients as effectively as
possible.
This is the reason why orchids become
stunted and slow growing as their roots
are prone to rotting and fungal
infections.
If the medium still contains residual
mineral salts or old fertilizer that you
apply directly, the roots will be
damaged. The plant will absorb nutrients
poorly and its flowering ability will
also decrease.
[Music]
After one week of fermentation, the
fertilizer solution will become clear
with bread residue settled at the bottom
and a white film on the surface. This is
a sign of good fermentation caused by
beneficial bacteria.
[Music]
I will pour out about 50 ml of the
solution to dilute and use as fertilizer
for each orchid pot. For the remaining
portion, close the lid tightly and store
it at room temperature. The solution can
last about 2 weeks while still retaining
its nutrients.
[Music]
A properly prepared fertilizer will have
a mild, pleasantly sour aroma, not sharp
or unpleasant.
This is when the solution is ready to be
applied to the orchid pot, helping the
plant absorb nutrients fully and grow
healthily.
Then dilute the 50mm solution with one
liter of water. Diluting makes the
fertilizer gentle and safe for the
orchid's roots and leaves while ensuring
the plant absorbs nutrients optimally.
Method one, after diluting, water each
orchid pot with this fertilizer mixture
once a month.
This simple but consistent habit will
help the plant absorb nutrients steadily
with strong roots, lush green leaves,
and long lasting blooms. With just a
little patience, your orchids will
always be full of vitality and bloom all
year round.
[Music]
When you water with this natural
fertilizer mixture, the orchid roots
receive ample nutrients, helping the
plant grow strong from the inside out.
The beneficial microorganisms in the
solution will also stimulate the growth
of new roots and improve the quality of
the growing medium, making the soil
loose and uh better at retaining water.
Moreover, they also balance the
microbial system in the growing medium,
preventing harmful fungi and bacteria
and keeping the roots clean and healthy.
[Music]
When the roots are healthy, the plant
absorbs water and minerals more
efficiently, resulting in lush green
leaves and longlasting flowers.
[Music]
Finally, this watering also helps wash
away excess mineral salts, preventing
root rot and disease, creating a strong
foundation for orchids to bloom all year
round.
[Music]
Method two, you you can pour the diluted
fertilizer mixture into a spray bottle
and spray it directly onto the orchid's
base and roots.
This method is very convenient, allowing
the solution to penetrate the growing
medium evenly, and you can easily adjust
the amount of fertilizer for each pot.
This habit will help the plant absorb
nutrients effectively, develop strong
roots and lush green leaves, and prepare
for the upcoming vibrant flower
clusters.
Uh when you spray the fertilizer mixture
onto the base and roots, the plant
quickly absorbs the nutrients, promoting
strong and evenly growing roots.
The beneficial microorganisms in the
solution will enhance the vitality of
the growing medium, balance the
ecosystem in the pot, and prevent fungal
diseases.
Spraying fertilizer evenly around the
roots also stimulates the growth of new
roots faster, creating a strong
foundation for the plant to anchor
firmly and absorb nutrients efficiently.
[Music]
Additionally, spraying directly provides
nutrients to the leaves and base of the
plant, helping the leaves stay lush and
healthy while reducing burn spots caused
by nutrient deficiencies.
[Music]
Spraying once a month will increase the
plant's resistance to diseases and
environmental stress, helping it grow
steadily and produce beautiful,
long-lasting blooms all year round.
[Music]
About 15 minutes after spraying, if you
notice the leaves are still wet from
water droplets, use a soft cloth to
gently dry them.
[Music]
This step helps prevent mold or leaf
diseases while keeping the leaves clean
and allowing them to absorb nutrients
more effectively.
[Music]
Small actions like these contribute to
helping the orchid grow healthily and
produce beautiful, long-lasting blooms
all year round.
[Music]
After drying the leaves, place the
orchid pot in a spot with gentle
sunlight so the plant can perform
photosynthesis effectively. No matter
how good the fertilizer is, if the plant
lacks light, flowering will be affected.
So remember the saying, enough sunlight,
flowers will bloom because light is a
crucial factor for orchids to grow
healthily and produce vibrant blooms.
In summary, to keep your orchids healthy
and blooming all year round, you need to
follow all the steps. Prepare the
natural fertilizer. Water before
fertilizing. Apply the fertilizer
directly or spray the mixture. Dry the
leaves if water remains. And finally,
place the pot in a spot with gentle
light for the plant to photosynthesize.
When practiced consistently, the orchid
roots will be strong, the leaves lush
and green, and the buds and flowers will
develop evenly and last long.
Care for your plants with all your love
and patience, and you will see your
orchid pots bloom like gifts from
nature, always bringing joy and beauty
to your space.
Thank you for watching the video. I
always pray for God's blessings to be
upon all of you.