Welcome to the channel. Today I will
share how to care for orchids that will
surely help them bloom more, look more
beautiful, and grow healthier daybyday.
If you haven't subscribed to the
channel, click the subscribe button now
so you won't miss any great orchid care
tips in the future.
Uh, please comment and let me know which
country you are watching this video
from. It's wonderful that we can chat
together from all over the world.
[Music]
You can see this orchid is blooming
brilliantly and continuously producing
fresh, vibrant and lively flowers.
[Music]
First, you need to remove the wilted
flowers and dead stems.
[Music]
This will help reduce stem rot and
stimulate new shoots. And the nutrients
will be concentrated to produce new
shoots.
[Music]
These buds have finished blooming and
cannot produce new flowers, so please
remove them.
[Music]
Do you have any onions?
Onions contain sulfur compounds and some
antibacterial substances which help
prevent harmful fungi and bacteria for
plants.
I use the peel of an onion to make
fertilizer for orchids because it is
rich in nutrients, helping the roots
grow strong and the leaves become
greener day by day.
Put all the onion peels into a clean jar
ready to be made into nutrient-rich
fertilizer for orchids.
[Music]
The next ingredient we need is flour, a
component that will make the fertilizer
more nutritious for orchids as
Take one teaspoon of flour and add it
together with the onion peels.
Then add one liter of water to the
mixture and bring it to a boil, allowing
the nutrients from the onion and flour
to fully dissolve.
[Applause]
[Music]
Cover the jar, let it sit, and wait for
the water to cool, allowing the
nutrients from the onion and flour to
fully dissolve in the water.
[Music]
After about 2 hours, when the water has
cooled, we filter out the residue to
leave only the nutrient-rich solution
for the orchids.
[Music]
This helps the solution become clearer
and easier to absorb while ensuring the
nutrients are ready to nourish the
orchids for healthy growth.
Then dilute the solution with an
additional liter of water so the orchids
can easily absorb the nutrients without
it being too strong.
[Music]
Step one, water each orchid pot with
this mixture, ensuring every part of the
plant receives full nutrients.
[Music]
Um, the extract from onions or onion
peels not only helps stimulate strong
root growth, but also aids the orchid in
absorbing nutrients better, keeping the
plant healthy and the leaves lush and
green.
Flower provides a valuable source of
nutrients for plants, especially vitamin
B, which helps roots grow strong and
leaves stay lush and green.
[Music]
When using flour, it also helps retain
moisture in the soil around the roots,
creating favorable conditions for the
orchid to grow healthily and bloom
evenly.
[Music]
Some studies show that flour not only
stimulates strong root growth but also
enhances the overall health of plants,
helping leaves stay lush and flowers
bloom evenly.
[Music]
After watering, you can leave the orchid
pot soaking in the mixture for about 20
minutes, allowing the roots to absorb
the maximum nutrients and grow strong.
[Music]
Step two, pour the remaining water into
a spray bottle ready to mist the leaves
and around the orchid pot, helping the
plant absorb nutrients comprehensively.
[Music]
This is similar to using folure
fertilizer for orchids, helping the
plant quickly absorb nutrients through
the leaves and enhancing overall health.
Onion peels contain natural compounds
with antibacterial and antifungal
properties, helping protect orchids from
diseases and keeping the plants healthy.
This type of folure fertilizer provides
all essential nutrients such as
nitrogen, phosphorus, potassium along
with trace elements, helping orchids
grow vigorously and bloom evenly.
This type of folure fertilizer also
helps the orchid flowers become more
vibrant and longasting, contributing to
the plant's beauty and aesthetic value.
[Music]
You should do this in the morning just
after sunrise
before the heat rises when the orchid
leaves are no longer wet. It helps the
plant absorb nutrients more effectively.
[Music]
Ideally, you should wipe off the water
droplets on the leaves before it gets
hot to prevent leaf damage and help the
plant absorb nutrients better.
Um, please comment and let me know which
country you are watching this video
from. It's wonderful that we can chat
together from all over the world.
[Music]
Previously, this leaf was full of water,
and when the hot sun shone on it, it
acted like a magnifying lens, causing
the leaf to burn. As you see here, I'
[Music]
um you should follow these steps about
one to two times per month to keep the
orchids and blooming evenly.
Or you can combine it with other organic
fertilizers that I have shared on the
channel, helping orchids grow more
comprehensively and healthily.
[Music]
After soaking for 20 minutes, take the
orchid pot out and place it in a spot
with gentle scattered sunlight, helping
the plant carry out photosynthesis and
grow healthily.
[Music]
And here are the results after caring
for the orchids with natural fertilizer
in my garden. You can see the root
system has grown very strong, helping
the plant stay healthy and ready to
bloom.
Healthy roots help the plant retain
moisture more effectively, especially
during dry weather, keeping the orchids
always fresh and thriving.
[Music]
Healthy roots help the plant absorb
water and nutrients from the surrounding
environment quickly and efficiently,
supporting the overall growth of the
orchids.
And you can see the leaves become
greener and shinier, showing that the
orchid is growing healthily.
When the root system is healthy, the
plant can supply sufficient water and
nutrients to the leaves, helping them
stay vibrant and grow better.
[Music]
Healthy roots help maintain the overall
health of the plant, creating conditions
for new flowers to bloom while the old
flowers remain fresh on the stems.
[Music]
Strong, deep, and wide roots help the
orchid easily access more nutrients from
the soil or growing medium and
supporting comprehensive growth.
[Music]
Healthy roots create a favorable
environment for beneficial
microorganisms to thrive, helping break
down nutrients so the orchid can absorb
them more easily.
[Music]
A healthy root system is the foundation
for the strong vitality of the orchid.
It helps the plant absorb water and
nutrients efficiently, thereby promoting
leaf growth and vibrant blooms.
[Music]
Proper root care, including adequate
watering, sufficient fertilization, and
maintaining a good growing environment
will help orchids grow healthily and
bloom brilliantly.
[Music]
Um, what do you think about the way I
care for my orchids? Please write a
comment with your feedback and let me
know.
[Music]
with This care method, all types of
orchids can develop healthy root
systems, keeping the plants lush and
blooming regularly.
[Music]
Uh, take care of your orchids with all
the love you have for plants and you
will be rewarded with beautiful,
vibrant, and lively flowers.
It helps us feel full of energy, more
youthful, and love life more each day.
[Music]
Seeing the flowers in full bloom, we
feel the youthfulness in our souls and
the love for this life.
I hope you enjoy this video. If you find
it helpful, don't forget to like and
subscribe to the channel so you won't
miss future tips on caring for orchids
naturally and easily.
If you encounter any difficulties while
growing orchids, don't hesitate to
comment. I am always ready to support
you so you can grow healthy orchids that
bloom abundantly.
[Music]
In addition to English voiceover, we
have now created French, German,
Italian, Spanish, Portuguese, Japanese,
Hindi, Dutch, Polish, Korean, and
Indonesian versions to help you listen
and understand the content easily.
To listen in your preferred language,
open the video and click on settings,
the gear icon to select the appropriate
audio language.
Thank you for watching. Goodbye and wish
you a day full of joy with beautiful
flowers.