Welcome to the happiness garden where
every flower tells its own story.
Here you can see an orchid that is
wilting. Perhaps it is because the plant
has not been watered properly or maybe
the direct sunlight has been too strong
on the plant causing the leaves to
weaken.
Um if you want the orchid to recover and
grow quickly, take some time to watch
this video very carefully.
Please leave a comment to let me know
which country you are watching this
video from. It's wonderful that we can
chat together from all around the world.
And if you haven't subscribed to the
channel yet, please hit the subscribe
button to support me and not miss any
orchid growing tips. It's wonderful to
have you along.
[Music]
And now I will share with you a truly
amazing trick.
You only need one aloe vera leaf. The
gel from this aloe vera leaf is truly
amazing for reviving an orchid.
[Music]
Now apply the aloe vera gel to both the
top and bottom surfaces of the leaf.
Aloe vera gel has excellent moisturizing
properties helping the orchid regain its
health.
In addition, aloe vera also contains
vitamins's A, B, C, and natural minerals
like nitrogen, phosphorus, and
potassium, which are very good for the
orchid's recovery process.
Do this every 5 days.
[Music]
Then place the plant in a cool area for
3 weeks, allowing the leaf to fully
recover.
[Music]
Next, take one liter of warm water and
pour it into a container.
Next, soak one spoon of rice in the
water for about 30 minutes. During this
time, the nutrients in the rice will
gradually dissolve into the water,
creating a gentle yet energizing
solution for the orchid.
[Music]
Uh the remaining aloe vera leaf will be
prepared to make a natural fertilizer
for the orchid. This is a great way to
make full use of the aloe leaf. Nothing
goes to waste and the plant absorbs even
more nutrients.
[Music]
Add about 300 ml of water. Then blend
the aloe vera thoroughly. When the aloe
is finely blended, its nutrients will
easily dissolve in the water, helping
the plant absorb them more effectively.
[Music]
After blending, strain out the residue
to get a smooth, clear aloe solution.
This liquid is a pure source of
nutrients that your orchid will
absolutely love.
[Music]
Add one more liter of room temperature
water to the filtered aloe solution.
This helps make the mixture gentler,
suitable for watering or or spraying on
the orchid without shocking its roots.
[Music]
After soaking for about 30 minutes,
strain out the clear rice water. This
part contains the most nutrients,
helping the orchid recover faster and
grow stronger.
[Music]
Then mix the rice water with the aloe
solution you just prepared. This
combination creates a wonderful natural
fertilizer that helps the orchid recover
from roots to leaves.
[Music]
before. Before applying this liquid
fertilizer, I place a bit of moss on the
surface of the pot. This moss layer
helps retain moisture for the roots and
allows the plant to absorb nutrients
more effectively.
[Music]
[Applause]
Since the orchid is wilting, after
watering, you can soak the entire pot in
this mixture for about 2 hours. This
helps the roots fully absorb the
nutrients and regain vitality more
quickly.
After soaking for about 2 hours, take
the orchid pot out and place it in a
cool, airy spot. This helps the orchid
relax, absorb nutrients better, and
begin its natural recovery process.
[Music]
Uh, if you don't use up all of this
liquid fertilizer mixture, you can pour
it into a tray and freeze it for future
use.
This method helps preserve the nutrients
in the aloe and rice water for a longer
time while maintaining their
effectiveness.
[Music]
When you want to reuse the frozen liquid
fertilizer, thaw it until the solution
returns to room temperature before use.
Doing this helps the plant absorb
nutrients more easily and prevents
temperature shock.
[Music]
After naturally thawing, you can use
this solution to spray on the leaves or
water directly at the base of the
orchid. By doing this once or twice a
week, the plant will gradually recover,
grow new roots, and thrive again.
[Music]
And here is the result after 2 weeks of
recovery with this natural fertilizer.
You can see that the leaves have become
firmer and healthier than before.
[Music]
And new roots have also started to grow,
which shows that the orchid has truly
recovered and is is continuing to grow
healthily.
[Music]
Uh, these new roots will help transport
water and nutrients from the base to the
stem, spreading to every tiny part of
the plant and nourishing the entire
orchid to become healthier each day.
[Music]
When the roots supply enough water and
nutrients, the leaves will gradually
become fresher, greener, and firm again
as they were before.
[Music]
And here is the result after 1 month of
reviving the wilted orchid with natural
nutrients. You can see that the plant
has started to grow new leaves. And the
older leaves have also become firmer,
brighter, and much more vibrant than
before.
[Music]
The root system has now grown strong
with new roots stretching out and even
clinging to the outer side of the pot,
showing that the plant is full of
vitality.
[Music]
The leaves have now almost fully
recovered, returning to their lush green
color and vibrant vitality as before.
Don't leave the video just yet. Stay a
little longer to see the wonderful final
result of this recovery process.
And here is the result. After 6 months
of recovery with natural fertilizer from
a wilted orchid that seemed almost dead,
it has now fully revived and is blooming
with vibrant, lively flowers.
You can see that the old leaves which
were once wilted have now fully
recovered, becoming firmer and healthier
than ever.
These vibrant petals show that the
orchid has fully recovered and is
growing healthily.
[Music]
Every time you revive an orchid, you
experience a different joy, a truly
special feeling. The orchid not only
comes back to life, but also brings you
excitement and positive energy.
[Music]
Seeing the leaves turn green again and
the flowers bloom brightly, you will
feel life becoming lighter and daily
work and worries seem easier to
overcome.
[Music]
Caring for orchids is not just about
taking care of the plant, but also about
nurturing the soul. An experience that
helps you find joy and peace in every
moment.
[Music]
I hope you enjoy this video. If you find
it helpful, don't forget to hit like and
subscribe to the channel so you won't
miss future tips on caring for orchids
naturally and easily.
Thank you so much for watching. I truly
appreciate your time and support. Don't
forget to like, subscribe, and share if
you enjoyed this video. Wishing you a
wonderful day filled with joy and
blooming orchids. See you in the next
video.
Welcome to part two of the video. In
this part, I will guide you through
simple yet effective steps to propagate
Phelinopsis at home, helping you expand
your orchid collection without much
effort. After the orchid has just
dropped all its petals, this is the best
time to propagate from the flower spike.
At this point, the mother plant has
completed its flowering process and is
ready for a new growth phase, helping
the offshoots grow healthy and
effectively.
[Music]
Then take one clove of garlic and
squeeze out the juice. The garlic juice
will be used as a natural solution to
provide antibacterial protection,
safeguard the flower spike, and support
the orchid propagation process
effectively.
[Music]
If you haven't subscribed to the
channel, please hit the subscribe button
to support me and not miss any orchid
growing tips. It's wonderful to have you
along.
Please comment and let me know which
country you are watching the video from.
It's wonderful that we can chat together
from all around the world.
[Music]
Next, use a cotton swab to dip into the
garlic juice and apply it directly onto
the node that needs stimulation to grow
an orchid offshoot. The garlic juice
will help provide antibacterial
protection, safeguard the spike, and
naturally stimulate the formation of new
shoots.
Only the nodes that have not yet bloomed
can sprout and grow into orchid
offshoots. So, you should apply the
garlic juice only to the young unopened
nodes. This ensures that the new shoots
will grow healthy and easily develop
into offshoots.
[Music]
Then use a transparent plastic wrap to
cover the part of the flower spike where
the node you want to stimulate into an
orchid offshoot is located. This helps
retain moisture, protect the young chute
from insects and bacteria, and create an
ideal environment for the offshoot to
develop.
Make a small hole for ventilation,
allowing the chute to receive enough
oxygen and preventing moisture that can
cause rot or fungus.
uh creating the best conditions for the
orchid offshoot to grow.
[Music]
And here's the result after 3 weeks of
care.
[Music]
You can see that the spot where the
garlic juice was applied has formed a
very healthy orchid offshoot. However,
at this stage, the offshoot has not yet
developed visible leaves or roots. This
is an early sign that the new chute is
beginning to grow and is ready for the
next stages of development.
[Music]
And here's the result after the next 2
months.
You can see that the orchid offshoot has
grown very healthily on the flower spike
with leaves starting to open clearly and
young roots forming.
This is an important step showing that
the new chute is ready to develop into
an independent plant in the future.
Note, throughout the process of
stimulating the node to grow into an
orchid offshoot, place the orchid pot in
a shaded area with high humidity as this
helps the young shoot form and develop
easily.
Conversely, if the orchid pot is placed
in a sunny area with low humidity, the
plant is more likely to produce flowers
instead of an offshoot.
[Music]
I have also applied this little tip to
another orchid and you can see the
result is that many healthy orchid
offshoots have formed on the flower
spike.
This simple yet effective method helps
propagate phelinopsis easily and
naturally at home.
Be persistent in applying these methods
and gradually you will have a thriving
and vibrant orchid garden just like
mine. Each offshoot will grow healthy,
bloom beautifully, and bring joy when
cared for at home.
I hope you enjoy this video. If you find
it useful, uh don't forget to hit
subscribe and share so that many others
can also learn these effective orchid
care and propagation tips.
[Music]