hello
everyone welcome to my channel in
today's video I will continue to share
how to make organic fertilizer that
helps weak Orchids with yellowing leaves
recover and leaves and Bloom abundantly
and
[Music]
sustainably let's get started
when growing orchids it is impossible to
avoid the phenomenon of yellowing leaves
and leaf rot which weakens the
[Music]
Orchid if you have an orchid with yellow
or rotten leaves like this Orchid this
is the video to help you take better
care of it in the
[Music]
future first remove all damaged leaves
on the Orchid to prevent the rot from
spreading
[Music]
further then remove the D damaged roots
on the
[Music]
Orchid damaged Roots can lead to
diseases removing them helps prevent the
spread of bacteria and
fungi by removing damaged Roots the
plant can focus on developing new
healthy Roots improving its ability to
absorb water and nut
[Music]
nutrients then spread a little moss on
top of the Orchid pot to help retain
moisture better and stimulate new roots
[Music]
Moss adds a natural beauty and decorates
the Orchid pot making the planting area
more vibrant
[Music]
which country are you watching the video
from please comment
below uh it's great that we can chat
together from all over the world
[Music]
if you haven't subscribed yet please
subscribe to support my channel thank
you very
[Music]
much um then I use bananas as fertilizer
to care for this
Orchid take one banana and cut it into
thin slices
bananas are rich in essential nutrients
like pottassium phosphorus and magnesium
which are crucial for orchid growth
especially during
[Music]
flowering put the bananas in the jar
jar do you have aloe
[Music]
vera take one Alo leaf and cut it into
thin
[Music]
slices aloe vera contains many vitamins
and minerals providing essential
nutrients for orchid growth
put aloe vera in the
jar aloe vera gel improves the plant's
ability to absorb water and nutrients
keeping the soil moist without water
logging
[Music]
then add 2 cups of warm water about 500
mL uh if you haven't subscribed yet
please subscribe to support my channel
thank you very much
now I add beer for
[Music]
fermentation beer contains various B
vitamins and minerals providing
essential nutrients for orchid
growth the sugars and yeast in beer help
stimulate the growth of the root system
allowing orchids to develop
stronger add 100 ml of beer about half
cup beer can enhance the plant's ability
to absorb water and nutrients making the
orchids
healthier then cover and leave in a cool
place for 3 weeks to create synthetic GE
from banana and aloe vera
[Music]
and this is the GE banana and aloe vera
product I fermented 3 weeks
ago take 50 Millies of this synthetic GE
about 3
[Music]
tablespoons add 2 L of water about four
cups
[Music]
stir well so that the nutrients dissolve
evenly in the
[Music]
water stir well so that the nutrients
dissolve evenly in the
water water and soak the Orchid pot in
this liquid
[Music]
fertilizer the combination of bananas
aloe vera and beer creates a natural
liquid fertilizer with many positive
effects for
orchids the fermented extract from
bananas and aloe vera contains a variety
of vitamins minerals and enzymes
providing essential nutrients for the
holistic development of the
[Music]
plants uh the enzymes in aloe vera and
compounds and bananas stimulate root
growth enabling orchids to absorb water
and nutrients more effectively
[Music]
uh then soak the Orchid pot in this
fertilizer solution for about 20 minutes
to help the roots absorb nutrients and
water best
[Music]
step
two use a soft cotton to absorb this
liquid fertilizer and gently wipe the
top and bottom of the
[Music]
leaves wiping the leaves provides
additional vitamins and minerals from
the extract supporting the plant's
growth
this method of cleaning leaves will
remove dust and debris allowing better
air circulation and enhancing the
plant's ability to
[Music]
photosynthesize the antibacterial and
anti-fungal properties of the extract
help protect the leaves from harmful
bacteria and fungi
the antibacterial and antifungal
properties of the extract help help
protect the leaves from harmful bacteria
and
[Music]
fungi wiping the leaves with the extract
helps orchids enhance their resilience
against environmental factors and
diseases
[Music]
which country are you watching videos
from please comment
[Music]
me it's nice that we can chat with each
other from all over the world
[Music]
step
three and then you put this amount of
liquid fertilizer into a spray bottle
then you spray the entire
[Music]
Orchid spraying the liquid fertilizer
helps strengthen the plant's resistance
against diseases and unfavorable
environmental factors
using the liquid fertilizer supports
robust growth of the orchids from Roots
to leaves and
[Music]
flowers after soaking for 20 minutes
take the Orchid pot out and place it in
a place with lots of sunlight so the
Orchid can photosynthesize well
[Music]
after soaking for 20 minutes take the
Orchid pot out and place it in a place
with lots of sunlight so the Orchid can
photosynthesize
well the orchid has grown many new
[Music]
Roots uh new Roots play a very important
role in the growth and development of
orchids
uh new Roots help the plant absorb water
and essential nutrients from the
environment uh supporting its growth and
development healthy Roots enhance the
orchid's resistance to diseases and
unfavorable environmental conditions
[Music]
new Roots help the plant establish a
strong connection with its habitat
thereby providing more
[Music]
stability Roots can also store nutrients
helping the plant maintain its life and
growth during difficult times
[Music]
the development of new Roots stimulates
the growth of other parts such as stems
leaves and
flowers new roots are a decisive factor
in the healthy growth and development of
orchids directly affecting the plant's
ability to absorb nutrients and its
resilience
[Music]
finally give your love and care to your
plant
companions nurture your Orchids with all
your heart
and you will be rewarded with their
amazing
Beauty hope you like the video please
comment to let me know how you liked
it goodbye and see you again in the next
videos wishing you luck and success in
your plant care Journey