Welcome to my happiness garden.
Today I'm going to continue sharing with
you a special way to make natural
fertilizer that helps care for orchids
at home.
By following some simple steps, you'll
see your orchids thrive and bloom all
year round.
Let's get started.
To make this fertilizer, I need coffee
or you can also use coffee grounds.
[Music]
Take one teaspoon of coffee powder into
the pot and add one liter of hot water.
[Music]
That's my maid. How do you like it?
Uh, incubate and wait for the water to
cool.
[Music]
Two hours later.
Stir until the nutrients are completely
dissolved into the water.
Filter out residue.
[Music]
Then add one liter of water at room
temperature.
Step one,
[Music]
use a soft cloth soaked in coffee water
to gently wipe the top and bottom of the
leaves thoroughly.
Wiping the leaves helps remove dust and
impurities, allowing the plant to
photosynthesize more effectively.
Coffee can also help increase humidity
for the leaves which is beneficial for
the development of orchids.
Coffee contains many nutrients such as
nitrogen which helps promote plant
growth.
[Music]
The compounds in coffee can enhance the
plant's ability to resist diseases.
Coffee can provide a pleasant aroma to
the surrounding space.
These combined benefits help your
orchids stay healthy and thrive better.
Do this step one to two times a month.
Step two,
put the ground coffee solution into a
spray bottle.
And then you spray your entire orchid.
The coffee solution contains nitrogen
and other minerals promoting plant
growth.
Nitrogen is crucial for protein
synthesis and chlorophyll production
necessary for photosynthesis.
Compounds in coffee can help orchids
resist certain diseases and pests,
potentially reducing the need for
chemical pesticides.
Uh spraying coffee solution increases
humidity for the leaves and the
surrounding environment.
After spraying, wiping off the excess
water on orchid leaves is crucial for
several reasons.
Um, water accumulation on leaves can
create a favorable environment for the
growth of fungi and bacteria.
If water is not dried off, the plant is
more susceptible to diseases like leaf
rot or mold.
When water sits on the leaves, sunlight
may be reflected, reducing the plant's
ability to photosynthesize.
Wiping the leaves dry optimizes the
photosynthesis process.
Step three.
When orchid roots appear silvery white
and the growing medium is dry, this
usually indicates that the plant is
lacking water and needs to be watered
immediately.
[Music]
Coffee solution contains nitrogen,
phosphorus, and potassium, essential
nutrients for plant growth.
[Music]
Nitrogen supports leaf and stem
development, stimulating photosynthesis.
[Music]
Phosphorus strengthens roots, enhancing
water and nutrient absorption.
[Music]
Potassium boosts plant resilience
against harsh environmental conditions.
[Music]
The natural compounds in coffee can
fight fungi and bacteria, help orchids
fight common diseases such as mold and
root rot due to the antibacterial
properties of coffee.
[Music]
You can soak in this water for about 20
minutes to help kill bacteria in the
growing medium and help the roots absorb
enough water and nutrients.
[Music]
After soaking the orchid pot for 20
minutes, take it out and place the
orchid pot in a place with natural light
but not exposed to direct sunlight.
[Music]
Light that is too strong can cause leaf
burn.
[Music]
Now let's see the results of caring for
the orchids with natural fertilizer.
Do this one to two times a month and you
will get great results.
After only 2 weeks of care with this
natural fertilizer, the orchid leaves
became healthier and greener than
before.
New roots develop and the root system
remains healthy and rot-free.
Strong roots help the plant efficiently
take up water and nutrients from the
growing medium.
A robust root system helps the plant
resist diseases and harsh environmental
conditions.
Roots also store energy supporting the
plant through various growth stages.
Well-developed roots facilitate
effective gas exchange, enhancing the
plant's respiration.
When an orchid absorbs sufficient
nutrients and is healthy overall from
its roots, stems, and leaves.
If you haven't subscribed to the channel
yet, please hit the subscribe button to
support me and not miss any orchid
growing tips. It's great to have you as
a companion.
In addition to the English dub, we've
now created dubs in French, German,
Italian, Spanish, Portuguese, Japanese,
Hindi, and Indonesian to help you hear
and understand the content. videos are
easier.
Um, if you encounter any difficulties in
the process of growing orchids, do not
hesitate to comment for me. I am always
ready to support you so that you can
grow healthy orchids and bloom a lot of
flowers.
Now, let me see the results after 2
months.
You can see the orchid has grown
healthier than before and has produced
two new very healthy flower branches.
The tough glossy leaves indicate that
this organic fertilizer is very
effective in promoting the healthy
growth of the orchid and aiding nutrient
absorption.
The large thick flower spike branching
into many fishbone like stems shows that
the orchid is getting ready for a
promising blooming season with many
flowers.
This proves that the natural fertilizer
is excellent for blooming, helping the
plant not only grow vigorously but also
stimulate the formation of many healthy
flower spikes.
[Music]
After blooming, the flowers not only
retain their fresh appearance, but also
display more vibrant and richer colors
than usual, making the orchid pot stand
out and look even more captivating.
Remarkably, the flowers stay on the
spike for a long time before wilting,
showing the plant's strong vitality and
the excellent nutritional support
provided by the natural fertilizer.
With this method of care, the orchid
will bloom repeatedly throughout the
year, bringing fresh and vibrant beauty
all year round.
Uh, the flowers stay on the spike for an
extended period lasting up to 6 months,
allowing the orchid to showcase its
beauty for an extended time, filling the
space with fresh and magnificent charm.
With this simple natural fertilizer care
routine, anyone can effectively take
care of orchids at home without spending
much, allowing the plant to thrive and
bloom beautifully without the need for
expensive products.
Uh, I hope this video provides helpful
information and helps you take better
care of your orchids.
If you found it useful and enjoyable,
don't forget to like, share, and
subscribe to the channel so you won't
miss any future videos.
Uh, I hope this video provides helpful
information and helps you take better
care of your orchids.
If you found it useful and enjoyable,
don't forget to like, share, and
subscribe to the channel so you won't
miss any future videos.
Hello everyone.
[Music]
Uh in today's video, we will explore how
to create an amazing organic fertilizer
that helps sick orchids recover quickly
and grow vigorously.
[Music]
With easily accessible ingredients, you
will learn how to create a nutrient-rich
solution that promotes lush green leaves
and faster blooming. Stay tuned to take
care of your orchids effectively.
[Music]
Let's get started.
Pytheium or risonia fungi often cause
soft rot, especially in wet conditions.
When you see a rotten orchid like this,
cut off the rotten part as quickly as
possible.
[Music]
Lemon is an easily accessible ingredient
and very useful for caring for orchids,
especially when they are rotting.
[Music]
Which country are you watching this
video from? Please leave a comment for
me.
It's wonderful that we can chat with
each other from all around the world.
[Music]
If you haven't subscribed to the channel
yet, please subscribe to support me and
not miss any tips on my channel.
In addition to the English dub, we have
now created dubs in French, German,
Italian, Spanish, Portuguese, Japanese,
Hindi, and Indonesian to help you listen
and understand the content more easily.
Videos are now more accessible.
[Music]
I take the peels of four lemons and cut
them into small pieces.
Lemon peels contain many micronutrients
such as vitamin C, calcium, magnesium,
and potassium, which help provide
nutrients for the plant.
[Music]
Add 300 ml of water, about 1 cup.
Then blend until smooth.
[Music]
Then strain out the residue.
Step one,
use a soft cotton pad to soak up this
liquid and gently wipe both the upper
and lower surfaces of the leaves.
Lemon peels contain antibacterial
compounds that help eliminate harmful
bacteria and fungi, preventing diseases
in plants.
[Music]
Lemon peel smoothie contains many
beneficial micronutrients for plants,
helping the leaves stay vibrant and
healthy.
The underside of the leaves has many
stamata where photosynthesis takes
place.
Cleaning off dust and impurities helps
the plant photosynthesize more
efficiently.
Okay.
Uh, wiping the leaves also helps remove
dust and impurities, reducing the risk
of pests attacking the plant.
Uh, wiping the leaves also helps remove
dust and impurities, reducing the risk
of pests attacking the plant.
[Music]
Lemon is acidic, which helps dissolve
dirt, mineral salts, and chemicals on
the leaves, making them easier to
remove.
The natural compounds in lemon peels act
as a gentle cleanser, helping to clean
without harming the leaves.
Carefully tending to both sides of the
leaves will help orchids grow healthier
and produce more beautiful flowers.
[Music]
Mix 3 L of water, about 0.8 US gallons,
into this lemon peel smoothie.
Step two,
lemon peel smoothie contains many
vitamins and minerals providing
essential nutrients for plants.
The acidity in lemons helps regulate the
soil's pH, creating an ideal environment
for root growth.
The compounds in lemon peels have
antibacterial properties helping to
prevent harmful fungi and bacteria.
[Music]
Uh, watering with lemon infused water
can stimulate root growth and help the
plant thrive.
After each watering, soak the orchid pot
in this lemon peel smoothie for about 20
minutes.
[Music]
5 minutes later.
Do you see snails and insects crawling
on the surface of the orchid pot?
[Music]
The compounds in lemon peels have a
bitter taste that makes insects
uncomfortable, forcing them to move
upward in search of a safer place.
[Music]
The lemon peel smoothie creates an
environment unsuitable for snails and
insects, forcing them to move out of the
growing medium in search of another
place.
[Music]
Step three.
Now pour this liquid into a spray
bottle.
[Music]
Then spray this liquid over the entire
orchid.
[Music]
Lemon peel smoothie contains
antibacterial and antifungal compounds.
The compounds in lemon peels contain
many micronutrients that help boost
plant health and growth.
helping to prevent and treat plant
diseases.
[Music]
After soaking for 20 minutes, take the
orchid pot out and place it in a spot
with plenty of diffused light so the
orchid can absorb more light for
photosynthesis.
Photosynthesis is the process by which
plants convert sunlight into chemical
energy.
Plants use this energy to grow, develop,
and sustain their vital functions.
Results. After 10 days,
the leaves become greener, shinier, and
stronger.
[Music]
During photosynthesis, plants produce
glucose, which is the primary nutrient
that helps them grow vigorously and
bloom.
[Music]
After 10 days, new roots also begin to
grow vigorously.
[Music]
New roots help the plant absorb water
and nutrients from the growing medium,
providing the necessary energy for
growth.
Healthy new roots help the plant grow
faster, produce more flowers, and
develop shiny green leaves.
If you encounter any difficulties while
growing orchids, don't hesitate to leave
a comment. I'm always ready to support
you so you can grow healthy orchids that
bloom beautifully.
[Music]
Take care of your orchids with all the
love you have for plants, and they will
reward you with blooming flowers,
vibrant colors, and a sweet fragrance.
[Music]
Dedicated care not only brings beauty to
your living space but also makes life
more wonderful.
Let orchids be a source of inspiration
bringing joy and peace to your soul.
[Music]
I hope this video brings you great value
in taking care of your orchids at home
in the best way possible.
If you find the content helpful, please
like and share or leave a comment to
support me.
[Music]
I always wish you goodness and
blessings.
Wishing you lots of luck and success in
life.