hello
everyone to help your orchids bloom
beautifully all year round today I'll
share a simple and effective way to make
natural
fertilizer with easily accessible
ingredients you'll have an amazing
option for carrying for your
orchids if you haven't subscribed to the
channel yet please click the Subscribe
button to support me and not miss any
Orchid growing tips it's great to have
company
let's get
started let's get
started to make this fertilizer I took
an apple and cut it into small
pieces remove damaged Apple Parts this
will not the quality of natural
[Music]
fertilizer please comment to me which
country you are watching the video
[Music]
from In addition to the English dub
we've now created dubs in French German
Italian Spanish Portuguese Japanese
Hindi and Indonesian to help you hear
and understand the content more
[Music]
easily apples contain nutrients like
potassium phosphorus and Elements which
help orchids grow
healthily apples enhance root
development and stimulate
flowering additionally apples help
improve the soil's microbial
[Music]
system this creates a favorable
environment for orchids to absorb
nutrients
put the apples in a jar and pour in one
liter of water about four cups of
water then add 5 tspoons of rice
and add 2 teaspoons of wine
yeast then stir the mixture well
then stir the mixture
[Music]
well this is a jar of natural fertilizer
I fermented 3 weeks ago
then take about 50 mm 3 spoons of this
fermented fertilizer
[Music]
mix with two L of water about 8
cups this way you've created a wonderful
fertilizer for orchids
this way you've created a wonderful
[Music]
cut off damaged roots to prevent root
rot from spreading to healthy
Parts it also stops wasting energy on
unhealthy parts this creates a better
environment for new roots to grow
um I keep these unfl flowered nodes to
stimulate them to bloom
again for buds that have finished
blooming cut them off
uh cutting again to prevent the cut from
being crushed will limit rot in the cut
then apply cinnamon powder to the cut to
help the wound heal quickly
step
one water the roots with this liquid
fertilizer solution and soak for 20
minutes
watering and soaking Orchid roots in
liquid fertilizer made from fermented
apples and rice provides natural
nutrients stimulates root growth
improves the orchid's health and
enhances its flowering
ability The Beneficial microorganisms in
the fertilizer also improve the soil
environment making it easier for the
plant to absorb nutrients
step
two now thoroughly wipe the top and
bottom of the orchid leaves with this
liquid fertilizer solution
wiping the top and bottom of the orchid
leaves with liquid fertilizer helps
provide nutrients directly to the leaves
stimulating growth and enhancing
photosynthesis this makes the plant
healthier improves nutrient absorption
and supports blooming
the microorganisms in the fertilizer
also help keep the leaves clean
preventing
[Music]
diseases step
three put this solution into a spray
bottle and spray it on your
[Applause]
orchid spraying the liquid fertilizer
Solution on the Orchid provides direct
nutrients to the leaves and stems
stimulating growth enhancing
photosynthesis and promoting overall
plant health
it also helps the Orchid absorb
nutrients quickly improves its
resistance to diseases and supports the
blooming process
step
[Music]
four afterward you need to wipe off any
excess solution left on the orchid
leaves wiping off any excess solution
helps prevent fungal issues or Leaf burn
Leaf burn caused by the fertilizer
solution being exposed to direct
sunlight it also helps the leaves dry
faster preventing the creation of a
moist environment that Pro that promotes
the growth of bacteria and fungi
[Music]
after soaking for 20 minutes remove the
Orchid and plant it in a new pot to help
it grow better
[Music]
I grow it using chopped Pine bark as the
substrate planting with shredded pine
bark helps with good drainage but still
creates enough moisture for orchids to
grow without being water logged
when growing orchids you need to observe
the time to water
[Music]
them observe the roots silver gray means
they need watering check the soil
moisture the leaves show signs of
wrinkling the pot is lighter than normal
and water in the morning
from now on you can uh nurture and care
for this Orchid with this fermented
Apple fertilizer following the four
steps I share two to three times per
month then remember to place the Orchid
pot in a place with light sunlight for
best photosynthesis
[Music]
photosynthesis helps plants generate
energy from sunlight converting CO2 and
water into oxygen and glucose this
process provides food for plants
supports growth and produces oxygen for
the
[Music]
environment results after 2 months
as you can see after being cared for
with this natural fertilizer the orchid
leaves become Greener glossier and
stronger The Roots grow vigorously
sprouting many new Roots proving that
this fertilizer is truly suitable and
highly
effective especially the plant has grown
two new flower spikes proving that the
fertilizer provides abundant nutrients
stimulating strong
blooming even more impressively this Old
Flower Spike has grown two new branches
at the top near the cut Point proving
that the plant continues to absorb
nutrients well and thrive
uh I hope you enjoy this video please
leave your comments Below in the video's
comment section for
me take care of your Orchids with all
the love you have for plants and you
will be rewarded with beautiful healthy
flowers that bloom all year
round thank you for watching and don't
forget to support the channel by liking
sharing and
subscribing goodbye and see you in the
next video