Hello everyone. I'm so glad you came to
my
channel. When growing orchids, everyone
wants the flowers to bloom for a long
time,
right? And each orchid pot will bloom a
lot of flowers all year
[Music]
round. Now, I will show you what is the
best fertilizer for orchids.
Uh, if you follow us till the end of
this video, you will learn how to make
orchids bloom all year
[Music]
round. Now, let's get
started. And when the flowers have all
bloomed, I cut off all the places that
are no longer able to flower.
[Music]
Then sprinkle white cement on the cut to
help the wound dry faster, limit
bacteria and fungi from entering,
thereby promoting ing the wound healing
[Music]
process. Unflowered nodes like this will
have the potential to sprout buds or
flower buds.
[Music]
Here I peel off the protective film that
will make it easier to germinate.
[Music]
Then I took the tomatoes to make natural
fertilizer for the
[Music]
orchids. Take a slice of tomato like
this.
Tomatoes contain a lot of vitamin A,
vitamin C, and are rich in potassium,
calcium, and phosphorus, which are very
good for orchids. Therefore, when caring
for orchids with tomatoes, orchids will
grow very quickly.
[Music]
Puree tomatoes with 1 cup
water. Then filter the water.
[Music]
I added water to get
2.20462 lb of tomato juice, about one
[Music]
liter. Method one. Then gently wipe the
leaves with the tomato mixture, a
natural way to clean and nourish the
[Music]
plant. Then using cotton soaked in
tomato mixture and wrapping it around
the dormant buds is a good way to
stimulate bud growth.
[Music]
You should do this every 7 days to
create the right humidity to stimulate
dormant buds to develop into flowers.
[Music]
I continue to wrap cotton soaked in
tomato mixture here will help this
flower branch continue to bloom new
flowers.
[Music]
This method maintains moisture for the
flower stem and the flower tip recovers
very
quickly. On normal days, you just need
to use regular water to keep the flower
branches
moist. Way
[Music]
two. Way
too. Tomatoes contain many vitamins and
minerals that can help make the leaves
healthier while removing dirt and
residue on the leaf surface.
[Music]
Uh, you can use a soft cotton or clean
cloth soaked in a diluted tomato mixture
to gently wipe, helping the plant absorb
light better and grow
strongly. Please apply this every 2
weeks to the tree.
[Music]
the leaves after being taken care of
will be green and healthy like
[Music]
this. Way three.
You can also use this tomato juice to
spray on the top and bottom of the
[Music]
leaves. And spray evenly on the
root. Wave four.
Use this water to water the orchid once
every two
weeks. Orchids grow because nutrients
are transported from the roots to all
parts of the orchid, including the
flower stock furthest from the
roots. Before fertilizing, water the
orchid pots thoroughly. This will help
the plant absorb the fertilizer better.
[Music]
Now, let's see the results after taking
care of them with natural fertilizer
from
[Music]
tomatoes And with this simple way, the
regenerated flower branches will be very
big and
[Music]
fat. Uh this way I also get a seedling
orchid.
[Music]
This way also helps flower buds to be
big and
[Music]
healthy. So many flower buds are reborn
in this way.
[Music]
So, my house always has flowers blooming
all year
round. Welcome to part two of the
video. If you want more orchids, flowers
bloom for a long time on the branch
before the bright color of the flower
fades.
[Music]
Like my orchids, flowers can last up to
months. Flowers bloom all year round,
one flower after another. There are
always many flowers growing on the same
[Music]
branch. If you want that, do the
following. One, place the orchid pot in
a place with mild
[Music]
sunlight or on a window sill.
Avoid the sun and strong
[Music]
wind. Two, before fertilizing, water the
orchid. This will make it easier for the
roots to absorb nutrients from the
fertilizer.
[Music]
Uh after each watering, soak the orchid
roots in water for 20 minutes so that
the plant can absorb enough
[Music]
water For leaves, you use a spray. Spray
to wet the leaves with water to help
open
[Music]
stamata. After soaking for 20 minutes,
the roots absorb enough water and will
turn green like this.
[Music]
Then I take it out and wait 30 minutes
before
[Music]
fertilizing. Three, use lemon as an
organic fertilizer for orchids.
[Music]
Use the remaining juice of half a
lemon. Mix lemon juice into 0.5 US
gallon, about 2 L of water.
[Music]
pour the lemon juice mixture into a
spray bottle.
Then spray evenly on the top and bottom
of the
leaves. Lemon juice is packed with
nutrients like vitamin C, citric acid,
potassium, and magnesium.
[Music]
These substances are quickly absorbed
through the leaves of the orchid,
helping to provide the nutrients needed
to promote the health and growth of the
[Music]
plant. After spraying, use cotton to dry
the leaves.
[Music]
Pay attention to drying the upper leaf
crevices.
[Music]
Regular fertilization of orchid leaves
will keep them green like this and the
leaves will not be infected with fungus.
[Music]
Four, add 1 teaspoon of honey to the
lemon juice solution
[Music]
earlier. Water this solution for orchid
roots one to two times month.
[Music]
Honey has the ability to stimulate
growth and cell division in
[Music]
plants. Uh when using honey mixed with
lemon juice as a fertilizer, it it will
help the plant thrive, produce many new
shoots, and have beautiful petals.
[Music]
Honey has antibacterial and antifungal
properties, helping orchids better
resist diseases.
[Music]
When using honey mixed with lemon juice
as fertilizer, uh it all helps it also
helps orchids have bright colors, a
sweet fragrance, and prolongs the life
of
[Music]
flowers. You can also soak in this water
for 20 minutes, letting the roots absorb
the most
nutrients. Welcome to part three of this
video.
Orchids are a tropical plant with a very
strong
[Music]
vitality. When you see this orchid,
don't rush to throw it
away. Today, I will show you how to
restore a wilted orchid like this in the
fastest way.
[Music]
Today I will show you how to restore a
wilted orchid like this in the fastest
way.
[Music]
Today I will show you how to restore a
wilted orchid like this in the fastest
[Music]
way. Rinse with water.
dry the cut.
Drop the molten candle solution on the
freshly cut wound. It will help orchids
not lose water and also work against
fungal diseases.
[Music]
Use one teaspoon of cinnamon powder.
Add four cups of boiling water, about
one
liter. Close the lid and wait for the
water to
[Music]
cool. Now the water has cooled.
Filter out the residue.
[Music]
Uh, soak orchids in cinnamon water for
30 minutes.
[Music]
Spray this mixture evenly on the top and
bottom of the orchid leaves. Um,
cinnamon has antiseptic properties, so
it helps to eliminate fungi and insects
that are harmful to orchids very
well. Cinnamon also contains many
minerals, vitamins, and amino acids that
are very beneficial for the revival of
orchids.
[Music]
Do this once a month to keep your orchid
protected and
[Music]
healthy. After soaking for 30 minutes,
take out the orchid cutings and plant
them.
I plant in shredded pine bark to help
with drainage, but also provide the
right amount of moisture for the orchid
to
[Music]
thrive. Spread one turn of dry moss on
top of the pot.
[Music]
Leave in a cool place and do not water
for one week so that the fungus does not
grow harmful.
[Music]
One week later, start watering to keep
the orchid
[Music]
moist. Pour water into the dish at the
bottom of the pot to create the right
humidity for the orchid to to revive
quickly.
Recycling plastic bottles into miniature
green houses makes it easier for orchids
to revive.
[Music]
One month later.
Since the tree has grown roots, I use
organic fertilizer made from fish waste
to fertilize the orchid.
The baby orchid is still very small, so
I only apply it on the outside edge of
the pot to avoid causing the baby orchid
to be shocked with
[Music]
feces. Watering and moisturizing once a
week.
[Music]
2 months later.
From now on, take care like other mature
orchids. See you in the next videos.
[Music]