Welcome to the Happiness Garden, where
we explore the gentle beauty of nature
and the secrets of orchid care in a
simple yet loving way. Each video is a
small journey that helps you connect
more closely with the world of vibrant
petals and the wonders of greenery.
In this video, I will share with you a
completely new way to make organic
fertilizer that's easy to prepare at
home.
[Music]
This fertilizer not only helps orchids
grow strong from roots to leaves, but
can also stimulate them to bloom all
year round naturally and sustainably.
[Music]
Do you have bananas?
To make natural fertilizer, I need two
ripe bananas.
[Music]
If you haven't subscribed to the channel
yet, please hit the subscribe button to
support me and never miss any orchid
growing tips. It's truly wonderful to
have you along on this journey.
[Music]
Every time you eat a banana, don't throw
away the peel just yet.
[Music]
That seemingly useless peel actually
contains many wonderful nutrients that
can become a precious gift for your
orchid.
[Music]
Take two ripe banana peels and cut them
into small pieces.
[Music]
Then put the chopped banana peels into a
blender.
[Music]
Leave a comment and let me know which
country you're watching from. It's
amazing that we can connect and chat
from all around the world.
[Music]
Next, add about 300 ml of filtered
water. This just right amount of water
will help the mixture blend smoothly and
retain all the nutrients from the banana
peels.
[Music]
After blending, pour the mixture into a
clean jar
[Music]
and add about 700 ml of water so that we
have one liter of the mixture.
The next ingredient is blackstrap
molasses. It's rich in minerals and
helps promote the growth of beneficial
microorganisms during the fermentation
process, which in turn enhances the
nourishing effect for your orchid.
You only need to add one teaspoon of
blackstrap molasses. Just a small amount
is enough to provide excellent energy
for the fermentation process, helping to
create a truly effective natural
fertilizer.
[Music]
After adding the blackstrap molasses,
stir the mixture well to combine all the
ingredients. Then close the lid tightly
and let it sit for 1 day to start the uh
natural fermentation process.
[Music]
This is the orchid I just bought. And
right now, I will share with you the
first step in taking care of a new
orchid, helping it adapt quickly, grow
healthily, keep its flowers on the stem
longer, and bloom again soon after the
current ones fade.
[Music]
First, take some time to carefully
observe the orchid. If you notice any
leaves that are wilted, turning yellow,
or showing signs of rot, you should
gently trim them off.
Then check the growing medium and the
root system. If the medium is decayed or
too wet, you should replace it to
prevent root rot.
Take a close look at the orchid roots.
Healthy roots are usually silvery white
or light green, while damaged ones will
be dark, mushy, and need to be trimmed
off.
[Music]
Since the growing medium is old spagna
moss and the roots are starting to show
signs of rot, I decided to remove all of
the old medium.
This helps prevent root rot and creates
the best conditions for treating and
caring for the roots properly.
After removing the growing medium, I
trimmed off the damaged roots.
[Music]
Soft, darkened, or hollow roots need to
be removed to help the plant recover
more quickly and to prevent the damage
from spreading to the healthy roots.
[Music]
After trimming and treating the roots, I
repotted the plant into a new pot.
I wrapped a small amount of new fungus
treated dry moss around the roots. This
layer of moss will gently retain
moisture for the roots while helping the
plant stay stable and adapt more easily
to the new pot.
These new roots will be wrapped and
protected by the layer of moss, helping
to maintain stable moisture and create
an ideal environment for continued root
growth.
Next, I used a growing medium made of
crushed pine bark that has been treated
for fungus and thoroughly dried.
[Music]
This type of medium helps retain just
the right amount of moisture, provides
good air flow, and creates ideal
conditions for the roots to grow strong
in the new pot.
[Music]
Finally, I spread a thin layer of moss
on the surface of the pot. This moss
layer helps retain moisture in the
growing medium while creating a cool and
clean environment for the orchid to grow
more steadily.
[Music]
After potting, to keep the orchid stable
and prevent it from wobbling, I used a
plasticcoated steel rod bent into a
support brace.
[Music]
In addition to the English voiceover, we
have now created versions in French,
German, Italian, Spanish, Portuguese,
Japanese, Hindi, Dutch, Polish, Korean,
and Indonesian to help you listen and
understand the content more easily.
To listen in your preferred language,
open the video and click on settings,
the gear icon to select the appropriate
audio track.
[Music]
This support helps keep the plant steady
in the pot, creating favorable
conditions for the new roots to anchor
firmly into the growing medium.
[Music]
At the same time, the support brace also
helps secure the flower spike,
preventing it from breaking or tipping
over during care. This allows the orchid
to maintain its elegant shape with the
blooms safely and naturally supported.
This is an orchid that has finished
blooming. And now with the second
method, I'll guide you on how to care
for your orchid after the flowers have
faded.
This is a very important stage that
helps the plant recover its energy, grow
strong, and get ready for the next
blooming season.
[Music]
I only keep the unopened buds on the
spike as they still have the potential
to develop and produce new flower spikes
in the near future.
As for the buds that have already
bloomed, I gently cut them off so the
plant doesn't waste more energy on them.
This allows it to focus on nourishing
the healthy parts and getting ready for
the next blooming cycle.
[Music]
When the spent buds are removed, the new
flower spikes receive more nutrients.
This helps the plant focus on nourishing
young shoots, promoting growth, and
preparing for the next fresh blooming
cycle.
[Music]
Then I continue trimming away the old,
damaged, or hollow roots.
[Music]
Removing the non-functional roots will
help the plant develop new roots more
easily and absorb water and nutrients
more efficiently.
[Music]
After letting the mixture ferment for 1
day, we begin the preparation process.
This is an important step to create a
natural fertilizer that is easy for
orchids to absorb and safe for their
growth.
[Music]
First, we need to filter out the residue
from the mixture. This helps make the
solution clearer, easier to use, and
prevents clogging the growing medium or
damaging the roots when watering the
plant.
[Music]
After filtering, I dilute the solution
with 3 L of clean water. This ratio
ensures that the nutrients are
sufficient for the plant to absorb
effectively while still being safe for
the orchid's sensitive roots.
[Music]
Step one, use a soft cloth to soak up
the diluted solution. Then gently wipe
it over the surface of the leaves.
Wiping the leaves with this mixture
helps remove dust, residue, and even
bacteria that have accumulated on the
leaf surface. When the leaves are clean,
the plant can photosynthesize more
effectively, boosting metabolism and
promoting stronger growth.
Through leaf wiping, a portion of the
nutrients in the mixture will be
absorbed through the leaf surface. This
is a quick and effective way to provide
nutrition, especially for orchids that
are recovering or nutrient deficient.
The natural ingredients in the mixture
helped strengthen the leaf's natural
protective layer, making the leaves
healthier and more resistant to fungal
infections, pests, and harmful
environmental factors.
You should wipe the leaves with this
mixture twice a month. This frequency is
enough to help the plant absorb
nutrients effectively, boost its
resistance, and still keep the leaves
naturally healthy and well ventilated.
Step two, pour the diluted solution into
a clean spray bottle. Using a spray
bottle helps distribute the nutrients
more evenly across the entire plant from
the stem and leaves to the surface of
the growing medium.
[Music]
Then gently spray the solution over the
entire plant, including the top and
underside of the leaves, the stem, and
the surface of the growing medium.
[Music]
Um, spraying the solution on both the
top and underside of the leaves allows
the plant to quickly absorb uh essential
micronutrients through the leaf surface,
supporting more efficient photosynthesis
and metabolism.
The fermented solution contains natural
ingredients with mild antibacterial
properties, helping protect the plant
more effectively against fungi and pests
that commonly appear in humid
conditions.
[Music]
When evenly sprayed on the stems and
leaves, the nutrients in the solution
also help stimulate the growth of new
roots and the formation of new shoots,
supporting faster recovery after
blooming.
You should spray this solution twice a
month.
Uh, step three, pour the remaining
solution directly into each orchid pot.
This gently and effectively delivers
nutrients to the roots, supporting the
plant's growth from root to tip.
[Music]
When poured directly at the base, the
nutrients in the solution quickly soak
into the root zone, allowing the plant
to absorb them more efficiently and
promoting overall growth.
Uh this organic solution creates ideal
conditions for young roots to form and
grow healthily. New roots help the plant
stay stable in the pot and absorb water
and nutrients more effectively.
Regularly watering with the solution
also helps improve the growing medium's
environment by nourishing beneficial
microorganisms which keep the plant
healthy and reduce the risk of root rot
and fungal diseases.
You can also soak the orchid pot in this
solution for about 20 minutes.
Soaking allows the roots to absorb
maximum nutrients while also softening
the growing medium, creating favorable
conditions for new root development.
Step four, while waiting for the orchid
pot to soak, you can use a soft cloth to
gently wipe off any excess moisture on
the leaves and stem.
[Music]
Uh this helps reduce the risk of water
accumulation that can cause leaf rot
while also keeping the plant clean and
healthy.
[Music]
Wiping off excess moisture with a soft
cloth also helps reduce the risk of mold
forming on the leaves, especially in
humid conditions. This better protects
the orchid and keeps it looking fresh
and clean.
[Music]
After soaking for the appropriate time,
gently remove the orchid pot and place
it in a spot with soft sunlight. Gentle
light will help the plant
photosynthesize effectively, support
nutrient absorption, and promote overall
growth.
[Music]
You can absolutely use the remaining
solution to spray on other orchid pots
in your garden.
This is a simple way to care for your
entire orchid garden naturally,
economically, and effectively.
However, be careful not to spray the
solution directly on the flowers. Doing
so may cause the petals to become
discolored or wilt faster, reducing the
natural beauty of the orchid blooms.
[Music]
And this is the result after 10 days of
caring for the plant with this natural
fertilizer.
As you can see, the leaves have become
much greener and shinier compared to
before. This is a sign that the plant is
absorbing nutrients well and growing
steadily.
[Music]
Even though it is a newly purchased
orchid recently repotted into a new pot,
you can already see new roots starting
to grow. This is a great sign that the
plant is adapting and growing well.
[Music]
And here is the orchid that had already
finished blooming. After some time of
being cared for with this natural
method, its leaves have now turned green
and glossy again, showing that the plant
is recovering very well.
[Music]
Many new roots have grown, thick, plump,
and healthy. This is a wonderful sign
that the plant is absorbing nutrients
well and is ready for its next growth
cycle.
[Music]
These new roots will help the orchid
anchor firmly into the growing medium,
absorb water and nutrients more
efficiently, and thereby promote the
orchid's overall growth and development.
[Music]
What do you think about the way I
revived these orchids? Feel free to
leave a comment and share your thoughts.
I'd love to hear your feedback and learn
about your own experiences.
[Music]
Take care of your orchid pots with all
the love and gentleness in your heart.
When you nurture nature with sincere
affection, it will always return the
most wonderful things to you.
Every drop of water, every moment you
spend caring is a small gift that brings
life, radiant blooms, and endless joy to
your garden.
Thank you for watching. Wishing you a
joyful day full of energy and
overflowing with love from your little
garden. Goodbye and see you in the next
video.
[Music]