Hello everyone. Today I continue to
share with you how to help orchid pots
that have unfortunately rotted recover,
grow back strongly, and bloom again soon
using only familiar ingredients
available in every household.
Uh during the process of growing
orchids, sometimes we will encounter
leaf rot, a fairly common phenomenon
caused by various reasons.
[Music]
Just like this orchid pot of mine, the
leaf rot is spreading very quickly. If
not treated in time, the disease can
attack the entire plant and cause the
orchid to weaken or even die in just a
few days.
Um, the main cause of soft rot in
orchids is fungi and bacteria attacking
the roots, stems, or leaves. Usually
when the plant is water logged, has poor
drainage or is exposed to high humidity
for a prolonged period.
Uh, one of the indirect causes of soft
rot disease in orchids is insects that
pierce or chew, creating open wounds on
the plant.
Oh, here you can see a slimy snail
crawling on an orchid flower. Therefore,
the cause of orchid rot can be insects
chewing and creating open wounds.
These wounds are the gateway for fungi
and bacteria to easily enter, especially
in humid conditions or when the plant is
not kept clean.
[Music]
Next, we need to check the roots and the
growing medium to see if they are
excessively wet or water logged.
You can see that the growing medium is
holding too much water causing water
logging. This is also one of the common
causes of soft rot in orchids.
[Music]
We need to completely remove the old
growing medium as it can be a place
where pathogens accumulate and retain
excessive moisture making the orchid
roots more vulnerable.
[Music]
When the pot is not changed for a long
time, the growing medium can decay or
have poor drainage, easily retaining
water and creating conditions for
bacteria to grow, leading to soft rot in
orchids.
[Music]
An excessively wet growing medium, high
humidity, and stagnant air create an
ideal environment for fungal diseases.
[Music]
When the growing medium decays and
retains too much water, but you continue
to water frequently, it keeps the medium
constantly wet, suffocates the roots,
prevents respiration, and creates
favorable conditions for bacteria to
thrive.
[Music]
I recommend addressing the water logging
issue by watering only when the growing
medium is dry and at the same time
ensuring that the pot has excellent
drainage.
[Music]
After completely removing the old
growing medium, we continue by cutting
off all the damaged roots to prevent the
disease from spreading and to help the
plant recover better.
[Music]
Damaged and old roots usually lose their
ability to absorb water and nutrients.
If kept, they are not helpful and may
even cause rot to spread to healthy
roots. Removing them helps the plant
focus on nurturing stronger new roots.
[Music]
Damaged roots are often vulnerable to
attacks by bacteria and fungi. If not
removed in time, pathogens can spread to
the healthy parts of the roots and stem,
causing soft rot or other serious
diseases.
When we cut off old and dead roots, the
plant naturally responds by pushing out
new roots, helping it recover faster,
grow better, and prepare for the next
blooming season.
[Music]
Oh, I just discovered a rot spot still
on the leaf base. So, I need to remove
this leaf immediately to prevent the
disease from spreading to the rest of
the plant.
I rinse the orchid affected by soft rot
under running water to completely remove
the remaining growing medium and any
leftover pathogens.
[Music]
Uh after rinsing thoroughly, we let the
orchid dry completely before proceeding
with the next treatment steps.
Next, prepare 5 L of room temperature
water and pour it into a clean
container.
Next, you need to prepare a methylene
blue solution, a mild antiseptic that
helps protect the orchid from harmful
bacteria and fungi.
We only need to add about 10 drops of
methylene blue to create a gentle
antiseptic solution for the orchid.
Then stir the solution well to
completely dissolve the methylene blue
in the water.
Step one, soak the orchid roots in this
solution for about 10 minutes to
disinfect and thoroughly clean them.
[Music]
Step two, use this same solution to
clean the wounds on the stem and leaves
of the orchid, helping to disinfect and
prevent the spread of disease.
[Music]
Step three, soak a soft cloth in the
solution. Then gently wipe both the
upper and lower surfaces of the leaves
to clean and disinfect them.
[Music]
Wiping the leaves with a methylene blue
solution effectively disinfects small
wounds on the leaves. This prevents
harmful bacteria and fungi from entering
and spreading, especially in humid
conditions.
Additionally, cleaning the surface of
the leaves helps remove dust and
bacteria clinging to them, thereby
improving photosynthesis and helping the
orchid recover more quickly.
[Music]
After soaking for about 10 minutes, take
the orchid out and replant it in a new
pot with fresh, clean, and well-
draining growing medium.
[Music]
The growing medium I use for replanting
is crushed pine bark, which has been
soaked for sterilization and completely
dried, ensuring it's free of pathogens
and provides good drainage.
[Music]
Um, the orchid pot I use has drainage
holes at the bottom which help prevent
water logging and protect the roots from
rotting.
[Music]
Step four. After replanting, use the
methylene blue solution again to
thoroughly soak the growing medium.
[Music]
This helps disinfect the entire
environment around the roots and reduces
the risk of reinfection.
[Music]
Step five, sprinkle cinnamon powder
directly onto the wounds on the orchid.
Cinnamon powder has natural
antibacterial properties that help dry
out wounds and prevent harmful bacteria
and fungi from entering.
Let me know in the comments which
country you're watching from.
It's wonderful that we can connect and
chat from all around the world.
If you haven't subscribed yet, please
hit the subscribe button to support me
and never miss any orchid care tips.
It's truly wonderful to have you along
on this journey.
After finishing the treatment, you
should place the orchid pot in a cool,
wellventilated area with gentle light,
avoid direct rain, and do not water it
for 1 week. This helps the plant
stabilize, reduces the risk of
infection, and creates ideal conditions
for the wounds to heal faster.
[Music]
After one week without watering, once
the wounds have dried and the roots
begin to stabilize, we can start caring
for the orchid with a liquid fertilizer
to stimulate root and leaf growth again.
[Music]
Step five, take care of the orchid using
liquid fertilizer.
[Music]
I take one teaspoon of wheat flour and
mix it with one liter of room
temperature water. This mixture will
provide a gentle source of nutrients,
helping the orchid roots grow healthier.
[Music]
After mixing, you need to filter out the
residue to obtain a clear solution,
which helps the plant absorb it more
easily and prevents the growing medium
from getting dirty.
Um, pour the filtered solution into a
spray bottle, getting it ready to gently
and effectively care for your orchid.
[Music]
Spray the solution evenly over the
entire orchid, including the leaves,
stem, and roots, so the plant can absorb
the nutrients optimally.
[Music]
Then use this liquid fertilizer mixture
to water the roots and the growing
medium directly, nourishing the plant
from below and helping the roots absorb
nutrients more effectively.
[Music]
And remember to wipe off any water
remaining on the leaf surface and
between the leaf joints to prevent
creating conditions for bacteria and
fungi to grow.
You should care for your orchid using
the natural fertilizers I've shared on
the channel once every 2 weeks to help
the plant stay healthy and grow
sustainably.
Natural fertilization for orchids should
be done in the morning before the sun
becomes too intense to help the plant
absorb nutrients more easily and avoid
heat stress.
And place the orchid pot in a spot with
gentle sunlight and good air circulation
so the plant can recover and grow
better.
[Music]
And here is the result after 45 days of
recovery using a gentle and safe natural
fertilizing method for the rotted
orchid.
[Music]
You can see that the root system has
grown vigorously strong and full of
vitality. A very positive sign of
recovery.
[Music]
Because the orchid lost its crown, you
can see that from a node on the stem, it
has sprouted a new kei, a sign that its
vitality is strong again.
[Music]
The baby orchid is still small, but its
leaves are already firm and healthy, a
promising sign of recovery.
[Music]
After a period of care and recovery, you
can see that the leaves of the mother
orchid have become much glossier and
firmer than before.
[Music]
And it is these new roots that will help
the plant absorb nutrients more
efficiently, creating a strong
foundation for the development of new
leaves, shoots, and the next blooming
cycle.
What do you think about the way I
revived this rotting orchid?
Don't hesitate to leave a comment and
share your thoughts. I'd love to hear
your feedback and experiences.
With just simple ingredients available
at home and a little patience, you can
completely revive your orchid at home
with ease and lots of love.
Every orchid that someone threw away, I
picked up and patiently revived. One by
one, one by one. Gradually, through time
and the love I have for orchids, I've
created a whole garden filled with
vibrant, thriving orchid blooms.
[Music]
If you find the content helpful and
meaningful, don't forget to like, share
so more people can see it, and subscribe
to support my channel. Thank you for
always being with