Welcome to the happiness garden where
every petal tells a little story of love
and patience.
Today I want to share with you a simple
yet truly magical secret. Feed your
orchid this way and you'll witness
something wonderful. Your plant will
bloom more beautifully than ever before.
You don't need expensive fertilizers or
complicated methods. With just a little
care and the right approach, your orchid
will thrive with vitality, grow strong,
and burst into blossoms that melt your
heart.
[Music]
This is an orchid that has finished
blooming, but don't worry, its beauty
hasn't ended yet. Right now, I'm going
to share with you a special way to care
for it, so the plant can continue to
grow strong and soon bloom again with
vibrant, radiant flowers, just like its
first time. Here
you can see a leaf that has turned
yellow. The cause might be snails or
small insects biting the leaf, which
damages the plant and makes it more
susceptible to bacterial infection,
leading to leaf rot. In this case, we
need to gently cut off the rotten part
of the leaf to prevent the disease from
spreading and to help the plant recover
more quickly.
When checking the growing medium, I
found that the roots are still healthy
and firmly attached.
The substrate is still loose and clean,
so there's no need to replace it right
now.
It's important to only repot when the
roots show signs of rot or the medium
has decomposed. Otherwise, let the plant
continue growing naturally.
[Music]
The first ingredient I need to care for
the leaves is a lime. Of course, if you
have a lemon instead, you can use it,
too. Both work equally well.
[Music]
Squeeze about 1 teaspoon of fresh lime
juice. This tiny amount of liquid works
wonders. It helps clean the surface of
the leaves, removing dust and bacteria
that cling to them.
[Music]
Uh after getting the lime juice, I'll
add about 100 ml of clean water to
dilute it.
[Music]
And the next ingredient I need is
coconut oil. Just add about three small
drops into the mixture. Then stir well
so all the ingredients blend together.
Coconut oil helps make the orchid leaves
shinier while forming a natural
protective layer that keeps them
moisturized and healthy for longer.
[Music]
After stirring the mixture well, use a
soft cloth to gently soak up the diluted
lime and coconut oil solution.
Then carefully wipe both the top and
underside of the leaves to remove dust
and let the nutrients absorb evenly.
Just take your time and do it gently.
You'll soon notice your orchid's leaves
becoming shinier and healthier day by
day.
When wiping the leaves with the lime and
coconut oil mixture, the layer of dust
on the surface will be removed. This
allows the leaves to breathe better and
enhances photosynthesis, contributing to
the overall nourishment of the plant.
[Music]
The combination of lime and coconut oil
creates a light glossy layer on the
leaves, making the orchid look fresh and
full of vitality. With shiny, healthy
leaves, the plant appears well cared
for. And the natural beauty of the
orchid stands out even more.
[Music]
Lime juice has mild antibacterial
properties, helping to limit the growth
of bacteria and fungi on the leaves.
Combined with coconut oil, the leaves
are better protected, reducing the risk
of rot disease spreading and keeping the
plant healthy for a long time.
[Music]
Coconut oil forms a thin moisture
retaining layer on the leaves,
preventing water from evaporating too
quickly. This is especially helpful in
dry air, keeping the orchid leaves soft,
smooth, and healthy.
[Music]
When the leaves are healthy, shiny, and
clean, the plant can focus its energy on
blooming. This helps the buds and
flowers develop evenly and last longer,
producing vibrant, lively blooms, just
as you hope.
[Music]
Next, once a month, give each orchid pot
a thorough watering.
Thorough watering helps moisten the
roots and the growing medium, making it
easier for the plant to absorb water. At
the same time, uh, the water washes away
excess mineral salts in the substrate,
preventing harmful buildup around the
roots and keeping the growing
environment clean and healthy.
After thoroughly watering, let the water
naturally soak in for about 20 minutes.
This time allows the roots to absorb
enough moisture and nutrients while
letting the growing medium balance its
moisture without becoming water logged.
[Music]
After letting the water soak in, take
the orchid pot out to drain.
Leave it like this for about an hour,
allowing the substrate and roots to dry
just enough, not too wet, not too dry.
Only after this time should you
fertilize the roots, helping the plant
absorb nutrients efficiently and
avoiding water shock.
Uh to make a fertilizer that stimulates
blooming, I usually use banana peels
when eating bananas. Banana peels are
not only rich in potassium and essential
minerals, but also help the orchid
develop buds and flowers evenly, lasting
longer.
First, wash the banana peel thoroughly
to remove any dirt and bacteria. This
ensures that when making the fertilizer,
the orchid receives nutrients safely and
effectively.
Let me know in the comments which
country you're watching from. It's
wonderful that we can connect and share
with each other from all around the
world.
And if you haven't subscribed yet, click
the subscribe button to support me and
make sure you don't miss any orchid care
tips.
It's wonderful to have you along on this
journey.
[Music]
Next, cut the banana peel into small
pieces and put them into a clean jar to
prepare for soaking. Chopping the peel
helps the nutrients dissolve into the
water more easily, creating a natural,
nutrient-rich fertilizer for the orchid.
Uh the final ingredient for the roots is
rice. Rice not only provides energy but
also helps stimulate the orchid roots to
grow strong, firm, and healthy.
Add about 3 teaspoons of rice into the
jar with the chopped banana peel.
[Music]
After adding the rice to the jar, pour
in about one liter of clean water. The
water helps dissolve the nutrients from
the banana peel and rice, creating a
natural energy richch fertilizer for
your orchid.
After stirring the mixture well, cover
the jar and let it sit for about 1 to
two hours. This soaking process allows
the nutrients from the banana peel and
rice to fully blend into the water,
creating an energy richch solution ready
to nourish the orchid roots and promote
healthy growth.
[Music]
After soaking for about 2 hours, stir
the mixture once more. Then strain out
the solids.
[Music]
This step makes the solution clear and
easy to use while ensuring the nutrients
are fully dissolved and ready to nourish
the orchid roots effectively.
With just a few simple steps, you now
have a natural nutrient-rich fertilizer
that supports healthy roots and overall
plant growth.
[Music]
Once the solution is ready, pour the
mixture directly onto the roots and
growing medium twice a month.
[Music]
Uh the mixture of rice and banana peel
provides essential nutrients helping the
orchid roots grow long, firm, and
healthy. Healthy roots absorb water and
nutrients more efficiently, creating a
solid foundation for overall plant
growth.
As the roots absorb nutrients from this
mixture, the orchid leaves become lush
and glossy. Healthy leaves are not only
visually appealing, but also ensure good
photosynthesis, supplying energy for the
entire plant and its flowers.
The nutrients from rice and banana peel
help the plant form buds evenly and
firmly, reducing the risk of early bud
drop. The plant has enough energy to
develop uniform buds, preparing for
vibrant, healthy blooms.
Or you can also pour this mixture into a
spray bottle. This allows you to spray
evenly onto the roots and growing medium
while easily controlling the amount of
fertilizer to avoid excess.
Using a spray bottle is also convenient
for smaller orchid pots, helping the
nutrients penetrate evenly and be
absorbed more effectively by the roots.
[Music]
When using a spray bottle, spray evenly
on both the top and underside of the
leaves while lightly misting the stems
and growing medium as well.
[Music]
This approach helps the nutrients reach
the entire plant, nourishing the roots
while also caring for the leaves and
stems, setting the stage for strong
growth and spectacular blooms.
[Music]
After watering or spraying the solution,
you can also soak the orchid pot in the
fertilizer mixture for about 20 minutes.
Soaking allows the roots and growing
medium to absorb nutrients more deeply,
enhancing the overall nourishment of the
entire plant.
[Music]
After soaking, take the orchid pot out
of the mixture. If water remains on the
leaves, gently blot it with a soft cloth
to remove all moisture, preventing leaf
rot or fungal infections.
[Music]
After wiping and draining, place the
orchid pot in a spot with gentle
sunlight. Soft light helps the plant
photosynthesize effectively, keeping the
leaves lush and green and the roots
strong while also preparing the plant
for blooming. Remember, no matter how
good the fertilizer is, without enough
light, the plant will struggle to bloom.
Sufficient sunlight ensures vibrant,
beautiful flowers.
[Music]
And here are the results after one month
of care.
You can see that the orchid leaves have
become shinier and firmer than before,
indicating that the plant has absorbed
nutrients well and is growing healthily.
[Music]
And the special thing is you can see the
orchid has produced two very healthy new
shoots. These young shoots are a clear
sign that the plant is growing
vigorously from roots to leaves,
preparing for vibrant blooms in the near
future. It's wonderful to see the plant
revived and full of life after just one
month of proper care.
In addition, the roots have grown strong
and have gradually become much denser
than before. These new roots not only
help the plant absorb water and
nutrients more efficiently, but also
provide a solid foundation for overall
growth.
[Music]
Next, I will continue caring for the
plant using natural fertilizer made from
rice and banana.
[Music]
Water the base or spray the mixture over
the entire plant every 2 weeks. This
regular care ensures the roots, leaves,
and stems receive enough nutrients while
stimulating strong growth and preparing
the plant for new buds. By maintaining
this routine, the plant will stay lush
and green, the roots strong, and the
buds will bloom evenly and vibrantly.
You can also care for your orchid with
other natural fertilizers alternately.
Rotating different types of fertilizer
helps the plant absorb a variety of
nutrients while stimulating balanced
healthy growth of roots, leaves, and
flowers.
[Music]
And here are the results after 2 months
of care.
You can see that from a flowerless
orchid, the plant is now blooming
brilliantly with lush green leaves,
strong roots, and vigorous new shoots.
It's wonderful to witness the orchid's
revival, proving that proper care with
natural fertilizers supports overall
growth and consistent flowering.
Remember, caring for an orchid isn't
just about watering or fertilizing. It's
also about love, patience, and observing
every little detail. Every step you
take, from wiping the leaves and
watering the roots to applying natural
fertilizer, contributes to bringing
vitality and vibrant beauty to the
plant.
If you are persistent, day by day, you
will witness the plant grow from young
shoots to blooming flowers. And you
yourself have created that miracle. Care
for the plant with all your love, and
each vibrant bloom will be a sweet
reward for your patience.
[Music]
This brings our video to an end. I hope
these tips will be very helpful for you
in caring for your orchids at home using
natural fertilizers. If you found this
video meaningful, don't forget to like,
share so more people can see it, and
subscribe to support me. Thank you for
watching and see you in the next orchid
care videos.
[Music]