Welcome to the happiness garden. Today I
continue to share with you a method of
propagating orchids from spent flower
spikes, making the most of every part of
the plant. In this way, it not only
helps the mother plant continue to grow,
but also opens up the opportunity to
create healthy new orchid plants.
When the petals begin to fade, that is
the best time to cut the flower spike
for propagation. If cut too early, the
young spike is prone to rot and hard to
recover. While if left too old, the
chances of sprouting will decrease
significantly.
The flower nodes that have bloomed will
no longer have the ability to sprout
into new orchid plants, so we will
remove them.
[Music]
The nodes that have not bloomed yet like
this are the parts we can take advantage
of to propagate from the flower spike.
This is where new life is hidden with
the potential to grow into healthy young
orchid plants.
After cutting, use a very sharp knife to
trim again uh making the cut smoother
and removing the damaged tip. This is
very important because damaged tips are
prone to rot, affecting the ability to
propagate. A clean cut will help the
flower spike heal quickly and reduce the
risk of infection, creating the best
conditions for new shoots to grow.
[Music]
Next, gently peel off the outer
protective layer to wake up the dormant
bud. This step helps the bud come into
contact with air and light, creating
favorable conditions for it to start
growing.
Be very careful not to damage the bud
inside because this is where new life
will begin.
[Music]
Leave me a comment letting me know which
country you are watching from. It's
wonderful that we can connect and chat
with each other from all around the
world.
And if you haven't subscribed yet, click
the subscribe button to support me and
not miss any orchid care tips. It's
wonderful to have you along.
[Music]
Now I will prepare a natural fertilizer
to support the propagation process to go
better.
The first ingredient I choose is ginger.
A familiar spice but with amazing
effects in stimulating bud growth.
Take a small piece of ginger, then slice
it into very thin pieces. Slicing thinly
will help the nutrients in the ginger
dissolve more easily into the water,
bringing better results when used to
care for the flower spike.
[Music]
After slicing, put the ginger slices
into a very clean container. Uh, using a
clean container helps keep the solution
pure and prevents bacteria or mold from
harming the flower spike.
[Music]
Um, the next ingredient I choose is
rice. Just about 3 teaspoons of rice is
enough. Rice is a wonderful natural
source of nutrients for the plant,
containing many vitamins and minerals
that help stimulate the growth of roots
and young shoots. When combined with
ginger, they create a solution that is
both mildly antibacterial and provides
energy to help the buds sprout more
strongly.
Now, pour one liter of clean water into
the prepared ginger and rice.
Stir the mixture well, then cover it and
let it sit for 20 minutes. The soaking
time will help the nutrients from the
ginger and rice completely dissolve into
the water, creating a natural,
nutrient-rich solution. This is an
important step to obtain a mixture that
is both mildly antibacterial and
stimulates the buds and roots to grow
stronger.
Next, take 400 ml of clean water and
pour it into a cup. This will be the
water used to mix the medium
disinfecting solution, helping to
eliminate harmful bacteria and fungi
before replanting.
Then add about 3 to four drops of
methylene blue. This is a mild
disinfectant that helps eliminate any
remaining bacteria and mold in the
growing medium.
Next, I put the dried moss growing
medium into the prepared solution and
soak it for about 20 minutes. This
soaking time will help the moss be
completely disinfected, removing
pathogens and harmful bacteria. At the
same time, the moss will absorb enough
moisture, creating an ideal environment
for the flower spike when replanting.
While waiting for the moss to finish
soaking, I reuse plastic cups to recycle
them into tools for sprouting baby
orchids from the flower spike. This
recycling not only saves costs but is
also environmentally friendly. The small
cups will create a humid and warm
environment which is very suitable for
young shoots to grow.
[Music]
after soaking for about 20 minutes, stir
the mixture once more. This step helps
the nutrients in the ginger and rice
fully dissolve, creating a uniform and
nutrient-rich solution. This is when the
solution is ready for you to strain out
the clear liquid and use it for
propagation.
[Music]
After straining, pour the clear liquid
into a clean cup and soak the flower
spike for about 20 minutes. This soaking
time will help the spike absorb enough
nutrients, wake up the dormant buds, and
stimulate them to start growing. This is
an important step to lay the foundation
for healthy baby orchids to form from
the spent flower spike.
[Music]
The remaining solution can be used to
water the roots and growing medium of
the mother orchid. This will provide
extra nutrients, help the roots grow
strong, and stimulate the plant to form
new flower spikes. This is a simple yet
effective way to help the mother plant
recover quickly, and soon bring another
beautiful blooming season.
This yellow leaf will be cut off to help
the orchid focus its nutrients on
feeding the roots, new leaves, and new
flower buds. Removing old leaves helps
the plant stay healthier, reduces the
risk of pests and diseases, and creates
favorable conditions for new growth.
This is a small but important step to
keep the plant lush and ready for the
next blooming season.
Then take a little cinnamon powder and
gently sprinkle it on the sprit on the
cut on the flower spike. The cinnamon
powder will act as a natural
disinfectant, preventing bacteria and
fungi from entering and helping the cut
dry quickly.
[Music]
After soaking for 20 minutes, take out
the moss. Gently squeeze it until it is
just moist and then let it drain.
[Music]
Next, put the moss into the prepared
propagation container, forming a loose
and clean base layer. This is an
important step to create an ideal humid
environment, helping the flower spike
easily grow roots and the young shoots
develop healthily.
[Music]
After soaking for 20 minutes, remember
to gently ly take out the flower spike
and dry its surface. This helps remove
excess moisture, preventing the spike
from rotting when placed in the growing
medium.
[Music]
Then take a little cinnamon powder and
gently sprinkle it on the cut of the
flower spike. The cinnamon powder will
act as a natural disinfectant,
preventing bacteria and fungi from
entering and helping the cut dry
quickly. This is a simple yet effective
way to protect the flower spike,
creating a safe environment for the new
buds to grow.
Next, carefully place the flower spike
into the prepared propagation container.
Make sure the spike is gently secured on
the loose moss layer so the buds can
have good contact with the medium.
Arranging it carefully will help the
spike stay stable and create favorable
conditions for the roots and young
shoots to grow strongly.
[Music]
Then pour water into the glass cup just
enough to touch the growing medium
slightly. Be careful not to let the
water cover the medium too much. Similar
to semihydroponic orchid planting, this
method allows the spike roots to get
enough moisture without rotting,
creating an ideal environment for the
young shoots to grow healthily.
[Music]
Then, Place the cup in a well ventilated
area with gentle sunlight. This
condition helps the flower spike
maintain moderate moisture and receive
enough light for the buds to grow. A
balanced environment of light and air
will provide the best conditions for
healthy roots and young shoots to form.
[Music]
And here's the result after 2 months of
propagation.
[Music]
You can see that from a single
repurposed flower spike, it is now grown
into a young orchid with two small
leaves and new roots beginning to
emerge. This is proof that utilizing
spent flower spikes not only saves
resources but also produces healthy
orchids ready to grow and bloom in the
future.
[Music]
We need to change the water regularly
once a week to ensure the environment in
the cup stays clean.
Fresh water helps remove harmful
bacteria and fungi while providing fresh
nutrients for the roots and young orchid
buds.
Maintaining clean water is an important
factor for the healthy growth of the
young plants and preventing root rot.
[Music]
Then continue to place the cup in a well
ventilated area with gentle sunlight for
propagation.
Now let's take a look at the mother
orchid to see how it has recovered.
You can see that the mother orchid has
started to grow a new flower spike,
showing that the plant is regaining
health and energy after our care.
[Music]
In addition, the old flower spike that
was kept has also started to grow new
buds at the top. This shows that even
parts of the spike that seemed spent can
still continue to nourish and bloom.
This is clear evidence of the
effectiveness of proper care and making
full use of every part of the orchid.
[Music]
And here is the result after 3 months of
propagation.
[Music]
You can see that the young orchid has
grown very well with sturdy glossy green
leaves and a dense healthy root system.
This is clear evidence that utilizing
the flower spike and providing proper
care can produce healthy young orchids.
[Music]
At the leaf axle, a small flower has
also started to bloom. This is a rather
rare phenomenon, usually occurring when
we place the propagation cup in a spot
with plenty of sunlight.
Adequate light stimulates the buds to
form flowers, bringing a pleasant
surprise during the propagation process.
[Music]
But before planting the young orchid
into a new pot, we need to remove the
flower. This allows the plant to focus
all its nutrients on the roots and new
leaves, creating the best conditions for
the young orchid to grow healthily.
[Music]
What do you think about my method of
propagating orchids using the flower
spike? Don't hesitate to leave a comment
and share your thoughts. I'm very eager
to hear your feedback, experiences, and
tips on caring for and propagating
orchids.
[Music]
When planting, gently place the young
orchid into the pot and carefully fill
the medium around it. Be careful not to
damage the tips of the young roots, as
this is the part that helps the plant
absorb water and nutrients. Handling it
gently will ensure the young orchid
stays stable and grows healthily in its
new environment.
[Music]
I hope this video will bring you a lot
of useful knowledge for for pro
propagating orchids right at home. With
these simple yet effective steps, you
can fully utilize the flower spike to
create healthy young orchids. Be
patient, observe, and care for each
young chute so that your garden remains
lush and full of life.
[Music]
If you find this video helpful and
meaningful, please like and share it so
so more people can learn how to care for
and propagate orchids at home. This
small action also gives me more
motivation to continue sharing natural
and effective orchid care tips. Thank
you so much for accompanying me and
caring for my little garden.
As long as you patiently follow each
step I have guided gradually, you will
have an orchid garden blooming
brilliantly like mine. Every small step
contributes to the plant's vitality and
the final result will truly satisfy you.
Care for and love each orchid pot so
that your garden is always full of
colorful blooms and life.
[Music]
This brings the video to an end. Thank
you for watching and accompanying me on
the journey of caring for and
propagating orchids. I hope the tips
shared in this video will give you more
knowledge and joy in your own garden.