Hello everyone. I'm very happy to
welcome you to the channel today. I hope
the sharing here will inspire you.
Today I will share a method to help
orchids quickly recover when affected by
soft rot caused by insects or harmful
fungi.
With just simple ingredients readily
available in every household kitchen, we
can easily revive and help a rotting
orchid quickly grow back. and then the
flowers will bloom brightly again,
continuing to shine in your beautiful
garden.
Let's get started.
Um, for orchids that have rotted like
this, don't rush to throw them away.
You can see this orchid is suffering
from soft rot, which may be caused by
insect bites followed by fungal
infection, or it could also be due to
the environment, making the orchid prone
to disease.
[Music]
Soft rot develops very quickly in hot
and humid climates. If not treated
promptly, the disease can spread widely
and cause the orchid to rot completely.
We need to quickly separate the orchid
with soft rot from the garden and
immediately remove the rotted part to
prevent the disease from spreading.
[Music]
After that, we need to check the roots
and the growing medium to see if they
are still airy and clean so the plant
has better conditions to recover.
When checking, I see the growing medium
is still clean and airy, so there is no
need to replace it immediately.
[Music]
You can see that many roots are still
healthy and growing well, giving the
plant a better chance to recover faster.
You can trim the old and weak roots to
help the plant focus nutrients on the
healthier roots.
[Music]
Having many healthy roots will help the
orchid recover quickly after soft rot.
[Music]
You can see this orchid is being
attacked by insects, leaving wounds on
the leaves.
[Music]
We need to remove the insects
immediately because they are one of the
main causes of soft rot disease on
orchids.
Insect bites on the leaves combined with
hot and humid weather create favorable
conditions for fungal infections to
invade, causing soft rot on the orchid.
And now we will make natural fertilizer
together to help the orchid recover
faster.
The first ingredient I choose to make
natural fertilizer is garlic because
garlic has strong antibacterial and
antifungal properties helping protect
the orchid from harmful agents.
Take two cloves of garlic and slice them
thinly to easily release the
antibacterial essences when soaking the
fertilizer.
[Music]
Is there a lot of garlic where you live?
I'd love to know. Please leave a comment
for me.
Please comment to let me know which
country you are watching the video from.
It's
wonderful that we can chat together from
all around the world.
After putting the sliced garlic into a
jar, pour one liter of room temperature
water to soak.
Cover the jar and let it sit for a few
hours so the essences from the garlic
can fully release.
[Music]
After 2 hours, stir well so the essences
in the garlic blend thoroughly into the
fertilizer water.
[Music]
Then strain out the residue to collect
the clear garlic water ready to be used
as fertilizer for the orchid.
[Music]
To help the orchid recover quickly, I
add vitamin B1 because it stimulates
root growth and increases the plant's
resistance.
Add three vitamin B1 tablets to enhance
root stimulation and help the orchid
recover faster.
If you haven't subscribed to the channel
yet, please click the subscribe button
to support me and not miss any orchid
growing tips. It's wonderful to have you
along for the journey.
Then pour this liquid fertilizer mixture
into a spray bottle to easily mist onto
the orchid.
[Music]
And spray thoroughly over all the orchid
leaves, especially the damaged areas, so
the fertilizer can deeply penetrate and
be effective.
[Music]
The pressure from the spray bottle helps
push away the decayed patches from the
orchid, keeping the plant cleaner and
making it easier to absorb nutrients for
faster recovery.
[Music]
Then pour this liquid fertilizer mixture
into the pot to soak the orchid roots
and growing medium, helping disinfect
while directly providing nutrients.
promoting healthier root growth.
Soak for about 20 minutes to allow the
nutrients to deeply penetrate the roots,
stimulate root growth, and increase the
orchid's resistance.
[Music]
Next, we need to treat the orchid with
fresh insect bites on the leaves to
prevent fungal infection and protect the
plant from the risk of soft rot.
[Music]
Um, you need to cut off old flower
spikes or damaged roots, if any, to help
the orchid focus its energy on recovery
and strengthen its resistance against
diseases.
[Music]
Then spray this liquid fertilizer
mixture over the entire orchid,
especially on the insect bite marks to
disinfect, prevent fungal infections,
and support faster healing.
[Music]
This orchid, after being bitten by
insects and exposed to hot and humid
weather conditions, became infected with
fungus, causing the young leaves to rot.
[Music]
Because insects often prefer to eat
young leaves, the young leaves are also
more easily damaged and suffer soft rot
compared to older leaves.
Quickly separate the orchid from the
garden and immediately remove the rotted
parts to prevent the disease from
spreading to other plants.
Then spray the liquid fertilizer mixture
directly onto the soft rot area. The
water pressure helps push away buildup
and harmful bacteria from the plant,
supporting faster recovery.
Then spray evenly over all the other
parts of the orchid to provide
comprehensive protection, prevent fungal
infections from spreading, and help the
plant become healthier.
[Music]
After spraying, gently wipe the water
droplets on the leaves with a soft
cloth, especially in the leaf crevices
to prevent vent prolonged moisture that
can cause fungal diseases.
[Music]
Garlic contains natural essential oils
that repel insects. So when sprayed,
insects hiding under the growing medium
or in leaf crevices will automatically
come out, making it easier for us to
detect and remove them.
[Music]
After wiping off the water droplets on
the leaves, place the orchid pot in a
spot with gentle sunlight to help the
plant photosynthesize better and enhance
its recovery.
[Music]
Uh, you should choose pots with good
drainage holes or create additional
drainage holes for the orchid pot,
helping water not to accumulate,
preventing root rot, and keeping the
plant healthy.
[Music]
After soaking for 20 minutes, take the
orchid out and replant it into a new,
more ventilated pot to help the roots
grow better.
With moss as the growing medium that
retains moisture well, uh you should
only water again after 2 to 3 weeks or
when you see the medium starting to dry
to avoid root rot.
If your orchid is planted in a well-
draining medium such as pine bark or
pummus, you should base your watering
schedule on the moisture level of the
medium to avoid overwatering that can
cause root rot.
And here is the result. After 1 month of
recovery, the orchid has visibly revived
with larger new leaves and the rot spots
have dried up.
[Music]
You can see that the rot spots on the
orchid have completely dried, proving
that this natural fertilizer is very
effective in treating soft rot disease.
[Music]
And you can also see the new roots
growing vigorously, which proves that
the orchid is recovering well and
absorbing nutrients effectively.
Thank you.
[Music]
Uh, these new roots help the orchid
increase its ability to absorb water and
nutrients, thereby promoting overall
growth and enhancing the plant's
resistance.
How do you find my method for reviving
weak orchids? Please write your feedback
and suggestions in the comments to let
me know.
[Music]
Every time you revive an orchid, little
by little over the years, you will
gradually have a vibrant garden filled
with colorful orchid blooms, bringing
joy and peace to your soul.
[Music]
If you encounter any difficulties in the
orchid growing process, don't hesitate
to comment for me. I am always ready to
support you so that you can grow healthy
orchids that bloom abundantly.
I hope you will like this video. If you
find it useful, don't forget to hit like
and subscribe to the channel so you
won't miss the next shares about how to
care for orchids naturally and simply.
I always pray that God blesses everyone
with many blessings and peace.