welcome to my
[Music]
Channel today I will share an easy and
quick way to propagate orchids from
flower spikes helping you propagate
orchids at home
effortlessly let's get
[Music]
started this orchid has just finished
blooming now I will cut this flower
Spike to start propagating the Orchid
the best time to propagate orchids is
when the petals start to
[Music]
fade the nodes that have already bloomed
cannot be used for propagation so I will
cut this part
[Music]
off uh we can use the nodes that haven't
bloomed yet for orchid propagation
[Music]
I am removing the protective layer of
the dormant Bud uh to help it Sprout
faster
[Music]
please comment and let me know which
country you are watching from it's
amazing that we can connect from all
around the
[Music]
world in addition to the English dub
we've now created dubs in French German
Italian Spanish Portuguese Japanese
Hindi and Indonesian to make it easier
for you to hear and understand the
content enjoy the videos
[Music]
I cut it again so that the Orchid stem
is not
[Music]
crushed this diagonal cut increases
surface area allowing for better water
absorption when propagating from
[Music]
cuting for
then I apply cinnamon powder to the cut
to help it heal quickly and prevent
rotting
[Music]
I continue applying cinnamon powder here
to help the cut heal quickly
then I add 1 teaspoon of cinnamon powder
into a jar and mix it with 2 cups of hot
water about 0.5
[Music]
L cinnamon powder contains natural
minerals such as nitrogen phosphorus
potassium and calcium it also has anti
antibacterial and antiseptic properties
making it excellent for caring for and
propagating orchids from
cuttings after mixing we let it sit for
2 hours to allow the nutrients to
dissolve into the water and also to let
the water cool down before
applying then take an aloe vera leaf
which contains Sal iyc acid and and
enzymes that stimulate root formation
help helping the cuting develop new
Roots
[Music]
quickly insert the Orchid cutting into
the aloe vera leaf and wait for 1 hour
thanks to its antibacterial properties
aloe vera helps protect the cutting from
infections and harmful bacteria or
[Music]
fungi aloe vera contains essential
minerals and vitamins including calcium
magnesium zinc and vitamins a c and e
which support the Healthy Growth of
young
plants the compounds in aloe vera Help
The Cutting resist adverse and
environmental conditions increasing its
survival and growth
potential then wait for 1 hour to allow
the nutrients to absorb into the
cutting after 1 hour remove the Orchid
cutting from the aloe vera gel
[Music]
then slice the aloe vera leaf into
pieces and put them into the jar
[Music]
add four cups of hot water about 1 liter
cover the jar and wait for the water to
cool before
[Music]
using after the water cools mix the
cinnamon water and aloe vera water
together to create a nutrient-rich
solution
[Music]
the mixture of cinnamon water and aloe
vera water is a highly effective natural
method for propagating orchids from
[Music]
cuting aloe vera contains oxin and
salicylic acid which helps stimulate
root growth
[Music]
aloe vera provides essential vitamins a
c e and minerals calcium magnesium zinc
that help the cutting stay
healthy cinnamon contains cinnam alahh
which helps promote cell division making
Roots grow faster and
[Music]
stronger cinnamon is especially
effective in preventing mold and root
rot uh providing a clean environment for
The Cutting to grow
[Music]
n thanks to the bioactive compounds in
cinnamon and aloe vera the plant will
have better resistance to environmental
stress and harmful insects
[Music]
soak the Orchid cutting in this mixture
for 20
[Music]
minutes use the remaining mixture to
care for other orchids
[Music]
wiping orchid leaves with the cinnamon
and Alo Vera mixture provides many
benefits not only keeping the leaves
shiny but also enhancing the overall
health of the
[Music]
Orchid dust on the leaves can reduce the
plant's ability to absorb light wiping
the leaves with this mixture helps keep
them clean shiny and improves
photosynthesis
efficiency aloe vera gel provides
natural moisture preventing the leaves
from drying out or losing water too
quickly um especially use ful in dry
[Music]
weather the scent of cinnamon can help
repel certain pests especially
spidermites mbgs and other harmful
insects apply this method one to two
times per month to keep orchid leaves
healthy and shiny
[Music]
green then water each Orchid pot with
this
mixture aloe vera contains oxin and
salicylic acid which promote fast and
healthy root growth cinnamon stimulates
cell division helping Orchid Roots grow
longer and anchor firmly to the
[Music]
substrate to propagate orchids from
flower spikes I use dried Moss to
maintain optimal moisture
levels before propagation I soak the
dried moss in the cinnamon and aloe vera
mixture to sterilize the growing medium
[Music]
this is an important step to ensure the
Orchid cutting has a clean safe and
nutrient-rich environment for quick root
development we need to soak it for about
minutes then we take out the Moss to
propagate the Orchid
cutting for
[Music]
insert the Orchid cutting into the pot
ensuring the node is close to the
surface of the moist Moss to prevent rot
then cover the cover the top of the
orgid propagation pot with a transparent
plastic lid with a ventilation
hole spray water to maintain moisture in
the Orchid propagation pot once a week
[Music]
place the Orchid propagation pot in a
spot with gentle sunlight and a
temperature between 23 to 28° C 73 to
82° F which is the ideal condition for
the Orchid cutting to sprout
now let's take a look at the results
after 45 days of
propagation amazing you can see that the
orchid seedlings have sprouted and
developed healthy looking
roots for
[Music]
however the Orchid is still small so
I've decided to continue nurturing it in
the pot until it grows bigger before
transplanting continue misting once a
week and keep the nursery pot in a spot
with gentle sunlight
[Music]
now let's check the results after
another 45 days of
propagation you can see that after 90
days of propagation from the cutting the
orchid has grown strong with firm leaves
and healthy roots
[Music]
with this simple method you can
propagate orchids at home by reusing
flower spikes after the blooms have
faded
[Music]
if you find this content helpful and
meaningful don't forget to like share so
more people can learn and subscribe to
support me thank you for always being
with
[Music]
me now I am planting them in pots so
they can grow in an outdoor environment
[Music]
I using crushed pine bark because it
retains the necessary moisture to keep
the Orchid from drying out at the same
time it provides good drainage
preventing root rot or plant decay
[Music]
and after planting in the pot we spread
a thin layer of moss on top to maintain
proper humidity helping the you know
helping the Orchid adapt smoothly to its
new environment without stress
[Music]
um after planting we should water
regularly to maintain moisture whenever
the growing medium feels dry avoid
fertilizing until the new Roots have
firmly attached to the
substrate if you stay patient and
dedicated in nurturing them one day
you'll have a vibrant Garden where
orchids bloom beautifully just like
mine thank you for watching the video
wishing you good luck and endless joy in
life
it's