[Music]
Welcome to my channel.
If you have an orchid after blooming
like this,
[Music]
which country are you watching the video
from? Please leave a comment for me.
It's wonderful that we can chat with
each other from all around the world.
Cut off wilted flower stems.
[Music]
Uh this helps nutrients no longer
concentrate on wilted flower branches.
[Music]
and the rot from the flower stem will
not spread down the stem.
[Music]
Please comment to me which country you
are watching the video from. It's great
that we can chat together from all over
the world.
[Music]
Then remove all yellow leaves.
If you haven't subscribed to the channel
yet, please click the subscribe button
to support me and not miss any orchid
growing tips. It's great to have
company.
Uh, cut off rotten leaves so the rot
doesn't spread to other leaves.
[Music]
and this is is a weak orchid. Its leaves
wither.
Cut off wilted branches, yellow leaves,
and damaged roots.
[Music]
Then sprinkle cinnamon powder on the cut
to help it heal quickly.
[Music]
Cinnamon has antibacterial and
antiseptic properties that help cuts
prevent further rot and heal quickly.
[Music]
Um then leave it for one day without
watering to let the cut heal completely.
This is a potato including potato
sprouts.
[Music]
Potato sprouts contain a lot of oxin, a
plant growth stimulant.
This will stimulate weak orchids to grow
strongly, especially roots and shoots.
[Music]
Then peel and use the potato peels as
fertilizer for the orchids.
[Music]
Potato peels contain many vitamins and
minerals providing nutrients for plants.
[Music]
Cut the potato skin into small pieces.
Then put all the potato peels into a
glass jar.
[Music]
Add one liter of boiled water.
Then incubate for one day so that the
flower nutrients can completely dissolve
into the water.
One day later.
[Music]
Filter this potato juice.
Add one liter of water.
[Music]
Method one,
water your orchid with this water.
Potato sprouts and potato peels contain
some plant hormones such as oxin which
helps uh stimulate root growth.
[Music]
Water each orchid pot thoroughly.
Apply every two weeks.
[Music]
After watering for about 3 to 4 weeks,
the weak orchid will grow new roots.
Soaking the roots in this water for 20
minutes helps the roots absorb nutrients
better.
Method two,
[Music]
use this water to thoroughly wipe the
top and bottom of the leaves.
This helps remove dirt, insects, and
fungal diseases residing on the leaves
that harm the orchid.
create favorable conditions for orchids
to photosynthesize light to create
chlorophyll.
[Music]
Helps orchids grow and increase
resistance to fungal diseases.
[Music]
Thanks to that, your orchid leaves will
always be lush, green, and sturdy.
[Music]
This is a spider nest, so it needs to be
removed immediately from the orchid.
[Music]
If you encounter any difficulties during
the orchid growing process, Don't
hesitate to comment. I am always ready
to support you so you can grow healthy
orchids and bloom lots of flowers.
In addition to the English dub, we've
now created dubs in French, German,
Italian, Spanish, Portuguese, Japanese,
Hindi, and Indonesian to help you hear
and understand the content. Videos are
easier
to listen to the language. Open the
video and click settings gear icon to
select the appropriate audio language.
[Music]
Um, this is a meie bug species that
harms orchids. If cleaned regularly,
meie bugs will be eliminated.
[Music]
Fertilize one to two times a month to
protect orchids.
[Music]
And then you pour the remaining water
into the spray. spray bottle.
[Music]
Method three, spray this water on the
entire orchid.
Potato peels and potato sprouts
decompose and provide organic matter to
the soil, improving soil structure and
moisture.
[Music]
Certain compounds in potato sprouts help
fight fungi and bacteria, protecting
orchids from disease.
[Music]
Nutrients in potato sprouts help keep
leaves green and healthy, promoting
photosynthesis.
[Music]
helps improve soil structure, enhance
water holding capacity, helping orchid
leaves stay green and healthy.
[Music]
Do it twice a month and can combine with
other organic fertilizers as I shared.
[Music]
results after 3 weeks.
After only three weeks, this weak orchid
has developed a very strong root system.
[Music]
This orchid has greener and stronger
leaves.
[Music]
and grow many new roots.
This orchid's roots grow very large and
healthy.
[Music]
When the roots are strong, they will
absorb nutrients easily.
[Music]
And if you provide enough fertilizer as
I instruct and keep the orchid in
diffused sunlight,
make sure the orchids will bloom and the
flowers will stay on the branches for a
long time before fading.
Hope you will like the video.
[Music]
Wishing you luck and success in life.
There you go.
[Music]
Welcome to my channel.
I am an orchid care specialist.
Do you have vitamin B1?
Subscribe to the channel and watch till
the end to see the magic.
[Music]
Five tablets of vitamin B1.
Mix in four cups of room temperature
water, about one liter.
[Music]
keep in a cool place away from direct
sunlight for 1 hour.
[Music]
Then I took five eggshells
Eggshells contain many nutrients needed
by plants, including calcium, potassium,
and trace elements such as iron,
magnesium, manganese, copper, and zinc.
[Music]
Therefore, eggshells will help provide
necessary nutrients for orchids.
[Music]
Dry on low heat for 5 minutes.
This helps to eliminate fungal diseases
before using as fertilizer.
[Music]
When using eggshells as fertilizer, it
also helps to increase the pH of the
soil, helping orchids grow better.
[Music]
In addition, I also use 100 g of organic
fertilizer from livestock waste pressed
into dry pellets.
[Music]
Then mix the two types together.
With the orchids that have bloomed all
the last flowers,
[Music]
I apply about 1 oz, about 30 g per Hot
orchid after full bloom is very
exhausted. So I need to apply this
fertilizer to quickly recover.
[Music]
Pay attention to fertilizing far from
the root.
[Music]
with orchids in full bloom.
This fertilizer also helps flowers bloom
for a long time.
If you apply this fertilizer every 2
months, it is guaranteed that the orchid
will bloom for 6 months without wilting.
[Music]
With orchids with buds, I also apply
this fertilizer to help flower buds grow
faster.
[Music]
1 hour after
decant the clear water above.
[Music]
Use this absorbent cotton.
Clean the top and bottom of the leaves.
Helps eliminate fungal diseases and
prevent parasitic insects on leaves.
At the same time, it supports the supply
of nutrients through orchid leaves.
Orchids are always green and growing.
[Music]
Sprinkle the remaining water into the
orchid growing medium.
[Music]
Vitamin B1 helps strengthen the root
system and promote plant health while
improving the soil's ability to absorb
nutrients.
Vitamin B1 has the effect of protecting
plants from external agents such as
drought, sunburn, and cold, and enhances
resistance to plant diseases.
[Music]
You should fertilize B1 for orchids once
a month in the cool afternoon.
Results after 1 week.
You can see that after 15 days, the
flowers are still very fresh and more
fragrant than usual.
and flowers can bloom again and again
all year round in the garden.
[Music]
This helps me to always enjoy the
blooming flowers and the gentle
fragrance from the garden.
[Music]
And you can see that after just a week
of using, the orchid has grown a lot of
new roots.
[Music]
So we can use these organic fertilizers
to take care of orchids very well.
[Music]
However, keep in mind that an overdose
can also harm plants. Therefore, it is
advisable to adhere to the dosage that I
have instructed.
Hopefully, the video will be of great
help to you in effectively taking care
of orchids at home.
If you find the content interesting and
meaningful, don't forget to like and
share so that more people know and
subscribe to support the channel. Thank
you for always accompanying me.
Thank you for watching the video. I
always pray for God's blessings to all
of you.