Welcome to the garden of happiness,
where every leaf and every petal is
cared for with love and patience. To
give you more options for natural
fertilizers, today I will share a
special formula that helps orchids stay
healthy. Even the weakest ones can
revive, grow strong, and bloom
beautifully all year round.
Let's get started and discover the
secret to nurturing the natural beauty
of your orchids in your little garden.
You can see that this orchid is having a
problem. Its leaves are turning yellow
and showing signs of rot.
This is a common condition that happens
when the plant is overwatered, lacks
sunlight, or has weak roots that can no
longer absorb enough nutrients.
Rotten, soft, and watery leaves like
these actually contain a lot of harmful
bacteria. If left for too long, they can
spread to the healthy parts of the plant
and make the condition even worse.
Therefore, removing them as soon as
possible is the first important step to
protect your orchid.
Uh please comment and and let me know
which country you're watching from. It's
wonderful that we can connect and chat
from all around the world.
And if you haven't subscribed yet,
please hit the subscribe button to
support me and never miss any orchid
care tips. It's wonderful to have you
with me.
Then we gently check the entire root
system of the plant. Roots that are
rotten, soft, or have an unpleasant
smell need to be cut off immediately as
they can no longer absorb water and
nutrients for the plant.
You can see that many roots are damaged,
turning brown and mushy. So, we need to
handle the plant very gently when taking
it out of the pot to avoid injuring the
healthy roots.
This step will help us easily inspect
the entire root system and take timely
action before the disease spreads
throughout the plant.
In addition to English dubbing, we have
now created versions in Polish, Bangla,
Portuguese, Hebrew, Hindi, Dutch,
Korean, Indonesian, Italian, Malayalam,
Japanese, French, Punjabi, Tamil,
Telugu, Spanish, German, and Arabic to
help you listen to and understand the
content easily.
To listen in your preferred language,
open the video and click on settings,
the gear icon to select the appropriate
all language.
After removing the damaged leaves and
roots, the next step is to prepare for
disinfecting and stimulating root growth
for the orchid.
To make the disinfecting and root
stimulating solution, start by preparing
5 L of clean water in a container.
Next, take a fresh aloe leaf and
carefully cut it into small pieces. The
aloe will release natural nutrients when
mixed into the water, helping to fight
bacteria and stimulate strong root
growth for the orchid.
These aloe pieces will blend into the
solution, creating a safe and effective
mixture to nourish the orchid after
pruning.
Next, we will add the banana enzyme gel
that I have prepared earlier. Take about
100 milllers of banana gel and mix it
into the water solution with the aloe.
The banana gel is rich in nutrients and
natural enzymes which will help the
orchid roots recover faster and
stimulate healthy growth of leaves and
new flower buds.
And finally, we add vitamin B1 to boost
the vitality of the roots.
Add six vitamin B1 tablets, each 2.5 mg,
into the solution and stir well to
dissolve completely.
Vitamin B1 helps the orchid roots
recover quickly, absorb nutrients
better, and prepare the plant for lush
green leaves and vibrant new flower
buds.
Place the freshly cut aloe slices on a
clean cloth and gently press to extract
the gel into the water. This aloe gel
will dissolve evenly in the solution,
carrying natural nutrients that help
fight bacteria and stimulate strong root
growth for the orchid.
In this way, we maximize the benefits of
aloe, creating an ideal environment for
the plant to recover and bloom
beautifully.
Then pour the entire solution into a
container and soak the orchid roots for
about 20 minutes.
This time is enough for the roots to
absorb nutrients from the aloe, banana
gel, and vitamin B1 while being gently
disinfected to eliminate any remaining
bacteria. By the end, you will see the
roots looking fresh and smooth, ready to
be replanted and grow healthily.
Um, use the remaining aloe pulp in the
cloth to gently wipe both the top and
bottom surfaces of the orchid leaves.
This helps remove dust, bacteria, and
excess residue on the leaves while
creating a clean environment for the
leaves to absorb light and nutrients
more effectively.
After wiping, the leaves will be fresh
and smooth, ready for the orchid's
healthy growth process.
After soaking the roots and cleaning the
leaves, the next step is to prepare the
growing medium to replant the orchid. We
will mix 80% pine bark and 20% moss,
creating an airy environment that
retains moderate moisture and is rich in
nutrients for root development.
This growing medium will help the plant
anchor firmly, absorb water and
nutrients efficiently, and provide a
solid foundation for lush green leaves
and vibrant blooms in the future.
After soaking the roots in the solution
for about 20 minutes, we replant the
orchid into a new pot. I choose a pot
with drainage holes at the bottom to
ensure the roots do not become water
logged and the plant always receives
enough oxygen.
Planting in a suitable pot with a loose
growing medium will help the roots
anchor firmly, absorb water and
nutrients better, and lay the foundation
for healthy growth and vibrant blooms.
When filling the growing medium around
the roots, gently arrange each piece of
pine bark and moss evenly, being careful
not to crush the young roots.
After planting, place the orchid pot in
a cool, airy spot for about a week and
do not water it. This period allows the
newly cut roots and young parts of the
plant to stabilize while reducing the
risk of rot from early water exposure.
After about a week, when the roots and
plant have stabilized, we proceed to
fertilize the orchid.
Add 3 teaspoon of rice into a clean
container. Uh the rice will serve as a
natural source of nutrients rich in
starch, helping to stimulate the growth
of roots and new shoots on the orchid.
Next, add the rice to one liter of water
and stir well.
Then cover the container and let it sit
for about 30 minutes so that the starch
in the rice fully dissolves, creating a
nutrient-rich solution for the orchid.
After soaking for 30 minutes, stir the
solution once more and strain out any
remaining rice residue.
This makes the solution smooth and
easier for the orchid roots to absorb
while preventing blockage in the growing
medium or pot. In this way, the natural
rice fertilizer will work at its best,
nourishing the plant to be healthy with
lush green leaves and vibrant blooms.
Step one, use a soft cloth to soak up
the solution and gently wipe both the
top and bottom surfaces of the orchid
leaves. This helps remove dust,
bacteria, and excess residue while
providing nutrients directly to the
leaves.
After wiping the leaves will become
clean and smooth. ready to absorb light
and nutrients for healthy growth.
Uh, step two, use the prepared solution
to water directly onto the orchid's
roots and growing medium. This helps the
roots absorb nutrients from the rice,
aloe, and vitamin B1 while also
nourishing the entire surrounding
medium.
The natural nutrients from rice, aloe,
and vitamin B1 not only nourish the
roots, but also create a favorable
environment for new shoots to form,
helping the plant grow quickly and bloom
more evenly and vibrantly.
You should apply this mixture twice a
month. Regular maintenance helps the
orchid roots stay healthy, the leaves
remain lush, and the flower buds develop
consistently. When applied consistently,
the orchid will have long-lasting
vitality, ready to bloom beautifully,
bringing full beauty to your garden.
And here are the results after 2 months
of consistent care. You can see the
roots growing vigorously with many new
roots extending long and firm, signaling
the orchid's abundant vitality.
At the same time, the leaves become
lush, glossy, and full of life. The
vitality of the leaves is the clearest
sign that the roots are absorbing
nutrients effectively and the plant is
growing healthily.
And the special thing is that you can
see the flower buds emerging, proving
that the plant has fully recovered. Now,
the orchid is not only healthy with
strong roots and lush green leaves, but
also ready for the next vibrant blooms,
bringing full beauty to your garden.
It's wonderful to see the orchid revive
and prepare to bloom, like a natural
gift for you.
I continue to care for the orchid by
watering it with the natural rice
fertilizer every 2 weeks. Maintaining
this routine helps the roots stay
healthy, the leaves remain lush, and the
flower buds develop evenly, preparing
for vibrant blooms.
In addition, you can alternate with
other natural fertilizers to provide
complete nutrients for the orchid.
This rotation helps the plant receive a
variety of vitamins and minerals,
promoting healthy roots, lush green
leaves, and evenly developing flower
buds. As a result, your orchid will
always be vibrant, bloom beautifully and
brilliantly all year round, bringing joy
every time you admire it.
And here are the results after 3 months
of persistent care. You can see that a
plant that once had rotting leaves and
roots has now grown strong and sturdy
with lush green leaves and vibrant
flowers beginning to bloom. It's
wonderful to witness the plant's
complete revival, bringing new life and
full beauty to your garden.
This revival process is a testament to
the power of patience and love for
plants. With just simple care steps,
natural solutions, and consistent
attention, you can completely transform
a weak orchid once thought hopeless into
a healthy plant that blooms beautifully.
Believe that with love and dedicated
care, any orchid can revive, bringing
joy, beauty, and endless inspiration to
your garden.
Every lush green leaf and every vibrant
bloom is the result of the love and
patience you give to the plant.
Remember, caring for orchids is not just
a task but a journey of connecting with
nature, learning patience, and enjoying
each small yet precious moment. With a
natural, simple, and consistent
approach, you can completely transform
your garden into a space full of life,
where each orchid pot tells a story of
revival and lasting beauty.
I hope you enjoy this video. If you find
it useful and interesting, please like,
share so more people can know and
subscribe to support me in upcoming
orchid care videos. Thank you for
watching and see you in the next videos
with more tips for growing healthy
orchids and making them bloom
beautifully.