I'm sure many of you have encountered
the situation where your orchid after
the flowers have faded looks like it has
lost all its
vitality, right? Uh but don't worry.
Today I will share with you a super
simple yet effective tip that will help
your wilting orchid recover quickly and
grow new roots
consistently. After the orchid blooms,
the plant often becomes weak and prone
to diseases due to the loss of its
resistance.
The reason is that throughout the
blooming process, the the plant has
expended a lot of energy to nurture
those beautiful flowers which reduces
its ability to protect itself. This is
also the time when we need to provide
special care to help the plant recover
and continue to grow
healthily. Uh my orchid is wilting, so
we need to check the roots and the
growing medium to find the cause of the
wilted leaves.
[Music]
Let me know in the comments which
country you're watching from. It's
amazing that we can connect and chat
from all around the world.
[Music]
After checking, I found that the entire
root system was damaged, which made the
orchid weak and unable to absorb the
necessary nutrients and water, leading
to the wilting of the
plant. I need to cut off all the damaged
roots to stop the spread of disease and
help the plant focus its energy on
growing new roots.
[Music]
Then cut off the old flower stems. This
helps the plant focus its nutrients on
growing new leaves and roots instead of
continuing to nourish the faded flower
stems.
[Music]
Then rinse the orchid under running
water to remove any dirt, bacteria, and
mold left on the stem. This helps clean
the plant, creating favorable conditions
for recovery and growth after the root
damage.
[Music]
To revive the wilted orchid, I use aloe
vera leaves with gel. As aloe vera gel
is very good for plant recovery.
I apply aloe vera gel all over the
wilted orchid as this helps provide
moisture, soothe the wounds and promote
the recovery process.
[Music]
Aloe vera gel also has antibacterial
properties, helping protect the plant
from bacteria and fungi while
stimulating the growth of new
roots. If you haven't subscribe to the
channel yet, please hit the subscribe
button to support me and never miss any
orchid care tips. It's truly wonderful
to have you along on this
[Music]
journey. Aloe vera gel also has
antibacterial properties, helping
protect the plant from bacteria and
fungi while stimulating the growth of
new roots.
Um, after chopping it finely, place the
aloe vera into a bottle and dilute it
with one liter of room temperature
water.
Then add one teaspoon of honey. Uh as
honey has antibacterial properties and
provides nutrients that help the orchid
recover quickly.
Honey also helps the plant strengthen
its resistance, promoting healthier
growth of new
roots. Then stir vigorously to dissolve
the aloe vera gel and honey evenly into
the water, creating a homogeneous
solution.
[Music]
Filter out the residue to make the
solution smooth and easy for the plant
to absorb.
[Music]
Step one, use a soft cloth to soak up
the aloe vera and honey mixture. Then
carefully wipe both the top and bottom
of the orchid.
This helps the aloe vera gel and honey
soak evenly into the plant, providing
nutrients and supporting quick recovery.
[Music]
Then soak the orchid stem in this
mixture for about 20 minutes to help
stimulate faster root growth.
Soaking helps the plant absorb the
maximum nutrients from the aloe vera and
honey, creating favorable conditions for
the growth of new
[Music]
roots. Use the remaining mixture to
water the other orchids in the garden.
[Music]
This helps uh provide nutrients to the
other orchids supporting their healthy
growth and boosting their resistance.
Uh, this mixture is very beneficial. You
can water each orchid pot with it twice
a
[Music]
month. It's best to water in the early
morning or late afternoon so the plant
can absorb nutrients more effectively
and avoid heat shock.
[Music]
Each time just water with a sufficient
amount to keep the growing medium moist
without causing root rot.
[Music]
In addition to the English voiceover,
we've also created French, German,
Italian, Spanish, Portuguese, Japanese,
Hindi, and Indonesian versions to help
you listen and understand the content
more easily.
To listen to the language, open the
video and click the settings gear icon.
Then select the appropriate audio
language.
[Music]
In addition to watering, you can also
use this aloe vera and honey mixture to
lightly mist the orchid leaves once a
week.
[Music]
This method allows the leaves to
directly absorb nutrients, enhances
their shine, retains moisture, and
strengthens the plant. Especially
helpful during dry weather.
You can spray the mixture on the leaves,
stems, roots, and growing medium. This
helps the orchid absorb nutrients
comprehensively, supporting the growth
of new roots, improving the health of
the leaves and stems, and providing the
necessary moisture for the growing
medium.
[Applause]
However, you should not spray the
mixture on the flowers as wetting them
can cause the flower stems to drop or
the blooms to fade faster. Focus only on
spraying the leaves and stems to ensure
the plant absorbs the nutrients without
affecting the beauty of the flowers.
[Music]
Uh if you apply this natural fertilizer
regularly, one to two times a month,
your orchid will receive all the
necessary nutrients, helping stimulate
strong growth.
The plant will produce many flower
spikes on the same orchid, creating a
beautiful, vibrant, and more dazzling
orchid bloom than ever
[Music]
before. Many large, plump, and healthy
flower spikes will grow on the same
orchid. As a result, the plant will
thrive with beautiful flowers that bloom
longer and stay vibrant and full of
life. When the orchid is healthy, you
will easily see flowers blooming
consistently with bright colors and
large
sizes. Uh the flowers will bloom with
vibrant bright colors and last a long
time, bringing lasting beauty to your
space.
[Music]
The orchid will continue to grow
steadily, producing many healthy flower
spikes, creating a fresh and vibrant
landscape. After soaking the orchid for
20 minutes, remove the plant and use a
soft cloth or clean towel to absorb any
remaining water on the leaves and stem.
This helps prevent stem rot, mold, and
ensures the plant doesn't become too
wet, creating favorable conditions for
the growth of new
[Music]
roots. After drying the orchid, sprinkle
turmeric powder on the cut to help the
wound heal quickly.
Turmeric powder has antibacterial
properties and helps stimulate the
healing process while also protecting
the plant from harmful agents like
bacteria and fungi.
[Music]
Uh to revive the orchid, I take a clear
cup and fill it with water.
[Music]
Use a plasticcoated steel rod to secure
the orchid after planting it in the
water
cup. Secure the orchid to the support
rod. This helps keep the plant stable,
preventing movement during the recovery
process and ensuring the plant doesn't
topple over. The steel rod also prevents
the plant from touching the sides of the
cup, minimizing damage to the new
roots. Make sure the orchid stem doesn't
touch the water. The moisture rising
from the bottom will create the right
humidity to stimulate faster root growth
without causing the plant to rot. This
helps the orchid absorb the necessary
moisture for recovery while keeping the
stem dry, preventing diseases caused by
excess
humidity. Then place the orchid pot in a
spot with gentle sunlight, avoiding
direct sunlight to prevent the plant
from getting
[Music]
sunburned. Now, let's take a look at the
results of the orchid's recovery after 1
month.
[Music]
As you can see, after just one month and
a few simple steps, the orchid has grown
many new healthy roots.
[Music]
And here is another orchid where I also
applied this recovery method. You can
see that the orchid has grown very
strong new roots, proving that this
method is truly effective in helping the
orchid recover and thrive.
[Music]
This orchid is the same with strong new
roots that help the plant absorb
nutrients more
effectively. This proves that this
method is truly effective in helping the
orchid grow strong again.
[Music]
Uh, when the roots are healthy, it's the
perfect time to transplant the orchid
into a new
pot. Uh, when the roots are healthy,
it's the perfect time to transplant the
orchid into a new pot.
[Music]
What do you think about my method for
reviving weak orchids? Please leave a
comment and share your thoughts with me.
[Music]
Uh, if you encounter any difficulties
while growing your orchids, don't
hesitate to leave a comment. I'm always
here to support you so you can grow
healthy orchids that bloom beautifully.
[Music]
If you haven't subscribed yet, please
hit the subscribe button to support me
and never miss any orchid growing tips.
It's truly wonderful to have you along
on this journey.
I use sterilized pine bark chips as the
growing
medium. Pine bark helps create
irerration for the roots, preventing
water logging while providing an ideal
environment for the orchid to grow
healthy. Make sure the pine bark is
properly sterilized to prevent bacteria
and mold from harming the plant.
On top of the orchid pot, sprinkle a
layer of sterilized orchid moss uh to
help retain moisture and prevent water
from evaporating too quickly.
Um, this layer of moss also helps
protect the orchid roots from harmful
agents and keeps the growing medium
stable, creating the best conditions for
the plant's growth.
[Music]
When planting the orchid into the pot,
remember to secure the plant to a stake
to prevent it from shifting, keeping the
plant stable and allowing the roots to
grow in the right direction. So
[Music]
grow this also helps prevent the orchid
from tipping over during the recovery
process, creating favorable conditions
for the plant to grow strong and
healthy.
[Music]
I hope this video will be helpful to
many of you in taking care of and
reviving your orchids.
If you find the content helpful and
meaningful, don't forget to like, share
so more people can benefit and subscribe
to support my
channel. Thank you for always being with
me.
[Music]
Thank you for watching. I wish you
success with healthy orchids that bloom
beautifully and brilliantly.