[Music]
Welcome everyone to the little garden
called Happiness Garden. A place where I
share simple but heartfelt things for
plants in life.
If you grow many orchids, bacterial or
fungal soft rot is something that's hard
to avoid.
Um, in this video, I will show you how
to help an orchid with rot recover
quickly and continue to grow healthily.
[Music]
First, check if the roots are healthy.
Uh, if you haven't subscribed to the
channel yet, please press the subscribe
button to support me and not miss any
orchid growing tips. It's wonderful to
have you along for the journey.
[Music]
Please comment and let me know which
country you are watching the video from.
It's wonderful that we can chat together
from all over the world.
[Music]
Um, this orchid of mine has lost all its
roots. So, I will cut off all the rotten
parts of the plant.
[Music]
This orchid of mine has lost all its
roots. So I will cut off all the rotten
parts of the plant.
[Music]
Next, gently dry the plant to avoid
harmful Full moisture.
[Music]
Applying toothpaste on the cut will help
the wound heal quickly and prevent the
orchid from rotting.
[Music]
Then take an aloe vera leaf and cut it
into thin slices to prepare for the next
care step.
[Music]
Add one teaspoon of honey to enhance the
care effectiveness.
Add half a liter of room temperature
water to the mixture.
Stir well so that the nutrients from the
aloe vera gel and honey fully blend with
the water.
[Music]
Then soak the orchid in this mixture for
about 30 minutes so the nutrients can
penetrate deeply.
[Music]
Add half a liter of warm water into the
bottle.
Add 1 teaspoon of cinnamon powder into
the cup of water.
[Music]
Let the mixture sit for 30 minutes to
allow the cinnamon powder to dissolve
completely before use.
[Music]
After soaking for 30 minutes, strain out
the sediment to get the clear solution.
[Music]
Soaking moss in cinnamon water for 30
minutes helps antibacterial and promotes
the growth of the orchid.
[Music]
place the orchid in a transparent glass
pot and mist to keep it moist every 5
days.
[Music]
Place the orchid pot in a cool, airy
spot and patiently wait for the roots to
grow.
[Music]
And here is the result after one month
of care.
[Music]
With this simple method, after just one
month, the orchid has started to root
and grow healthily.
[Music]
If you find this video helpful, please
remember to subscribe to the channel,
like and share so I have more motivation
to make more videos.
[Music]
Now I will transfer the orchid into a
pot to help it grow better in the
outdoor environment.
[Music]
Hydroponic planting plastic beads are
placed at the bottom of the pot or you
can replace them with large pine bark,
pummus or baked clay.
On the surface, moss is covered to
better retain moisture for the orchid.
[Music]
After planting, water and care for it
like other ordinary plants.
[Music]
Uh, I hope this video will bring a lot
of usefulness to you in caring for and
restoring weak orchids right at home.
Wishing you success and always happiness
in life.
Goodbye and see you in the next videos.
I'm very happy that you are here.
If you have an orchid, I'm sure you
always want it to bloom for a long time.
Right. Right.
[Music]
Orchids are known for their ability to
keep flowers on their branches for 3 to
6 months.
[Music]
For that to happen, you need to nurture,
water, and feed it well.
[Music]
Now, I will show you what is the best
fertilizer for orchids.
[Music]
If you follow us till the end of this
video, you will learn how to make
orchids bloom like crazy.
[Music]
Now, let's get started.
Take a bowl and put 5 tsp of rice in it.
If you haven't subscribed to the channel
yet, please subscribe to support me and
not miss any orchid care tips.
[Music]
Pour in 500 ml of water at room
temperature.
Mix the rice well and wash the rice
before cooking.
[Music]
Then filter the water to wash the rice.
Please comment to me which country you
are watching the video from. It's great
that we can chat together from all over
the world.
[Music]
Use a cotton ball soaked in water to
wash this rice.
Then wipe on the top and bottom of the
leaves
[Music]
will help clean the surface of the
leaves, remove disease fungi and insects
on orchids. At the same time, it
provides the necessary nutrients for the
orchid's growth.
[Music]
Repeat after 2 weeks will help The
orchids stay green.
[Music]
Or you can also pour the rice water into
a spray bottle.
[Music]
Then spray evenly on the top and bottom
of the leaves.
[Music]
This method also has the same effect as
the previous method using cotton balls.
[Music]
Do not spray rice water on flowers.
Now take a deep bowl in which you will
place the orchid ready for watering and
soaking.
[Music]
Rice water is a great natural fertilizer
for orchids as it encourages the
flowering of this beautiful plant.
[Music]
You can soak the orchid in this rice
water for about 1 hour so that the
orchid roots can absorb the most
nutrients.
[Music]
Then remove and repeat this treatment
every 14 days.
[Music]
You can also freeze rice water to water
your orchids.
[Music]
When needed, you just need to take a few
cubes.
[Music]
Wait for them to defrost and reach room
temperature. You can feed your orchids
again.
[Music]
Never place frozen blocks directly on
the base of the orchid because orchids
don't like the cold.
[Music]
After only 2 to 3 weeks of use, the
leaves will be green.
[Music]
Um, you can see that after fertilizing
the new roots grow very strongly. This
will help the orchid best absorb
nutrients through its roots.
[Music]
If you find the content interesting or
meaningful, don't forget to like, share
so that more people know and subscribe
to your support channel. Thank you for
always accompanying me.
With enough nutrition, your orchid will
flower all year round.
[Music]
And that will be all we have prepared
for you for this video.
[Music]