welcome to my
channel if you want orchids to bloom a
lot orchids always grow
healthily uh then join me in discovering
organic fertilizers in this video
[Music]
take 50 g of coffee grounds about 2
oz soak in 2 L of hot water
[Music]
wait for the water to
cool after the water cools filter to
remove
[Music]
sediment add water to make 5 L of
solution about 1.3 us gall
[Music]
method one fertilize Orchid
Roots coffee grounds contain many
important nutrients such as nitrogen
potassium phosphorus and minerals
[Music]
um when used as fertilizer it helps
promote their growth and
[Music]
flowering coffee grounds also have the
ability to hold water helping to
maintain the necessary humidity for
orchids
[Music]
method two spray the entire
Orchid you can also spray this
fertilizer on the entire
[Music]
Orchid like folar fertilization for
orchids
[Music]
coffee grounds often have a slightly
acidic pH which reduces the alkalinity
of the
soil this is beneficial for orchids
because many orchids prefer a soil
environment with a slightly acidic pH
[Music]
the second type of fertilizer I want to
share with you is also made from coffee
[Music]
grounds I took 3 tbspoon of coffee
grounds add 2 quarts of warm water about
0.53 us gall
[Music]
leave
space add 1 teaspoon of
sugar add 1 tbsp yeast
[Music]
cover with vented
lid cover with vented lid
[Music]
1 month
later take 50 mL of fermented coffee
water about 3 tblspoon
[Music]
add water to make 5 L of Sal solution
about 1.3 us
[Music]
Gall method one water The
Roots You water the roots with
fertilizer from fermented coffee 1 to
two times a month
[Music]
coffee grounds when fermented will
become nutrient-rich organic
[Music]
fertilizer fermented coffee grounds
contain many important nutrients for
plant growth such as nitrogen potassium
phosphorus calcium and minerals
[Music]
this is a natural source of nutrients
that helps orchids grow
[Music]
healthily method two clean the
leaves clean the top and bottom of the
leaves with this water
[Music]
helps kill fungi insects and harmful
bacteria very
[Music]
effectively if you fertilize one to two
times FR a month the leaves will always
be green and disease free
[Music]
let's see the
results after 3 weeks new Roots begin to
grow
[Music]
after 5 weeks The Roots grow a
lot uh this helps the plant R Roots
absorb the most nutrients through the
roots
[Music]
flower buds also develop faster
many flower stems grow on the same same
[Music]
orchid flowers bloom with more vibrant
colors
[Music]
flowers bloom with more vibrant colors
hope the video will help you a
lot if you find it interesting please
share and like so more people know about
this
[Music]
video thank you for watching the video
good luck and see you in the next videos