Welcome to our happiness garden, where
you will explore with me the beauty of
nature and how to care for beautiful
orchids using simple ingredients right
in your kitchen.
In this video, I will show you how to
use natural fertilizer to help spent
flower stems revive, grow new shoots,
and continue blooming, bringing fresh
vitality to your orchid. Subscribe to
the channel so you won't miss any tips
on caring for and growing orchids,
helping you always have healthy orchids
with lush green leaves and vibrant
blooms.
These are the stems after the flowers
have dropped their petals, but they are
still full of potential to keep growing
if cared for properly.
I cut off all the dry stems so the plant
doesn't waste energy, allowing nutrients
to focus on the green parts, helping the
orchid recover quickly and get ready to
grow new shoots.
[Music]
After that, I sprinkle a thin layer of
cinnamon powder on the cut to disinfect
it and help it heal quickly, protecting
the plant from fungus and supporting
better recovery.
After that, I let the plant rest for a
day without watering, giving the cut
time to dry and heal completely before
moving on to the next stage of care.
I take a fresh aloe vera leaf and slice
it into thin pieces so that when used,
the nutrients in the aloe can easily
absorb into the orchid stem and nourish
the plant better.
[Music]
Then I gently apply the aloe vera gel to
the spent flower stems. This helps the
stems recover quickly, stimulates new
shoots to grow, and prepares for the
next blooms.
[Music]
Uh please comment and let me know which
country you're watching this video from.
It's wonderful that we can connect and
chat from all around the world.
And uh I also continue applying aloe
vera gel to the leaves once a week. This
not only helps eliminate pathogens but
also allows wilted orchids to recover
quickly, making the leaves turn glossy
green and full of life.
[Music]
I put the sliced aloe vera into a clean
jar. Then add 2 L of boiled water to
extract all the natural nutrients from
the aloe.
[Music]
Um, add a spoonful of rice to the jar.
Rice is rich in natural vitamins and
minerals, especially vitamin B1, which
helps stimulate strong root growth, keep
the leaves lush green, and speed up the
orchid's recovery. Then, I add three
crushed eggshells to the mixture.
Eggshells provide natural calcium,
helping the stems and leaves become
stronger and increasing the orchid's
resistance, reducing root rot and
yellowing leaves.
I close the lid and wait for the water
to cool completely, allowing the
nutrients from the aloe, rice, and
eggshells to fully dissolve, creating a
nutrient-rich solution for the orchids.
After the water has cooled, I stir well
to fully dissolve the nutrients. Then
strain out the residue, leaving a clear
solution ready to water the orchids.
[Music]
I water the orchids with this solution
two to three times a month. This helps
provide complete nutrition, allowing the
plant to recover quickly, grow strong
roots, and regain lush green leaves.
I soak the whole orchid pot in this
solution for about 20 minutes so the
roots can fully absorb the nutrients.
Then take it out and place it in a spot
with gentle sunlight to let it dry and
continue photosynthesizing well.
[Music]
The second method, you can pour this
mixture into a spray bottle and mist it
directly on the leaves, roots, and
growing medium. This method helps the
plant absorb nutrients faster, makes the
leaves shiny green, and promotes even
root growth.
[Music]
Be sure to spray thoroughly on both the
top and underside of the leaves as well
as the growing medium so the plant can
fully absorb the nutrients.
[Music]
Do this regularly two to three times a
month and you will see your orchid
become healthier with lush green leaves
and rapidly growing roots.
This method also effectively eliminates
harmful fungi and bacteria, keeping the
plant clean and healthy while reducing
root rot and yellowing leaves.
Uh after soaking for about 20 minutes,
remember to take the orchid pot out and
place it in a spot with gentle sunlight,
allowing the roots to dry naturally and
the plant to continue photosynthesizing
for faster recovery.
[Music]
And here is the result after a month of
care. You can see uh new flower buds
beginning to appear on the old stems,
signaling a stunning blooming season
ahead.
This method helps the new shoots grow
very quickly. After just one month, many
new shoots have appeared, making the
plant look full of vitality and ready
for the next bloom.
[Music]
These young flower buds will gradually
grow, preparing to bloom, bringing fresh
colors and a gentle fragrance to the
entire orchid pot.
[Music]
Uh continue caring for the orchid with
this fertilizer solution two to three
times a month. Doing this regularly will
help the flower buds develop fully. The
blooms last longer and retain vibrant
colors while the roots and leaves remain
healthy and full of life.
[Music]
And here is the result after the
following month. You can see the flowers
in full bloom, showing off their colors
and fragrance, bringing complete joy to
the caretaker.
The orchid has now fully recovered with
lush green leaves, strong roots, and
ready for the next blooming seasons.
[Music]
Although the old flower stems have
withered, the newly bloomed flowers
still retain their bright, vibrant
colors, bringing full vitality to the
entire orchid. This proves that with
proper care, orchids always have the
ability to recover and continue
showcasing their beautiful blooms.
[Music]
The flowers are very healthy and sturdy,
so they will stay on the stems for a
long time before fading, providing
lasting beauty and joy to admire.
So, you can see that with this simple
method, uh, we can fully care for
orchids at home, helping them bloom year
round with lush green leaves and strong
roots. With patience and regular care,
you will enjoy the vibrant beauty and
full vitality of your beloved orchids.
Um, what do you think of how I revived
this small orchid? Don't hesitate to
leave a comment and share your thoughts.
I'm really eager to hear your feedback,
tips, and orchid care experiences.
[Music]
If you encounter any difficulties while
growing orchids, don't hesitate to leave
a comment for me. Um, I'm always ready
to support you so you can care for
healthy orchids and enjoy vibrant
blooming seasons.
I hope you enjoy this video. If you find
it helpful, don't forget to hit like and
subscribe to the channel so you won't
miss future tips on caring for orchids
naturally, simply, and effectively.
Thank you for watching. Goodbye. And I
wish you always have healthy orchids
with lush green leaves and vibrant
blooms.
[Music]