Welcome to my channel. Here we will
explore together how to care for
beautiful orchid pots. From small tips
to natural tricks that help the plants
stay healthy and bloom brilliantly.
When your orchid petals begin to wither,
if you want the plant to continue
blooming and not become exhausted,
follow the steps that I will guide you
through right now.
First, gently cut off all the withered
petals. This is an important step to
release energy for the plant, helping
the roots and leaves receive adequate
nutrition, preparing for new, healthy,
and vibrant buds in the near future.
[Music]
Only keep the fresh petals and the buds
that have not yet opened so the plant
can continue to bloom and display
vibrant colors. This helps the plant
focus its energy on the living parts,
nurturing the flowers and buds in the
best way.
Um, if you haven't subscribed to the
channel, please click the subscribe
button to support me and not miss any
orchid growing tips. It's wonderful to
have you along for the journey.
Uh next we will remove the old pot in
which the plant was bought from the
industrial orchid garden and carefully
check the roots and the growing medium.
[Music]
Carefully cut off the damaged and
rotting roots. Uh, this helps the plant
focus nutrients on the healthy roots
while preventing the spread of fungi,
allowing the orchid to grow strongly and
prepare for new vibrant buds.
[Music]
Then remove about half of the old
growing medium, but keep the remaining
half so the plant does not get shocked.
This helps the orchid roots gradually
adapt to the new environment while
utilizing the remaining nutrients in the
medium for continued healthy growth.
[Music]
This method also helps the remaining
flowers and buds on the stem continue to
develop, maintaining their freshness and
vibrancy while not weakening the plant.
[Music]
Please comment and let me know which
country you are watching the video from.
It's wonderful that we can chat together
from all over the world.
Next, pour four cups of water equivalent
to about one liter into a container to
prepare the disinfecting solution before
replanting the orchid.
[Music]
Then add five drops of methylene blue to
the solution. This helps disinfect the
roots and growing medium, protecting the
orchid from bacteria and fungi, uh
creating favorable conditions for the
plant to grow healthily and bloom again.
[Music]
Next, pour the solution mixture into the
pot to soak the roots and growing medium
for about 10 to 20 minutes. This helps
disinfect all the roots and medium,
eliminating harmful bacteria or fungi.
This step helps the orchid roots stay
safe and get ready for replanting into
the new growing medium.
[Music]
Next, add the pine bark growing medium
into the solution mixture to soak. This
helps disinfect the medium, remove
impurities and harmful bacteria while
making the medium clean and ready to
support healthy root growth when
replanting the orchid.
[Music]
For the leaves, use a soft cloth soaked
in this solution and gently wipe both
the top and bottom surfaces of the
leaves.
[Music]
Uh, wiping the leaves helps remove dust
on their surface, keeping the orchid
leaves clean, allowing them to absorb
light better, and enhancing
photosynthesis efficiency.
Uh, the solution mixture has a
disinfecting effect, helping reduce the
risk of harmful bacteria and fungi,
protecting the health of the leaves and
the entire orchid.
[Music]
Clean leaves help the plant absorb CO2
and light more effectively, supporting
photosynthesis and nourishing the roots,
leaves, and flower buds.
When the leaves are healthy and clean,
the plant's energy is focused on
nurturing the flowers and buds, helping
the blooms last longer and maintain
vibrant colors.
In addition to English voiceover, we
have now created French, German,
Italian, Spanish, Portuguese, Japanese,
Hindi, Dutch, Polish, Korean, and
Indonesian voiceovers to help you listen
and understand the content easily.
To listen in your preferred language,
open the video and click on settings
gear icon to select the appropriate
audio language.
[Music]
After soaking for about 20 minutes, we
remove the pine bark medium ready to
replant the orchid.
[Music]
Uh the thoroughly disinfected growing
medium will help the orchid roots grow
strong, absorb nutrients well, and
support the plant in blooming
brilliantly.
[Music]
Next, gently take the orchid out and
plant it into the new pot with the
prepared growing medium. This step helps
the roots stay stable, grow healthily,
and prepare for new vibrant buds to
bloom in the near future.
[Music]
I choose large-sized pine bark as the
growing medium. When combined with the
old moss, it creates good erration for
the roots while retaining some necessary
moisture, helping the orchid grow
healthily and bloom beautifully for a
long time.
[Music]
When placing the pine bark into the pot,
do it carefully to avoid breaking the
roots or damaging the plant.
Careful handling ensures the orchid
roots are not damaged, allowing the
plant to immediately absorb nutrients
from the new medium, supporting healthy
growth and nurturing the next buds to
bloom brilliantly.
Thus, the replanting is complete and you
can see that the orchid is not affected
at all. Right after planting, the roots
are ready to absorb nutrients from the
new medium.
[Music]
To keep the orchids stable and avoid
disturbing the roots, we need to insert
stakes to secure the two flower stems.
This helps prevent the flowers from
tilting or breaking while allowing the
roots to stay in place to absorb
nutrients effectively and support
healthy plant growth.
If you encounter any difficulties during
the orchid planting process, don't
hesitate to comment. I am always ready
to support you so you can grow healthy
orchids that bloom abundantly.
Uh after planting, place the orchid pot
in a cool, ventilated area for one day
and do not water it.
And now I will guide you on how to make
natural fertilizer for orchids.
The first ingredient I choose is rice.
Just one teaspoon. rice will provide
gentle natural nutrients helping the
orchid roots absorb them effectively.
[Music]
Uh the next ingredient is an eggshell.
Just one shell. The combination of rice
and eggshell creates a mixture rich in
natural nutrients providing calcium and
energy for the orchid roots to grow
healthily while also helping the plant
bloom more beautifully.
Next, put the rice and eggshell mixture
into one cup of water, equivalent to 120
mm, and then blend it finely.
[Music]
This helps the nutrients dissolve in
water, making them easier to absorb by
the orchid roots, supporting healthy
growth and beautiful blooming.
[Applause]
Then pour the mixture into a clean jar,
cover it, and let it ferment for one
day.
[Music]
The fermentation process helps release
additional nutrients, creating a
nutrientrich natural fertilizer that
supports orchid roots in absorbing
effectively and promotes healthy plant
growth.
After one day, you need to stir the
mixture well so that the nutrients are
evenly distributed.
[Music]
Then strain out the remaining residue in
the mixture. This makes the fertilizer
solution smooth, allowing it to
penetrate the orchid roots easily,
ensuring the plant absorbs nutrients
effectively and grows healthily.
Next, dilute the mixture with four cups
of water, equivalent to about one liter.
This helps the solution become
moderately diluted, allowing it to
penetrate the orchid roots easily,
providing nutrients effectively and
safely for healthy plant growth.
[Music]
Method one, pour the mixture into a
spray bottle. This allows you to evenly
spray the solution onto the roots and
leaves, providing nutrients directly to
the orchid.
Then spray the solution onto both the
top and bottom surfaces of the leaves.
This helps the nutrients penetrate
evenly, nourishing healthy leaves,
supporting root and bud development, and
resulting in beautiful, vibrant flowers.
Spraying the solution allows nutrients
to be absorbed directly by the leaves
and buds, uh, supporting photosynthesis
and healthy flower development,
resulting in vibrant and longlasting
colors.
[Applause]
[Music]
This lightly fermented mixture also
helps protect the leaves from bacteria,
fungi, and some pests, keeping the
orchid healthy and reducing the risk of
damage during flowering.
[Music]
Method two, pour this mixture directly
onto the roots and growing medium.
Evenly pour the solution over the roots,
thoroughly wetting the growing medium.
This allows the nutrients to penetrate
deeply, ensuring the roots absorb them
well.
[Music]
Uh the nutrients from the fermented rice
and eggshell promote rapid and strong
root growth, helping the plant absorb
water and nutrients more effectively.
[Music]
The mixture provides calcium and
essential minerals, helping the orchid
roots grow strong and giving the plant a
solid nutritional foundation.
[Music]
Watering with the solution nourishes the
buds and flowers, helping them stay
fresh longer, maintain vibrant colors,
and reduce the risk of premature
dropping.
This fermented mixture also contains
beneficial microorganisms helping the
orchid resist fungi, bacteria, and
pests, keeping the plant healthy for a
long time.
[Music]
Uh, after watering, soak the orchid pot
in the mixture for about 20 minutes.
This helps the roots absorb maximum
nutrients and allows the growing medium
to be evenly saturated.
While waiting for the soak, use a dry
cloth to absorb any water on the leaves,
especially in the leaf crevices.
[Music]
Wiping off the water on the leaves helps
prevent a damp environment, reducing the
risk of mold and bacterial growth and
protecting the orchid's health.
[Music]
When the leaves are dry, the absorption
of nutrients from the fertilizer
solution and through the roots is more
effective, helping the plant grow
healthily and bloom beautifully.
[Music]
After soaking for 20 minutes, take the
orchid pot out and place it in a spot
with gentle sunlight. This helps the
leaves carry out photosynthesis
effectively, providing energy to nourish
the roots, leaves, and buds, supporting
healthy growth and vibrant blooming.
[Music]
And here's the result after 2 weeks of
recovery. You can see the orchid
continuing to bloom from the preserved
buds, demonstrating the strong vitality
and effectiveness of this natural care
method.
Looking at the orchid after 2 weeks, we
see lush green leaves, strong roots, and
plump buds ready to bloom. This clearly
demonstrates that with proper care,
using natural methods, the orchid not
only recovers but also grows more
vigorously.
To maintain the health and beauty of the
orchid, continue applying natural
fertilizer regularly, water moderately,
and place the plant in a spot with
gentle light. These care steps help the
roots, leaves, and buds stay healthy,
ensuring long-lasting blooms and
sustainable plant growth.
I hope you will enjoy this video. Um, if
you find it useful, don't forget to like
and subscribe to the channel so you
won't miss future tips on caring for
orchids naturally and easily.
Thank you for watching the video.
Wishing you happiness, good health, and
beautiful orchids that bloom brilliantly
all year round. See you in the next
videos.
[Music]