Welcome to the little garden full of
love and inspiration for orchid lovers.
Here we explore natural, gentle, yet
effective ways to help orchids stay
healthy and bloom beautifully all year
round.
The growth journey of an orchid begins
with healthy roots, spreads through lush
green leaves, and culminates in the
vibrant beauty of blooming flowers full
of life.
If cared for properly, the plant will
thrive from its roots and foliage and
continue to give you vibrant blooming
seasons in the future.
[Music]
Each root is like a silent heart
nurturing the plant. Each leaf is like
the cool breath of life and each flower
is the crystallization of an entire
journey of perseverance.
When you care for the roots and tend the
leaves with love and patience, the
flowers will naturally respond with
their most beautiful beauty.
[Music]
Has your orchid ever had yellowing
leaves? This is a sign that many orchid
growers often encounter, but don't worry
too much.
Yellow leaves can be the plant's way of
reacting to its environment or a gentle
reminder that it needs a little
adjustment in care. Let's explore the
causes and how to fix them.
This orchid leaf, as you can see, has
turned yellow. But unlike a case of
overwatering, the leaf is dry and has
lost its plumpness.
This is a sign that the plant is lacking
water or the roots are having trouble
absorbing moisture.
Observe carefully to find the right
solution before the condition becomes
more serious.
[Music]
As for this orchid leaf, although it is
yellow, it is still fresh and firm.
When you cut it off, you will notice
that the leaf is quite tough and clings
tightly to the stem.
[Music]
Um, this is a sign of the natural aging
process and is not a major concern. On
the other hand, if the orchid is over
watered, just a light touch can cause
the leaf to fall off easily due to the
base being mushy and rotten.
[Music]
After removing the yellow leaves, the
next step is to eliminate the withered
and damaged roots.
These root parts can no longer absorb
water and nutrients, and if left, they
may affect the plant's growth. Cleaning
the roots helps the plant become
healthier and ready for the recovery
phase.
[Music]
When checking the growing medium, you
will see that it is still fresh and not
decomposed. This indicates that the
cause does not come from the substrate.
The orchid may have developed yellow
leaves due to a sudden change in
environment or prolonged lack of water,
which caused the roots to be unable to
support the leaves.
Uh, I added a bit of moss to the surface
of the pot to retain moisture and create
a cooler environment for the roots.
[Music]
This thin layer of moss not not only
helps regulate moisture but also adds a
natural soothing look to the orchid pot.
[Music]
before fertilizing the orchid, you need
to water it to moisten the roots first.
This helps reduce the risk of fertilizer
shock and protects the tender root tips
from being burned by overly concentrated
fertilizer.
[Music]
Water thoroughly so that the entire
growing medium is evenly moistened.
[Music]
After watering, you can soak the orchid
pot in water for about 20 minutes. This
method helps the roots absorb enough
moisture and is especially useful for
plants that are dry or in need of
recovery.
[Music]
After soaking for about 20 minutes,
gently take the orchid pot out and place
it in a cool, airy spot to drain.
Each time you water and soak like this,
it also helps cleanse the growing
medium, washing away pathogens, harmful
fungi, and excess salts with the water.
[Music]
To start making the fertilizer, I
measure about 1.5 L of clean water into
the container. Using clean water ensures
that the the mixture is free from
harmful impurities for the orchid roots
and also helps the ingredients dissolve
more effectively.
[Music]
The first ingredient I use is molasses.
This type of molasses is rich in
minerals and natural sugars which help
stimulate the growth of beneficial
microorganisms,
thereby improving root health and
increasing the orchid's ability to
absorb nutrients.
Just add one teaspoon of molasses to the
water container and that's enough.
[Music]
The next ingredient I use is liquid
fertilizer made from bananas. This is a
natural source of potassium that is very
beneficial for orchids, helping to
stimulate root growth, thicken leaves,
and promote flowering.
[Music]
I take about 30 ml of liquid banana
fertilizer and add it to the container.
This small amount is enough to provide
the necessary nutrients without
overwhelming the plant.
[Music]
Remember to stir well so that all the
ingredients dissolve completely in the
water.
[Music]
Step one, use a soft cloth to gently
soak up the banana fertilizer mixture.
Then carefully wipe both the upper and
lower surfaces of the leaves.
Wiping the leaves with the mixture helps
them absorb nutrients through the
surface, especially the potassium from
bananas and the minerals in molasses.
As a result, the plant's photosynthesis
and metabolism are enhanced, helping the
orchid grow more healthily.
[Music]
During the growth process, orchid leaves
are prone to collecting dust or
bacteria. Wiping the leaves with this
natural solution not only cleans the
surface, but also helps eliminate mold
or harmful pathogens.
[Music]
The natural sugars in the mixture create
a gentle polishing effect, making the
leaves lush and glossy without the need
for chemicals. As a result, the orchid
looks fresher and more eye-catching.
[Music]
When the leaves are wellnourished and
kept clean, the plant will have stronger
resistance to weather changes and pests.
the leaves become sturdier, less likely
to fall off, and always full of
vitality.
[Music]
Uh, you only need to wipe the leaves
with this mixture about one to two times
a month.
[Music]
Step two, use this solution to water
directly at the base of the orchid.
When watering the banana fertilizer and
molasses mixture at the base, the orchid
is provided with a natural source of
potassium, sugars, and beneficial
minerals.
When watering the banana fertilizer and
molasses mixture at the base, the orchid
is provided with a natural source of
potassium, sugars, and beneficial
minerals.
These nutrients penetrate deeply into
the growing medium, stimulating healthy
root growth, the emergence of new
shoots, and enhancing the plant's
ability to absorb water and nutrients
from the environment.
For orchids in the recovery stage after
drought, yellowing leaves, or repotting,
watering with this gentle mixture acts
like a natural vitamin dose.
Um, for orchids in the recovery stage
after drought, yellowing leaves or
repotting, watering with this gentle
mixture acts like a natural vitamin
dose. It not only provides timely
moisture, but also supplies energy for
the roots to regenerate quickly,
supporting the plant's vitality, leaf
development, and preparation for the new
blooming season.
[Music]
Step three, pour the mixture into a
spray bottle and gently mist the leaves,
stems, and the entire orchid plant.
When spraying this mixture over the
entire plant, the natural nutrients from
bananas and molasses will absorb through
the epidermis of the leaves and stems.
As a result, the plant is not only
nourished through the roots, but also
absorbs additional nutrients directly
from the outside, helping it recover
faster and develop more fully.
[Music]
You only need to carry out these care
steps about one to two times a month.
This frequency is just right to provide
nutrients, help the plant recover from
stress, and maintain the orchid's
vitality without causing overload.
Step four. After spraying, use a dry
cloth to gently wipe off any remaining
water on the leaves and in the leaf
crevices.
Wiping off the excess water helps
prevent prolonged dampness in the leaf
crevices and at the base of the leaves,
areas where mold or bacteria can easily
develop and cause rot.
[Music]
Gently wiping with a dry cloth helps the
leaf surface quickly return to a dry,
airy state, allowing the leaves to
breathe better.
This is especially beneficial for the
photosynthesis process, helping the
plant absorb light effectively and grow
healthily.
After soaking for about 20 minutes,
gently take the orchid pot out and place
it in a spot with gentle sunlight.
Soft morning or late afternoon light
will help the plant dry naturally while
also stimulating photosynthesis without
causing heat stress.
[Music]
And here's the result after 3 weeks.
You can see that the root system is
growing very strongly with many new
roots emerging densely and full of
vitality.
[Music]
This is a sign that the plant is
recovering well and is ready to enter
its next vigorous growth stage.
[Music]
These new roots play a very important
role, helping the plant absorb water and
nutrients more effectively.
When the roots grow strong and healthy,
the plant will quickly recover, become
lush and green, and soon prepare for the
next blooming cycle.
[Music]
And especially you can see that the
leaves have become much more glossy and
green than before.
The vibrant green color and firm healthy
leaf surface are signs that the plant is
absorbing nutrients well and growing
steadily.
[Music]
Um, with this simple and natural method,
you can absolutely take good care of
your orchid pots at home.
With just a little patience and love,
the plant will grow strong and soon
bloom beautifully as a gift to you.
What do you think about the way I
revived that little orchid? Don't
hesitate to leave a comment and share
your thoughts. I'd love to hear your
feedback, stories, and experiences.
I hope you'll enjoy this video. Um, if
you find it helpful, don't forget to
like and subscribe to the channel so you
won't miss upcoming tips on natural and
simple orchid care.
Thank you for taking the time to watch
the video. Wishing you happiness, good
health, and plenty of beautiful orchids
in your living space.
[Music]
Welcome to my channel where we share our
passion for orchid care and enjoy the
gentle beauty that nature offers.
You can see this orchid has yellowed
leaves and a rotting base. Many people
think it's dead and quickly throw it
away, but the truth might surprise you.
Now, let's see how I revived this orchid
that seemed beyond hope. You'll witness
a miracle born from the simplest things.
First, I will remove all the yellow
leaves that have been infected by fungus
to prevent the disease from spreading
and to help the plant recover more
easily.
Next, I will cut off the old withered
flower spikes along with the rotting
roots so the plant no longer has to
waste energy on dead parts and can focus
on recovering.
[Music]
After that, I will gently remove all the
infected leaf sheets as this is where
fungi and bacteria often hide and
continue to harm the plant if not
treated in time.
[Music]
Leave a comment and let me know which
country you're watching from. It's
wonderful that we can connect and share
with each other from all around the
world.
To begin the recovery process for the
orchid, I prepare about 20 gram of
onion, a familiar kitchen ingredient,
but one that has strong antibacterial
properties and supports the plant's
growth from within.
Then I add about 600 ml of water to
blend with the onion, helping to release
the essential nutrients needed for the
plant's recovery process.
Bulbs and sprouts, especially onions,
contain many essential minerals,
vitamins, and amino acids that play a
vital role in nourishing the roots,
stimulating growth, and boosting the
plant's resistance.
Then, place the orchid into this mixture
and soak it for about 20 minutes so the
nutrients can deeply penetrate the
roots, helping to cleanse pathogens and
stimulate a more effective recovery
process.
After soaking for about 20 minutes, take
the orchid out and hang it in a cool,
airy place to let it dry naturally,
which helps prevent fungal infections
uh and creates the best conditions for
the roots to start recovering.
[Music]
While waiting for the plant to dry, I
reuse a used plastic bottle and turn it
into an orchid pot. A simple,
cost-effective, and environmentally
friendly method.
[Music]
If you haven't subscribed yet, please
hit the subscribe button to support me
and never miss any orchid growing tips.
It's truly wonderful to have you along
on this journey.
[Music]
I make an extra drainage hole at a fixed
position so that when growing the orchid
in a semi-hydroponic style, the water
level in the pot stays stable and
doesn't rise too high, which could lead
to root rot.
Then I continue to make several small
holes around the sides of the bottle to
ensure the roots stay well ventilated,
reduce water stagnation, and help the
plant grow more healthily.
[Music]
Uh with just a few simple steps, you now
have a convenient recycled orchid pot
that saves money and also helps protect
the environment.
I use crushed pine bark to grow orchids.
It's an ideal growing medium because it
retains moisture well, drains quickly,
and provides a well ventilated
environment for healthy root
development.
[Music]
I use clear plastic wrap to create a
sealed cover like a mini greenhouse.
This method helps retain moisture and
maintain a stable temperature, creating
ideal conditions for the orchid to
recover more quickly.
[Music]
After planting, you can reuse the onion
juice mixture used for soaking to
lightly water the roots and growing
medium. This helps with antibacterial
protection, stimulates root growth, and
boosts the orchid's ability to recover.
[Music]
After watering, soak the plant for about
5 minutes. Then you should discard the
excess onion water to avoid water
accumulation in the pot, which helps
reduce the risk of mold and root rot.
[Music]
You only need to mist with clean water
about once every 5 days, just enough to
maintain light humidity for the plant
without soaking the growing medium,
allowing the orchid roots to develop in
a well ventilated environment.
Place the orchid pot in a cool spot with
gentle light and good airflow. Now, all
you need is patience. The orchid will
gradually recover and soon return to its
healthy state.
And here is the result after 3 weeks.
[Music]
When the orchid loses its crown, meaning
the main growing tip is no longer
present, the plant immediately activates
its regeneration mechanism by developing
a new growth point. And those are
exactly the two young shoots you see
here.
Continue
misting with clean water every 5 days to
maintain gentle humidity, creating ideal
conditions for the roots and new shoots
to grow strong and healthy.
[Music]
And here is the result after 3 months.
From an orchid that seemed beyond
saving, it has now made a strong
comeback with two baby orchids growing
from the mother stem, each with healthy
roots and vibrant green leaves full of
life.
[Music]
From now on, to help the orchid continue
growing healthily, I use unsweet
sweetened fresh milk as a natural care
method. It not only provides nutrients,
but also helps boost the plant's
resistance.
[Music]
I mix one spoon of unsweetened fresh
milk with two spoons of clean water to
create a diluted solution that is easy
for the orchid to absorb and safe for
its roots when applied.
[Music]
I use a cotton ball soaked in the
diluted milk solution and gently wipe
both the top and underside of the
leaves. This method not only helps clean
off dust but also supports the removal
of insects, fungi, and harmful bacteria
on the leaf surface.
When the stamata on the leaf surface are
cleaned, they open up, allowing the
orchid to photosynthesize more
effectively. As a result, the plant
absorbs nutrients better and the leaves
become healthier, greener, and full of
vitality.
Uh, I hope this video content provides
you with helpful knowledge making orchid
care at home easier and more effective.
I hope you'll enjoy this video. If you
find it helpful, don't forget to like
and subscribe to the channel so you
won't miss miss upcoming tips on natural
and simple orchid care.
Don't forget to turn on the notification
bell so you won't miss future videos
where I'll continue sharing many helpful
and natural tips for easy orchid care at
home.
Thank you for watching until the end of
the video. Wishing you joy, patience,
and success on your journey of caring
for your beloved orchids. See you in the
next videos. Goodbye.
[Music]
Welcome to the little garden full of
joy. Let's explore the beauty of
orchids.
If your orchids become weak or fail to
bloom due to improper care, don't worry.
Improve their environment, provide
proper nutrition, and adjust watering.
With patience, they will recover and
bloom again.
Let's get started.
This is an orchid infected with leaf rot
caused by a fungus.
[Music]
We need to separate the diseased plant
from other orchids.
Now I will share how to restore this
this rotten orchid with only one leaf
left.
[Music]
Cut off all damaged roots.
If you haven't subscribe to the channel
yet, please click the subscribe button
to support me and not miss any orchid
growing tips. It's great to have
company.
[Music]
Leave fresh roots like this.
Then rinse with water.
[Music]
In addition to the English dub, we've
now created dubs in French, German,
Spanish, Spanish, Portuguese, Japanese,
Hindi, and Indonesian to help you hear
and understand the content more easily.
[Music]
Oh, this leaf also falls.
Watch me restore this leafless orchid.
[Music]
Cut off all rotten parts of the orchid
stem.
This will help prevent the orchid stem
from rotting further.
[Music]
Then sprinkle cinnamon powder on the cut
to help the wound heal quickly.
[Music]
Cinnamon powder has very good
antibacterial and antiseptic properties.
[Music]
Then place in a cool place for 2 hours
to let the cut dry completely.
[Music]
Take one clove of garlic and mince it.
Garlic contains allisonin, a substance
with powerful antibacterial and
antifungal effects. Helps prevent
diseases and infections in orchids.
[Music]
Add 500 ml of water at room temperature.
Cover and leave for 2 hours so that the
garlic's nutrients are completely
dissolved in the water.
[Music]
After 2 hours, filter out the residue to
get garlic juice.
[Music]
After seeing that the cut has dried,
soak the orchid roots in garlic water
for 10 minutes.
[Music]
This helps to disinfect the orchid,
preventing rot while also stimulating
its growth and quick recovery.
[Music]
After soaking for 10 minutes, take the
orchid out and plant it in a new pot to
help it help it recover and grow faster.
[Music]
Use sterilized dry moss to grow plants.
Dry moss will absorb moisture and help
the cut heal completely.
[Music]
Then leave it in a cool place and do not
water it for 1 week to let the cut heal
completely.
This garlic water is used to water other
orchids in the garden.
[Music]
Nutrients found in garlic, such as
calcium, potassium, and selenium, help
stimulate the growth of orchid roots,
helping the plant recover quickly.
[Music]
Do this every two weeks to increase the
orchid's resistance and supplement
nutrients for the orchid.
[Music]
Garlic also has the effect of repelling
insects. So, it helps protect plant
leaves.
[Music]
After one week, we start watering the
orchids again.
[Music]
Then use recycled plastic bottles to
create a miniature greenhouse to grow
orchids. It's
[Music]
spray water every time the growing
medium and orchid are dry.
[Music]
Cover and place in a cool, well-lit
place.
[Music]
results after 1 month.
You can see a new baby orchid being
revived from the trunk of an old dying
orchid.
New roots also grow a lot, which will
help the baby orchids grow faster.
From a bare orchid stem, an extremely
healthy baby orchid has now been
revived.
[Music]
When the root system is strong, we
fertilize it to help the orchid grow
faster.
[Music]
Take 1/2 teaspoon of flour.
Add 500 ml of room temperature water,
about two cups.
Using wheat flour helps stimulate the
growth of beneficial microorganisms in
orchid pots, helping increase the
plant's ability to absorb water and
nutrients.
Wait 1 hour before using to fertilize
orchids.
[Music]
One hour later.
Filter out residue.
[Music]
Then water this mixture every 2 weeks.
Continue
[Music]
[Applause]
to cover and place in a cool place with
enough light.
[Music]
results after 2 months.
>> Uh the baby orchids have grown and
developed very healthily.
[Music]
The root system grows very healthy.
Leaves are green and sturdy.
[Music]
Continue using fertilizer from wheat
flour to water the orchids.
[Music]
Wheat flour contains a lot of
carbohydrates which serves as food for
beneficial microorganisms in the soil or
orchid growing medium.
[Music]
Um these microorganisms help improve
soil structure, enhance the ability to
decompose organic substances and help
plants absorb nutrients better.
[Music]
results. After 3 months,
the orchid has grown stronger and
produced buds.
[Music]
growing roots help the orchid absorb
nutrients best.
[Music]
The leaves are green and strong.
This leaf has a rot disease, so it must
be removed immediately.
[Music]
Continue
to use wheat flour fertilizer to water
the orchids every 2 weeks.
[Music]
Results after 4 months
from the bare orchid stem. It has now
revived and grown into a mature orchid.
[Music]
The flowers bloom brightly and
beautifully.
[Music]
If you find the video meaningful, please
like and share so more people know.
[Music]
And don't forget to subscribe to the
channel to help my channel reach 10
million subscriptions soon.
[Music]
Thank you for watching and supporting my
channel.
[Music]
Wishing you success and joy in life.
Goodbye and see you again in the next
videos.