welcome to my
channel if you have orchids after
[Music]
blooming if all the flowers have fallen
don't rush to throw them
away uh let me tell you how to help
these branches continue to bloom
strongly again
[Music]
these nodes can continue to bloom very
well
[Music]
when you eat bananas don't throw away
the peel
[Music]
thinly sliced bananana peels contain
many vitamins and minerals that are very
good for the bud formation
process please comment to me which
country you are watching the video from
it's great that we can chat together
from all over the world
[Music]
[Applause]
soak banana peels in 1 liter of boiled
[Music]
water then take 3 tblsp of coffee
grounds
[Music]
then soak this coffee grounds in 1 liter
of boiled water
then wait for the water to
[Music]
cool after the water cools filter to
remove sediment
[Music]
dip a cotton ball in water extracted
from coffee grounds and wash the
[Music]
leaves helps eliminate pests and
diseases of orchids
[Music]
and leaves will photosynthesize
better um if you haven't subscribed to
the channel yet please subscribe to
support me and not miss any orchid care
tips
[Music]
mix these two types
together dip cotton balls in this water
and clip them to nodes that are likely
to continue blooming
[Music]
do it once a
week will help stimulate rapid Sprout
growth
[Music]
uh keep the cotton pad on the branch
like that for 20 minutes
and then remove
[Music]
it then water The Roots once a week
soak it for 10 minutes then lift it
[Music]
out and spray this water once a week to
help supplement nutrients through the
leaves
[Music]
after 20 minutes remove the cotton pad
and then place the plant in a place with
lots of light so it can bloom easily
1 month
[Music]
later many buds have grown
if you encounter any difficulties during
the Orchid growing process don't
hesitate to comment I am always ready to
support you so you can grow healthy
orchids and Bloom lots of flowers
[Music]
cons
Pony if there in
[Music]
then place the plant in a place with
lots of light so it can bloom
[Music]
easily after the next one month
from the dry branches many beautiful
flowers have sprouted and
[Music]
bloomed the leaves are strong and sturdy
very resistant to pests and diseases
[Music]
the flower color is also more vibrant
than
[Music]
usual hope the video will help you a lot
if you find it interesting please like
share and subscribe to the channel to
help my channel reach 1 million
subscribers soon
[Music]
my videos have subtitles in many
different languages so you can choose
the appropriate
[Music]
language thank you for watching the
video good luck and see you in the next
videos
[Music]
hello everyone to easily care for
orchids to always grow healthily there
are more flower Buds and Flowers stay on
the branches longer today I share a very
easy way to keep orchids growing
healthily
[Music]
when eating bananas don't throw away the
peel because banana peels contain many
nutrients especially organic potassium
very good for the growth of buds flowers
and has anti-d drought effects
[Music]
I cut the banana peel thinly and put it
in a jar
[Music]
next I took a piece of
bread bread contains phosphorus which
plays an important role in plant growth
especially stimulating root growth
[Music]
adding one teaspoon of yeast helps
decompose organic matter faster and
prevents it from
[Music]
rotting and adding a spoonful of sugar
helps nourish the growth of beneficial
microorganisms
[Music]
add 500 M warm
water then leave in a cool place for 3
[Music]
weeks 3 weeks
later take 2 L of water which is
equivalent to about 528 US gallons
[Music]
um after 3 weeks of composting we have
this wonderful
[Music]
fertilizer take 50 mm which is
equivalent to about
0.0132 us
[Music]
Gall then mix into water
method one fertilize The
[Music]
Roots water each Orchid pot with this
water 5 to 10 spoons per week
[Music]
this fertilizer provides potassium an
important mineral that improves plant
health and vitality
[Music]
this type of fertilizer also helps
retain water and enhances the plant's
ability to absorb
[Music]
water beneficial fungi microa will grow
to help the plant more easily absorb
nutrients from the Orchid growing medium
[Music]
method
two use this water to spray on the
leaves
[Music]
helps supplement nutrients through
leaves very
[Music]
effectively helps orchid leaves become
strong and healthy
[Music]
and spray it on aerial roots to help
aerial Roots grow and easily absorb
nutrients in the
[Music]
air um you should do it early in the
morning and by noon the leaves will dry
very quickly
[Music]
do this once a week to keep the Orchid
healthy
[Music]
method
three now I wash the leaves with this
[Music]
water beneficial microorganisms will
help kill mold and insects very
effectively
do this every 2 weeks to protect your
[Music]
orchids let's check the result together
after fertilizing orchids will always be
green and
[Music]
healthy pottassium in banana peels and
bread helps flower buds grow strongly
[Music]
when the flowers bloom they will stay on
the branches for a long
[Music]
time flowers can last on branch for up
to 6 months before
[Music]
fading hopefully the video will help you
a lot in taking better care of orchids
at home
[Music]
next I will show you how to revive a
rotten Orchid like
[Music]
this when the orchid has withered all
the leaves only the stem and Roots
remain do not rush to throw it away
[Music]
here are still fresh
FRS first cut off all damaged rotten
roots
[Music]
apply a molten Candle on the cut so that
the water does not penetrate the
[Music]
tree use 2 teaspoons of cinnamon
powder for
[Music]
[Applause]
adding 1 liter of boiled water is
equivalent to about 2642 us gall
[Music]
close the lid and wait for the water to
cool the water has cooled down
[Music]
filter out residue
soak orchids in this water for 30
minutes
[Music]
the rest of the water I will spray on
other orchids to help protect the Orchid
from insects and fungal diseases
[Music]
after soaking for 30 minutes plant
it uh using pine bark and dry pmus Stone
to plant will help absorb moisture in
the roots making the Orchid roots not
[Music]
rot add some dry moss on the
face put in a cool and well- lit place
for 7
days after 7 days you can spray water to
keep keep the plants
[Music]
moist cover with a clear vented plastic
container and wait for the plant to
revive after 3 weeks
[Music]
a sprout has
sprouted uh spray water once every 5
days to keep the Sprouts
[Music]
moist after 2 months
hope this sharing content will help you
in resurrecting weak orchids to grow
[Music]
again if you you find it interesting
remember to like share and subscribe so
that my channel can soon reach 10
million
subscribers the video I've created many
subtitles you can choose the appropriate
language to understand my
[Music]
shares good luck to you
all see you in the next videos
hello
[Music]
everyone how are
you for orchids to be healthy Bloom many
flowers and even bloom all year round
today I continue to share new methods
make organic fertilizer for
[Music]
orchids let's let's get
started first take 1 teaspoon of baking
soda and put it in a
[Music]
cup then mix in 4 cups of water about 1
lit
[Music]
do you have pets how do you like
it method one
use a soft cotton soaked in baking soda
solution to gently wipe the top and
bottom of the
[Music]
leaves baking soda has mild
antibacterial properties helping to
clean leaf surfaces and prevent the
growth of fungi and
[Music]
bacteria baking soda helps prevent some
common fungal diseases in orchids such
as powdery mildew
[Music]
baking soda solution helps remove dirt
and residue making leaves shiny and
easier to photosynthesize
[Music]
baking soda can help adjust the pH of
water creating a better environment for
plant growth
[Music]
apply one to two times a month in this
way to protect orchid leaves and keep
them green and shiny
[Music]
method
two next I took two
[Music]
grapes add 1 cup of water about 250 m
then
puree grapes contain many vitamins
minerals and natural sugars which help
provide nutrition for orchids
[Music]
nutrients and grapes support
photosynthesis and plant
[Music]
growth then filter out the residue
mix with four cups of water about 1
[Music]
liter then mix the baking soda solution
with the grape juice solution
stir the solution well and you have a
great liquid fertilizer for your
orchids now take this water and water
each Orchid pot
[Music]
grapes contain many vitamins minerals
and natural sugars which help provide
energy for the
[Music]
plant baking soda has mild antibacterial
and antifungal properties helping to
prevent diseases in orchids
[Music]
baking soda can help adjust the pH of
the environment creating better
conditions for nutrient
[Music]
absorption nutrients and grapes support
photosynthesis promoting leaf and root
growth
[Music]
grape solution provides necessary
moisture for plants helping to maintain
freshness
[Music]
when you combine these two solutions you
can take advantage of the nutritional
benefits of grapes and the protective
properties of baking
soda soaking in this water for 20
minutes minut will be good for your
[Music]
orchid method
three if you have many Orchid pots you
can choose to spray them with a spray
bottle
spray the entire
Orchid spray both the top and bottom of
the leaves
[Music]
helps remove fungus insects and dirt on
leaves um baking soda helps clean the
amount of industrial Garden salt that is
still left on the leaves when purchased
helping the leaves Stay Green and
shiny and this is the same as using
foler fertilizer for
[Music]
orchids do it one to two times month to
supplement nutrition for orchids
[Music]
after soaking for 20
[Applause]
minutes take the Orchid pot out and
place it in a place with with lots of
scattered light for the Orchid to
photosynthesize
[Music]
let's see what the results
are this combination helps orchids grow
healthier thereby increasing their
ability to bloom making them larger and
more beautiful
[Music]
when you combine grapes and baking soda
you provide more than just nutrition but
also protect plants from diseases
creating an optimal environment for
[Music]
growth remember fertilizer is very good
but if the Orchid lacks light the plant
will be weak and grow slowly
[Music]
therefore you need to place the Orchid
pot where there is a lot of scattered
light for the Orchid to
[Music]
thrive the photosynthesis process will
help orchid's metabolism go well
[Music]
take care of your Orchids with all the
love you have for
plants and flowers are guaranteed to
bloom throughout your
[Music]
garden hope you will like the video
if you like remember to like and share
so more people
know and if you haven't subscribed yet
subscribe to my support
[Music]
Channel thank you for viewing I always
pray for God to bless
[Music]
everyone goodbye and see you again in
the next
videos for
[Music]