Welcome to the happiness garden where
every flower tells a story and every
leaf brings a small joy in life. Let's
explore, care for, and enjoy the natural
beauty around us.
[Music]
Today, we will prepare garlic fertilizer
together for our beloved orchids,
helping them stay healthy from roots to
leaves and make each flower shine.
We will need to prepare two fresh garlic
cloves, the main ingredient that makes
the fertilizer powerful and nourishes
the orchids from within.
Cut the garlic into small pieces so the
nutrients can easily dissolve and
penetrate deeply into the soil. Garlic
is an excellent natural fertilizer for
orchids, helping them stay healthy, grow
new roots, and bloom more brilliantly.
[Music]
Place the garlic along with its peel
into a clean jar, preparing for the
natural fertilizer fermentation step to
help the orchids grow strong.
[Music]
If you haven't subscribed to the channel
yet, please click the subscribe button
to support me and not miss any orchid
growing tips. It's wonderful to have you
with me.
[Music]
Next, pour one liter of water into the
jar, allowing the nutrients from the
garlic and peel to fully dissolve.
[Music]
Let the mixture soak for for a few hours
so that every nutrient from the garlic
penetrates deeply and is ready to
nourish the orchids.
[Music]
After a few hours, stir the mixture well
so that the nutrients are fully blended,
ready to nourish the orchids from roots
to leaves.
[Music]
Then strain the mixture to remove the
residue, keeping only the nutrientrich
solution for the orchids.
[Music]
Step one, after preparing the
fertilizer, use a soft cloth to soak up
the solution and gently wipe both the
top and underside of the leaves, helping
the plant absorb the nutrients to the
fullest.
Do each leaf one by one, moving gently
to avoid harming the plant. After
wiping, you will see the orchid leaves
shiny and full of vitality, ready for
the next growth and blooming process.
Wiping the leaves with garlic solution
helps remove dirt clinging to the leaf
surface, allowing the leaves to perform
photosynthesis more effectively, so the
orchids receive more energy to grow.
[Music]
Garlic water also contains natural
nutrients that help strengthen the leaf
leaf's protective membrane, increase
disease resistance, and reduce the risk
of pest attacks, keeping the leaves
healthy.
[Music]
When wiping both the top and underside
of the leaves, the nutrients from garlic
penetrate the leaves, directly
nourishing the leaf tissues and
supporting metabolic processes, helping
the plant grow balanced and stronger.
[Music]
After being wiped with garlic solution,
the orchid leaves become shiny, smooth,
and full of vitality while also
supporting the future blooming process,
helping each flower open brilliantly and
last longer last longer.
[Music]
After completing the leaf wiping for all
the orchids, you can be assured that
they have been thoroughly cared for,
fully absorbing the nutrients from
garlic, ready for strong growth and
blooming in the near future.
[Music]
Carry out this method once or twice a
month to keep the orchids always healthy
with shiny leaves and strong root
development.
Please comment and let me know which
country you are watching the video from.
It's wonderful that we can chat together
from all around the world.
[Music]
Method two, you can use this mixture to
water the roots and growing medium
directly, helping the orchids naturally
absorb nutrients from the roots to the
tips.
[Music]
When watering the garlic solution
directly onto the roots and growing
medium, the nutrients penetrate deeply
into the root system, helping the plant
absorb better and grow strong new roots.
Watering evenly onto the growing medium
also helps balance moisture and enhances
beneficial microorganisms, creating an
ideal environment for the orchids to
grow strong and sustainably.
The garlic water mixture also has
natural antibacterial properties,
protecting the roots and growing medium
from pathogens, keeping the plant
healthy and ready for vibrant blooms in
the coming seasons.
After finishing watering the roots and
growing medium, you can finish by wiping
the leaves with this mixture. Both
adding nutrients and making the leaves
shiny and full of vitality.
Method three, you can pour this mixture
into a spray bottle and mist it evenly
over the leaves, both top and underside,
as well as the crevices of the orchid,
allowing the nutrients to penetrate
deeply and nourish the plant from every
direction.
[Music]
When spraying the garlic water mixture
onto the leaves, the nutrients evenly
coat the surface, helping the leaves
absorb quickly and nourish the plant
from the outside in.
[Music]
Spraying evenly into all the crevices of
the plant also helps protect the orchids
from pests thanks to the natural
antibacterial properties of garlic.
[Music]
The garlic water mixture also helps
balance moisture on the leaves, keeping
them smooth, shiny, and full of
vitality.
[Music]
Regularly spraying this mixture also
stimulates metabolism and promotes
better growth for the plant, keeping
roots, leaves, and flowers healthy.
If you haven't subscribed to the channel
yet, please click the subscribe button
to support me and not miss any orchid
growing tips. It's wonderful to have you
along for the journey.
Spray this mixture once or twice a
month, alternating with regular
watering, so the orchids stay healthy,
the leaves remain shiny, and nutrients
are absorbed consistently.
After spraying, you can soak the entire
orchid pot in this mixture for about 20
minutes, allowing the nutrients to
penetrate deeply into the roots and
growing medium, helping the plant stay
healthy from roots to tips.
[Music]
Uh after soaking for about 20 minutes,
gently remove the orchid pot to avoid
water logging and ensure the roots
absorb the nutrients optimally.
If the leaves are still wet, use a soft
cloth to blot all the water on the leaf
surfaces and in the leaf crevices,
helping the leaves stay dry, clean, and
preventing mold.
Wiping off the water droplets also helps
remove any small debris or dust
remaining on the leaves, keeping the
leaf surface clean and supporting more
effective photosynthesis.
In addition, drying the leaves helps
reduce the risk of pests developing on
wet surfaces, keeping the orchids
healthy and ready to absorb nutrients
from other care methods.
[Music]
Then place the orchid pot in a spot with
gentle sunlight.
No matter how good the fertilizer is, if
the plant lacks light, it will struggle
to synthesize nutrients and bloom
brilliantly.
[Music]
And here are the results after 3 weeks
of care.
You can see the orchid leaves becoming
lush, green, and glossy. A sign of a
plant being properly cared for.
[Music]
Uh these lush green leaves are not only
visually appealing but also act as a
natural shield helping the orchids
resist pests and harsh environmental
conditions.
And when the leaves are healthy and
shiny, you will see the entire orchid
full of vitality, ready for the next
vibrant blooms.
You can see new roots growing strong,
smooth, and white, spreading evenly,
indicating that the orchid is absorbing
nutrients optimally from the growing
medium.
The old roots also grow densely,
anchoring firmly into the growing
medium, creating a solid foundation for
the orchid to continue thriving and
bloom brilliantly.
[Music]
You will see vibrant flowers blooming on
the stems for a long time, spreading
their colors and bringing complete
beauty to the orchid.
Um the flowers not only bloom for long
for a long time but also keep their
bright colors bringing lasting beauty to
the entire space.
[Music]
Admiring the vibrant longlasting blooms
will fill you with inspiration to keep
caring for and loving your little garden
everyday.
[Music]
Today's video comes to an end here.
Thank you for staying with me until the
very end, and I hope you found new
inspiration to care for your orchids.
If you found this video helpful, please
support by liking and sharing it so more
people can learn how to care for
orchids.
[Music]