Hello everyone. I hope you are having a
wonderful day and are ready to spend
some time relaxing beside the beautiful
orchid pots.
This orchid is having a problem with
yellow leaves. The cause is often
insects sucking the plant sap creating
small wounds and then fungi and bacteria
enter through those wounds.
When the plant encounters this disease,
the leaves, although still turgid, fall
off very quickly.
You can see that the entire orchid has
only one healthy leaf left, while all
the other leaves have been infected.
If not treated promptly, the spots on
the leaves will quickly spread and cause
the orchid to become severely weakened.
I cut here to check the inside of the
stem to see how far the disease has
spread.
[Music]
I will remove all the infected leaves to
protect the orchid.
[Music]
If you haven't subscribed to the channel
yet, press the subscribe button to
support me and not miss any orchid
growing tips. It's wonderful to have you
along.
This spot is exactly where the fungi
reside, so it needs to be removed to
protect the plant.
Please comment and let me know which
country you are watching the video from.
It's wonderful that we can chat together
from all around the world.
[Music]
Cement helps create a protective layer
on the orchid's cut, preventing fungi
and bacteria from entering, thereby
effectively preventing stem and leaf
rot.
[Music]
Then you prepare 5 tsp of cement.
Then you mix 5 L of water to prepare the
solution.
[Music]
Stir the solution well and then let the
sediment settle.
[Music]
We're better.
After about 10 minutes, when the
sediment has settled, uh we pour off the
clear water from the top and discard the
sediment at the bottom.
[Music]
Then use a soft cloth to soak up the
solution and gently wipe the leaves and
stem of the orchid thoroughly.
The cement water will create a
protective layer on the cut, preventing
fungi and bacteria from entering. As a
result, the orchid is effectively
protected against stem and leaf rot.
[Music]
Then gently wash the orchid in this
solution, allowing the leaves and stem
to be thoroughly cleaned.
[Music]
Now scoop this solution and pour it
directly onto the orchid's stem in the
pot while also soaking the entire
growing medium.
During the watering process, you should
also take the opportunity to wash the
cut on the stem with this and with this
solution. By carefully attending to such
small details, the orchid will be better
protected and have a chance to recover
quickly.
Then soak the entire orchid pot in this
solution for about 10 minutes so that
the stems, roots, and growing medium are
thoroughly cleaned.
[Music]
I also soak the moss in this solution
for about 10 to 20 minutes to treat the
growing medium before replanting the
orchid, helping to eliminate any
remaining fungi in the medium.
[Music]
Next, prepare 10 eggshells which will
provide calcium and important nutrients
for the orchid.
[Music]
Put the eggshells into one liter of
boiling water to soak, helping to
extract the nutrients into the water.
[Music]
Cover and let the solution cool
completely before use.
Eggshells also help increase slight
alkalinity, aiding the orchid roots to
grow healthy.
In the meantime, I recycle plastic
bottles into tools for propagating
orchids. Recycling is not only
convenient, but also helps protect the
environment.
Pay close attention and follow me so
that your orchid can also grow healthy.
[Music]
After the water is cooled, pour off the
liquid and discard the eggshells.
[Music]
Then add three vitamin B1 tablets to the
solution. Each tablet containing 2.5
millig.
[Music]
The combination of eggshells and vitamin
B1 will create a nutrient-rich mixture,
helping the orchid develop strong roots
and increase its resistance.
Then soak the upper stem and leaves of
the orchid in this solution for about 20
minutes, allowing the nutrients to
penetrate deeply and nourish the plant
to grow healthy.
After soaking for 20 minutes, remove the
plant and gently wipe the leaves and
stem dry.
Next, apply dry cement to the cut,
helping the wound from rotting and
healing faster.
[Music]
Now we take out the moss and proceed to
replant the orchid.
[Music]
I put the growing medium into the tool
that was prepared beforehand.
[Music]
Then place the orchid stem and leaves
into the growing medium to replant it.
Cover the tool and you will have a
miniature greenhouse for propagating the
orchid.
[Music]
Next, pour a little clean water into a
tray and place the orchid propagation
pots on it.
[Music]
and place the orchid pots in a well
ventilated area avoiding direct
sunlight. The water will be absorbed
into the growing medium from the bottom
of the pot, helping to maintain moisture
without becoming soggy. This creates an
ideal environment to stimulate the
orchid to grow new roots.
After about 1 week, start misting to
keep the leaves moist, doing it once
every 5 days.
[Music]
With the lower part of the stem that
remains in the old pot, you should also
water it with a fertilizer mixture made
from eggshells and vitamin B1 about 1 to
two times per month.
Then pour a little clean water into a
bowl and place the orchid pot inside.
The water will be absorbed from the
bottom of the pot into the growing
medium, helping to maintain moderate
moisture without water logging.
Next, use a transparent plastic bowl
with ventilation holes and cover the
orchid pot. It will act like a miniature
greenhouse, creating an ideal
environment for the orchid to grow and
recover.
Place the orchid pot in a well
ventilated area and after 1 week start
misting every 5 days to keep the leaves
moist.
[Music]
And here are the results after one month
of propagating the orchid.
[Music]
Wow. You can see that the top part of
the orchid has grown many new roots,
healthy and full of vitality.
This proves that the method of properly
caring for and propagating the orchid is
truly effective.
[Music]
Now let's observe the lower part of the
orchid stem.
Wow. You can see that up to two baby
orchids have grown from the mature stem
of the mother plant and they are growing
very healthily.
[Music]
Thus, with just familiar and common
ingredients found in every household, we
can still use them to effectively care
for and revive orchids at home.
What do you think about how I revived
this small orchid? Don't hesitate to
leave a comment and share your opinion.
I'm very eager to hear your feedback and
experiences.
When you care for your orchid with all
the love you have for plants, you will
be rewarded with vibrant flowers and
full of life.
These fresh flower buds not only bring
beauty, but also serve as proof of your
care and patience.
Continue to love and care for every leaf
and stem so that your orchid garden is
always lush and full of life.
During the process of growing orchids,
if you encounter any difficulties, don't
hesitate to leave a comment for me. I am
always ready to support you so that you
can grow healthy orchids that bloom
abundantly.
[Music]
If you find the content interesting and
meaningful, don't forget to like, share
so that many people can know about it
and subscribe to support me. Thank you
for always accompanying me.
Thank you for watching. Goodbye and
wishing you happiness and good health
along with your beautiful orchid pots.
[Music]