Welcome to the happiness garden, where
each orchid pot is a little story full
of hope. When we start growing orchids,
all of us share a common dream to see
vibrant blooms throughout all four
seasons.
That's why in today's video, I will
share with you how to care for orchids
using homemade organic fertilizer. With
just simple ingredients readily
available in every kitchen, you can help
your orchid grow strong from roots to
blooms.
By making use of easy to find,
inexpensive ingredients that still bring
surprising results, you not only save
money, but also help care for your
orchid in a more natural and sustainable
way.
The revival of an orchid pot not only
brings small daily joy, but also
contributes to creating a fresh,
peaceful, and vibrant living space
around you.
Uh, if you haven't subscribed to the
channel yet, please hit the subscribe
button to support me and not miss any
orchid growing tips. It's wonderful to
have you along.
Let's get started.
[Music]
Uh, the first ingredient I choose to
make natural fertilizer is used coffee
grounds. Those small and seemingly
useless coffee grounds contain many
beneficial nutrients that help improve
the soil and stimulate root development.
Just take about 20 g of used coffee
grounds and mix them with one liter of
warm water.
The second ingredient I use is molasses,
also known as blackstrap molasses. This
is a mineralrich ingredient that
provides a natural source of energy,
helping orchids absorb nutrients more
effectively and boosting their
resistance.
You only need one teaspoon of blackstrap
molasses to mix with the watering
solution.
[Music]
The next ingredient is proby yogurt.
Thanks to its natural probiotics and
enzymes, yogurt helps improve the
microbial environment in the growing
medium, supports nutrient absorption,
and stimulates stronger root
development.
Just one spoonful of probiotic yogurt is
enough.
After adding all the ingredients, stir
well, cover tightly, and let the mixture
sit for a day to ferment.
[Music]
The fermentation process will activate
beneficial microorganisms, making the
fertilizer more effective when used on
orchids.
[Music]
When an orchid is kept in the same pot
for too long, the roots can easily
become suffocated and rot due to
prolonged moisture. This can lead to
root rot and leaf decay.
From the outside, the roots may still
look healthy and green, but in reality,
they might have already started to rot
inside. These signs are often hard to
detect without careful inspection, and
the orchid can gradually weaken without
you even realizing it.
[Music]
When the roots are water logged and lack
ventilation, the orchid will quickly
weaken.
The leaves start turning yellow, become
soft and limp, and are highly
susceptible to fungal infections. This
is a clear sign that the growing
environment is no longer suitable, and
the plant needs timely rescue.
Therefore, it's best to repot the orchid
after about a year and a half to provide
better ventilation and a healthier
environment for the plant.
[Music]
As you can see, white fungal spots have
started to appear on the roots. a clear
sign that the orchid pot has become too
cramped and lacks proper ventilation.
When air circulation and moisture are
not balanced, fungal infections can
easily develop and attack the root
system.
At this point, you may also notice some
roots becoming hollow due to internal
rotting.
[Music]
At this stage, what you need to do is
cut off all the damaged, rotten or
hollow roots. This is an important step
to prevent the spread of fungal
infections and to create the conditions
for the orchid to recover in a healthy
way.
Uh with growing media that has been used
for a long time without being replaced
or treated, there is a high risk of
attracting harmful insects, especially
slugs and snails.
Because when the growing medium stays
moist for too long, it forms a slimy
moss layer which becomes an ideal
environment for them to breed and damage
the orchid roots.
[Music]
Next, carefully trim off any damaged
leaves that show signs of fungal
infection. If left untreated, these
infected spots can quickly spread to
healthy parts of the leaves, making the
orchid weaker and harder to recover.
Leave a comment and let me know which
country you're watching from. It's truly
wonderful that we can connect and chat
from all around the world.
After treating the roots and leaves, the
next step is to clean the old growing
medium.
This is an important step to completely
eliminate any remaining bacteria, fungi,
and insects, creating a safe foundation
for the orchid to grow back healthily.
Just take one teaspoon of baking soda
and mix it with water. Baking soda has
mild antibacterial properties that help
clean the old growing medium and prevent
mold, creating a safer environment for
the roots when repotting.
[Music]
Dissolve 1 tbsp of baking soda in 2 L of
clean water. This solution will be used
to soak and clean the old growing
medium, helping to eliminate bacteria,
fungi, and insects before reuse.
Soak the orchid roots and growing medium
in this mixture for about 20 minutes.
This is the ideal amount of time for the
antibacterial properties to take effect,
helping eliminate any remaining fungi
and insects before repotting.
In addition to its disinfecting effect,
the baking soda solution also helps
balance the pH in the growing medium. As
a result, the growing environment
becomes more stable, allowing the orchid
roots to absorb nutrients more
effectively and grow healthier.
Uh while waiting for the roots and
growing medium to soak, you can use a
soft cloth dipped in the baking soda
solution to gently wipe both the top and
underside of the leaves.
Wiping the leaves with the baking soda
mixture helps remove long-standing dust
and residue from the leaf surface.
Uh when the leaves are clean, the plant
can carry out photosynthesis more
effectively, which in turn supports the
orchid's growth and development.
[Music]
The baking soda solution has mild
antibacterial properties that help clean
fungal spores and bacteria from the
leaves. Regular wiping reduces the risk
of yellowing, rotting, or the appearance
of disease spots caused by
microorganisms.
Uh to prepare the new growing medium, I
use crushed pine bark as the main
component and mix in about 5 to 10%
moss. This combination provides good
irration for the orchid roots while
gently retaining moisture, helping the
plant grow steadily and healthfully.
[Music]
After mixing the new growing medium, you
should soak the entire mixture in the
baking soda solution for about 20
minutes. This helps thoroughly eliminate
any remaining bacteria, mold, or insect
eggs, ensuring a truly safe environment
for the orchid.
[Music]
After soaking the growing medium for
about 20 minutes, take the orchid out
and let it drain completely.
[Music]
After that, you also need to take out
the soaked growing medium and let it
drain completely before planting.
[Music]
Once everything has drained, you can
start planting the orchid in the new
pot.
Gently place the orchid in the center of
the pot. Arrange the roots neatly. Then
slowly fill in the growing medium around
them so the roots are held firmly but
still well ventilated.
[Music]
Repotting gives the orchid a fresh,
clean, and well ventilated living
environment. It's also an opportunity to
remove damaged roots, refresh the
growing medium, and create the best
conditions for the plant to recover,
grow vigorously, and bloom again soon.
[Music]
Next, I'll show you how to care for
orchid pots that have just finished
blooming, but aren't yet due for
repotting or a change of growing medium.
[Music]
For these orchids, gentle care and
proper nutrient supplementation will
help them recover quickly and prepare
for the next blooming cycle.
[Music]
I cut off the nodes that have already
bloomed and keep the unopened ones as
they still have the potential to grow
and bloom in the near future.
[Music]
This method prevents the plant from
wasting energy on faded flowers and
helps it focus its strength on nurturing
the remaining buds.
[Music]
I also trim off any damaged yellowing or
diseased leaves.
Removing weak leaves helps improve air
circulation, reduces the spread of
fungal diseases and creates better
conditions for healthy leaves to thrive.
[Music]
I also trim off any pseudo bulbs and
roots that are damaged, dried out, or
rotting.
[Music]
Uh, removing non-functional roots helps
prevent the spread of fungal infections
and allows the plant to focus on
nourishing the remaining healthy roots.
[Music]
If you encounter any difficulties while
growing orchids, don't hesitate to leave
a comment. I'm always here to support
you so you can grow healthy orchids that
bloom beautifully.
[Music]
Uh after trimming roots or leaves, I
sprinkle a bit of cinnamon powder on the
cut areas. Cinnamon has natural
antibacterial properties that help
prevent infections and promote quick
healing, creating favorable conditions
for the plant to recover.
[Music]
Uh after planting and treatment, you
should place the orchid pot in a cool,
well ventilated area, avoiding direct
sunlight for about 1 day to allow the
plant to stabilize.
After one day of fermentation, strain
out the residue and keep the clear
liquid from the mixture of coffee
grounds, molasses, and probiotic yogurt.
[Music]
This is a natural nutrient solution rich
in microorganisms and minerals which
helps orchids absorb nutrients easily
and recover quickly.
Uh before using, you need to dilute the
filtered liquid with one liter of clean
water. Diluting the solution makes it
gentler, suitable for the orchid roots,
and helps avoid shocking the plant.
Step one, pour the diluted mixture into
a spray bottle. This allows you to
evenly mist the solution onto the leaves
and roots, ensuring the plant absorbs
the nutrients gently and effectively.
[Music]
Step two, then evenly spray the solution
onto both the top and underside of the
leaves as well as the entire orchid
stem.
[Music]
The mixture contains many beneficial
microorganisms and natural minerals,
helping the orchid absorb nutrients
quickly through the leaves. As a result,
the roots grow stronger and the leaves
become glossy and firm.
[Music]
The beneficial bacteria from probiotic
yogurt act as a natural protective
layer, boosting the orchid's immune
system.
The plant becomes less susceptible to
fungal infections, especially in humid
conditions.
Coffee helps clean the leaves and
enhances their ability to absorb light.
When the plant photosynthesizes
efficiently, it produces more energy,
making it healthier and ready for the
next blooming cycle.
[Music]
After blooming or right after repotting,
orchids are often weak and need
recovery.
[Music]
This mixture provides gentle nutrients
that help the plant regenerate energy
and regain vitality quickly.
[Music]
Apply this spray mixture about twice a
month. Maintaining this routine will
keep your orchid healthy, promote good
growth, and enhance its natural disease
resistance.
Step two, water this mixture directly
onto the orchid's roots. This nourishes
the roots from within, promotes healthy
growth, and enhances the plant's ability
to absorb nutrients.
[Music]
Uh when watering the roots, the mixture
supplies beneficial microorganisms and
essential minerals that help the orchid
roots grow stronger, improve their grip,
and better absorb nutrients from the
growing medium.
[Music]
The natural nutrients in the mixture
help boost the orchid's vitality, making
the plant healthy with glossy green
leaves and less stress from
environmental changes.
The beneficial bacteria in the mixture
help inhibit the growth of harmful
fungi, reducing root rot and other root
related diseases.
[Music]
The mixture helps improve the growing
medium and the environment around the
roots, thereby supporting the roots to
absorb nutrients and water more
effectively, promoting sustainable plant
growth.
[Music]
After watering, you can soak the orchid
pot in this mixture for about 20 minutes
to allow the nutrients to penetrate
deeply into the roots.
[Music]
Step three, after spraying and watering,
use a soft cloth to gently wipe off any
water droplets on the leaf surfaces and
in the leaf axles.
Wiping off water droplets helps
eliminate moist environments where mold
and bacteria can easily grow. As a
result, the leaves stay healthy and are
less prone to fungal diseases.
When the leaves no longer have water
droplets, their surfaces become clean,
allowing light to reach them more easily
and supporting more efficient
photosynthesis.
Water trapped in the leaf axles can
attract small insects like aphids or
mites. Wiping it dry helps reduce the
risk of these pests nesting and harming
the plant.
Then gently take the orchid pot out and
place it in a spot with gentle sunlight.
Gentle light will help the plant absorb
the necessary energy without causing
stress or leaf burn. Creating an ideal
environment for recovery and growth.
[Music]
And here is the wonderful result after 3
weeks of care and recovery.
You can see the newly developed root
system is dense and healthy, proving the
effectiveness of the care and recovery
process.
The leaves become glossy green, healthy,
and firm, reflecting vibrant vitality
and the plant's optimal ability to
absorb nutrients from its surroundings.
This is a clear sign of an orchid that
is recovering well and growing
healthily.
[Music]
These roots will help the orchid absorb
more nutrients, creating a strong
foundation for sustainable growth.
[Music]
What do you think about how I revived
this little orchid? Don't hesitate to
leave a comment and share your thoughts.
I'd love to hear your feedback and
experiences.
Um, as long as you are patient and care
with the right techniques, the orchid
will not disappoint you. It will bloom
brilliantly, showing off its vibrant
colors as a well-deserved reward for
your dedication and love.
I hope you enjoy this video. If you find
it helpful, don't forget to like and
subscribe to the channel so you won't
miss future shares on natural and simple
orchid care methods.
Thank you for watching the video.
Wishing you happiness, good health, and
many vibrant orchid pots in your garden.