Welcome to Happiness
Garden. Today we will explore how to
care for weak orchids, helping them
recover strongly from roots to leaves
and bloom
beautifully. Don't forget to like and
subscribe so you won't miss any great
tips. You can see that this orchid
hasn't grown for 6 months. Its leaves
are gradually wilting. The roots are
rotting and the plant is on the brink of
dying. Have you ever encountered a
similar situation and didn't know what
to do to save your beloved
orchid? Uh, first I'll carefully remove
all the wilted and damaged leaves. This
is important because unhealthy leaves
can drain the plant's energy, hindering
its recovery and
growth. Next, I'll cut off all the
damaged roots. This is essential because
rotten roots can spread decay to healthy
parts of the plant, preventing it from
from absorbing nutrients properly.
[Music]
Uh, finally, I'll cut off any old flower
stems if present. This helps the plant
focus its energy on new growth rather
than wasting resources on fading
flowers.
[Music]
Then I'll rinse the orchid thoroughly
with water to remove any remaining dirt
or contaminants that could harm the
plant.
Uh, which country are you watching this
video from? Leave a comment and let me
know. It's It's amazing that we can
connect with each other from all around
the world.
[Music]
Then I'll place the orchid into an empty
jar. Now I'll add one liter of water
into the jar.
Next, I'll add 1 teaspoon of baking soda
to the water and mix it well.
Baking soda helps prevent mold and
bacterial diseases on
[Music]
orchids. Then I'll pour the baking soda
mixture into the jar and soak the orchid
in it for 10 minutes to disinfect the
roots and eliminate harmful mold and
bacteria.
This helps the orchid recover quickly,
prevent the recurrence of diseases, and
promote the plant's
[Music]
growth. Next, I'll take three teaspoon
of rice to make natural fertilizer for
the orchid.
Add it to one liter of
[Music]
water. Rice water contains vitamins and
minerals that stimulate root development
and improve the health of wilted
orchids. After rinsing the rice, you can
let the rice water ferment overnight to
create beneficial bacteria for the
orchid.
[Music]
After soaking the orchid in the baking
soda solution for 10 minutes, gently
remove the plant and pat it dry with a
soft cloth. This helps remove any
residual solution, prevents mold and
bacteria growth, and allows the orchid
to recover quickly and healthily.
[Music]
Then let it sit to allow the cut to heal
complete.
completely. This is moss for planting
orchids. I put it into the jar.
Then pour the baking soda mixture into
the jar to soak the
moss. Soaking the moss before planting
orchids helps eliminate harmful bacteria
and mold while providing a clean and
safe environment for the orchid's roots
to thrive.
I soak it overnight before using it to
plant the
orchids. Um, after one night, I take the
orchid and place the roots into the cup
like this.
[Music]
Then strain out the residue and keep the
rice water to make a liquid fertilizer
which is very beneficial for orchids.
[Music]
Then soak the orchid roots in the rice
water for 20 minutes. This helps
stimulate rapid root growth because the
rice water is rich in nutrients and
beneficial microorganisms that promote
root development.
[Music]
While waiting, I take a soft cotton pad,
soak it in the rice water, and gently
wipe the leaves to help revive wilted
leaves. Because the rice water nourishes
and moisturizes the leaves, promoting
recovery and healthy growth.
[Music]
If you haven't subscribed yet, please
subscribe to support me.
After soaking for 20 minutes, take the
orchid out and plant it immediately into
the new pot.
[Music]
Take the moss that has been soaked in
the baking soda solution, ring out the
excess water, and then use it to plant
the orchid.
[Music]
Planting orchids with soaked moss helps
the wilted orchid quickly grow roots
because moss has good moisture
retention, providing an ideal
environment for strong root development.
Additionally, moss retains nutrients
from the soaking solution, aiding the
plant in recovery and rapid growth.
[Music]
After that, water the orchid with rice
water once every 10 days to help it
recover quickly.
[Music]
On regular days, if the orchid is dry,
you only need to mist it with water to
maintain
moisture. After watering, remember to
place the orchid pot in a spot with with
gentle sunlight so the plant can
photosynthesize and improve its
metabolic processes.
The results after 3
weeks. As you can see, the wilted leaves
have become greener, shinier, and a bit
[Music]
sturdier. The orchid has also grown a
new healthy leaf that looks very strong.
[Music]
The orchid has developed numerous new
roots which efficiently absorb water and
nutrients. Um this helps speed up the
recovery process and helps the wilted
plant recover faster.
Uh, if you find the video helpful, don't
forget to like, share, and subscribe to
the channel to support me.
Uh after that I continue taking care of
the orchid with natural fertilizer made
from rice water once every 10 days.
[Music]
If you encounter any difficulties in
caring for your orchids, don't hesitate
to comment. comment below the video and
I'll be ready to advise
you. The result after the next month
You can see that the orchid has grown
two new very healthy leaves, which
proves that the orchid is growing very
well, showing that the care method
applied is effective.
You can see that the orchid has grown
two new very healthy leaves, which
proves that the orchid is growing very
well, showing that the care method
applied is effective.
You can see that the orchid has grown
two new very healthy leaves, which
proves that the orchid is growing very
well, showing that the care method
applied is effective.
[Music]
The result after the next 3
months, you can see that the orchid has
almost fully recovered with the leaves
becoming healthy and
strong. And the orchid has even grown a
new flower spike that's very healthy.
With this simple care routine, the
orchid has quickly recovered and bloomed
beautifully, just like any other healthy
orchid.
[Music]
This natural fertilizer not only
supports the recovery process of your
beloved orchid, but also helps the
flowers bloom more vibrantly, uh, last
longer, and stay in bloom for up to 6
months before wilting.
[Music]
I hope this video will be helpful to you
in caring for orchids at home. If you
find it useful, please like, share, and
subscribe to the
[Music]
channel. Thank you all for watching. I
always pray that blessings will come to
you. Wishing everyone good health.
Goodbye and see you next
time. Hello
everyone. Welcome to my
channel. Today I'm excited to continue
sharing with you a new organic
fertilizer that helps orchids grow fully
and bloom more flowers.
If you haven't subscribed to the channel
yet, please click the subscribe button
to support me and not miss any orchid
growing tips. It's great to have
company. Let's get
started. Do you have
[Music]
potatoes? Wash the potatoes and peel
them like me.
[Music]
Then don't throw away the peel, but keep
it as
[Music]
fertilizer. Potato peels are an
excellent source of nutrients for
orchids.
When recycled into fertilizer, potato
peels provide essential vitamins and
minerals that help the plants grow
stronger. In addition to the English
dub, we've now created dubs in French,
German, Italian, Spanish, Portuguese,
Japanese, Hindi, and Indonesian to help
you hear and understand the content.
Videos are
easier. Cut the potato skin into small
pieces. They also improve soil moisture
and structure, creating better
conditions for the orchid roots to
thrive.
[Music]
Next, I need eggshells.
Like I take two eggshells and make them
crumble.
Eggshells are a valuable source of
nutrients for
orchids. Um, when crushed and used as
fertilizer, eggshells provide calcium,
which which helps strengthen root
structure and support plant growth.
Then put all the ingredients into the
[Music]
jar. Add four cups of boiled water,
about one liter.
[Music]
Incubate and wait for the water to
cool. Two hours later.
[Music]
After cooling, filter this water.
Add four cups of water, about one
liter. Step one.
Use a soft cotton to absorb this water
and gently wipe the top and bottom of
the leaves
thoroughly. Wiping orchid leaves with
fermented water from potato peels and
eggshells offers numerous benefits for
the plants.
This fermented water is rich in vitamins
and minerals, enhancing leaf vitality
and stimulating photosynthesis.
Uh the calcium from eggshells
strengthens cell structure making the
leaves sturdier and reducing the risk of
disease.
Remove yellow and damaged leaves.
Additionally, the fermented water
provides moisture to the leaves, aiding
the plant in better nutrient absorption.
The wiping process also removes dust and
potential pathogens, keeping the leaves
clean and healthy, which ultimately
boosts the plant's growth potential.
Which country are you watching videos
from? Please comment and let me know.
It's nice that we can chat together from
all over the world.
Step
two, put this water in a spray bottle.
Then spray the entire
orchid. Then spray the entire orchid.
This fermented water is rich in
vitamins, minerals, and beneficial
microorganisms which help enhance the
plant's resistance.
The calcium from eggshells supports root
development and improves cell structure,
making the leaves
sturdier. Regular use of this solution
will help orchids thrive, bloom
beautifully, and last longer.
Step three,
[Music]
uh, water this water into each orchid
pot
[Music]
temp. Watering orchids with fermented
water from potato peels and eggshells
provides numerous practical benefits.
This fermented water is rich in
vitamins, minerals, and beneficial
microorganisms supplying essential
nutrients to the plants.
[Music]
The calcium from eggshells not only
strengthens root structure but also
supports plant
[Music]
growth. Apply the three steps like the
video to your orchids one to two times
month.
[Music]
Then you soak the orchid pot in this
water for 20 minutes so that the roots
can absorb more water and nutrients.
After soaking for 20 minutes, take out
the orchid pot and place it in a place
with plenty of light to grow.
Orchids require light to carry out
photosynthesis, which helps convert
light energy into chemical energy.
[Music]
Now we invite you to join us in seeing
the
[Music]
results. Um, with this method, new roots
spread very quickly after only one
month.
New roots help the plant absorb water
and essential minerals from the
environment, ensuring a steady supply of
nutrients for growth.
[Music]
Uh, new roots often host beneficial
microorganisms that improve nutrient
metabolism and stimulate plant growth.
[Music]
New roots can quickly adapt to different
environmental conditions, allowing
orchids to survive and thrive in
challenging situations.
[Music]
Some roots can store nutrients,
providing the plant with a reserve
during times of need, especially during
dry
[Music]
periods. To ensure healthy growth, keep
the following points in mind. Orchids
generally need moderate light, avoiding
harsh sunlight. Place them in a spot
with bright light but shielded from
direct midday
[Music]
rays. Orchids need about 12 to 14 hours
of light daily. You can use LED lights
if natural light is
insufficient. If the leaves turn yellow
or light green, the plant may be lacking
light. Conversely, if the leaves are
sunburned, reduce direct sunlight
exposure.
Sometimes you may need to relocate the
plant to ensure it receives adequate
light without
damage. Using organic fertilizers helps
the plant absorb light and nutrients
more
effectively. Thank you for watching the
video. If there is anything you don't
understand, don't hesitate to comment to
me so I can guide you further.
[Music]
Welcome to my
channel. I am an orchid care
specialist. Do you have vitamin
B1?
Subscribe to the channel and watch till
the end to see the
[Music]
magic. Five tablets of vitamin B1.
Mix in four cups of room temperature
water, about one
[Music]
liter. Keep in a cool place away from
direct sunlight for 1 hour.
[Music]
Then I took five
eggshells. Eggshells contain many
nutrients needed by plants including
calcium, potassium, and trace elements
such as iron, magnesium, manganese,
copper, and zinc.
[Music]
Therefore, eggshells will help provide
necessary nutrients for
orchids. Dry on low heat for 5
minutes. This helps to eliminate fungal
diseases before using as fertilizer.
[Music]
When using eggshells as fertilizer, it
also helps to increase the pH of the
soil, helping orchids grow better.
[Music]
In addition, I also use 100 g of organic
fertilizer from livestock waste pressed
into dry pellets.
[Music]
Then mix the two types together.
With the orchids that have bloomed all
the last
[Music]
flowers, I apply about 1 oz, about 30 g
per
[Music]
pot. Orchid after full bloom is very
exhausted. So I need to apply this
fertilizer to quickly
[Music]
recover. Pay attention to fertilizing
far from the
[Music]
root with orchids in full bloom.
This fertilizer also helps flowers bloom
for a long
time. If you apply this fertilizer every
2 months, it is guaranteed that the
orchid will bloom for 6 months without
wilting. With orchids with buds, I also
apply this fertilizer to help flower
buds grow faster.
[Music]
1 hour
After decant the clear water above.
[Music]
Use this absorbent
cotton. Clean the top and bottom of the
leaves. Helps eliminate fungal diseases
and prevent parasitic insects on
leaves. At the same time, it supports
the supply of nutrients through orchid
leaves. Orchids are always green and
[Music]
growing. Sprinkle the remaining water
into the orchid growing medium.
[Music]
Vitamin B1 helps strengthen the root
system and promote plant health while
improving the soil's ability to absorb
[Music]
nutrients. Vitamin B1 has the effect of
protecting plants from external agents
such as drought, sunburn, and cold, and
enhances resistance to plant diseases.
[Music]
You should fertilize B1 for orchids once
a month in the cool
[Music]
afternoon. Results after 1
week. You can see that after 15 days,
the flowers are still very fresh and
more fragrant than usual.
and flowers can bloom again and again
all year round in the
[Music]
garden. This helps me to always enjoy
the blooming flowers and the gentle
fragrance from the
garden. And you can see that after just
a week of using, the orchid has grown a
lot of new roots.
[Music]
So we can use these organic fertilizers
to take care of orchids very well.
[Music]
However, keep in mind that an overdose
can also harm plants. Therefore, it is
advisable to adhere to the dosage that I
have
instructed. Hopefully, the video will be
of great help to you in effectively
taking care of orchids at home.
If you find the content interesting and
meaningful, don't forget to like and
share so that more people know and
subscribe to support the channel. Thank
you for always accompanying
me. Thank you for watching the video. I
always pray for God's blessings to all
of you.