Welcome to Happiness Garden, a peaceful
little corner where I share simple care
tips and inspiration to help your
orchids stay healthy and bloom
beautifully.
[Music]
During the process of growing orchids,
almost everyone has encountered the
problem of orchids rotting when the
weather turns hot.
This is a common issue that worries
growers because just a slight delay in
treatment can cause the plant to get
damaged very quickly.
If you are new to growing orchids and
suddenly face the problem of your plant
rotting without knowing how to handle
it, don't worry. This is an issue many
orchid growers have experienced. And
there is definitely a way to save the
plant if you act in time.
When encountering this situation, the
first thing you need to do is gently
check the entire root system and cut off
the damaged roots as they can spread
disease to the healthy ones, causing the
plant to weaken and making recovery
difficult.
Leave me a comment and let me know which
country you are watching from. It's
wonderful that we can chat together from
all around the world.
If you haven't subscribed yet, please
please hit the subscribe button to
support me and not miss any orchid care
tips. It's wonderful to have you along.
Next, you need to remove the rotted leaf
sheath and leaves. Uh this will help
prevent fungal diseases from spreading
to the healthy parts of the plant and
create a well ventilated environment for
faster recovery.
[Music]
In addition to English narration, we
have now created versions in French,
German, Italian, Spanish, Portuguese,
Japanese, Hindi, Dutch, Polish, Korean,
and Indonesian to help you listen and
understand the content more easily.
[Music]
After checking the growing medium, if
you see that it is still fresh, loose,
and drains well, there is no need to
replace it yet. This helps the plant
avoid shock after trimming the roots and
leaves, making it easier for the plant
to recover.
[Music]
[Applause]
After cutting off the damaged roots and
leaves,
wash the entire orchid under running
water to remove any remaining fungi and
bacteria on the roots, keeping the plant
clean and ready for the next step.
After rinsing the orchid under running
water, place it in a cool, well
ventilated area away from direct
sunlight and wait until it is completely
dry.
To help the orchid recover quickly, I
will use a natural fertilizer that I
make myself. This this fertilizer is
safe and provides all the essential uh
nutrients, helping the roots grow back
quickly and the leaves develop strong
and healthy.
Take three teaspoons of rice and put
them into a clean container to prepare
the fertilizer solution. Um, rice will
provide natural starch and minerals
helping to nourish the roots and
stimulate faster recovery.
The next ingredient I use is coffee
grounds as they contain many minerals
such as nitrogen, potassium, and
phosphorus which help the plant grow
strong, produce roots quickly, and
develop greener leaves.
Next, pour one liter of boiling water
into the container to extract all the
nutrients from the rice and coffee
grounds, creating a nutrient-rich
solution for the plant.
[Music]
Close the lid tightly and let it ferment
for one day so that the rice and coffee
grounds release all their nutrients,
allowing the solution to ferment
slightly and making it easier for the
orchid to absorb when watered.
After the growing medium has completely
dried, we proceed to plant the orchid in
a new pot. This provides a clean and
well ventilated environment, reduces the
risk of fungal diseases and creates
ideal conditions for new roots to grow
strong and healthy.
[Music]
I usually choose a pot with plenty of
drainage holes at the bottom so the
roots stay dry and avoid water logging.
The growing medium I use is crushed pine
bark, which provides just the right
amount of moisture, drains well, and
creates an ideal environment for orchid
roots to grow strong and healthy.
[Music]
When planting, gently tuck the pine bark
around the roots to secure the plant,
avoiding breaking the young roots.
Packing it just right will help the
plant stand firm, allowing the roots to
anchor to the medium and grow faster.
[Music]
The combination of the old moss that is
still good and the new crushed pine bark
will help maintain stable moisture while
still ensuring proper irration, creating
ideal conditions for new roots to grow
vigorously.
After planting, you should place the
orchid pot in a cool, wellventilated
area for one day and avoid watering.
This step allows the root cuts to dry
completely, reducing the risk of rot and
helping the plant adapt to its new
environment before you start watering
and fertilizing again.
[Music]
After fermenting for one day, stir the
solution well to dissolve the nutrients
from the rice and coffee grounds,
ensuring the fertilizer is evenly mixed.
[Music]
Next, strain out the sediment from the
solution, keeping only the nutrient-rich
liquid, which allows the orchid to
absorb it easily and prevents the roots
from getting clogged when watered.
When combining the fermented rice water
and coffee water, this solution provides
all the natural nutrients such as
nitrogen, potassium, and essential
vitamins, helping orchid roots grow
quickly, leaves develop healthily, and
promoting recovery after trimming
damaged roots and leaves.
[Music]
Uh the first method is to water this
mixture directly onto the roots and
growing medium. This allows the
nutrients to penetrate deeply into the
root system, stimulating new root growth
and creating a strong foundation for the
plant to recover vigorously.
[Music]
When the roots develop well, the leaves
and stem will also receive more
nutrients, becoming lush and sturdy.
This not only helps the plant recover
from rot, but also creates conditions
for the mother plant to produce new
offshoots at the base or grow new leaves
at the tip if the growing point is still
intact, allowing the plant to sustain
life and grow sustainably.
[Music]
The second method is to pour this
mixture into a spray bottle and lightly
mist it onto the leaves, stem, and
surface of the growing medium.
[Music]
This method allows the nutrients to
spread evenly, enhances absorption
through the leaves and simultaneously
retains moisture retains moisture in the
growing medium supporting faster
recovery of the orchid.
[Music]
The advantage of the spraying method
compared to direct watering is that the
nutrients are evenly distributed over
the leaves, stem, and surface of the
growing medium, allowing the plant to
absorb them more quickly through
multiple parts, not just the roots. At
the same time, spraying lightly retains
moisture in the medium without flooding
the roots, reducing the risk of rot and
creating a well ventilated environment
for healthy growth.
[Music]
If the growing medium dries out after
watering, you can you can leave the
orchid pot to soak in this mixture for
about 20 minutes. This method allows the
roots and medium to absorb the nutrients
evenly while providing the necessary
moisture for the plant to recover
quickly without shocking or damaging the
roots. Any
remaining mixture can be used to spray
on other healthy orchids in your garden.
This not not only makes use of the
nutrient-rich solution, but also helps
the other orchids grow greener with
stronger roots and leaves.
After spraying or soaking, simply place
the orchid in a cool, wellventilated
area away from direct sunlight and avoid
watering for a few hours to allow the
nutrients to penetrate deeply into the
roots and leaves. Regularly following
this method will help the plant stay
healthy and ready for the next blooming
cycles.
[Music]
After soaking for 20 minutes, gently
remove the orchid pot and check the
leaves.
If there is still water on the leaves,
use a soft cloth to dry them to prevent
fungal growth and ensure the leaves
remain dry, creating the best conditions
for the plant to recover.
When wiping the leaves, do so very
gently from the base to the tip to avoid
damaging the leaf tissue. Once the
leaves are completely dry, place the
plant in a cool, wellventilated area
away from direct sunlight and continue
caring for it as usual.
[Music]
And here are the results after 1 month
of recovery.
You can see that uh many new healthy
roots have grown and the orchid has even
sprouted two new leaves at the tip. This
shows that the plant has fully
recovered. The roots are developing well
and its growth potential remains strong,
promising even more spectacular blooms
in the upcoming flowering cycles.
[Music]
The old leaves have become firmer and
glossier, indicating that the orchid has
not only recovered, but is also
efficiently absorbing nutrients,
improving overall health, and enhancing
photosynthesis, helping the plant grow
vigorously, and be ready for new leaves
and blooms.
[Music]
I continue to care for this orchid using
the lightly fermented natural fertilizer
made from rice and coffee grounds.
Regular fertilization provides a steady
supply of nutrients, nourishing the
roots, leaves, and stem while
maintaining continuous growth.
[Music]
You can flexibly choose either the
method of watering directly onto the
roots and growing medium or the spraying
method depending on your conditions and
preference. Both methods help the orchid
absorb nutrients effectively, nourish
strong roots, green leaves, and support
recovery as well as long-term growth.
[Music]
Maintaining a regular care routine with
this natural fertilizer will keep your
orchid lush, promote strong root growth,
and improve its flowering consistency.
Over time, you will see the plant
becoming healthier with sturdier new
leaves.
And here are the results after 2 months
of recovery.
You can see that from an orchid that had
only one leaf and seemed close to dying,
it has now fully recovered and grown
many new leaves at the tip.
This proves that the care method using
lightly fermented natural fertilizer
from rice and coffee grounds is truly
effective, helping the plant stay
healthy and ready for the upcoming
flowering cycles.
You can see that the root system is
becoming denser, stronger, stronger, and
firmly anchored into the growing medium.
This not only helps the plant absorb
water and nutrients more efficiently,
but also provides a solid foundation for
long-term growth, including the
formation of new leaves and future
flower buds.
When you care for orchids with all the
love and patience you have for plants,
every action from watering and
fertilizing to monitoring the roots and
leaves becomes meaningful.
Um, this love not only helps the orchid
recover and grow vigorously, but also
brings joy and a deep connection between
you and your lush green garden.
With dedicated and consistent care, the
orchid will reward you with lush green
leaves, strong roots, and vibrant,
lively blooms.
Every time you see the plant grow,
sprout new leaves, or bloom, it's a
little joy reminding you that love and
patience always bring wonderful results
in your garden.
[Music]
Continue to spend time observing and
caring for every small detail, as these
simple actions help the orchid maintain
long-term health. When the plant grows
vigorously and blooms brilliantly, you
will feel the joy and deep satisfaction
that comes from the bond between humans
and nature.
[Music]
Thank you for watching. Wishing you a
joyful day, a garden that's always lush
and orchids that bloom beautifully.