Welcome to my channel. Today I will
share a very exciting secret. How to
propagate orchids right on the branch
while still helping the plant bloom all
year round easily.
[Music]
Uh this orchid has just finished its
flowering season and the last petals
have also fallen. This is the ideal time
to cut the flower spike, preparing for
branch propagation.
[Music]
If done at the right time, the plant
will quickly recover and start producing
healthy new shoots ready for the next
flowering season. Proper care from this
stage will help you maximize the
orchid's ability to bloom all year
round.
[Music]
We should only propagate from buds that
have not yet bloomed like this because
inside the bud there are still potential
dormant shoots. Choosing the right bud
greatly increases the chances of new
shoots and flowering from the cut
branch.
Buds that have already bloomed should be
cut off immediately because they no
longer contain dormant shoots and cannot
produce new growth.
[Music]
You should spray alcohol on the tools
before cutting to disinfect them. Then
trim the cut again to remove any crushed
parts. This helps reduce the risk of the
cutting rotting while also creating
conditions for the new orchid branch to
grow healthily. Just a small step, but
extremely important to ensure a high
survival rate for the cutting.
[Music]
Next, gently peel off the outer
protective layer of the dormant bud.
This step allows the bud to come into
direct contact with air and nutrients,
thereby stimulating the new chute to
grow quickly.
[Music]
[Applause]
Handle carefully to avoid damaging the
bud as this is the most important part
that determines the success of the
cutting.
[Music]
On this mother plant, there is one leaf
that has been infected with fungus. So,
I carefully cut off the diseased parts
of the leaf.
Timely removal not only helps prevent
the fungus from spreading to healthy
parts, but also allows the mother plant
to focus its nutrients on nurturing new
healthy shoots and leaves.
[Music]
Now we will prepare a special fertilizer
to restore the mother orchid and
stimulate the young orchid to grow
vigorously during branch propagation.
[Music]
First, take a fresh clove of garlic. A
simple ingredient, but extremely
effective.
[Music]
Garlic not only provides natural
antibacterial properties but also
stimulates roots and new shoots to grow
healthily.
The next ingredient, prepare a small
aloe vera leaf because aloe vera
contains many nutrients and natural
growth stimulants.
When combined with garlic, this mixture
will help the mother orchid recover
quickly and promote the flower spike
along with the cutting to grow
healthily, laying the foundation for
vibrant flowers in the future.
Next, add 300 ml of water to the garlic
and aloe vera leaf.
Then, blend the mixture until all the
nutrients are fully dissolved.
[Music]
After blending, strain out the residue,
keeping only the nutrient-rich solution.
This step helps the fertilizer penetrate
deeper into the roots and flower spike
while also preventing clogging or root
rot when watering the mother plant and
the cutting.
[Music]
Next, pour the filtered fertilizer
mixture into a small cup and soak the
cutting for about 20 minutes.
This soaking helps the cutting fully
absorb nutrients, stimulates roots and
new shoots to grow faster, and increases
the survival rate of the cutting. This
is an important step to ensure that each
cutting has a healthy start.
[Music]
Pour the remaining mixture into a spray
bottle and use it to mist the mother
orchid.
[Music]
This helps the leaves and roots of the
mother orchid receive nutrients
directly, stimulating quick recovery and
vigorous growth.
Ginger has mild antibacterial
properties, while aloe vera provides
many growth stimulants, helping the
plant become healthy with green leaves
and a flower spike ready to grow.
[Music]
Misting the ginger and aloe vera mixture
also helps increase the stress
resistance of the mother orchid.
When the plant receives nutrients and
natural growth stimulants, it responds
better to environmental changes,
insects, or diseases while maintaining
stable vitality and consistent growth
for new shoots and flowers.
[Music]
After soaking the cutting for 20
minutes, take it out and gently wipe off
any fertilizer remaining on the surface.
[Music]
[Applause]
Next, take a little cinnamon powder and
sprinkle it on the cuts of the cutings.
Uh, cinnamon has natural antibacterial
and disinfectant properties, helping the
cuts heal quickly while also preventing
mold and rot. This is a small but
important step ensuring that the cutings
grow healthily from the very beginning.
[Music]
Then place the cutings in a cool, airy
spot for about 1 day, allowing the cuts
to dry and heal completely before
planting them in the medium.
You should also sprinkle cinnamon powder
on the cuts of the mother orchid, which
helps protect the cuts from bacteria and
fungi, uh, while also supporting a quick
healing process.
[Music]
After sprinkling cinnamon powder on the
cuts, place the orchid pot in a cool,
airy spot and do not water for 1 to two
days. This helps the cuts on the mother
plant dry and heal faster while also
preventing mold and root rot.
[Music]
After one day, when the cuts on the
cutings have completely dried, we
proceed to plant the cutings into the
medium.
[Music]
The medium we use is clay pebbles.
Commonly used in hydroponic vegetable
gardens. Clay pebbles have the advantage
of retaining moderate moisture, draining
well, and providing air to the roots,
helping the cutings develop rooted
quickly and healthily.
Uh next, pour 300 mm of clean water onto
the clay pebbles so that the pebbles
float on the surface.
[Music]
Uh after preparing the medium, place the
cutings into the clay pebbles.
This helps the new chute grow in the
right direction while the orchid roots
quickly attach to the medium.
You can also lightly mist some water to
keep the cutting moist immediately after
placing it in the medium.
[Music]
Then use a plastic cup with holes around
and place it over the propagation pot.
This cup helps maintain stable humidity
for the cutting while also ensuring good
air circulation and preventing mold.
Next, place the cutting pot in a spot
with gentle sunlight so the plant
receives enough light without being too
harsh.
Soft light helps stimulate new chute
growth.
[Music]
And here are the results after one month
of cutting propagation.
[Music]
You can see that from the small dormant
buds they have now grown into healthy
young orchids right on the cutings.
[Music]
Proper and patient care has helped each
young chute sprout and produce new
leaves.
Uh this is clear evidence that with just
a few simple yet scientific steps, you
can easily propagate orchids.
Since the young orchids have not yet
produced any roots, you need to continue
caring for them and maintaining moisture
carefully until the roots develop
healthily before planting them in a new
pot.
[Music]
We need to change the water once a week
to keep the cutting environment clean.
This helps prevent mold, bacteria, and
root rot while also ensuring that the
young orchids continuously absorb
nutrients and develop healthy roots and
new shoots.
You can see that today's branch cutting
propagation method brings very good
results, right? So, don't rush to leave.
Keep watching to see how the young
orchids develop in the coming days.
[Music]
And here are the results after the next
2 months.
You can see that the young orchids on
the cutings have grown very healthily.
New roots and leaves are emerging
evenly, showing that proper care helps
the plants absorb nutrients effectively
while also preparing them for strong
growth in the future.
You can see that the young orchids on
the cutings have grown very healthily.
New roots and leaves are emerging
evenly, showing that proper care helps
the plants absorb nutrients effectively
while also preparing them for strong
growth in the future.
[Music]
I choose a pot with drainage holes and a
medium of pine bark that has been
treated for fungi to plant the orchids.
This ensures that water does not
stagnate. The roots receive sufficient
air and do not rot, while the clean
medium helps the plants grow healthily,
providing a good foundation for regular
sprouting, rooting, and flowering in the
future.
[Music]
When placing the medium into the pot,
you should do it gently, ensuring the
young orchid roots are not damaged. Uh,
make sure the roots are adequately
surrounded by the medium so the plant is
secure while still retaining the
necessary air and moisture.
[Music]
What do you think about my my method of
propagating orchids from cutings? Please
leave your comment and share your
thoughts with me.
As long as you patiently care for each
step, gradually you will have a vibrant
orchid garden with many blooming flowers
just like mine. Patience and love for
the plants will bring wonderful results,
making each flowering season beautiful
and rewarding.
If you find this content interesting and
meaningful, don't forget to like, share
so that more people can see it and
subscribe to support me. Thank you for
always being with me.
Uh, thank you for watching the video. I
always pray that God blesses all of you.