Welcome to Happiness Garden. This is
where we explore simple but effective
orchid care tips together, helping your
plants stay healthy and bloom
beautifully.
I want to bring you many options for
caring for orchids at home with organic
fertilizer. In today's video, we will
explore more new simple and effective
methods together.
If you haven't subscribed to the channel
yet, don't forget to hit the subscribe
button to support me and not miss any
orchid care tips. It's wonderful to have
you with me on this orchidloving
journey.
To make this compost, you will need
eggs. More precisely, about 10
eggshells.
[Music]
Please comment and let me know which
country you are watching the video from.
It's wonderful that we can connect and
chat together from all around the world.
Then wash the eggshells with water to
remove remaining egg white, keeping the
mixture clean and safe for the plant.
[Music]
[Applause]
Next, place the eggshells under the sun
to dry completely. This step makes them
more brittle and easier to crush. And
the sunlight also helps naturally
disinfect them.
[Music]
After about 3 hours of sun drying, the
eggshells are completely dry and ready
for the next step.
Now, just crush them first and then
grind them finely. The finer the shells,
the easier it will be for the plant to
absorb the nutrients and grow better.
[Music]
After grinding finally, take one
teaspoon of the eggshell powder and put
it into a clean bottle. This will be the
main ingredient for making the watering
solution for the orchids.
[Music]
After adding the eggshell powder to the
clean bottle, pour in about four cups of
boiling water, equivalent to one liter
of water. Stir well so that the
nutrients in the eggshells are
completely dissolved.
[Music]
After stirring well, close the lid
tightly and let it sit until the
solution cools completely. This step
helps the minerals in the eggshells
blend into the water more effectively.
[Music]
When the water has completely cooled,
strain out the eggshell residue and keep
the clear liquid. This is the calcium
and mineralrich solution to water your
orchids.
[Music]
The first method is to use a soft cloth
soaked in this solution. Then gently
wipe both the upper and lower surfaces
of the leaves.
[Music]
Eggshells contain a lot of calcium, an
important mineral for orchid growth.
Calcium helps form new tissues, makes
the leaves thicker and stronger than
usual, and also supports strong root
development.
[Music]
This method not only provides nutrients,
but also helps kill fungi and repel
insects effectively, keeping the plant
healthy and disease-free.
You can wipe the leaves every two weeks
to remove dust, helping them
photosynthesize better. When the leaves
are clean and clear, the plant will
absorb light more effectively, grow
stronger roots, and produce more blooms.
[Music]
Another tip is to wipe the leaves early
in the morning or late in the afternoon
when the sun is not too strong.
This allows the leaves to dry naturally,
preventing water from lingering and
causing rot or fungal issues.
[Music]
The second method is to pour this
mixture into a spray bottle. Then gently
mist the entire plant covering both the
upper and lower sides of the leaves so
the plant can absorb the nutrients more
evenly.
[Music]
You should mist in the early morning or
late afternoon when the sunlight is not
too harsh. This allows the leaves to dry
during the day, reduces the risk of
fungal diseases, and helps the plant
absorb nutrients to the fullest.
Maintain misting with this eggshell
mixture every 2 weeks. After just a few
weeks, you will see the leaves become
darker green, glossy, and healthy, and
the roots grow strong.
[Music]
After spraying the entire plant, let it
air dry. This spraying method not only
provides nutrients but also keeps the
leaves clean and healthy.
[Music]
The third method is to water each orchid
pot directly with this mixture.
[Music]
Gently pour around the base and onto the
growing medium. This helps the roots
absorb calcium and essential minerals,
nourishing the plant from within and
preparing it well for upcoming shoots
and flower buds.
[Music]
The calcium from the eggshell water
helps enhance orchid root growth while
improving the ability to absorb
nutrients from the growing medium. As a
result, the plant will grow stronger and
healthier.
[Music]
Calcium also helps orchids increase
disease resistance, making the plant
less prone to infections and health
problems. As a result, the flowers will
retain their color and stay vibrant for
a longer time.
[Music]
Maintain watering each orchid pot with
this mixture about once every 2 weeks.
This simple habit ensures the roots and
leaves receive enough calcium and
minerals, helping the plant grow healthy
with glossy green leaves and more even
blooms.
[Music]
Uh after applying this watering method
for some time, you will see strong
roots, glossy green leaves, and better
orchid flower development.
The fourth method is to sprinkle the
eggshell powder directly onto the
surface of the orchid pot.
This method helps gradually supplement
calcium, nourish the roots and growing
medium, and also improve the soil
structure, allowing better moisture
retention and irerration for the plant.
Sprinkle a moderate amount around the
pot surface, maintaining it regularly
every 2 to 3 weeks. This method helps
orchid roots grow strong, keeps the
growing medium loose, and ensures the
plant stays healthy. When applied
consistently, you will see the orchids
thriving and ready for new shoots and
flower buds.
[Music]
And here are the results after one month
of care. You can see the orchid has
developed many new roots. This helps the
plant absorb nutrients more effectively,
allowing it to thrive with glossy green
leaves and vibrant blooms.
These new roots not only help the plant
absorb nutrients better, but also create
a strong foundation for long-term
growth. When the roots are healthy, both
the leaves and flowers of the orchid are
optimally nourished, ready for the
upcoming blooming seasons.
[Music]
Um, with proper care, the petals bloom
soft, fresh, and stay on the stem
longer. This allows you to enjoy the
vibrant beauty of the orchids for an
extended time.
When consistently applying these care
methods, many flowers can bloom at the
same time while maintaining their
vitality, preventing the orchids from
wilting quickly. The orchids will always
be vibrant and full of life.
These fresh flowers not only beautify
the space, but also demonstrate the
plant's strong vitality. Each bloom is
healthy, brightly colored, and lasts
longer thanks to proper care combined
with nutrients from the roots, leaves,
and growing medium.
I hope this video will help you a lot in
caring for orchids at home. If you find
it useful, don't forget to hit like and
subscribe to the channel so you won't
miss the next orchid care tips and
methods naturally and simply.
In addition to English voiceover, we
have now created versions in French,
German, Italian, Spanish, Portuguese,
Japanese, Hindi, Dutch, Polish, Korean,
and Indonesian to help you listen and
understand the content easily.
To listen in your preferred language,
open the video and click on settings
gear icon to select the appropriate
audio language.
[Music]
Thank you for watching. Wishing you a
wonderful day with orchids always
healthy and blooming beautifully. See
you in the next videos.
[Music]