Welcome to the happiness garden. Here we
will explore together how to care for
orchids in a natural and effective way
so that the plants are always healthy
and bloom brilliantly. When caring for
orchids, the most important part is the
roots because healthy roots help the
plant absorb nutrients well, nourishing
fresh green leaves and brilliant
flowers.
Do you have cucumbers? When eating
cucumbers, don't rush to throw away the
peel. Keep it because cucumber peels
contain many wonderful nutrients for the
plants. You can turn the peels into
natural fertilizer, helping the plants
grow healthy from roots to leaves.
Please comment and let me know which
country you are watching this video
from. It's wonderful that we can connect
and chat together from all around the
world.
And if you haven't subscribed yet, click
the subscribe button to support me and
not miss any orchid growing tips. It's
wonderful to have you along for the
journey.
After peeling, take the peels and put
them into a blender to prepare for
grinding.
[Music]
The next ingredient is rice. You only
need one teaspoon of rice.
[Music]
Next, add 500 ml of water.
Then cover the mixture and let it
ferment for about 6 hours to allow light
fermentation. This fermentation process
will release more nutrients from the
ingredients, creating a nutrientrich
natural fertilizer that is easily
absorbed by the orchids.
[Music]
Um, after fermenting for about 6 hours,
blend the mixture again. Blending after
fermentation helps release the nutrients
to the maximum, creating a smooth
fertilizer solution that is easily
absorbed by the orchids.
[Music]
Next, strain out the solids to obtain a
smooth liquid fertilizer.
Removing the solids helps the solution
absorb easily into the orchid roots,
prevents clogging, and keeps the plants
clean.
[Music]
Then dilute with more water to get about
3 L of fertilizer mixture. Um, diluting
helps the solution be gentle enough for
the orchid roots to absorb effectively
while preventing it from being too
strong, which could harm the plants.
[Music]
First, we need to clean the leaves. Take
a soft cloth and wipe the leaves with
this mixture, making sure both the top
and bottom surfaces are cleaned.
[Music]
Wiping the leaves helps remove dust and
deposits on the leaf surface.
When the leaves are clean, light can
easily reach the photosynthetic tissues,
allowing the plant to synthesize
nutrients more effectively, thus
nourishing healthy leaves and flowers.
[Music]
Uh the leaf wiping mixture also helps
remove bacteria, fungi, and pathogens on
the leaves. This reduces the risk of
disease and protects the overall health
of the plant, especially in humid
environments.
Wiping the leaves with this mixture also
helps distribute nutrients from the
solution directly onto the leaf surface.
The leaves absorb a small amount of
nutrients supporting the plant to grow
healthy and maintain overall nutritional
balance.
Be careful to wipe the underside of the
leaves. The underside is often moist
where insects and fungi tend to hide.
They only wait for an opportunity and
when conditions are favorable, they can
harm and damage the orchids. Thoroughly
wiping the underside helps remove these
hiding spots for pests, protecting the
plant and maintaining vibrant blooms.
The orchid leaves once cleaned become
shinier.
A fresh leaf surface not only looks
beautiful but also helps the plant
absorb light better, enhancing
photosynthesis and supporting full
development from roots to flowers.
The habit of wiping leaves one to two
times a month helps you observe small
changes in the plant. You can detect
issues early, such as pests, yellowing
leaves, or weak roots, and take timely
care measures to keep the orchids
healthy and blooming brilliantly.
[Music]
Next, water this mixture onto the roots
and the growing medium.
Direct watering helps the nutrients
penetrate deep into the roots,
nourishing the plant from the base up,
while also enriching the growing medium,
creating an ideal environment for the
orchids to thrive.
When done regularly, the orchid roots
become stronger, leaves stay green, and
flowers bloom more brilliantly.
Regular watering helps stimulate the
roots to produce new shoots. Strong,
healthy roots mean green leaves and
brilliant blooms, bringing lasting
vitality and beauty to your garden.
[Music]
Regularly watering with the mixture also
stimulates vigorous growth of new roots.
Healthy new roots support lush green
leaves, beautiful flowers, and extend
the lifespan of the orchid.
The watering mixture also helps clean
the growing medium and wash away excess
mineral salts. This prevents root
toxicity and keeps the plant in optimal
growth condition.
This watering also helps maintain proper
moisture for the roots, preventing them
from drying out or becoming water
logged. When the roots have an ideal
moist environment, the orchids grow more
steadily and healthfully.
Apply this mixture twice a month,
alternating with regular watering when
the growing medium is dry.
You can also put the mixture into a
spray bottle to mist the plants. This
method allows the fertilizer solution to
evenly reach the leaves, roots, and even
small gaps in the growing medium while
gently adding moisture to the orchids.
Misting the mixture helps the orchid
leaves directly absorb nutrients from
the fertilizer, providing essential
trace elements to support healthy
growth. When the leaves receive enough
nutrients, the plant increases its
photosynthesis capacity, generating
energy to nourish roots and flower.
At the same time, spraying the leaf
surfaces helps clean dust and pathogens,
reducing the risk of pest development.
Clean and healthy leaves are the
foundation for the orchids to bloom
regularly and last longer.
The mixture also provides gentle
moisture to the leaves and leaf
crevices, helping maintain an ideal
humid environment, especially on dry
days. Well moisturized leaves stay
green, reducing wilting and maintaining
the plant's vitality.
[Music]
Spraying this fertilizer also stimulates
the growth of lateral roots and new
shoots.
uh as some nutrients seep into the
growing medium and roots. When the new
roots are healthy, the orchid absorbs
nutrients more effectively and the
leaves and flowers develop more
balanced.
[Music]
Regular spraying helps you easily
observe small changes in the plant,
detecting issues early, such as pests,
yellowing leaves, or weak roots. This
allows you to provide timely care,
keeping the orchids healthy and blooming
brilliantly all year round.
Note, do not spray the mixture onto the
flower petals. When the flowers are wet,
the petals can easily fall off or get
damaged, reducing the orchid's vibrant
beauty. Focus on spraying the leaves,
roots, and growing medium so the plant
can optimally absorb nutrients, helping
the orchids grow healthy and bloom
longer.
[Music]
Next, I will share how to care for weak
orchids using a natural fertilizer
mixture made from cucumber peels and
lightly fermented rice.
[Music]
You can see that this orchid has wilted
leaves. The roots are still fresh, but
overall the plant is very weak and needs
special care.
[Music]
First, use a soft cloth soaked in the
mixture to wipe the leaves clean, uh,
removing dust as well as pathogens,
fungi, and harmful insects on the
leaves. Cleaning the leaves helps the
orchids absorb light better, enhancing
photosynthesis.
This makes the plant healthier and more
resilient to adverse conditions while
preparing it for full recovery.
[Music]
Uh, if you haven't subscribed yet, click
the subscribe button to support me and
not miss any orchid growing tips. It's
wonderful to have you along for the
journey.
[Music]
You observe that when the orchid roots
turn silvery, it means the plant needs
watering. At this time, water the orchid
thoroughly with the natural fertilizer
mixture, helping the roots absorb enough
moisture and essential nutrients.
Watering at the right time and
thoroughly will help the plant recover
quickly with new roots developing and
new leaves forming. When the roots and
leaves are wellnourished, the orchid
will be healthier and ready to bloom
beautifully in the upcoming cycles. This
regular care habit creates a solid
foundation, helping the orchids grow
sustainably and maintain long- lasting
vitality.
[Music]
You can also put the mixture into a
spray bottle to mist the plants. This
method allows the solution to evenly
reach the leaves, roots, and growing
medium while gently adding moisture to
the orchids.
When done regularly, the orchids will
grow healthy with vibrant green leaves
and brilliant blooms, bringing full
vitality to your garden.
[Music]
And here is the result after 2 weeks of
care using the natural fertilizer made
from cucumber peels and lightly
fermented rice. You can see that from a
weak orchid in just 2 weeks, it has
developed many healthy new roots. This
recovery also means the leaves will be
greener and the plant is gradually ready
to bloom, bringing full vitality to your
garden.
[Music]
Um, what do you think about how I
revived this small orchid? Uh, don't
hesitate to leave a comment and share
your thoughts. I'm very eager to hear
your feedback and experiences.
If you encounter any difficulties while
growing orchids, don't hesitate to
comment. I'm always ready to support you
so you can grow healthy orchids that
bloom abundantly.
The roots of other orchids have also
grown very strong. This proves that
caring for them with a natural
fertilizer mixture made from cucumber
peels and lightly fermented rice is
truly effective.
[Music]
When the roots are healthy, the leaves
are green and the flowers bloom more
brilliantly, bringing lasting vitality
and beauty to the entire garden.
Not only do the flowers bloom
brilliantly, but the petals also stay uh
firmly on the stems for a long time
before wilting. This shows that the
orchid is not only healthy in its roots
and leaves, but also maintains
long-lasting vitality for the flowers.
With proper care, you can enjoy the
enduring beauty of each bloom, bringing
joy and color to your garden.
Uh, this is the end of the video. I hope
these instructions will help you care
for orchids at home effectively and
easily. Wishing you healthy orchids,
vibrant green leaves, and brilliant
blooms, bringing joy and color to your
living space.