[Music]
[Applause]
Heat. Heat.
[Music]
Hello and welcome back to the channel.
In today's video, I'm going to share
with you a simple yet fascinating method
to propagate orchids. Stem cutting.
When the last orchid blooms fall, that's
the perfect time to start propagating
orchids using the stem cutting
method. With just a few easy steps and a
bit of patience, you can create new
orchid plants from the very stems you
already have at
[Music]
home. When all the nutrients in the
orchid plant are focused on blooming,
the leaves at the base will suffer from
a lack of nutrients leading to
yellowing.
Therefore, cutting the stem for
propagation uh not only helps with
reproduction, but also aids the orchid
in recovering after blooming, allowing
the plant to continue growing
healthier. I will cut across here to
make a cutting.
The buds that haven't bloomed yet
actually contain dormant shoots. So, we
should keep these buds when propagating
orchids through stem
cutings. These dormant buds will help
the orchid grow stronger after being
propagated, opening up the possibility
for future
blooms. As for the buds that have
already bloomed, we will cut them off
because they no longer contain dormant
shoots.
[Music]
Removing these buds helps the plant
focus its nutrients on the parts that
are capable of growing and propagating
better.
[Music]
At the base of the cutting, I will make
a diagonal cut to increase the surface
area, helping the cutting absorb water
and nutrients more easily when
propagating. At the tip of the cutting,
I will make a horizontal cut to reduce
the cut surface area, helping the wound
heal quickly and minimizing water loss.
This method helps the plant recover
better and focus its nutrients on root
development.
[Music]
If you haven't subscribed to the channel
yet, please hit the subscribe button to
support me and never miss any orchid
tips. It's wonderful to have you as a
companion.
In addition to English dubbing, we have
now created French, German, Italian,
Spanish, Portuguese, Japanese, Hindi,
and Indonesian dubbing to help you
listen and understand the content
easily. For languages without dubbing,
we have created subtitles so you can
read and understand the content.
Then we will peel off the protective
layer around the dormant bud, allowing
it to develop into a new chute more
easily and quickly when
stimulated. This step helps the orchid's
growth process become more efficient and
faster.
Please comment to me which country you
are watching the video from. It's great
that we can chat together from all over
the world.
[Music]
Then I use Alo. Aloe vera to stimulate
the
cutting. Aloe vera not only helps with
antibacterial protection but also
provides moisture and natural nutrients
supporting the cutting to root quickly
and grow
[Music]
healthily. Aloe vera gel is a highly
effective natural ingredient for stem
propagation.
It helps stimulate faster root growth
thanks to its natural growth hormones
while also offering antibacterial
protection, good moisture retention, and
a variety of vitamins that support
quicker recovery of the
cutting. Insert the slanted cut end of
the cutting into the aloe vera gel. This
allows the cut to directly absorb the
nutrients and hormones in the gel,
stimulating faster root growth and
healthier development.
[Music]
The remaining aloe vera leaf I cut into
thin slices and place in a cup to make
natural fertilizer for the orchid.
[Music]
Aloe vera not only helps with stem
propagation but also provides nutrients
for the plant especially aiding recovery
after blooming and promote and promoting
strong growth for the next bloom
[Music]
cycle. Then place the aloe vera in one
liter of water and wait for about 30
minutes for the nutrients from the aloe
vera to dissolve into the water.
At that point, you'll have a natural,
nutrient-rich solution to water your
orchid, helping the plant recover and
grow
[Music]
better. Next, we need to use baking
soda. Baking soda helps adjust the pH
level in the orchid's growing medium,
creating an ideal environment for the
orchid to thrive.
Take one teaspoon of baking soda. Put it
in a cup. Dilute it with one liter of
water. Dissolve the baking soda in the
water to create a solution that helps
adjust the pH and supports the orchid's
better growth.
Please comment to me which country you
are watching the video from. It's great
that we can chat together from all over
the
world. Then wait for about 30 minutes
for the nutrients from the baking soda
to completely dissolve into the water.
for the cutting. After placing it in the
aloe vera gel, you should also wait for
about 30
minutes. This time allows the cutting to
absorb nutrients from the aloe vera gel,
providing the best conditions for root
development.
Then I will proceed to change the
growing medium for the orchid we
discussed
earlier. Changing the growing medium
provides a fresh environment for the
roots to grow healthy and absorb
nutrients more
[Music]
effectively. Over time, the old growing
medium can break down, reducing drainage
capacity and making it difficult for the
roots to access
oxygen. Um, not only that, but that the
pH level of the medium can also change
over time, becoming unsuitable for the
orchid's growth needs.
Therefore, we need to either replace the
growing medium or treat it to ensure a
stable and suitable pH level for the
[Music]
plant. After removing all of the old
growing medium, we trim off any damaged,
rotten, or dried roots.
[Music]
This helps eliminate potential sources
of disease and allows the plant to focus
on nurturing new healthy
[Music]
roots. Then rinse the orchid under
running water to completely remove any
remaining medium and clean the cuts on
the roots.
This step helps keep the plant clean,
reduces the risk of bacteria, and
prepares it well for the replanting
process.
[Music]
Next, I will treat the old growing
medium so that it can be reused.
[Music]
Pour the baking soda solution into the
growing medium and soak it for about 30
minutes.
[Music]
This solution will help disinfect,
adjust the pH, and refresh the growing
medium, creating the best conditions for
the orchid when reused.
After soaking for 30 minutes, strain out
the aloe vera residue, keeping only the
clean solution to soak the roots and
water each orchid pot.
Then soak the orchid roots in the aloe
vera solution for about 20 minutes.
This soaking time allows the roots to
absorb nutrients from the aloe vera,
promoting better growth and recovery.
Then use a soft cloth to absorb the aloe
vera mixture and gently wipe both the
top and bottom surfaces of the
leaves. This method helps the nutrients
from the aloe vera absorb into the
leaves, providing moisture and boosting
the plant's health.
[Music]
After soaking the growing medium for 30
minutes, remove it, squeeze out the
excess water, and proceed with
propagating the orchid
cutings. The growing medium has been
properly treated, providing ideal
conditions for the cutings to develop
roots and recover.
[Music]
Don't miss me.
Before propagating the cutting, apply
cinnamon powder to the cut end of the
cutting. This helps with antibacterial
action, preventing infection, and
promoting the healing of the cut,
creating better conditions for root
development.
[Music]
This helps with antibacterial action,
preventing infection and promoting the
healing of the cut, creating better
conditions for root development.
This ensures that the bud can easily
grow upwards, providing favorable
conditions for root development and the
overall growth of the
cutting. Then leave it overnight without
watering, allowing the cut to heal
quickly and preventing mold
growth. This helps stabilize the cutting
and creates the best conditions for root
development later on.
After one night, we proceed to spray
water to keep the cutting
moist. From now on, you need to
regularly monitor the growing medium. If
it appears dry, spray water immediately
to ensure stable humidity, which helps
the cutting develop roots better.
Uh after soaking the roots for about 20
minutes, we proceed to plant the orchid
into the new pot with fresh growing
medium. This creates the best conditions
for the plant to thrive with fresh
growing medium that allows the roots to
easily absorb nutrients and water,
helping the plant become healthier.
[Music]
I plant with pine bark because it has
excellent drainage capabilities and
helps provide oxygen to the roots,
creating a well ventilated environment
that prevents the growth of mold.
[Music]
In addition, pine bark helps maintain
stable moisture levels, making it
perfect for caring for orchids.
[Music]
On top of the orchid pot, we spread a
thin layer of moss to help retain
moisture in the medium while creating a
favorable environment for root
development.
Uh this moss layer also helps prevent
the growing medium from eroding and
protects the roots during their
[Music]
development. Then water the newly potted
orchid with the aloe vera solution to
provide natural nutrients, stimulate
root growth, and support the plant's
recovery after replanting.
Then place the newly potted orchid and
the pot with the cutting in a spot with
gentle sunlight, good air circulation,
and away from strong
winds. Gentle light will allow the plant
to photosynthesize softly, stimulating
root and bud development without causing
shock or
dehydration. Now, let's take a look at
the results after 2 weeks of
propagation.
[Music]
As you can see, the dormant buds have
started to swell and are getting ready
to sprout. A clear sign that the
propagated cutting is developing well
and responding positively to this
[Music]
method.
Continue placing the propagated cutings
into the potting medium. And remember to
mist with water whenever the medium
looks dry to maintain consistent
humidity for the
cutings. The right humidity and light
will help the buds grow faster and make
it easier for new roots to
form. And now let's take a look at the
results after 1 month of stem cutting.
You can see that the cutting has
developed well with new buds and roots
starting to emerge, ready for the next
phase of
growth. This is a great sign that the
cutting propagation method is proving to
be effective.
Um, if you haven't subscribed to the
channel yet, hit the subscribe button to
support me. Um, and never miss any
orchid care tips. It's so wonderful to
have you along on this journey.
I continue placing the cutings into the
pot for rooting. And remember to spray
water whenever the growing medium seems
dry to maintain a stable moisture level
for the cutings.
Now, let's take a look at the results
after 2 months of rooting the cutings.
You can see that the orchid cutting has
grown very well with strong leaves and
healthy roots, proving that our rooting
method has been highly effective.
This is the first successful step and
the plant is now ready to continue
growing vigorously in the future.
When the sapling on the cutting is
strong and healthy like this, it's best
to transplant it into a new pot where it
can thrive in a larger space with ideal
conditions for long-term growth.
[Music]
I plant the orchid using pine bark chips
because they provide excellent drainage,
create an airy space for the roots, and
prevent the growth of
[Music]
mold. Sprinkle a little moss on top of
the pot and then place the cutting grown
orchid plant on it.
This layer of moss not only helps retain
moisture for the plant, but also creates
a favorable environment for the roots to
grow strong.
The combination of pine bark as a
growing medium is ideal for orchids,
helping them thrive and grow strong in
their natural
environment. After that, you should care
for your orchid as usual, just like the
videos I've shared on this channel.
Make sure to provide enough water,
light, and nutrients for the plant to
continue growing healthy and blooming
[Music]
beautifully. Thank you all for taking
the time to watch the
video. If you found this video helpful
and interesting, don't forget to like
and subscribe so you won't miss out on
amazing orchid care tips in the upcoming
videos. Continue to love and care for
those beautiful orchids as they will
bring joy and beauty to your
life. Wishing you success with
propagating your cutings and taking care
of your orchids. Goodbye for now and see
you in the next videos.