Welcome to the happiness garden, where
the delicate beauty of nature combines
with joy and peace to create a wonderful
space for the soul. Here you will find
tips for caring for plants, especially
orchids, to help them grow healthy and
shine brightly in your living space
everyday.
Today, I will continue to share with you
a new simple but effective way to make
natural fertilizer. I hope this recipe
will give you more options to take care
of your orchid pots so they stay healthy
and always bloom brightly at home.
[Music]
Let's get started.
If you have an orchid with wilted leaves
and most of the roots are damaged, don't
worry too much. I will guide you on how
to care for and restore the plant in the
most effective way.
[Music]
If you haven't subscribed to the channel
yet, please press the subscribe button
to support me and not miss any orchid
growing tips. It's wonderful to have you
along.
[Music]
First, let's check the roots of the
plant. Healthy roots are usually white
or light green and firm, while damaged
roots are brown, black, or mushy.
You should carefully use scissors or
pruning shears to trim off any rotten
roots to prevent the spread of disease.
Cutting off the damaged roots helps the
plant focus its energy on developing new
roots, absorb nutrients more
effectively, and recover more quickly.
[Music]
When the rotten roots are removed, the
plant no longer needs to supply
nutrients to the nonfunctional parts. As
a result, new roots will grow stronger
and absorb nutrients more effectively.
[Music]
Rotten roots can compact the growing
medium, leading to a lack of oxygen.
When they are removed, this the space
around the base of the plant becomes
more ventilated, creating better
conditions for new root growth.
[Music]
Uh when only healthy roots remain, it
becomes easier to monitor the plant's
growth and detect signs of recovery or
new problems in time to take proper
action.
[Music]
Next, you'll need to remove any parts of
the growing medium that are rotten or no
longer provide proper irration. Damp,
moldy, decomposed pieces or those with a
strange odor can harbor harmful bacteria
and fungi.
[Music]
Decomposed growing medium is easily
compacted and retains water for too
long, which can suffocate the roots. By
replacing it with fresh medium, you
create conditions that allow the roots
to receive enough oxygen, helping the
plant stay healthy and grow better.
[Music]
You should also remove any flower spikes
that are dry or wilted.
This not only helps the plant look
neater and cleaner, but also prevents it
from wasting energy on parts that are no
longer needed.
[Music]
After handling the roots and removing
the old growing medium, soak the entire
orchid in clean water for about 30
minutes.
[Music]
Soaking the plant helps provide the
necessary moisture after the pruning
process while also helping to clean off
any remaining dirt and bacteria from the
roots and stem.
[Music]
Um while the plant is soaking, we'll
take the opportunity to prepare the
natural fertilizer.
[Music]
Now take about 1/3 teaspoon of sugar and
mix it into 500 ml of room temperature
water. This mixture will create a gentle
solution that provides an initial energy
boost for the plant, stimulates new root
growth, and supports the recovery
process naturally and effectively.
[Music]
Now, Next, take 500 ml of warm water and
add 1 teasp of dry yeast, the kind
commonly used for baking bread. Stir
well and let the mixture sit for about
an hour the yeast to activate and and
grow. Once ready, it will provide a
nutrient-rich source of enzymes,
beneficial microorganisms, which greatly
support the orchid's recovery and
growth.
[Music]
The the microorganisms in the yeast help
improve the microbial environment around
the roots, suppress the growth of
harmful bacteria and fungi, and thereby
reduce the risk of root rot or disease.
Once the roots are stabilized, the
nutrients from the yeast will help the
plant quickly produce new leaves and
flower buds.
[Music]
After soaking the orchid in water for
about an hour, gently take it out and
let it drain.
Next, soak the leaves in the prepared
sugar water solution for about 30
minutes.
Soaking the leaves in sugar water
provides an instant energy boost to the
plant through the leaf tissues, supports
the photosynthesis process, helps the
plant recover faster, and increases its
ability to grow new roots and shoots.
After soaking in the sugar solution for
about 30 minutes, gently remove the
orchid and let it drain.
[Music]
Now mix the sugar water solution with
the prepared yeast solution. This
combination will create a natural
fertilizer rich in microorganisms and
energy which helps stimulate the strong
growth of new roots.
[Music]
Soaking the orchid roots in this mixture
for about 30 minutes will help stimulate
the root growing process extremely
quickly.
[Music]
Thanks to the natural nutrients and
beneficial microorganisms in the yeast
and sugar, the plant will absorb the
energy it needs to regenerate a new root
system, allowing it to recover faster
and grow stronger in the next stage.
[Music]
And here are the orchid pots I regularly
care for using the natural fertilizer
made from sugar and dry yeast. You can
see the flowers blooming brightly, the
buds growing healthily, and the plants
always maintaining their vibrant
appearance.
Uh thanks to this gentle yet microbridge
source of nutrients, the plant not only
recovers quickly but also gains strong
momentum for its upcoming blooming
cycles.
You can make use of the remaining liquid
fertilizer to water other orchid pots in
your garden. For each pot, just about 10
tablespoons of the solution is enough.
This natural fertilizer will gradually
absorb into the growing medium,
stimulating stronger root growth,
helping the plant absorb nutrients more
efficiently, and soon produce new shoots
and buds in the coming days.
[Music]
Using this natural fertilizer about one
to two times a month will produce
noticeable results. The root system will
grow healthier, become denser, and
spread throughout the growing medium,
helping the plant stabilize and absorb
nutrients more effectively.
When the roots are healthy, the entire
plant will become stronger. The leaves
will stay green and vibrant, and more
shoots and buds will appear, laying the
foundation for consistent and
longlasting blooming.
This natural fertilizer also helps
balance the pH level in the orchid pot,
creating a stable and comfortable
environment for root development. When
the pH is maintained at an appropriate
level, the roots won't be harmed by
overly acidic conditions, allowing them
to grow healthily and absorb nutrients
more efficiently.
[Music]
When the roots are healthy, the leaves
are green and the plant is properly
nourished. The flowers will bloom larger
with brighter colors and longerlasting
beauty. That is the well-deserved reward
for the love and dedication you give to
each orchid pot.
[Music]
After soaking in the solution for about
30 minutes, gently take the orchid out.
At this point, the roots have become
plump and greener, and the leaves have
absorbed enough water, becoming firmer.
This is a positive sign that the plant
is recovering and ready to enter a new
growth phase.
[Music]
I use pine bark to grow orchids because
this type of medium is well airrated,
retains just the right amount of
moisture, and supports healthy root
development. Pine bark also helps
prevent water logging, which is one of
the most common causes of root rot in
orchids.
[Music]
I also add a bit of moss to help retain
moisture for the plant. Moss helps
maintain stable humidity around the
roots, which is especially useful during
dry weather or while the plant is
recovering.
[Music]
After placing the pine bark into the
pot, you can gently tap the sides of the
pot to help the bark pieces fill in the
gaps around the roots.
This method helps secure the plant
firmly while ensuring the roots have
even contact with the medium and still
maintain good air flow.
Adding a thin layer of moss on the
surface of the orchid pot will help
retain moisture better for the plant,
especially during dry or hot weather.
[Music]
Watering the remaining sugar and yeast
solution into the orchid pot will
provide additional nutrients and
beneficial microorganisms for the plant.
This mixture will gradually soak through
the growing medium, stimulating stronger
root development and supporting the
recovery process after repotting.
[Music]
On regular days, you just need to mist
the leaves lightly to maintain moisture
and water the plant when the growing
medium appears dry.
[Music]
Maintaining just the right level of
moisture helps the orchid grow steadily,
reduces the risk of root rot caused by
overwatering, and creates ideal
conditions for the plant to absorb
nutrients naturally and effectively.
[Music]
After that, place the orchid pot in a
cool area with enough natural light, but
away from direct harsh sunlight to help
the plant recover more quickly.
The result after 1 month.
In just 1 month, from their initially
wilted state, the leaves now look
healthier, gradually regaining their
plumpness and fresh green color.
[Music]
The orchid roots have grown
significantly and become noticeably
stronger.
These new roots play an important role
in efficiently absorbing nutrients and
water.
[Music]
A healthy root system is a strong
foundation for the orchid's overall
development. When the roots function
well, the plant can efficiently absorb
water and nutrients, which in turn
nourishes green leaves, young shoots,
and stimulates the formation of new
flower buds.
[Music]
Take 1/5 teaspoon of sugar and 1/3
teaspoon of dry yeast. Then mix them
with 300 ml of warm water. Stir well and
let the mixture cool to room temperature
before use.
[Music]
Once the water has water has cooled, you
can use this microbial fertilizer
solution to water your orchid about once
every 2 weeks. This simple method
provides beneficial microorganisms and
gentle energy for the plant, supporting
root development and maintaining overall
health.
After watering, you should place the
orchid pot in a cool area with gentle
indirect light.
[Music]
After 1 month of natural care, the
orchid has fully recovered. The leaves
have returned to a fresh green color
with normal thickness and firmness,
showing that the plant is effectively
absorbing water and nutrients.
[Music]
Shiny green leaves help the plant
photosynthesize more efficiently,
thereby generating energy to nourish the
entire plant.
Healthy leaves are not only a sign of a
well-rowing orchid, but also support the
formation of new shoots and flower buds.
[Music]
Many new roots have also started to
grow, spreading throughout the growing
medium.
This is a clear sign that the plant is
recovering well and developing steadily.
[Music]
Many of the older roots have also grown
longer, becoming thicker and stronger.
When both old and new roots develop
together, the plant gains a solid
foundation to continue growing
vigorously.
[Music]
Healthy and abundant roots help anchor
the plant firmly in the pot, reducing
the risk of wobbling or toppling over.
This provides a stable foundation for
the plant as it grows or begins to
bloom.
Well-developed roots are a key factor in
determining the plant's lifespan.
Orchids with strong root systems tend to
live longer, bloom for many years, and
are less prone to decline.
Hope this video will be helpful for you
all. If you find it useful, please like,
share, and subscribe to support the
channel.
Um, thank you for watching. Wishing you
good luck always and see you in the next
videos.
[Music]