Welcome to the little garden where I
cultivate not only greenery but also joy
and peace everyday. I hope you will find
a relaxing corner for your soul here.
In this video, I share how to care for
rotting orchids using natural, simple,
and easy to find ingredients right in
your own kitchen.
No chemicals needed, just a bit of care
and a love for plants, and you can
completely help your orchid recover,
turn green again, and continue its
journey to bloom.
Let's get started.
Leave a comment and let me know which
country you're watching the video from.
It's wonderful that we can connect and
chat from all around the world.
This is an orchid that's having a
problem. The leaves have started to show
signs of rot. If not treated in time,
the disease can spread quickly and
affect the whole plant. But don't worry,
we can still save it with a very simple
method using natural ingredients.
[Music]
If you haven't subscribed yet, hit the
subscribe button to support me and never
miss any orchid growing tips. It's truly
wonderful to have you along on this
journey.
[Music]
When orchids are grown in the same pot
for a long time without repotting or
changing the growing medium, the old
material gradually decays, retains water
for too long, and suffocates the roots.
[Music]
Uh you can see that the growing medium
in the pot is too old and retains too
much water.
This easily leads to root rot, stem rot,
and leaf rot as the plant can no longer
breathe and the environment has become
poorly ventilated.
You can see white mold patches appearing
on the surface of the growing medium.
This is a sign that the growing
environment is no longer clean and well
ventilated, which can harm the roots and
make the orchid more prone to fungal
infections if continued to be used.
[Music]
Um, when the roots start turning black
like this, it's a clear sign that they
are water logged. The roots can no
longer absorb nutrients and oxygen, and
if not treated in time, the stem and
leaves will quickly be affected as well.
[Music]
Therefore, I will remove all the old
growing medium to give the plant a new
clean and wellventilated environment.
This is an important step to stop the
spread of pathogens and create favorable
conditions for new healthy root growth.
[Music]
Next, I will cut off all the damaged
roots that have turned black or become
mushy.
Uh, this will help the plant avoid the
spread of disease and focus its energy
on nourishing the healthy remaining
roots.
After
[Music]
removing the damaged roots. I rinse the
entire orchid under running water.
This helps remove dirt, pathogens, and
cleanse the cut areas before moving on
to the next treatment step.
[Music]
After rinsing, I let the orchid dry
naturally in a well ventilated place.
[Music]
I start by pouring 2 L of clean water
into a bowl.
Then I add eight drops of methylene
blue. This solution has mild
antibacterial properties that help
protect the orchid from fungal
infections during the recovery process.
[Music]
Step one, use this same solution to soak
the roots and gently clean the surface
of the leaves.
[Music]
This helps eliminate any remaining
bacteria and fungi, creating favorable
conditions for the plant to recover more
quickly.
[Music]
Soak the plant in the solution for about
20 minutes to allow the active
ingredients to penetrate deeply,
effectively cleaning the roots and
disinfecting without harming the plant.
Step two, while waiting for the roots to
soak, use a soft cloth to gently dab the
solution and wipe each leaf clean.
[Music]
This helps remove dust, bacteria, and
makes the leaves cleaner, more
breathable, and healthier.
While wiping the leaves, I noticed that
the top leaf had started to rot. To
prevent it from spreading to other
parts, I immediately cut off the leaf.
[Music]
After cutting off the rotting leaf, I
clean the wound with this solution to
remove excess sap and prevent bacterial
infection.
This is a small but very important step
for the plant to recover safely.
[Music]
Step three. After soaking for 20
minutes, I gently take the orchid out
and hang it in a well ventilated place
for one day.
This allows the cut areas to dry
completely, reducing the risk of
infection before repotting it in a new
growing medium.
[Music]
I use pine bark as the growing medium
for orchids, but before use it needs to
be carefully treated to eliminate mold,
bacteria, and help the plant grow more
safely after planting.
[Music]
I reuse the prepared methylene blue
solution to disinfect the pine bark
before planting. This method is both
economical and helps eliminate any
remaining bacteria and mold in the old
growing medium.
[Music]
Um, I soak the pine bark in the solution
for about 20 minutes and to ensure that
any pathogens are eliminated before use.
[Music]
Um, I soak the pine bark in the solution
for about 20 minutes and to ensure that
any pathogens are eliminated before use.
[Music]
Next, we will prepare a natural
fertilizer to help the orchid recover
more quickly and grow stronger after
being repotted.
I pour one liter of warm water into a
container.
The next ingredient I use is molasses.
It's a natural source rich in minerals
that help stimulate the growth of
beneficial microorganisms for orchid
roots.
[Music]
Uh just one teaspoon of molasses is
enough. Even in a small amount, it
provides sufficient nutrients to support
the fermentation process and nourish the
orchid's root system.
[Music]
The next ingredient is used coffee
grounds.
[Music]
Although it may seem like waste, used
coffee grounds still contain many
minerals that help improve the soil and
stimulate orchid root growth.
Then I stir the mixture thoroughly so
that all the ingredients dissolve and
blend completely together.
[Music]
After stirring well, I cover the
container and leave it in a cool
ventilated place for 1 day. This time
allows the mixture to lightly ferment um
enhancing its nutritional effectiveness
for the orchid.
[Music]
After hanging for one day, you can see
that the orchid roots have completely
dried and turned white.
The cut areas have also sealed,
indicating that the plant is ready to be
repotted into the new growing medium.
Step four, I plant the orchid in a new,
thoroughly cleaned pot.
A clean pot helps minimize bacteria and
provides the best conditions for the
orchid roots to attach to the growing
medium and grow healthily.
Then I add the prepared growing medium
into the pot to replant the orchid. It's
important to arrange the medium evenly
and loosely so the roots can easily
attach and grow well.
[Music]
After planting, I use a small support
stick to secure the plant in place.
This helps the plant stay upright and
prevents the base from shifting,
creating favorable conditions for new
roots to grow and anchor firmly to the
growing medium.
[Music]
I spread a bit of moss over the surface
of the pot. This layer helps retain
moisture in the growing medium while
also creating a natural breathable
environment for for the orchid roots to
grow more healthily.
[Music]
Step four, I sprinkle a bit of turmeric
powder on the cut areas.
[Music]
Turmeric powder has natural
antibacterial properties that help the
wounds dry quickly, reduce the risk of
fungal infection, and support better
plant recovery.
[Music]
After fermenting the mixture for one
day, we proceed to strain out the coffee
grounds.
[Music]
straining makes the solution clearer,
easier to use, and safe for orchid roots
when watering.
[Music]
Uh, I dilute the filtered solution with
an additional one L of clean water to
make a total of 2 L of liquid
fertilizer.
This concentration is mild enough for
regular use without harming the orchid
roots.
Step five, use a soft cloth to soak the
diluted fertilizer solution. Then gently
wipe both the top and underside of the
leaves thoroughly.
Uh wiping the leaves with the natural
fertilizer solution provides
micronutrients through the leaf surface,
helping the plant recover quickly and
grow lush and healthy.
The mild antibacterial compounds in the
mixture, such as those from molasses and
coffee, help keep the orchid leaves
clean and effectively prevent fungal
diseases.
When dirt is removed, the leaves become
more breathable and absorb light better,
thereby increasing the plant's
photosynthesis efficiency.
Do this one to two times per month.
[Music]
Uh step six, I use the remaining
solution to water directly onto the
roots and growing medium.
Uh the natural nutrients from molasses
and coffee grounds help nourish the
roots, promoting faster and stronger new
root growth.
This solution supports the growth of
beneficial microorganisms, helping to
keep the growing medium loose. well
airrated and resistant to harmful fungi.
I place the orchid pot in a spot with
gentle sunlight and good air flow. This
is the ideal condition for the plant to
recover, roots to grow well, and leaves
to maintain a healthy green color.
[Music]
The remaining solution can be poured
into a spray bottle and used to lightly
mist the leaves of other orchid pots in
your garden.
[Music]
For orchids that are in bloom, this
natural fertilizer will help the flowers
last longer with brighter and more
vibrant colors over time.
[Music]
For orchids that haven't bloomed yet,
this fertilizer will help stimulate bud
formation, nourish the plant from roots
to leaves, and prepare the best
conditions for the upcoming flowering
season.
[Music]
You can also apply this fertilizer to
your orchid garden about twice a month.
Uh regular maintenance will help the
plants stay healthy, grow evenly, and
bloom consistently.
[Music]
And here is the result after 3 weeks of
care.
[Music]
You can see the new roots growing
densely and very healthy, indicating
that the plant is recovering well and
ready for vibrant blooming seasons
ahead.
A healthy root system helps the orchid
firmly attach to the growing medium,
absorb nutrients effectively, and better
resist harmful environmental factors.
And as you can see, the leaves have
become glossy and vibrant, an indication
that that the plant is growing strong
from within.
[Music]
Glossy green leaves are not only a sign
of a healthy plant, but they also play a
vital role in photosynthesis, helping
the plant store enough energy to form
buds and bloom beautifully.
[Music]
When the orchid is truly healthy, it can
produce hundreds of flowers, vibrant,
longasting, and blooming continuously
like a wonderful gift from nature.
Uh, a healthy orchid pot not only brings
beautiful blooms, but also contributes
to a fresh, relaxing, and inspiring
living space every day.
I hope you enjoy this video. If you find
it helpful, don't forget to like and
subscribe so you won't miss the next
tips on how to care for orchids in a
natural and simple way.
Thank you for taking the time to watch
the video. I wish you happiness, good
health, and many vibrant orchids in your
living space. See you in the next video.