Welcome to the Happiness Garden, where
we explore the gentle beauty of nature
and the secrets of orchid care in a
simple yet loving way. Each video is a
small journey that helps you connect
more closely with the world of vibrant
petals and the wonders of greenery.
In this video, I will share with you a
completely new way to make organic
fertilizer that's easy to prepare at
home.
[Music]
This fertilizer not only helps orchids
grow strong from roots to leaves, but
can also stimulate them to bloom all
year round naturally and sustainably.
[Music]
Do you have bananas?
To make natural fertilizer, I need two
ripe bananas.
[Music]
If you haven't subscribed to the channel
yet, please hit the subscribe button to
support me and never miss any orchid
growing tips. It's truly wonderful to
have you along on this journey.
[Music]
Every time you eat a banana, don't throw
away the peel just yet.
[Music]
That seemingly useless peel actually
contains many wonderful nutrients that
can become a precious gift for your
orchid.
[Music]
Take two ripe banana peels and cut them
into small pieces.
[Music]
Then put the chopped banana peels into a
blender.
[Music]
Leave a comment and let me know which
country you're watching from. It's
amazing that we can connect and chat
from all around the world.
[Music]
Next, add about 300 ml of filtered
water. This just right amount of water
will help the mixture blend smoothly and
retain all the nutrients from the banana
peels.
[Music]
After blending, pour the mixture into a
clean jar.
[Music]
and add about 700 ml of water so that we
have one liter of the mixture.
The next ingredient is blackstrap
molasses. It's rich in minerals and
helps promote the growth of beneficial
microorganisms during the fermentation
process, which in turn enhances the
nourishing effect for your orchid.
You only need to add one teaspoon of
blackstrap molasses. Just a small amount
is enough to provide excellent energy
for the fermentation process, helping to
create a truly effective natural
fertilizer.
[Music]
After adding the blackstrap molasses,
stir the mixture well to combine all the
ingredients. Then close the lid tightly
and let it sit for 1 day to start the uh
natural fermentation process.
[Music]
This is the orchid I just bought. And
right now, I will share with you the
first step in taking care of a new
orchid, helping it adapt quickly, grow
healthily, keep its flowers on the stem
longer, and bloom again soon after the
current ones fade.
[Music]
First, take some time to carefully
observe the orchid. If you notice any
leaves that are wilted, turning yellow,
or showing signs of rot, you should
gently trim them off.
Then check the growing medium and the
root system. If the medium is decayed or
too wet, you should replace it to
prevent root rot.
Take a close look at the orchid roots.
Healthy roots are usually silvery white
or light green, while damaged ones will
be dark, mushy, and need to be trimmed
off.
[Music]
Since the growing medium is old spagna
moss and the roots are starting to show
signs of rot, I decided to remove all of
the old medium.
This helps prevent root rot and creates
the best conditions for treating and
caring for the roots properly.
After removing the growing medium, I
trimmed off the damaged roots.
[Music]
Soft, darkened, or hollow roots need to
be removed to help the plant recover
more quickly and to prevent the damage
from spreading to the healthy roots.
[Music]
After trimming and treating the roots, I
repotted the plant into a new pot.
I wrapped a small amount of new fungus
treated dry moss around the roots. This
layer of moss will gently retain
moisture for the roots while helping the
plant stay stable and adapt more easily
to the new pot.
These new roots will be wrapped and
protected by the layer of moss, helping
to maintain stable moisture and create
an ideal environment for continued root
growth.
Next, I used a growing medium made of
crushed pine bark that has been treated
for fungus and thoroughly dried.
[Music]
This type of medium helps retain just
the right amount of moisture, provides
good air flow, and creates ideal
conditions for the roots to grow strong
in the new pot.
[Music]
Finally, I spread a thin layer of moss
on the surface of the pot. This moss
layer helps retain moisture in the
growing medium while creating a cool and
clean environment for the orchid to grow
more steadily.
[Music]
After potting, to keep the orchid stable
and prevent it from wobbling, I used a
plasticcoated steel rod bent into a
support brace.
[Music]
In addition to the English voiceover, we
have now created versions in French,
German, Italian, Spanish, Portuguese,
Japanese, Hindi, Dutch, Polish, Korean,
and Indonesian to help you listen and
understand the content more easily.
To listen in your preferred language,
open the video and click on settings,
the gear icon to select the appropriate
audio track.
[Music]
This support helps keep the plant steady
in the pot, creating favorable
conditions for the new roots to anchor
firmly into the growing medium.
[Music]
At the same time, the support brace also
helps secure the flower spike,
preventing it from breaking or tipping
over during care. This allows the orchid
to maintain its elegant shape with the
blooms safely and naturally supported.
This is an orchid that has finished
blooming. And now with the second
method, I'll guide you on how to care
for your orchid after the flowers have
faded.
This is a very important stage that
helps the plant recover its energy, grow
strong, and get ready for the next
blooming season.
[Music]
I only keep the unopened buds on the
spike as they still have the potential
to develop and produce new flower spikes
in the near future.
As for the buds that have already
bloomed, I gently cut them off so the
plant doesn't waste more energy on them.
This allows it to focus on nourishing
the healthy parts and getting ready for
the next blooming cycle.
[Music]
When the spent buds are removed, the new
flower spikes receive more nutrients.
This helps the plant focus on nourishing
young shoots, promoting growth, and
preparing for the next fresh blooming
cycle.
[Music]
Then I continue trimming away the old,
damaged or hollow roots.
[Music]
Removing the non-functional roots will
help the plant develop new roots more
easily and absorb water and nutrients
more efficiently.
[Music]
After letting the mixture ferment for 1
day, we begin the preparation process.
This is an important step to create a
natural fertilizer that is easy for
orchids to absorb and safe for their
growth.
[Music]
First, we need to filter out the residue
from the mixture. This helps make the
solution clearer, easier to use, and
prevents clogging the growing medium or
damaging the roots when watering the
plant.
[Music]
After filtering, I dilute the solution
with 3 L of clean water. This ratio
ensures that the nutrients are
sufficient for the plant to absorb
effectively while still being safe for
the orchid's sensitive roots.
[Music]
Step one, use a soft cloth to soak up
the diluted solution. Then gently wipe
it over the surface of the leaves.
Wiping the leaves with this mixture
helps remove dust, residue, and even
bacteria that have accumulated on the
leaf surface. When the leaves are clean,
the plant can photosynthesize more
effectively, boosting metabolism and
promoting stronger growth.
Through leaf wiping, a portion of the
nutrients in the mixture will be
absorbed through the leaf surface. This
is a quick and effective way to provide
nutrition, especially for orchids that
are recovering or nutrient deficient.
The natural ingredients in the mixture
help strengthen the leaves natural
protective layer, making the leaves
healthier and more resistant to fungal
infections, pests, and harmful
environmental factors.
You should wipe the leaves with this
mixture twice a month. This frequency is
enough to help the plant absorb
nutrients effectively, boost its
resistance, and still keep the leaves
naturally healthy and well ventilated.
Step two, pour the diluted solution into
a clean spray bottle. Using a spray
bottle helps distribute the nutrients
more evenly across the entire plant from
the stem and leaves to the surface of
the growing medium.
[Music]
Then gently spray the solution over the
entire plant, including the top and
underside of the leaves, the stem, and
the surface of the growing medium.
[Music]
Um, spraying the solution on both the
top and underside of the leaves allows
the plant to quickly absorb uh essential
micronutrients through the leaf surface,
supporting more efficient photosynthesis
and metabolism.
The fermented solution contains natural
ingredients with mild antibacterial
properties, helping protect the plant
more effectively against fungi and pests
that commonly appear in humid
conditions.
[Music]
When evenly sprayed on the stems and
leaves, the nutrients in the solution
also help stimulate the growth of new
roots and the formation of new shoots,
supporting faster recovery after
blooming.
You should spray this solution twice a
month.
Uh, step three, pour the remaining
solution directly into each orchid pot.
This gently and effectively delivers
nutrients to the roots, supporting the
plant's growth from root to tip.
[Music]
When poured directly at the base, the
nutrients in the solution quickly soak
into the root zone, allowing the plant
to absorb them more efficiently and
promoting overall growth.
Uh this organic solution creates ideal
conditions for young roots to form and
grow healthily. New roots help the plant
stay stable in the pot and absorb water
and nutrients more effectively.
Regularly watering with the solution
also helps improve the growing medium's
environment by nourishing beneficial
microorganisms which keep the plant
healthy and reduce the risk of root rot
and fungal diseases.
You can also soak the orchid pot in this
solution for about 20 minutes.
Soaking allows the roots to absorb
maximum nutrients while also softening
the growing medium, creating favorable
conditions for new root development.
Step four, while waiting for the orchid
pot to soak, you can use a soft cloth to
gently wipe off any excess moisture on
the leaves and stem.
[Music]
Uh this helps reduce the risk of water
accumulation that can cause leaf rot
while also keeping the plant clean and
healthy.
[Music]
Wiping off excess moisture with a soft
cloth also helps reduce the risk of mold
forming on the leaves, especially in
humid conditions. This better protects
the orchid and keeps it looking fresh
and clean.
[Music]
After soaking for the appropriate time,
gently remove the orchid pot and place
it in a spot with soft sunlight. Gentle
light will help the plant
photosynthesize effectively, support
nutrient absorption, and promote overall
growth.
[Music]
You can absolutely use the remaining
solution to spray on other orchid pots
in your garden.
This is a simple way to care for your
entire orchid garden naturally,
economically, and effectively.
However, be careful not to spray the
solution directly on the flowers. Doing
so may cause the petals to become
discolored or wilt faster, reducing the
natural beauty of the orchid blooms.
[Music]
And this is the result after 10 days of
caring for the plant with this natural
fertilizer.
As you can see, the leaves have become
much greener and shinier compared to
before. This is a sign that the plant is
absorbing nutrients well and growing
steadily.
[Music]
Even though it is a newly purchased
orchid recently repotted into a new pot,
you can already see new roots starting
to grow. This is a great sign that the
plant is adapting and growing well.
[Music]
And here is the orchid that had already
finished blooming. After some time of
being cared for with this natural
method, its leaves have now turned green
and glossy again, showing that the plant
is recovering very well.
[Music]
Many new roots have grown, thick, plump,
and healthy. This is a wonderful sign
that the plant is absorbing nutrients
well and is ready for its next growth
cycle.
[Music]
These new roots will help the orchid
anchor firmly into the growing medium,
absorb water and nutrients more
efficiently, and thereby promote the
orchid's overall growth and development.
[Music]
What do you think about the way I
revived these orchids? Feel free to
leave a comment and share your thoughts.
I'd love to hear your feedback and learn
about your own experiences.
[Music]
Take care of your orchid pots with all
the love and gentleness in your heart.
When you nurture nature with sincere
affection, it will always return the
most wonderful things to you.
Every drop of water, every moment you
spend caring is a small gift that brings
life, radiant blooms, and endless joy to
your garden.
Thank you for watching. Wishing you a
joyful day full of energy and
overflowing with love from your little
garden. Goodbye and see you in the next
video.
Welcome to my little channel where we
care for nature with love and patience.
Wishing you a peaceful day full of
inspiration.
In today's video, I continue to share
with you a new type of organic
fertilizer easy to make at home that
helps care for orchids to grow fully
from roots, stems, and leaves to flowers
all year round.
That's my helper. How do you like it?
[Music]
Let's get started.
Uh, this is the orchid I just bought.
Uh, when the delivery person brought it
and opened the package, the petals had
already wilted.
[Music]
the the surface of the leaves still has
a layer of mineral residue. It's
probably a mix of minerals and
pesticides sprayed from their industrial
orchid garden.
[Music]
Upon checking the roots, I found mold
and many rotting roots.
Which country are you watching this
video from? Leave a comment and let me
know where you are. It's amazing that we
can connect with each other from all
around the world.
[Music]
Cut off all the damaged roots.
Damaged roots are often home to harmful
fungi and bacteria. Removing them helps
reduce the risk of spreading disease to
the plant.
Then remove the old growing medium.
[Music]
The old growing medium may contain
harmful fungi, bacteria, or parasites.
Removing it helps reduce the risk of
spreading disease to the plant.
[Music]
Just keep a small amount of moss to
prevent the plant from going into shock
during repotting.
Then remove the wilted flowers.
[Music]
Wilted flowers absorb nutrients and
energy from the plant. Uh removing them
allows the plant to focus on growing new
blooms and healthy leaves.
[Music]
Then take 1 tbsp of baking. baking soda.
Add one liter of water.
[Music]
Then gently place the orchid pot into
the container.
Pour in the baking soda solution and let
it soak. This helps clean the roots,
relax them, and improve nutrient
absorption.
[Music]
This will help eliminate fungal diseases
and insects that cause root rot.
[Music]
Then use a soft cotton pad to wipe the
leaves with the baking soda solution.
Baking soda has antifungal properties
helping to prevent the growth of harmful
fungi and bacteria on the leaves and
roots.
[Music]
When you wipe the leaves with the baking
soda solution, it's not just about
cleaning. You're also removing dust,
mineral residue, and leftover
pesticides, allowing the leaves to
breathe better and absorb light more
effectively.
[Music]
Next, soak the orchid roots in this
solution for about 30 minutes. This is
the ideal time for a deep clean and
gentle mineral absorption.
[Music]
Do you have a cucumber?
Uh, every time I eat cucumber, I usually
peel it and never throw the skin away
because this peel is a wonderful
ingredient for making natural fertilizer
for orchids. It's both convenient and
nutrient-rich.
[Music]
Cucumber peel contains many minerals and
vitamins which help provide nutrients
for the plant and support its growth.
[Music]
Cut the peel of one cucumber into small
pieces.
In addition to the English voiceover,
we've also created versions in French,
German, Italian, Spanish, Portuguese,
Japanese, Hindi, Dutch, Polish, Korean,
and Indonesian to help you listen and
understand the content more easily.
To hear your preferred language, open
the video and click on settings, the
gear icon, to select the appropriate
audio language.
Put them into a container and add one
liter of boiling water.
Leave a comment and let me know which
country you're watching from. It's truly
wonderful that we can can connect and
chat from all around the world.
Add 3 tablespoons of rice into the
container.
[Music]
Rice, especially rice water, contains
many essential vitamins and minerals for
plant growth, such as nitrogen,
phosphorus, and potassium.
Then wait for the water to cool down
before using it.
After soaking for 30 minutes in the
baking soda solution, we repot the
orchid into a new pot.
Using chopped pine bark for planting
helps retain moisture while still
allowing good air flow for the roots.
[Music]
A new pot is usually larger, giving the
plant more space for root growth, which
in turn improves its overall
development.
[Music]
Once the water has cooled, strain it to
remove any residue.
[Music]
Dilute it with one liter of water to
make a total of 2 L of natural
fertilizer mixture.
Then water your orchid with this mixture
two to three times a month.
[Music]
Watering with this mixture also helps
gently moisturize the growing medium and
orchid leaves while providing natural
enzymes that keep the leaves cleaner,
boost photosynthesis, and make the
orchid flowers more vibrant and
longerlasting.
[Music]
Then soak a soft cotton pad in this
water and gently wipe the entire leaf.
[Music]
Cucumber juice is rich in vitamin C and
minerals which help nourish the leaves
and enhance the overall health of the
plant.
[Music]
Cucumber war water has moisturizing
properties helping to soothe the leaves
and provide the necessary hydration for
the plant.
Then place it in a spot with plenty of
indirect light so the orchid can
photosynthesize.
[Music]
And here is the result after 3 weeks.
You can see many new healthy roots
growing.
[Music]
New healthy roots help form a better
root network, improving drainage and
aeration in the growing medium
and you can see the leaves have become
greener and stronger.
[Music]
Uh, the flowers will last longer, not
only staying fresh, but also blooming
with new ones. A sweet response from
nature to your gentle care.
Uh, what do you think about the way I
revived this little orchid? Feel free to
leave a comment and share your thoughts.
I'd love to hear your feedback and
experiences.
Uh if you face any difficulties while
growing orchids, don't hesitate to leave
a comment. I'm always here to support
you so you can grow healthy orchids that
bloom beautifully.
Um other orchids cared for with this
method also have healthy root systems.
[Music]
And the leaves have become glossy Green.
Uh, take care of your orchid with all
the love you have for plants because
that very love will bloom through every
green leaf and every vibrant petal.
[Music]
And you'll feel fulfilled as you enjoy
and admire the beautiful orchids grown
by your own hands.
Hope you enjoy this video. If you find
it helpful, don't forget to hit like and
subscribe so you won't miss the next
tips on how to care for orchids
naturally and easily.
[Music]
Um, thank you for joining me today.
Wishing you happiness always with your
beautiful orchids. See you in the next
video.