Hello everyone. Today I'm going to share
with you a simple way to make natural
fertilizer at home, which will help your
orchids grow healthy, lush, and bloom
beautifully throughout the garden.
[Music]
Thanks to this natural fertilizer, the
roots and leaves of the plant will stay
healthy, which in turn helps the orchid
produce not only more flowers, but also
longerlasting blooms that retain their
color and stay on the stem for a long
time before fading.
The method is very simple. Anyone can do
it using familiar ingredients found
right in the kitchen.
Let's get started.
The ingredient to make today's natural
fertilizer is pure ground coffee.
You just need to put 3 tablesp of ground
coffee into a clean bottle. The gentle
aroma of coffee is not only pleasant but
also awakens the vitality of the orchid
when used properly.
[Music]
Then pour about 500 ml of boiling water
into the bottle. The high temperature
will help extract the maximum nutrients
from the coffee, creating a
nutrient-rich solution ready to nourish
the roots and leaves of the orchid.
[Music]
Tightly close the lid and let it sit
until the water has completely cooled.
During this time, the nutrients in the
coffee will slowly infuse into the
water, creating a gentle yet powerful
mixture for your orchid.
[Music]
This is an orchid entering the post-
blooming stage with its leaves starting
to wilt and weaken. This is the crucial
time to help the plant regain its
vitality from the roots to the leaves
and prepare for the next blooming cycle.
[Music]
If you haven't subscribed yet, please
hit the subscribe button to support me
and never miss any orchid growing tips.
It's truly wonderful to have you along
on this journey.
[Music]
First, you need to cut off the withered
flower spike so the plant no longer has
to use energy to support it. This helps
the orchid focus on recovery and
nourishes the roots and leaves back to
health.
After cutting off the flower spike,
gently check the roots. If the roots are
still healthy, light in color, and have
no strange smell, that's a good sign.
But if there are any rotten or dry
roots, uh you should cut them off to
prevent spreading and help the plant
recover more quickly.
Through this initial inspection, I
noticed that many roots have become
hollow and lifeless. Therefore, it's
necessary to examine the entire root
system more carefully to remove the
damaged parts and create the conditions
for the orchid to recover from the base.
Just as I expected when removing the
plant from the pot, you can see that
many roots are already damaged.
Now, confidently cut off all the damaged
roots. Removing the rotting roots will
help prevent disease from spreading and
allow the plant to develop a new,
healthier root system in the near
future.
[Music]
In addition to treating the roots, you
should also cut off any yellowing or
aged leaves.
These leaves no longer have the ability
to nourish the plant and it may even
drain its energy during the recovery
process.
[Music]
uh leave a comment and let me know which
country you're watching the video from.
It's wonderful uh that we can connect
and and chat with each other from all
around the world.
After pruning, rinse all the remaining
roots and leaves under running water.
The gentle stream of water will help
remove old soil, bacteria, and any
remaining pathogens, keeping the plant
clean and ready for the next step in
care.
Leave a comment and let me know at which
country you're watching the video from.
It's amazing that we can connect and
share with each other from all around
the world.
Once the coffee water has completely
cooled, stir the mixture well to evenly
distribute the nutrients in the water.
[Music]
Before using, you should filter out the
remaining residue in the solution. This
helps prevent the roots from getting
dirty and keeps the solution clean,
allowing it to absorb more easily into
each root cell of the orchid.
[Music]
Next, dilute the filtered coffee water
with 1.5 L of clean water. This gives us
a total of 2 L of solution. Gentle
enough not to burn the roots, yet rich
enough in nutrients to help the plant
recover from within.
[Music]
Step one, soak the orchid roots in the
diluted coffee solution for about 20
minutes.
[Music]
During this time, the nutrients will
slowly absorb into the roots,
stimulating regeneration and helping the
plant take in energy gently and
naturally.
[Music]
Step two, while waiting for the roots to
soak, you can use a soft cloth dipped in
the solution to gently wipe the surface
of the leaves.
[Music]
This not only helps remove dust from the
leaves, but also provides additional
nutrients through the surface, making
the leaves shinier and healthier.
The antioxidant compounds in coffee help
boost the plant's resistance, especially
during the recovery period after root
pruning
when applied to the leaves. The solution
also helps them become glossy and
beautiful, reducing yellowing and dry
tips caused by nutrient deficiencies.
While the orchid roots are soaking in
the solution, let's take the time to
prepare the growing medium for planting.
I choose a clean, well-arrated, and
moisture retentive medium, crushed pine
bark. I choose crushed pine bark as the
growing medium for this repotting.
I also mix in a bit of moss along with
the crushed pine bark.
[Music]
Combining pine bark with a bit of moss
creates a balanced environment, airy
enough for the roots to breathe well,
yet able to retain moisture long enough
to nourish the young roots.
[Music]
Next, pour 2 L of clean water into a
basin.
[Music]
Next, add one teaspoon of baking soda to
the basin of water to soak the growing
medium.
[Music]
Baking soda will help gently clean and
disinfect, creating a fresh and safe
environment for the roots when
replanting.
Um, simply pour the baking soda solution
over the growing medium. Then soak it
for about 10 minutes.
This is a small but very important step
to ensure that the growing medium is
clean, safe, and provides the best
support for the roots during the
recovery process.
After
[Music]
soaking, take the growing medium out and
let it drain.
Uh the growing medium should have
moderate moisture, not too dry and not
too wet to create an airy environment
that helps the orchid roots adapt easily
when replanted.
Uh step three, once everything is ready,
gently place the orchid into the new
pot.
Keep the roots neatly inside the pot.
Then slowly add the drained growing
medium around them to secure the plant
in place.
[Music]
Make sure the plant stands firmly but
still has enough space for the roots to
breathe and grow.
[Music]
Step four, gently water the orchid pot
with the diluted coffee mixture.
Make sure to evenly distribute the
solution so that every part of the roots
receives these valuable nutrients,
helping the plant recover quickly and
grow healthily.
Uh this solution will provide essential
nutrients helping the plant quickly
recover and develop a strong root system
while also stimul stimulating the lush
green growth of the leaves.
Step five, pour the remaining coffee
mixture into a spray bottle.
This will be the solution that allows
you to easily spray the leaves and other
parts of the plant, providing nutrients
more evenly and effectively during care.
[Music]
Gently spray evenly over the leaves and
stems. This not only provides additional
nutrients, but also adds moisture,
helping the orchid's leaves become
glossy and healthier each day.
Spraying the coffee solution helps
directly supply nutrients to the leaves,
stimulating a more effective
photosynthesis process. As a result, the
orchid's leaves become lush, green,
healthy, and more resistant to harmful
environmental factors.
Step six, after spraying the coffee
solution, gently wipe off the water
droplets on the leaves with a soft
cloth.
Uh, wiping off the water droplets on the
leaves not only helps prevent mold and
bacterial growth, but also avoids leaf
rot or soggess caused by excessive
moisture.
[Music]
At the same time, this helps keep the
orchid leaves dry and well ventilated,
creating favorable conditions for gas
exchange and photosynthesis to occur
more effectively.
Step seven, use a stake or a small
plasticcoated metal rod to secure the
orchid in the pot.
[Music]
This helps the plant stand firmly,
preventing it from falling or shifting
when watering or moving. At the same
time, it creates favorable conditions
for the roots to grow stronger and
healthier.
[Music]
Step eight, place the orchid pot in a
spot with gentle sunlight, avoiding
harsh direct rays. Soft light helps the
plant photosynthesize effectively
without leaf burn, supporting balanced
recovery and growth.
And here is the result after 3 weeks of
care.
You can see that many new roots have
emerged, a clear sign that the plant is
recovering well and starting to grow
again in its new environment.
These new roots will continue to grow
and spread throughout the growing
medium, helping the plant absorb water
and nutrients more effectively. They
create a strong foundation for the
orchid to develop new leaves and prepare
for its next blooming cycle.
[Music]
I hope you enjoyed this video. If you
find it helpful, uh, don't forget to
like and subscribe so you won't miss the
next tips on how to care for orchids
naturally and simply.
[Music]
And as you can see, the leaves have
become glossier and greener thanks to
the nutrients from the coffee and
regular cleaning. This is a sign that
the plant is recovering well and
becoming healthier each day.
Although there are still one or two
slightly wilted older leaves, once the
root system grows strong, the plant will
quickly recover these leaves. That's
because the roots are the heart that
nourishes the entire plant, transporting
water and nutrients to every leaf.
With just patience and a little love
each day, any orchid can be revived,
return to full health, and before long
bloom with vibrant, lively flowers once
again.
Even if you start with a wilted orchid,
you can still turn it into a radiant
gift from nature simply through gentle
care from the heart. Miracles always
begin with love and patience.
Thank you so much for taking the time to
watch the video. Goodbye and see you in
the next one.