Welcome to the happiness garden where we
nurture the beauty of nature together.
Every leaf, every petal with all our
love and patience.
Today I continue to share with you a
method of caring for orchids using
natural fert fertilizer.
A simple yet effective method that helps
orchids grow fully and bloom multiple
times a year.
[Music]
Let's get started.
This is an orchid that has finished
blooming and is weakened. I bought it
for just $1 from a local flower shop,
hoping to revive it and bring it back to
life.
[Music]
You can see that the leaves have wilted,
a clear sign that the plant is in
decline.
[Music]
To begin the recovery process, you first
need to cut off the old and withered
flower spikes. This helps the plant
conserve energy by no longer sustaining
the non-living parts.
After that, check the roots and the
orchid growing medium to see if they are
still good and and safe for the plant.
I noticed that although the orchid is
wilted, its roots are still healthy and
the moss used as the growing medium is
still white and not decayed. So, there's
no need to replace it at this time.
You should also carefully check and cut
off any damaged roots to avoid affecting
the growth of the healthy ones.
[Music]
Leave a comment and let me know which
country you're watching from. It's
wonderful that we can connect and chat
from all around the world.
[Music]
Next, prepare a container with one L of
clean water to mix a disinfectant
solution, which will help clean the
orchid before starting the recovery
process.
[Music]
Then add three drops of methylene blue
to create a mild disinfectant solution
that helps protect the orchid roots from
harmful bacteria and fungi.
[Music]
If you haven't subscribed to the channel
yet, please hit the subscribe button to
support me and never miss any orchid
growing tips. It's wonderful to have you
along on this journey.
[Music]
Next, soak the entire orchid along with
its growing medium in this solution for
about 20 minutes to gently disinfect and
help the plant get rid of any disease.
[Music]
Then take one tablespoon of breadcrumbs
as the ingredient to create a natural
fertilizer which will help gently and
safely revive the orchid.
[Music]
Next, add half teaspoon of baking yeast
used for making bread to activate the
fermentation process, helping to create
a natural source of nutrients for the
plant.
After that, add 500 ml of warm water to
dissolve the mixture, helping the yeast
work more effectively during the
fermentation process.
[Music]
Cover the container and let the mixture
ferment for 1 hour to allow the yeast to
work producing natural nutrients that
help revive the orchid.
[Music]
After soaking for 20 minutes, take the
orchid out and place it in a cool, airy
spot so the growing medium can drain
completely before continuing with the
care.
[Music]
Um, after fermenting the mixture for 1
hour, strain out the sediment to collect
the clear liquid from the fermented
breadcrumbs, preparing it to be used as
a natural fertilizer for the orchid.
Fermented breadcrumbs are rich in
microorganisms and enzymes that break
down organic matter to create vitamin B
and minerals, helping orchid roots stay
healthy and recover quickly after
wilting.
Microorganisms from fermented
breadcrumbs improve the growing medium,
stimulate beneficial microbes to
develop, and help orchid roots absorb
nutrients and grow strong, healthy roots
quickly.
[Music]
Then soak the growing medium and orchid
roots in this solution for about 20
minutes to allow the plant to absorb the
nutrients for recovery.
[Music]
While waiting, use a soft cloth soaked
in this solution to gently and
thoroughly wipe both the top and bottom
surfaces of the orchid leaves.
[Music]
This method helps clean dirt, prevent
fungal diseases, and remove harmful
insects from the plant.
Additionally, this method also helps
enhance nutrients, supporting the orchid
to grow healthier everyday.
[Music]
After soaking the orchid in the
fermented water mixture for about 20
minutes, gently take the plant out.
Then make a drainage hole at the side of
the pot to help prevent water from
rising too high, avoiding damage to the
orchid roots.
[Music]
Then pour water into the orchid pot to
maintain the necessary moisture for the
plant.
When you make a drainage hole like that,
the water level is always kept moderate,
just touching the growing medium,
helping maintain maintain the necessary
moisture without water logging the
orchid roots.
Then place the orchid pot in a spot with
gentle sunlight so the plant receives
enough light without the leaves getting
scorched.
Uh, every two weeks, care for the orchid
using the fermented breadcrumb mixture
once to help the plant grow healthy.
If you haven't subscribe to the channel
yet, please hit the subscribe button to
support me and never miss any orchid
growing tips. It's wonderful to have you
along on this journey.
In addition to English dubbing, we have
now created French, German, Italian,
Spanish, Portuguese, Japanese, Hindi,
and Indonesian versions to help you
listen to and understand the content
more easily.
[Music]
To listen in your preferred language,
open the video and click on settings,
the gear icon, to select the appropriate
audio language.
[Music]
Each time after fertilizing, you should
change the water in the orchid. pot
immediately or change it when you see
the water is dirty to keep the
environment clean for the plant.
[Music]
And here is the wonderful result after 6
weeks of caring for and reviving the
orchid using this natural method.
[Music]
You can see that many new roots have
developed and become noticeably
stronger.
Uh these new roots will help the plant
absorb nutrients more effectively,
thereby reviving the wilted leaves and
promoting the orchid's healthy growth
once again.
[Music]
What do you think about this method of
reviving a weak orchid? Leave a comment
and share your thoughts with me.
[Music]
Although the leaves are still wilted, as
the roots grow stronger, they will
absorb water and nutrients more
effectively, helping the leaves recover
quickly.
To help the orchid grow vigorously and
bloom soon, we need to transfer it to a
larger pot so the roots have space to
expand.
I chose sterilized and dried moss as the
orchid growing medium as it is both
disease-free and retains moisture well
for the roots.
Since moss retains moisture very well,
you only need to water it one to two
times a month. Overwatering can cause
the roots to become water logged and
rot.
[Music]
Uh after repotting from now on you only
need to care for the orchid with the
fermented breadcrumb fertilizer about
one to two times a month.
[Music]
Or you can also alternate with other
types of organic fertilizers to
supplement nutrients and help the plant
develop more fully.
[Music]
And don't forget to place the orchid pot
in a spot with gentle sunlight because
only when the plant photosynthesizes
well can it absorb nutrients to the
fullest and grow properly.
[Music]
And here is the result after another 3
months of caring for the orchid using
this natural method.
[Music]
You can see that the wilted leaves have
fully recovered. And even more
wonderfully, the orchid has grown many
new leaves.
[Music]
As long as you stay patient and revive
one plant at a time, over the years,
you'll have a whole garden full of
blooming orchids, just like I do now.
[Music]
If you also love orchids, leave a
comment below so we can connect and
share our orchid care experiences with
each other.
Or if you face any difficulties while
growing orchids, don't hesitate to leave
a comment. I'm always ready to help you
grow healthy orchids that bloom
beautifully.
I hope you enjoy this video. If you find
it helpful, don't forget to hit like and
subscribe to the channel so you won't
miss the next tips on how to care for
orchids naturally and simply.
Thank you for watching the video.
Wishing you lots of joy and beautiful,
healthy orchids blooming all year round.
[Music]