Hello everyone. All of us want to have
orc orchids healthy and has many flower
[Music]
buds. The flower buds grow a lot. The
flower branches grow very
[Music]
quickly. Today I share a new
fertilizer. With this very simple and
easy method in front, there will be more
flower buds, better green leaves, and
more flower
[Music]
branches. Let's start with this simple
method. Use cinnamon
powder. Uh, it always has antibacterial
properties. is it helps prevent orchids
from rotting and
fungus. Use one
[Music]
spoon. Add one liter of boiling water.
Cinnamon water will help prevent and
control fungi and bacteria that cause
diseases on orchids very well.
[Music]
Wait for this water to
cool. Next, I took a ripe banana.
Contains a lot of minerals. Helps
orchids grow and quickly produce many
flowers.
[Music]
and cut into small pieces.
Put all these banana peels in a
jar. Add one liter of boiling
water. Wait for this water to
cool.
Before fertilizing, water each orchid
pot. This method helps keep the
substrate and plant roots moist and also
a way to remove old fertilizer. Helps
new fertilizers be more easily absorbed.
[Music]
Which country are you watching videos
from? Please comment for
me. Um, it's great that we can chat with
people from all over the world.
[Music]
and leave for 20 minutes.
After 20 minutes, take it out.
[Music]
This is one of the causes of your orchid
does not grow and has no flowers.
[Music]
Uh after cooling filter to get cinnamon
juice.
[Music]
Step
Use it to immediately care for these
leaves. Applying this method once a week
will add a lot of nutrients through the
leaves. Helps the leaves stay
greener.
Remember to wipe both sides of the leaf
evenly because insects often cling to
the surface of leaves. Helps remove dirt
and insects on orchids very effectively.
When you do this for orchids, it will
always work. Um, regain the green color
of leaves and promote plant
photosynthesis happens faster. Leaves
are always green and healthy.
If the leaves are yellow or infested
with insects, this is it. One of the
very effective ways
Step
two, you use this water to spray
orchids.
[Music]
And we will do this in the morning. By
afternoon, the leaves will dry and the
tree will always be
[Music]
healthier. You should apply this method
once a week.
weak orchids will develop very healthy
[Music]
roots. Um, this is one of the very safe
and sustainable organic fertilizers for
orchids to grow quickly.
[Music]
It will help eliminate insects such as
spiders, aphids,
thris. But you should not spray it on
flowers because wet flowers will quickly
rot and lose their petals.
[Music]
Then we filter the banana peel water and
mix it with cinnamon water.
[Music]
Step
three, water the treere's roots
immediately every 2 weeks.
It will always protect and promote
sustainable development in
orchids. This is one of the very safe
and sustainable fertilizers for orchids.
The ability to absorb is slow, but once
grown, the tree is always
sustainable. You can alternate it with
other organic fertilizers.
[Music]
After fertilizing, soak the orchid pot
in this fertilizer solution for about 20
minutes.
Orchids are tropical plants, so don't
let the growing medium get too dry. It
will be very difficult for plants to
absorb nutrients from fertilizer.
[Music]
Then you take out and always place the
orchids in places with light during the
day. Leaves will be greener and plants
will photosynthesize better. Helps new
flower branches grow very quickly.
[Music]
Let's see the results of care with this
natural fertilizer. Your orchids are
cared for this way. The roots will grow
very healthy and the leaves will always
be green. The green color of the leaves
is very beautiful.
[Music]
weak orchids. It will gradually become
greener and the roots will grow very
healthy. This is one of the simple
fertilizers and very effective so your
orchids can grow quickly and easier.
[Music]
After just about 2 months of care with
natural fertilizer, you can see that my
orchid now has lush, firm green leaves.
A clear sign that the plant is absorbing
nutrients well and growing healthily.
[Music]
Not only that, the plant has also
produced many new roots, firmly clinging
to the growing medium in the pot,
showing that the orchid is truly healthy
and recovering
[Music]
impressively. Especially, the orchid has
even started to grow a new flower spike
with many side branches, proving that it
is accumulating enough energy to
continue its blooming cycle thanks to
proper care and rich natural nutrition.
[Music]
As for this orchid, you can easily see
the remarkable leaf growth, sturdy and
glossy as coated with wax, showing that
the plant is absorbing nutrients very
well and responding responding
positively to the natural fertilizer
care
[Music]
regimen. The flower spike is large and
plump, a clear sign that the plant is
full of vitality and has been provided
with all the nutrients it needs to
prepare for a brilliant bloom.
[Music]
And as you can see, the orchid has
developed a very healthy root system
with many new roots growing, indicating
that the plant is developing steadily
and absorbing nutrients effectively.
[Music]
Take care of your orchid with all the
love you have for plants, and you will
be rewarded with beautiful flowers that
will brighten your
garden. Flowers will also bloom longer
and last longer, lasting over time.
I always share many different ways to
care for orchids so you can see and
choose which method is most
[Music]
suitable. There are also many subtitles
on the channel for you to easily choose
from. Hope it will always help you a
lot. Don't forget to like, share, and
subscribe to the channel and press the
bell to conveniently follow. Goodbye and
see you again. Wish you always success.