I am very happy to welcome you to my
little garden, a peaceful corner to
breathe with nature. Here we will
explore the beauty of plants and share
simple yet inspiring ways to care for
them.
Today I happened to find a weak orchid
that had been thrown away. I suddenly
thought with just a little love and the
right care, the plant can still come
back to life beautifully. So, I want to
share with you a very simple yet
incredibly effective semi-hydroponic
method for growing orchids. One that you
can easily try at home. This method
helps the plant absorb moisture and
nutrients more steadily, allowing the
roots to grow strong and healthy. If you
love orchids and want a modern,
convenient way to care for them that
still feels natural and full of grace,
this is the perfect choice for you.
[Music]
First, you need to gently cut off all
the damaged leaves and roots. This helps
remove parts that could cause fungal
infections and allows the plant to focus
on on nurturing the remaining healthy
roots. Be sure to use clean, sterilized
scissors before cutting to avoid
spreading any infection to the plant.
After this step, the orchid will look
tidier and be ready for the recovery
process in the semi-hydroponic
environment.
[Music]
Um, since the plant no longer has
leaves, you can see that the two flower
spikes, although the petals have fallen
off, are still fresh. Inside these
spikes, there are still plenty of
nutrients. So, I decided to keep them.
When we let the spikes remain, the
remaining nutrients inside will
gradually return to the stem, giving the
plant extra energy to nourish and
develop new shoots and leaves.
After trimming, rinse the entire plant
under running water. The gentle stream
will help completely remove any
remaining dirt or mold from the roots
while also allowing the plant to
reabsorb a bit of natural moisture.
Be very gentle when handling the roots
as this is a stage when the plant is
very weak and sensitive.
After rinsing, place the plant in a well
ventilated area to let it dry
completely.
[Music]
Next, we will prepare a natural
fertilizer that helps the plant recover
quickly and grow strong.
The first ingredient is very familiar.
It's rice. You only need about 3
teaspoons of rice, a small amount, but
enough to create a rich source of
nutrients for the plant. Rice is not
only a food that provides energy for
humans, but also contains many B
vitamins, minerals, and starch, all of
which help nourish strong roots,
stimulate new shoots, and support the
plant's quick recovery.
Next, add about 600 ml of water to soak
the rice.
[Music]
The final ingredient is red apple cider
vinegar. Just one small spoonful is
enough. Apple cider vinegar provides
mild antibacterial properties, balances
the pH in the growing environment, and
stimulates the roots to absorb nutrients
more effectively.
If you don't have red apple cider
vinegar, you can easily replace it with
any other type of fruit vinegar you have
at home. Whether it's apple, grape, or
pineapple vinegar, they all offer
similar benefits in helping the plant
stay healthy and recover more easily.
[Music]
After mixing all the ingredients, let
the solution sit overnight to ferment
slightly. This natural fermentation
process helps break down the nutrients
in the rice, making them easier for the
plant to absorb.
[Music]
Please comment and let me know which
country you're watching the video from.
It's wonderful that we can connect and
share from all around the world.
After one night, the solution will have
a mild distinctive scent of fermented
rice. That's the sign your natural
fertilizer is ready to use.
[Music]
after stirring well, strain out the
residue and keep only the clear liquid.
The liquid you obtain is a nutrient-rich
natural fertilizer ready to help your
weak orchid revive and grow strong.
[Music]
Now, pour this nutrient-rich natural
fertilizer into a container and soak the
entire root system and stem of the
orchid for about 20 minutes.
This step allows the roots to directly
absorb the vitamins, minerals, and
enzymes in the solution, helping the
plant recover more quickly after damage.
Uh during the soaking process, you'll
notice the roots becoming softer and
fresher, a sign that the plant is
beginning to wake up and absorb energy
to revive.
[Music]
After soaking for about 20 minutes,
gently lift the plant out of the
solution and let it drain for a bit.
If you haven't subscribed to the channel
yet, please click the subscribe button
to support me and not miss any orchid
care tips. It's wonderful to have you
with me.
[Music]
I use a plasticcoated rustresistant
steel rod as a support stick to hold the
plant upright when placing it in the
semi-hydroponic pot. This support helps
keep the plant stable and prevents the
roots from shifting or breaking during
the recovery process.
[Music]
Um, after planting, pour clean water
into the pot so that the water level
touches the roots but does not
completely submerge them.
If you're using tap water, remember to
pour it into a container and let it sit
overnight before use. This allows the
chlorine to evaporate, preventing damage
to the plant's young roots.
[Music]
Clean, gentle water will help the plant
absorb nutrients better while creating a
safe environment for new roots. roots to
grow strong in the semihydroponic
system.
Then place the orchid pot in a spot with
with gentle sunlight, avoiding direct
harsh sun to prevent the leaves and
roots from burning.
At the same time, change the water once
a week to keep the environment clean,
maintain moisture, and ensure the plant
receives full nutrients from the
semi-hydroponic solution.
[Music]
After one week, feed the plant with the
natural fertilizer prepared earlier.
This helps provide additional vitamins,
minerals, and starch, stimulating strong
root growth and nurturing new leaf
shoots.
[Music]
I continue to feed the plant with the
natural fertilizer made from rice and
fermented red apple cider vinegar. This
solution is full of nutrients, enzymes,
and easily absorbable minerals, helping
the orchid's roots get deeply nourished
while promoting the growth of new leaf
shoots.
[Music]
Soak both the roots and stem of the
plant in this fertilizer solution for
about 20 minutes. During the soaking,
the nutrients from the rice and
fermented red apple cider vinegar will
directly penetrate the roots and stem,
providing the energy needed for the
plant to recover.
[Music]
After soaking for about 20 minutes,
gently lift the orchid out and replant
it into the semi-hydroponic pot with
fresh water.
Next, place the pot in a spot with
gentle sunlight, avoiding direct harsh
sun to prevent damage to the roots and
stem while allowing the plant to absorb
enough light to grow and recover better.
Uh, after soaking, you can use the
remaining fertilizer solution to water
the roots, the growing medium, or put it
in a spray bottle to mist other regular
orchids in your garden.
This method helps all the orchids
receive natural nutrients, stimulates
strong root and new chute growth, and
maintains vibrant vitality throughout
the entire garden.
Spraying the solution onto the stem and
leaves helps the plant absorb additional
easily assimilable nutrients, supporting
the formation and growth of new leaf
shoots. Moreover, these nutrients also
help the flowers bloom evenly and last
longer, allowing the orchid to remain
vibrant and beautiful throughout the
growing season.
[Music]
When spraying the mixture onto the
roots, the nutrients from the rice and
red apple cider vinegar will directly
penetrate, providing essential vitamins,
minerals, and enzymes. This helps the
orchid roots grow strong, thereby
promoting healthy recovery and growth.
[Music]
And here are the results after 45 days
of reviving the weak orchid using the
semihydroponic method.
Uh you can see that the root system has
grown very strong with many new roots
emerging ready to absorb nutrients and
water for the plant.
Not only that, the orchid has also grown
new leaves, showing that the recovery
process is progressing successfully and
the plant's vitality is increasingly
abundant.
These new roots and leaves will continue
to grow strong, helping the orchid
absorb more nutrients and water, thereby
speeding up its recovery. They will also
serve as a solid foundation for the
plant to form new shoots and flowers,
bringing vibrant vitality to the entire
plant.
[Music]
What do you think of how I revived this
small orchid? Don't hesitate to leave a
comment and share your thoughts. I'm
really looking forward to hearing your
feedback and experiences.
[Music]
Now I will continue to feed the plant
with the natural fertilizer prepared
earlier while also changing the water in
the semi-hydroponic orchid pot.
[Music]
This helps provide sufficient nutrients,
maintain stable moisture, and create an
ideal environment for the new roots and
leaves to continue growing strong. With
regular care like this, the orchid will
recover faster and be ready for vibrant
flower shoots in the near future.
[Music]
After soaking for about 20 minutes,
gently lift the orchid out and replant
it into the semi-hydroponic pot while
also adding fresh water.
[Music]
Next, place the pot in a spot with
gentle sunlight, avoiding direct harsh
sun to prevent damage to the roots and
stem, while allowing the plant to
receive enough light to grow and recover
healthily.
[Music]
And here are the results after 3 months
of reviving the weak orchid using the
semihydroponic method.
You can see that from a weak discarded
orchid with no leaves, rotting roots,
and only a few remaining root strands
and stem. The plant has now fully
recovered. The orchid has regrown with
many lush green leaves and strong roots,
showing that its hidden vitality is
still very strong when cared for using
the right method.
[Music]
You can see that after the plant
absorbed all the nutrients from the
still fresh flower spikes, they have now
aged, dried, and are no longer alive.
This is completely normal as the
nutrients in the flower spikes have been
fully used by the plant to nourish new
roots and leaves, helping it recover and
grow stronger.
[Music]
The dried flower spikes are now just
natural remnants and do not affect the
overall health of the orchid. So, we can
remove them. Removing the dried spikes
helps the plant look tidier, reduces the
risk of fungal infections, and creates
space for new leaves and shoots to grow
better.
Then continue planting the orchid into
the semi-hydroponic pot, ensuring the
roots are evenly spread and the stem is
securely supported. Don't forget to
change the water and feed the plant with
natural fertilizer every 1 to two weeks
to maintain stable moisture and provide
full nutrients. With this regular care,
the orchid will continue to recover,
grow new, strong roots and leaves, and
be ready for the next vibrant flower
buds.
And here are the semihydroponic orchid
pots that I planted previously.
You can see that they bloom vibrantly
with lush green leaves and look very
beautiful overall when grown in a
semi-hydroponic environment.
This shows that the semihydroponic
method not only helps the plant recover
quickly but also provides lasting
beauty, easy care, and maintains
vitality for the orchids.
[Music]
What do you think of how I grow orchids
using the semihydroponic method in my
garden? Don't hesitate to leave a
comment and share your thoughts. I'm
really eager to hear your feedback and
experiences.
[Music]
I hope you enjoy this video. If you find
it helpful, don't forget to like and
subscribe to the channel so you won't
miss future tips on caring for orchids
in a natural and simple way.
[Music]
Thank you for watching. Goodbye and
wishing you a day full of joy, peace,
and wonderful moments with your plants.
[Music]