Welcome to the happiness garden where
every moment is devoted to the beauty of
orchid petals.
Uh today to help you discover more
gentle yet effective natural fertilizing
methods for orchids, I will continue to
share a new technique that keeps your
plants healthy and blooming beautifully
throughout all four seasons.
Um if you haven't subscribed yet, please
click the subscribe button to support me
and not miss any orchid growing tips.
it. It's wonderful to have you along for
the journey.
The first ingredient we need is a ripe
banana. Simple yet rich in wonderful
nutrients for orchids.
Uh bananas contain plenty of potassium
and natural nutrients, helping orchid
leaves become glossier and stimulating
the plant to bloom continuously and
persistently over time.
In addition, uh the vitamins and
minerals in bananas also support strong
root growth, helping the plant absorb
nutrients more effectively and recover
more quickly after each blooming cycle.
After slicing the banana into thin
pieces, gently place them all into a
clean jar, preparing for the
fermentation step to extract the best
natural nutrients for your orchids.
[Music]
The next ingredient is eggshells. And
you only need about two eggshells to
provide the essential minerals for your
orchids.
[Music]
Eggshells contain plenty of natural
calcium, which is very good for orchids,
helping the stems and leaves become
stronger and maintain a healthy green
color throughout their growth.
Next, add about 500 ml of water.
Then blend the entire mixture until all
the nutrients are fully combined.
Uh leave a comment telling me which
country you're watching from. Uh it's
amazing that we can connect and chat
together from all around the world.
Once blended, pour the mixture into a
clean jar to begin the fermentation
process, allowing the nutrients to
ferment naturally and become more easily
absorbed by your orchids.
[Music]
Seal the jar tightly and place it in a
cool, airy spot for about 3 weeks,
allowing the mixture to ferment slowly
and create the best natural nutrients
for your orchids.
During the first week, open the lid once
a day to release the fermentation gases
and keep the mixture ventilated, helping
it ferment more evenly and creating a
truly safe nutrient source for your
orchids.
Uh, this orchid has just finished its
blooming cycle and right now it needs
more energy to recover, nourish its
roots, and prepare for the next
flowering phase.
Normally, after finishing a blooming
season, an orchid needs about 8 to 12
months to recover and accumulate enough
energy before blooming again. But if you
you care for it properly and provide the
natural nutrients it needs, then in just
3 to 4 months, the orchid can enter a
new blooming cycle, healthier and more
vibrant, vibrant than ever.
What you need to do now is remove all
the damaged, weak, or rotten roots so
the plant no longer wastes energy trying
to sustain nonfunctional roots. Once
they are removed, the orchid will focus
its strength on developing healthier new
roots.
[Music]
Next, gently remove the old and damaged
leaves as they no longer contribute
nutrients to the plant. Once these
weaker parts are cleared away, the
orchid will be better ventilated and
able to focus all its energy on
regenerating new healthy leaves and
roots.
Then cut off the old flower spike as it
has completed its purpose and can no
longer produce new buds. Removing it
helps the plant redirect its energy
toward regenerating roots and leaves and
preparing for the next blooming cycle.
[Music]
This is the fermented product after 3
weeks. And you can recognize good
quality when the mixture gives off a
light, mild, and pleasant fragrance. On
the other hand, if it has an unusual,
unpleasant smell, you should discard it
and make a new batch to ensure the
safety of your orchids.
Take about 50 ml of the fermented
mixture to prepare for dilution,
ensuring the solution is gentle and safe
for the orchid roots when applied.
Then add one liter of water to dilute
the 50mm mixture, creating a natural
nutrient solution that absorbs quickly
and is ideal for watering or soaking
orchid roots.
[Applause]
Step one, after mixing, use a soft cloth
to gently absorb the solution. Then
carefully wipe both the top and
underside of the leaves. This helps the
leaves absorb nutrients better and
maintain their natural glossy green
appearance.
Wiping the leaves with the fermented
banana and eggshell mixture first helps
the orchid leaves become naturally
naturally glossy as the nutrients are
absorbed directly through the leaf
surface giving them a fresher and
healthier appearance.
U when the leaf surf surfaces are gently
cleaned and nourished in this way, the
plant photosynthesizes more effectively,
absorbs light fully and converts energy
better for the recovery process.
Moreover, the nutrient layer from the
fermented mixture also helps prevent
mold and bacteria, keeping the leaves
well ventilated and minimizing common
orchid diseases.
[Music]
With regular protection and nourishment,
the orchid will strengthen its
resistance, recover quickly after each
blooming cycle, and maintain a stable
condition with less weakening.
[Music]
And when the leaves are healthy and
photosynthesizing well, the plant will
have enough energy to stimulate new root
growth and sprout young leaves, laying
the foundation for more beautiful and
sustainable blooming seasons ahead.
[Music]
Step two, pour the diluted solution into
a spray bottle ready to mist evenly over
the orchid leaves and roots. This method
helps the nutrients absorb quickly,
distribute evenly, and reach all parts
of the plant easily.
When spraying the mixture onto the
leaves and roots, the nutrients are
absorbed directly, allowing the orchid
to quickly take in essential vitamins
and minerals, nourishing it from root to
tip and promoting overall growth.
Thanks to the evenly distributed
nutrients, the plant will enhance its
photosynthesis, resulting in greener and
more vibrant leaves while efficiently
converting energy to recover quickly
after each blooming cycle.
At the same time, the thin layer of
solution covering the leaf surface also
helps prevent mold and bacteria, keeping
the leaves and roots well ventilated and
reducing the risk of pests and diseases.
Thanks to the potassium and calcium from
the mixture being absorbed evenly into
the roots and leaves, the plant will
stimulate new root growth, sprout young
leaves, and prepare flowers for the next
season, ensuring a faster and stronger
growth cycle.
Alternatively, you can also water this
fertilizer mixture directly onto the
roots and growing medium, allowing the
nutrients to penetrate deeply into the
root system, nourish the plant from
within, and keep the medium moderately
moist, supporting healthy root
development.
When watering directly onto the roots,
the nutrients penetrate deeply into the
soil and growing medium, helping the
roots quickly absorb essential minerals
and vitamins, promoting healthy growth
from root to tip.
[Music]
Even watering also helps maintain stable
moisture in the growing medium, creating
an ideal environment for new roots to
grow quickly and anchor firmly while
reducing the risk of roots drying out or
wilting.
[Music]
After watering, you can soak the orchid
roots in this mixture for about 20
minutes, allowing the nutrients to
penetrate deeper, helping the roots
fully absorb them and enabling the plant
to recover quickly, ready for strong
growth ahead.
After soaking for about 20 minutes,
remember to remove the orchid pot from
the mixture so the roots are not
submerged for too long, preventing root
rot and preparing the plant for the next
care stage.
Next, sprinkle a little cinnamon powder
on the cut of the flower spike to
provide antibacterial protection,
prevent mold, and help the cut heal
quickly, safeguarding the plant from
diseases after removing the old flowers.
If water remains on the leaves, use a
dry cloth to absorb all the droplets
from the leaf crevices, especially on
young leaves, to prevent moisture from
causing mold and to keep the leaves dry
and healthy.
[Music]
After the leaves have dried, you should
place the orchid in a cool, airy spot
with enough indirect light so the roots
and leaves recover well and the
nutrients from the fertilizer mixture
are optimally absorbed, preparing the
plant for the next blooming phase.
[Music]
And here are the results after 3 months
of caring for the orchid with natural
fertilizer following the end of its
blooming cycle.
You can see the lush green leaves,
strong root growth, and that the plant
is ready for the next blooming season
full of vitality.
And you can see that the orchid has
grown two new flower stems, one
developing vigorously, while the other
has just emerged, signaling a promising
and brilliant next blooming season.
Uh the leaves have become glossy which
shows that the orchid is absorbing
nutrients very well, healthy from root
to tip and ready for the upcoming
blooming cycles.
Both the large flower stem and the newly
emerging small stem are very healthy,
indicating that the orchid has been
properly cared for and has enough energy
to support blooming while maintaining
lasting vitality.
Um the roots in the pot as well as the
aerial roots are both growing vigorously
showing that both the natural fertilizer
and the orchid microclimate environment
are very suitable helping the plant
absorb nutrients optimally and develop
comprehensively.
When you care for your orchid with all
the love and attention you give to
plants, you will be rewarded with joy,
peace, and vibrant blooms. A
welldeserved reward for your dedicated
care.
Every time your orchid recovers, grows
new roots, or blooms beautifully, it is
not only the result of your hands, but
also a testament to your patience and
perseverance.
Remember, caring for each orchid is like
nurturing your own life. Every small
effort gradually creates wonderful
results, bringing joy and motivation
every day.
I hope you enjoy this video. If you find
it helpful, don't forget to hit like and
subscribe to the channel so you won't
miss future tips on caring for orchids
naturally and easily.
[Music]