Hello everyone. Thank you for visiting
my
garden. Today I'm very excited to
continue sharing with you how to
propagate orchids through cutings at
home using very simple ingredients that
you can easily find in your
kitchen. If you find this helpful, don't
forget to subscribe to the channel to
support me and to make sure you don't
miss any tips on plant care.
As you can see, this orchid has finished
blooming, and this is the perfect time
for us to start the process of
propagating orchids from
[Music]
cutings. I will cut across this old
flower stem to begin the process of
propagating the orchid through cutings.
[Music]
We need to cut neatly to avoid crushing
the cut, creating the best conditions
for the orchid cutting to grow into a
strong, healthy, young
[Music]
plant. Next, we remove the protective
layer around the dormant bud to help
stimulate it to sprout faster, which
will encourage the young plant to grow
strong and quickly.
Next, I take an onion as onions contain
a lot of nutrients and natural compounds
that are great for orchid
[Music]
propagation. Um, the components in
onions, especially antioxidants and
ends, help stimulate root formation and
enhance the growth potential of the
young plant.
[Music]
Onions also help prevent mold and
harmful bacteria, keeping the cutting
healthy throughout the development
process. I put the onion in here to
extract the onion juice.
[Music]
Please comment and let me know which
country you're watching the video from.
It's so amazing that we can chat
together from all around the
world. Do as I did. Then wait for about
10 minutes to allow the onion juice to
soak into the cutting.
[Music]
Uh after soaking the cutting in onion
juice for about 10 minutes, take it out
and let the cut dry naturally for a few
hours. This helps the cut to heal,
reducing the risk of infection and
creating optimal conditions for root
development later on.
Then apply a special plant glue to the
cut, which helps prevent water from
seeping into the wound. This will
protect the cut from bacteria and mold,
thus preventing rot and allowing the new
plant to grow
healthily. Then place the cutting in a
cool, wellventilated area to allow the
glue to dry completely.
This will help the glue dry evenly and
form a solid protective layer,
preventing bacterial infection and
supporting better growth of the
plant. While waiting for the glue to dry
completely, take one teaspoon of
cinnamon powder and soak it in one liter
of hot water to treat the growing medium
before inserting the cutting.
Cinnamon powder has antibacterial and
antifungal properties, helping to clean
the growing medium, prevent the growth
of harmful bacteria, and create a safe
environment for the cutting to
[Music]
develop. After the water cools, filter
out the residue to leave only the clear
liquid ready to be used for treating the
growing medium.
This ensures that the growing medium
will not be contaminated with
impurities, providing the best
conditions for the development of orchid
[Music]
roots. Then soak the dry moss in the
cinnamon water for about 20 minutes.
This will help the moss of absorb
nutrients from the cinnamon water while
also disinfecting it and creating a good
environment for the development of
orchid roots during the rooting process.
[Music]
Then remove the moss and let it drain.
The moss has now been treated and is
ready to be used as a growing medium for
rooting orchid cutings.
I have recycled a plastic bottle to
create a mini greenhouse which helps
speed up speed up the rooting process
and ensures better results for the
orchid cutings. Here I have created
ventilation holes in the plastic bottle
to ensure air flow helping to prevent
excessive moisture
buildup. Uh I also made drainage holes
at the bottom of the plastic bottle to
prevent water from accumulating which
could cause root rot in the cutings.
[Music]
After placing the moss inside, we will
insert the cutting and mist it regularly
to maintain moisture. This helps keep
the humidity stable for the cutting,
creating a favorable environment for
root development and allowing the young
orchid to sprout healthily.
Then place the mini greenhouse in a spot
with gentle sunlight and good
ventilation and continue to wait for the
orchid to
sprout. Soft light will help stimulate
the growth process without causing the
cutting to get sunburned or lose
moisture too quickly. Be patient. Those
lovely little sprouts will appear soon.
Now, let's take a look at the results
after 3 weeks of rooting the
[Music]
cutting. As you can see, the dormant bud
has now sprouted. This shows that the
cutting has adapted well to the
environment, absorbed enough nutrients,
and has begun developing into a healthy
young plant.
[Music]
I continue to mist regularly and place
the cutting in a spot with gentle
sunlight to maintain ideal conditions.
Uh helping the cutting develop steadily
and allowing the sprout to grow
healthily.
[Music]
Now, let's check the results after 3
months of rooting the
[Music]
cutting. As you can see, the young
orchid has grown healthily with lush
green leaves that are strong and sturdy.
[Music]
The roots have also developed strongly,
proving that the rooting process was
successful and the orchid is growing
[Music]
well. Once the roots are strong and the
plant is sturdy, transferring the orchid
to a pot will help it grow better,
providing ample space for the plant to
continue
[Music]
thriving. Now I can transplant the young
orchid into a new pot so it can thrive
in an outdoor environment.
[Music]
I recycle plastic bottles into orchid
pots using the semihydroponic
[Music]
method. This method helps the orchid
receive sufficient moisture from the
water at the bottom of the pot while
keeping the roots well ventilated and
preventing water logging, creating ideal
conditions for the plant's growth.
[Music]
with this planting method. After
planting, I only need to water once and
change the water when it becomes dirty
in the pot.
The semihydroponic method helps maintain
moisture for the plant without the need
for frequent watering while also
promoting strong and healthy root
[Music]
development. The semihydroponic method
helps maintain moisture for the plant
without the need for frequent watering
while also promoting strong and healthy
root development.
[Music]
If you haven't subscribed to the channel
yet, please hit the subscribe button to
support me and not miss any orchid care
tips. It's wonderful to have you along
on this journey of caring for and
propagating
[Music]
orchids. Thank you for watching the
video. Goodbye and see you in the next
ones. Wishing you beautiful and healthy
[Music]
orchids. Welcome back to Happiness
Garden. Orchids are special plants that
require proper care to thrive and bloom
beautifully all year round.
Today, I'll guide you on how to make
natural fertilizer using simple, easy to
find ingredients that you probably
already have at
[Music]
home. This method is not only budget
friendly, but also incredibly safe for
your
plants. Let's dive in and get started.
[Music]
Today I used coffee grounds to make
natural
fertilizer. Take one cake of coffee
grounds about 20
[Music]
g. The next ingredient I used is
eggshells to make natural fertilizer.
Take clean, dry eggshells and crush them
into small
pieces. Coffee grounds provide nitrogen
for lush leaves while eggshells add
calcium to strengthen roots.
The mild acidity of coffee grounds pairs
with the alkalinity of eggshells to
create a balanced pH suitable for
orchids.
[Music]
Put everything in a
jar. Add one liter of boiling
[Music]
water. If you haven't subscribed to the
channel yet, please click the subscribe
button to support me and not miss any
orchid growing tips.
In addition to the English voice over,
we have now created voiceovers in
French, German, Italian, Spanish, and
Portuguese to help you listen to and
understand the video content more
easily. How to select the audio language
on YouTube. One, open the video and
click on settings, the gear icon. Two,
select subtitles CC. Three, click on
audio and choose the language you want,
English, frutch, italiano, espanol, or
Portuguese.
Cover the jar and let it steep until the
water cools completely. Usually takes 1
to two
hours. Once cooled, strain out the
solids and keep the liquid
Um, I don't watch videos, but if you
want to know where your viewers are
watching from, feel free to ask them to
share in the
comments. It's great that we can chat
together from all over the world.
[Music]
Add one liter of
water. Step one.
[Music]
Use a soft cotton pad to gently wipe the
upper and lower sides of the leaves with
this
solution. This method will remove dust,
helping the plant breathe better by
keeping the stamata open.
This fertilizer solution helps prevent
certain pests or fungi due to the mild
acidity from the coffee grounds and
minerals found in eggshells.
Uh, wiping the leave leaves helps supply
additional nutrients directly to the
plant, especially to weak areas or parts
that show signs of nutrient deficiency.
It's good to wipe the leaves with this
solution once every 1 to two weeks to
provide nutrients and help the plant
thrive. If you need to clean the leaves
or remove dust, you can wipe the leaves
once a week.
[Music]
Step two.
Next, we put this solution into a spray
bottle and spray it on each orchid
pot. Uh, shake the spray bottle before
use to ensure the solution is well
mixed.
Lightly spray the solution on both the
top and underside of the leaves,
avoiding the flowers to prevent
damage. You can also spray around the
roots if accessible.
spray the fertilizer solution once a
week or as needed.
Be sure not to overspray the plant to
avoid water logging.
[Music]
Step
three, water the orchid's growing
medium, focusing on the roots and around
the base of the
plant. Avoid watering directly onto the
leaves or flowers to prevent damage.
Uh, water the orchid with the fertilizer
solution once a week or as needed.
[Music]
If the solution feels too concentrated,
you can dilute it with water, especially
if the plant shows signs of being
sensitive.
Soak the orchid pot in the fertilizer
solution for about 20 minutes to allow
the roots to absorb enough water and
[Music]
nutrients. After soaking, remove the pot
from the solution and allow it to drain
before placing it back in its usual
[Music]
spot. Step four.
After watering or soaking the orchid pot
in the fertilizer solution, gently use
the cloth to absorb any excess water on
the surface of the leaves, both the top
and underside.
[Music]
Be sure to absorb thoroughly so there is
no water left on the leaves, which helps
the plant avoid water logging and allows
it to better absorb the nutrients.
[Music]
Then place the orchid pots in a spot
with gentle sunlight to help the orchids
photosynthesize well.
[Music]
However, avoid direct sunlight,
especially the harsh midday sun, as it
can cause leaf burn, heat shock, and
stress to the plants.
[Music]
Results after one
month. Uh as you can see the roots have
developed quickly and are very healthy.
[Music]
Healthy new roots promote faster growth,
providing a strong foundation for the
plant to bloom and develop.
[Music]
Healthy new roots promote faster growth,
providing a strong foundation for the
plant to bloom and develop, enhancing
its resilience against harsh
factors. You can see that the orchid has
produced many new flower spikes.
You see, on the same tree, four new
flower branches can grow at the same
time.
[Music]
And the leaves also become green, shiny
and very strong and
healthy. Continue to care for your
orchids with all the love and dedication
you have for nature.
When you invest your time and effort,
the beautiful blooms you receive will be
a wonderful reward, a testament to the
patience and care you've given to each
leaf and root.
[Music]
Keep nurturing them with love and you'll
experience the joy and satisfaction
every time you watch those orchids
bloom, bringing beauty and pride created
by your own
hands. Hope this video was helpful.
Don't forget to like, comment, share,
and subscribe for more videos.
Thanks for watching and supporting the
channel. Wishing you success with your
orchids. See you next time.