Hello everyone.
To help your orchids bloom beautifully
all year round, today I'll share a
simple and effective way to make natural
fertilizer.
With easily accessible ingredients,
you'll have an amazing option for caring
for your orchids.
If you haven't subscribed to the channel
yet, please click the subscribe button
to support me and not miss any orchid
growing tips. It's great to have
company.
Let's get started.
To make this fertilizer, I took an apple
and cut it into small pieces.
Remove damaged apple parts. This will
not affect the quality of natural
fertilizer.
[Music]
Please comment to me which country you
are watching the video from.
[Music]
In addition to the English dub, we've
now created dubs in French, German,
Italian, Spanish, Portuguese, Japanese,
Hindi, and Indonesian to help you hear
and understand the content more easily.
[Music]
Apples contain nutrients like potassium,
phosphorus, and trace elements which
help orchids grow healthily.
Apples enhance root development and
stimulate flowering.
Additionally, apples help improve the
soil's microbial system.
[Music]
This creates a favorable environment for
orchids to absorb nutrients.
Put the apples in a jar and pour in one
liter of water. About four cups of
water.
Then add five tablespoons of rice.
And add two teaspoons of wine yeast.
Then stir the mixture well.
[Music]
This is a jar of natural fertilizer I
fermented 3 weeks ago.
Then take about 50 mm, three spoons of
this fermented fertilizer.
[Music]
Mix with 2 L of water about 8 cups.
This way you've created a wonderful
fertilizer for orchids.
[Music]
Cut off damaged roots to prevent root
rot from spreading to healthy parts.
It also stops wasting energy on
unhealthy parts. This creates a better
environment for new roots to grow.
Um, I keep these unflowered nodes to
stimulate them to bloom again.
For buds that have finished blooming,
cut them off.
Uh cutting again to prevent the cut from
being crushed will limit rot in the cut.
Then apply cinnamon powder to the cut to
help the wound heal quickly.
Step one.
Water the roots with this liquid
fertilizer solution and soak for 20
minutes.
Watering and soaking orchid roots in
liquid fertilizer made from fermented
apples and rice provides natural
nutrients, stimulates root growth,
improves the orchid's health, and
enhances its flowering ability.
The beneficial microorganisms in the
fertilizer also improve the soil
environment, making it easier for the
plant to absorb nutrients.
Step two.
Now, thoroughly wipe the top and bottom
of the orchid leaves with this liquid
fertilizer solution.
Wiping the top and bottom of the orchid
leaves with liquid fertilizer helps
provide nutrients directly to the
leaves, stimulating growth and enhancing
photosynthesis.
This makes the plant healthier, improves
nutrient absorption and supports
blooming.
The microorganisms in the fertilizer
also help keep the leaves clean,
preventing diseases.
[Music]
Step three,
put this solution into a spray bottle
and spray it on your orchid.
[Applause]
Spraying the liquid fertilizer solution
on the orchid provides direct nutrients
to the leaves and stems, stimulating
growth, enhancing photosynthesis, and
promoting overall plant health.
It also helps the orchid absorb
nutrients quickly, improves its
resistance to diseases, and supports the
blooming process.
Step for
[Music]
afterward you need to wipe off any
excess solution left on the orchid
leaves.
Wiping off any excess solution helps
prevent fungal issues or leaf burn leaf
burn caused by the fertilizer solution
being exposed to direct sunlight.
It also helps the leaves dry faster,
preventing the creation of a moist
environment that pro that promotes the
growth of bacteria and fungi.
[Music]
After soaking for 20 minutes, remove the
orchid and plant it in a new pot to help
it grow better.
[Music]
I grow it using chopped pine bark as the
substrate.
Planting with shredded pine bark helps
with good drainage, but still creates
enough moisture for orchids to grow
without being water logged.
When growing orchids, you need to
observe the time to water them.
Observe the roots. Silver gray means
they need watering. Check the soil
moisture. The leaves show signs of
wrinkling. The pot is lighter than
normal. And water in the morning.
From now on, you can uh nurture and care
for this orchid with this fermented
apple fertilizer following the four
steps I share two to three times per
month.
Then remember to place the orchid pot in
a place with light sunlight for best
photosynthesis.
[Music]
Photosynthesis helps plants generate
energy from sunlight, converting CO2 and
water into oxygen and glucose. This
process provides food for plants,
supports growth, and produces oxygen for
the environment.
[Music]
results after 2 months.
As you can see, after being cared for
with this natural fertilizer, the orchid
leaves become greener, glossier, and
stronger.
The roots grow vigorously, sprouting
many new roots, proving that this
fertilizer is truly suitable and highly
effective. Especially
the plant has grown two new flower
spikes, proving that the fertilizer
provides abundant nutrients, stimulating
strong blooming.
Even more impressively, this old flower
spike has grown two new branches at the
top near the cut point, proving that the
plant continues to absorb nutrients well
and thrive.
Uh, I hope you enjoy this video. Please
leave your comments below in the video's
comment section for me.
Take care of your orchids with all the
love you have for plants, and you will
be rewarded with beautiful, healthy
flowers that bloom all year round.
Thank you for watching and don't forget
to support the channel by liking,
sharing, and subscribing.
Goodbye and see you in the next video.
Welcome everyone to my beloved little
garden where I share simple yet
heartfelt things for my beautiful orchid
pots.
Today I will share with you how to make
a simple natural fertilizer at home to
help restore the or the orchid after it
has finished blooming so the plant can
continue to grow healthily and prepare
for the next blooming.
Um you can see that my orchid has many
spent flower stems but don't worry it's
a normal sign and we can help the plant
recover better.
We need to remove all the wilted petals
so the plant can focus its energy on
developing roots and leaves, preparing
for the next blooming.
[Music]
The unopened buds can be stimulated to
produce new flower stems here, helping
the plant bloom continuously throughout
the year.
As for the buds that have already
bloomed, they cannot bloom again. So, we
just need to take good care of the
remaining buds.
[Music]
Next, take about 250 ml of water into a
cup.
[Music]
Next, you need to prepare baking soda.
This is the main ingredient that helps
adjust the pH in the orchid pot and
prevent some harmful fungi and bacteria.
Just about a/ teaspoon of baking soda is
enough. No need for too much as we only
need the right amount to achieve the
desired effect without harming the
plant.
Next, you need neem oil. Neem oil helps
repel insects and prevent bacterial and
fungal diseases, helping to protect the
orchid plant and keep it healthy.
Just one teaspoon of neem oil is enough.
This amount of oil will create an
effective solution without overloading
the plant.
Stir well to ensure that the neem oil
and baking soda dissolve completely into
the water, creating a uniform solution
ready to use.
[Music]
Step one, use a soft cloth to soak up
this mixture and gently wipe both the
top and bottom of the leaves, helping to
remove dust and small insects while also
protecting the leaves from diseases.
[Music]
Neem oil can help maintain the natural
moisture of the leaves, preventing them
from drying out and keeping the leaves
soft and fresh.
The combination of baking soda and neem
oil not only helps remove insects, but
also creates a protective layer on the
leaves, helping the plant effectively
resist pests and diseases.
After wiping the leaves, pour this
mixture into a spray bottle. Make sure
the spray bottle is clean and ready to
spray evenly on the leaves and the
orchid's growing medium.
After wiping the leaves, pour this
mixture into a spray bottle. Make sure
the spray bottle is clean and ready to
spray evenly on the leaves and the
orchid's growing medium.
When sprayed on the leaves, this mixture
helps remove dirt and small insects,
protects the leaves from diseases, and
helps the plant photosynthesize more
effectively.
When sprayed on the stem, it helps
prevent the growth of bacteria and
fungi, keeping the stem healthy and
preventing it from rotting or getting
damaged.
When sprayed on the roots and growing
medium, it helps balance the pH in the
medium, promoting better root
development and more effective nutrient
absorption.
Step three, use a soft cloth to absorb
the excess water on the leaves and
between the leaf veins, helping the
leaves dry quickly and preventing mold
from developing.
Uh, please comment and let me know which
country you're watching the video from.
It's wonderful that we can chat with
each other from all around the world.
After that, place the orchid pot in a
spot with gentle sunlight and good
airflow. Do not water it for 3 days to
allow the plant time to absorb the
nutrients and recover naturally.
Next, we will prepare another very
special natural fertilizer for orchids.
You only need a few familiar
ingredients. Ripe banana, garlic, honey,
and warm water.
Take one ripe banana and slice it into
thin pieces. Bananas provide plenty of
potassium and natural nutrients that
help stimulate strong flowering in the
plant.
Um, then put the sliced banana into a
clean jar. A glass or plastic jar will
work as long as it has a tight fitting
lid for fermentation.
[Music]
Next, take three cloves of garlic and
chop them finely. Garlic helps with
antibacterial and antifungal properties
and boosts the orchid's resistance.
[Music]
If you haven't subscribe to the channel
yet, please hit the subscribe button to
support me and not miss any orchid
growing tips. It's truly wonderful to
have you along on this journey.
After slicing, add the garlic to the jar
along with the banana.
[Music]
The next ingredient is one teaspoon of
dry yeast. The dry yeast will help
ferment the mixture, creating enzymes
that are beneficial for the orchid's
growth.
Uh the next ingredient is honey. Add
about 1 teaspoon of honey, which will
enrich the mixture with nutrients and
support the fermentation process.
[Music]
Finally, add 0.5 L of warm water. The
warm water helps dissolve the
ingredients and stimulates the
fermentation process quickly.
[Music]
We should not fill the jar completely
with water leaving some space at the top
uh because fermentation will produce
gas. This space allows the mixture to
avoid overflowing as gas is created
during the fermentation process.
Then close the lid and place the jar in
a cool, airy spot for 3 weeks. After
this time, the mixture will ferment and
produce GE, growth enhancer, ready to be
used for the orchids.
[Music]
And here is the GE product I made 3
weeks ago. So, it's ready to be applied
to the orchids.
[Music]
Take 20 ml of GE and dilute it with one
liter of water. This mixture will
provide nutrients for the orchid,
helping the plant grow strong and bloom
longer.
[Music]
Step four, use a soft cloth to soak up
this mixture and wrap it around the
unopened buds to help stimulate the
growth of new flower stems. The GE will
provide nutrients to help these buds
develop and bloom in the future.
[Music]
Step four, use a soft cloth to soak up
this mixture and wrap it around the
unopened buds to help stimulate the
growth of new flower stems. The GE will
provide nutrients to help these buds
develop and bloom in the future.
Just water each pot with about 10
tablespoons of the GE mixture. Uh this
amount is enough to provide nutrients to
the plant without overwatering and
causing root rot.
[Music]
Uh in addition to the English voiceover,
we have now created voiceovers in
French, German, Italian, Spanish,
Portuguese, Japanese, Hindi, and
Indonesian to help you listen to and
understand the content more easily.
For languages without voiceovers, we
have created subtitles so you can read
and understand the content.
Then pour this mixture into a spray
bottle.
Step six, spray this mixture over the
entire orchid pot, including the leaves,
stem, roots, and growing medium.
Spraying helps evenly distribute
nutrients, stimulating the plant to grow
and bloom continuously.
When you spray it on the leaves and
roots, it helps the orchid easily absorb
essential nutrients from the GE mixture,
supporting healthy growth and
strengthening the root system.
Spraying on the stem and unopened nodes
helps stimulate the orchid to bloom
regularly, contributing to beautiful and
longlasting flowering periods.
The GE mixture helps repel harmful
insects and supports disease prevention,
making the orchid plant healthier.
Wait 20 minutes before removing the
cloth wrapped around the nodes. This
amount of time is enough for the
nutrients to be absorbed and to
stimulate the nodes to develop new
flower spikes.
Wait 20 minutes before removing the
cloth wrapped around the nodes. This
amount of time is enough for the
nutrients to be absorbed and to
stimulate the nodes to develop new
flower spikes.
[Music]
After 20 minutes, remove the cloth
wrapped around the nodes and repeat once
a week. This helps stimulate the growth
of new flower stems.
[Music]
After soaking the orchid pot for about
20 minutes, remember to take it out.
This helps the plant absorb nutrients
effectively without causing water
logging.
Step seven, use a cloth to absorb the
excess water on the leaves and leaf
axles. This helps prevent water from
accumulating, avoiding leaf rot and
keeping the leaves dry and well
ventilated.
[Music]
Um, after wiping the leaves, place the
orchid pot in a spot with gentle
sunlight. This helps the plant recover
and grow naturally without being
affected by harsh sunlight.
Use any remaining mixture to spray on
orchids that are currently blooming.
This helps the flowers last longer and
maintains the plant's health.
Um, the GE mixture helps boost the
orchid's resistance, allowing the plant
to defend against environmental
stressors like intense sunlight and
drought.
The nutrients in this mixture promote
root development, helping the orchid
absorb water and nutrients more
effectively.
[Applause]
The GE mixture provides nutrients that
help the orchids leaves grow strong,
shiny, and fresh, giving the plant a
healthy appearance.
The nutrients in GE not only help the
current flowers last longer, but also
stimulate the buds that haven't bloomed
yet, encouraging the orchid to flower
continuously.
Using GE fertilizer to care for orchids
is very beneficial, but it should be
done about twice a month. This allows
the plant to absorb nutrients
effectively without causing
overfertilization.
[Music]
Now, let me show you the results after
after 1 month of care with natural
fertilizer.
[Music]
You can see that the orchid has grown
many new roots, which proves that the
natural fertilizer has helped the plant
grow healthily and absorb nutrients
better.
[Music]
The leaves have become greener, shinier,
and stronger compared to before using
the natural fertilizer.
The orchid has grown a new leaf which
proves that the care method and natural
fertilizer are working very well for the
plant's development.
[Music]
And you can also see the flowers lasting
much longer, which proves that the
natural fertilizer helps the flowers
stay fresh for a longer time.
[Music]
In addition, new flower stems have
emerged from the buds that I had
stimulated when applying the natural
fertilizer a month ago.
[Music]
Uh, other orchids when treated with
natural fertilizer show larger flower
petals and multiple flower stems on the
same plant.
[Music]
Uh, other orchids when treated with
natural fertilizer show larger flower
petals and multiple flower stems on the
same plant.
How do you think about the way I revived
my weak orchid? Please leave a comment
and share your suggestions with me.
Uh if you encounter any difficulties
while growing orchids, don't hesitate to
leave a comment. I'm always ready to
support you so you can grow healthy
orchids with lots of beautiful blooms.
If you find the content helpful and
meaningful, don't forget to like, share
so more people can know about it and
subscribe to support me. Thank you for
always being with me.
I always pray that God blesses all of
you. Goodbye and see you next time.