Hello friends.
Nice to meet you on my channel.
You see here a withered orchid. Maybe
it's because you didn't water it or due
to direct sunlight shining on the
orchid.
Leave a comment to let me know which
country you are watching from. It's
truly wonderful that we can connect and
chat together from all around the world.
Um, if you want orchids to be nourished
and grow quickly, please watch this
video carefully.
[Music]
Now, I will share this amazing trick
with you.
You need one aloe vera leaf.
Which country are you watching the video
from? Please comment below.
[Music]
It's wonderful that we can chat together
from all around the world.
This aloe vera gel is great for reviving
orchids.
[Music]
Now apply aloe vera gel on the top and
bottom of the leaf.
[Music]
Aloe vera gel has a very good
moisturizing effect.
In addition, aloe vera also contains
vitamins A, B, and C and minerals such
as nitrogen, phosphorus, and potassium.
[Music]
Uh do this every 5 days and leave the
orchid pot in a cool place for 3 weeks.
[Music]
Next, take one liter of warm water and
put it in the bottle.
[Music]
Then take one spoon of rice and soak it
in this water for about 30 minutes. Let
the nutrients in the rice completely
dissolve into the water.
[Music]
Chop the remaining aloe vera leaves into
small pieces.
[Music]
Then puree with 300 mm of water.
Filter out residue. Then add 2 L of
water at room temperature.
[Music]
after soaking for 30 minutes. Filter
this rice water.
[Music]
Mix rice water with aloe vera juice.
So I ended up with about 3 L of this
wonderful liquid manure solution.
[Music]
Cover the pot with moss to retain
moisture better.
[Music]
Now you use the solution to water the
orchid every 5 days.
[Music]
Soak the orchid pot in this water for 2
hours.
[Music]
After soaking for 2 hours, remember to
lift the orchid pot and place it in a
cool place to let the orchid recover.
[Music]
Two weeks later,
Fertilize after 2 weeks for fresher
orchid leaves.
[Music]
New roots develop very well.
Many new roots are growing.
[Music]
New roots will help transport water and
nutrients from the roots to the stem.
If the leaves are provided with enough
water and nutrients from the roots, the
leaves will gradually become lush again.
One month later,
you see the leaves are very fresh.
[Music]
And the orchid grows a new leaf.
After the next two months,
the orchid has grown two branches, two
buds,
but the leaves at the base have turned
yellow. So I will cut off these yellow
leaves.
[Music]
Uh instinctively when an orchid buds, if
the plant lacks nutrients, the the base
leaves will turn yellow and fall off to
provide nutrients for the buds to
develop.
[Music]
Now I need to supplement the orchid's
nutrition by taking three spoons of
rice.
[Music]
Uh then soak in 2 L of water at room
temperature.
[Music]
and wait 30 minutes for the nutrients to
completely dissolve in water before
using.
[Music]
30 minutes later,
add 3 tablesp of milk.
[Music]
Rice water and milk are excellent
sources of nutrients for orchids to
grow.
[Music]
Now you water the orchid with this
solution once a week to help the orchid
recover quickly.
After
[Music]
the next one month,
you may notice that after about 3 to
four applications of liquid fertilizer,
made from milk and rice water, the
orchid has already started to sprout
many new roots.
And when the root system develops
strongly, the plant will absorb enough
water and essential nutrients. As a
result, the leaves quickly become green
and fresh again.
And this is the result after the
following month. You can easily notice
that the orchid has started to grow new
leaves, while the leaves that were once
withered have now fully recovered,
regaining their vitality.
The young roots continue to reach out,
growing vigorously day by day. They
cling firmly and spread as if bringing
the plant a new and abundant source of
energy.
[Music]
The leaves have fully recovered,
becoming sturdy and green like clear
proof of the orchid's abundant vitality.
Uh the special thing is that after
recovering, the orchid unexpectedly grew
two new flower spikes. Both are
developing very vigorously.
The petals with their bright colors
gently display their radiant and lasting
beauty. They can remain on the spike for
a long time before fading as if wishing
to prolong the joy and grace for those
who admire them.
I hope this video will bring you a lot
of usefulness in your journey of caring
for your beloved orchids.
[Music]
Um, if you find this video meaningful,
please give it a like and share it so
that more people can know about it.
[Music]
And if you haven't subscribe to the
channel yet, don't forget to hit the
subscribe button and turn on the
notification bell. That way you will
always receive useful tips on how to
grow and care for orchids without
missing any video.
[Music]
Thank you for watching today's video.
Goodbye and see you again in the next
videos. I wish you always have much joy
with your beautiful orchids.