welcome to the happiness
Garden after the orchid has finished
blooming proper care is essential for it
to continue growing and blooming today I
will guide you on how to create a
natural fertilizer using onion and rice
a simple yet effective method to nourish
the roots and leaves of your orchid
preparing it for the next
Bloom uh additionally this natural
fertilizer is also great for roses and
other types of
flowers let's get
[Music]
started um which country are you
watching this video from leave a comment
and let me know
[Music]
uh it's wonderful that we can chat with
each other from all around the
[Music]
world I cut off the spent nodes because
they can no longer produce
[Music]
flowers um the spent nodes no longer
have dormant buds to regenerate so they
will be
removed if you haven't subscribed yet
hit the Subscribe button to support me
and not miss any Orchid growing tips
it's wonderful to have you as a
companion
[Music]
these nodes still have dormant buds so
they can be stimulated to grow and
produce new
choots removing the decayed medium will
prevent fungal infections and create
space for new roots to
grow next trim the damaged Roots cutting
off the unhealthy Roots allows the plant
to focus its nutrients on the healthy
roots and stimulates the growth of new
ones
in addition to the English voiceover we
now have voiceovers in French German
Italian Spanish Portuguese Japanese
Hindi and Indonesian to help you listen
and understand the content more
easily then avoid watering and let the
plant rest overnight so that the cuts
can heal completely
now I'm taking a small onion to make a
natural fertilizer for the Orchid
[Music]
washing it thoroughly with water helps
remove mold and bacteria that could harm
the Orchid
[Music]
next apply onion extract to the cut
areas to stimulate Bud growth from the
nodes on the stem and disinfect the cuts
[Music]
then I cut the onion into the smallest
slices possible
[Music]
onions contain essential nutrients and
natural compounds that help promote the
growth of healthy roots and
leaves onions provide essential vitamins
and minerals that help the Orchid
quickly recover and prepare for the next
blooming cycle
uh place the chopped onion into a jar
and mix it with one liter of water about
4 cups of
[Music]
water next I add 1 tbsp of rice to the
mixture
cover the jar and let it sit overnight
for the nutrients to dissolve into the
water after one night
stir well to ensure that all the
nutrients are fully dissolved into the
water and then strain out the
residue add another liter of water about
4 cups to dilute the mixture
step
one use a soft cotton pad to soak the
mixture and gently wipe both the top and
bottom of the
leaves onion EXT ract has natural
antibacterial properties protecting the
leaves from bacteria and
fungi cleaning the leaves and providing
nutrients helps the plant perform
photosynthesis more efficiently
this mixture provides essential
nutrients directly through the leaves
helping the plant absorb them quickly
[Music]
step
two pour this mixture into a spray
bottle and evenly spray it over the
entire orchid plant
this method helps clean off fungi and
bacteria on the leaves and Roots
protecting the plant from microbial
diseases uh the mixture provides
essential vitamins and minerals from
onion and rice helping the Orchid
recover and grow
[Music]
step
three attach a soft cotton pad to the
nodes with dormant buds
and spray this mixture onto them to
stimulate Bud
[Music]
growth this mixture will quickly
stimulate the dormant buds to develop
into new
[Music]
shoots step
four water the Orchid pot with about 10
tblspoon of this mixture
[Music]
this mixture supports the recovery
process and overall health of orchids
especially for those that are weakened
or recovering after
[Music]
blooming step five
use a dry cloth to wipe off any
remaining mixture on the leaves to
prevent mold and bacteria growth
protecting the plant's health
remember to wipe off any remaining water
droplets on the new leaves as they are
still soft and very prone to rotting
then remove the soft cotton pad from the
dormant buds on the flower
Spike repeat all five steps for the
Orchid every 10 days to keep the plant
healthy and ensure the best blooming for
the next
season uh then place the Orchid pot in a
spot with gentle sunlight to allow the
plant to photosynthesize most
effectively
the leftover fertilizer mixture after
feeding the Orchid can also be used to
nourish roses or other flowers in your
garden it will help all the flowers in
your garden bloom abundantly throughout
the year
[Music]
results after 1
month the dormant buds have been
stimulated to develop into new chots
preparing the plant for the next
blooming season
oh many new roots are growing from
inside the Orchid
pot the new Roots growing from inside
the Orchid pot not only help the plant
recover its Health after being drained
of energy from blooming but also improve
its ability to absorb nutrients from the
soil and fertilizer mixture
these roots support the strong growth of
the Orchid and prepare it for the next
blooming season
[Music]
now I will repot the Orchid into a new
pot to help it grow better and create an
ideal environment for the roots to make
contact with the soil and absorb
nutrients the growing medium I've chosen
is shredded pine bark which helps ensure
good air circulation and drainage while
creating a natural ideal environment for
the Orchid root fruits to
develop uh take care of the plants in
your garden with all the love you have
for
nature when you pour love and care into
your garden you'll be rewarded with a
beautiful display of vibrant flowers
blooming in every corner
they will chase away stress filling your
life with beauty peace and renewed
Joy not just orchids roses in the Bloom
year round their sweet intoxicating
fragrance filling the
air they lift your spirits making you
feel light and peaceful as you immerse
yourself in the beauty and Tranquility
of
nature if you enjoy my video and want to
continue joining me on the Journey of
plant care and discovering the beauty of
nature don't forget to like share and
subscribe to my
channel your support means a lot to me
and inspires me to create even more
helpful and engaging content in the
future thank you so much