hello everyone and welcome back to
happiness
Garden today I'll share with you how to
make natural fertilizer from bananas to
help your orchids grow healthy and Bloom
Bloom beautifully all year
round banana is always my choice for
making natural fertilizer to encourage
more flowers because bananas contain a
lot of potassium and natural minerals
that are very beneficial for orchids
[Music]
if you found this information helpful
don't forget to like subscribe and hit
the notification Bell to watch more
videos now let's get
started to make this natural fertilizer
today I'm using one green banana which
is rich in nutrients providing essential
vitamin and minerals to help your
orchids grow and Bloom
[Music]
healthily what country are you watching
this video from let me know in the
comments
below it's amazing that we can chat and
connect with each other from all around
the world
[Music]
next I put the banana into the blender
add 300 M of water and and blend it into
a smooth
[Music]
mixture if you haven't subscribed to the
channel yet click the Subscribe button
and hit the notification Bell so you
won't miss any new videos
uh pour the Blended banana mixture into
a bottle and add another 700 M of water
to create a liquid solution
add one teaspoon of sugar to help the
mixture ferment and prevent it from
spoiling finally add 1 teaspoon of yeast
to ensure the the fermentation process
goes perfectly and to prevent
spoilage stir well then place the
mixture in a cool dry Place avoiding
direct sunlight for 1 month
[Music]
after 1 month the mixture becomes a
wonderful fermented natural fertilizer
for orchids
[Music]
take 50 mL of the mixture which is
approximately 00132 Gall us
[Music]
then dilute it with 1 liter of water
which is approximately 0.26 417 Gall
us the nutrients and bananas help
stimulate root growth allowing the
Orchid to develop a strong root system
and grow more
vigorously bananas are rich in
pottassium vitamin B and minerals that
help promote plant growth especially
during the blooming stage
[Music]
the fermented mixture helps strengthen
the plant's immunity allowing the Orchid
to resist certain types of fungi and
bacteria uh step one use a soft cotton
pad to soak the mixture then gently wipe
both the top and bottom of the
leaves this not only cleanse the leaves
and improves the photosynthesis process
but also prevents pests and diseases
helping the plant stay healthy and grow
strong currently my channel supports
multiple languages including English
Italian French German Portuguese and
Spanish you can go to the settings and
select your preferred language to enjoy
the best video
experience um for countries without an
audio language option you can go to the
settings and select subtitles in the
appropriate language to better
understand the video content
in addition this method provides
nutrients directly through the leaves
helping the plant absorb them more
quickly and grow
better step two if you have many Orchid
pots you can pour the mixture into a
spray bottle
[Music]
then spray the mixture over the entire
orchid plant just like f your feeding to
effectively provide nutrients through
the
leaves this method also helps wash away
dirt mold and insect that may cling to
the surface of the
leaves additionally spraying this
mixture helps the plant stay healthy
enhances its ability to photosynthesize
and stimulates the growth of roots and
leaves
please avoid spraying this solution
directly on the flowers because it may
cause them to become damaged or Wilt
flowers are more sensitive to excess
moisture and nutrients which can
negatively affect their appearance and
longevity
[Music]
step three water the roots with this
mixture to provide essential nutrients
stimulate healthy root growth and ensure
the roots effectively absorb the
necessary elements from the soil
[Music]
you water the diluted mixture into the
roots and growing medium to provide the
necessary nutrients for the plant to
grow
[Music]
healthily this fertilizer helps the
plants Roots absorb essential vitamins
and minerals for Healthy Growth
it helps boost the plant's immunity
preventing common diseases caused by
bacteria and
[Music]
fungi it helps maintain the right level
of moisture and prevents root rot caused
by overwatering or excessive
[Music]
humidity step four use a soft cloth to
gently blot any any excess mixture on
the leaves to remove impurities prevent
the Orchid from becoming overly damp and
keep the leaves clean and well
[Music]
ventilated this method helps keep the
Orchid well ventilated preventing common
diseases especially rot caused by
excessive humidity
[Music]
then place the Orchid pot in a location
with gentle sunlight to allow the plant
to photosynthesize enhance nutrient
exchange and promote its
[Music]
growth follow all four steps for each of
your orchids every 10 to 15 days to
ensure they grow healthy and achieve the
best results
for orchids that have finished blooming
it's crucial to remove the old flower
spikes and any damaged Roots this allows
the plant to focus its energy on Healthy
Growth and future
[Music]
blooms this will help redirect the
plant's energy towards new New Growth
promote stronger
roots and encourage the development of
future
blooms regular maintenance like this
will ensure your orchid stays healthy
and thrives for the next blooming cycle
then I use the fermented banana
fertilizer and follow the four steps I
outlined at the beginning of this video
to care for this
Orchid if you haven't subscribed to the
channel yet please subscribe to support
my channel don't forget to like share
and hit the notification Bell so you
won't miss any new videos thank you for
your
support if you follow the steps I've
outlined your orchid will surely recover
quickly and Bloom beautifully in the
next flowering season
for orchids affected by Soft rot we need
to take a different approach to care
ensuring the plant doesn't rot further
and recovers quickly this includes
removing the affected Parts improving
air flow and using the right treatments
to help the plant
[Music]
heal properly trimming the affected
areas improving air circulation and
applying appropriate treatments are
crucial steps in helping the Orchid heal
and recover these actions will encourage
Healthy Growth and prevent further
damage
next use a soft cotton pad to soak the
fermented banana fertilizer mixture and
gently wipe both the top and bottom of
the
leaves this will help remove dust
insects and harmful fungi that could
damage the
Orchid then place the Orchid in a cool
well-ventilated area and refrain from
watering for one week to allow the plant
to recover on its own
the result after using this natural
fertilizer is that you'll notice the
leaves becoming Greener shinier and
stronger than
before the flower buds will appear in
abundance plump and won't Wilt or drop
before blooming
hundreds of flower buds have appeared
and are not falling off promising a
vibrant new blooming
season this natural fertilizer also
helps the flower petals grow larger and
stay on the stem for a long time before
wilting the flowers can stay on the stem
for up to 6 months before before the
pedals
fall I hope this video will be very
helpful in taking better care of orchids
at
home if you found this helpful don't
forget to like share and subscribe to
support my channel