Welcome to my channel.
If you have orchids after blooming,
if all the flowers have fallen, don't
rush to throw them away.
Uh, let me tell you how to help these
branches continue to bloom strongly
again.
[Music]
These nodes can continue to bloom very
well.
[Music]
When you eat bananas, don't throw away
the peel.
[Music]
Thinly sliced banana peels contain many
vitamins and minerals that are very good
for the bud formation process.
[Music]
Please comment to me which country you
are watching the video from. It's great
that we can chat together from all over
the world.
[Music]
[Applause]
Soak banana peels in one liter of boiled
water.
[Music]
Then take 3 tablespoons of coffee
grounds.
[Music]
Then soak this coffee grounds in one
liter of boiled water.
Then wait for the water to cool.
[Music]
after the water cools. Filter to remove
sediment.
[Music]
Dip a cotton ball in water extracted
from coffee grounds and wash the leaves.
[Music]
Helps eliminate pests and diseases of
orchids.
[Music]
and leaves will photosynthesize better.
Um, if you haven't subscribed to the
channel yet, please subscribe to support
me and not miss any orchid care tips.
[Music]
Mix these two types together.
Dip cotton balls in this water and clip
them to nodes that are likely to
continue blooming.
[Music]
Do it once a week.
will help stimulate rapid sprout growth.
[Music]
Uh, keep the cotton pad on the branch
like that for 20 minutes and then remove
it.
[Music]
Then water the roots once a week.
Soak it for 10 minutes, then lift it
out.
[Music]
And spray this water once a week to help
supplement nutrients through the leaves.
[Music]
After 20 minutes, remove the cotton pad.
and then place the plant in a place with
lots of light so it can bloom easily.
One month later,
[Music]
many buds have grown.
If you encounter any difficulties during
the orchid growing process, don't
hesitate to comment. I am always ready
to support you so you can grow healthy
orchids and bloom lots of flowers.
[Music]
Cony old pony get sis if there were sex
in there.
[Music]
Then place the plant in a place with
lots of light so it can bloom easily.
[Music]
After the next one month,
from the dry branches, many beautiful
flowers have sprouted and bloomed.
[Music]
The leaves are strong and sturdy, very
resistant to pests and diseases.
[Music]
The flower color is also more vibrant
than usual.
[Music]
Hope the video will help you a lot.
If you find it interesting, please like,
share, and subscribe to the channel to
help my channel reach 1 million
subscribers soon.
[Music]
My videos have subtitles in many
different languages, so you can choose
the appropriate language.
[Music]
Thank you for watching the video. Good
luck and see you in the next videos.
Welcome to my channel.
In this video, I continue to share how
to make orchids bloom at the same time
with many flower branches.
Orchids after flowers fade.
[Music]
We cut off all the spent flower stems.
If the plant has never bloomed, it must
have three or more pairs of leaves
and healthy roots.
Which country are you watching this
video from? Please leave a comment and
let me know.
It's amazing that we can chat together
from all around the world.
Sprinkle cinnamon powder on the wound to
help it heal quickly.
[Music]
Then wait one day for the cut to dry.
Then take half small onion and cut it
into thin slices.
[Music]
Add one liter of water and bring to a
boil.
[Music]
Wait a day, then use.
Next, take three spoons of rice.
[Music]
Then soak in one liter of water and
leave for one day before using.
[Music]
after a day. Filter out the residue.
Mix the two types together.
[Music]
Clean the leaves with this water.
Helps eliminate fungi and bacteria to
help orchids grow better.
[Music]
Do it once a week.
Then use this water to water the orchid
roots.
[Music]
This will help stimulate root and flower
stem growth.
[Music]
Do it once a week.
Place cotton balls between two leaves.
[Music]
Then spray this water on the cotton pad.
This stimulates flower stems to grow
[Music]
and spray on the top and bottom of the
leaves to help supplement nutrients
through the leaves for the orchids.
[Music]
This should be done early in the morning
so that by noon the leaves will dry
before the sun shines.
[Music]
After 30 minutes, remove the cotton and
repeat once a week.
[Music]
And take out the orchid pot.
2 months later,
[Music]
many flower stems grow at the same time.
Orchids also grow many new roots.
With this simple method, you can easily
care for blooming orchids at home.
[Music]
Tips for recovering rot infected
orchids.
[Music]
Um, when orchids are old and have poor
resistance, we need to rejuvenate them.
[Music]
First, you need to cut off all damaged
leaves and roots.
Keep only fresh roots.
[Music]
Onions have very good antiseptic and
growth stimulating effects.
[Music]
Take about 20 g of thinly sliced onion.
Take one teaspoon of baking soda. Helps
balance pH levels and eliminate fungal
diseases harmful to orchids.
[Music]
Add 2 L of water at room temperature.
wait 30 minutes before using.
[Music]
After 30 minutes, filter to remove
residue.
[Music]
Then water the orchid with onion water
and baking soda.
[Music]
Soak in this water for 30 minutes.
Cover the pot with a layer of dry moss.
[Music]
Place the dried moss in this transparent
plastic box.
[Music]
Leave in a cool place for one day
without watering.
[Music]
One day later,
from now on, water your orchids once a
week
[Music]
or water. When the moss is dry,
be careful to keep the moss moist. If
the moss is water logged, the orchid
will easily rot.
[Music]
Then place it in a cool place with
enough light for the orchid to grow.
[Music]
3 weeks later.
Many baby orchids have sprouted.
[Music]
Take 2 L of water at room temperature.
Then add five spoons of rice.
[Music]
Water the orchid with rice water once a
week.
[Music]
Helps stimulate baby orchids to grow and
take root quickly.
Continue
[Music]
to place in a cool, well-lit place for
the orchid to grow.
[Music]
After
the next one month,
[Music]
the baby orchids grow very healthy.
Hopefully the video will help you a lot
in taking care of orchids at home.
[Music]
If you find it interesting, please click
like and share so more people know.
And u don't forget to subscribe to the
channel so your channel can soon reach 1
million subscriptions.
[Music]
Next, to help you have many options when
caring for orchids at home with organic
fertilizer helps orchids grow and bloom
with many longlasting flowers. In this
video, I continue to share new methods.
[Music]
When eating oranges, don't rush to throw
away the peel.
[Music]
Right now, I will share this tip for
making organic fertilizer from orange
peels.
[Music]
If you haven't subscribed yet, please uh
subscribe to support me and to not miss
any orchid care tips. And don't forget
to share so more people can learn these
great tips.
[Music]
I cut the peel of an orange and put it
in a jar.
Add 2 L of warm water.
Then add one spoon of sugar and one
spoon of yeast.
[Music]
Punch holes in the lid. Close the lid
and leave in a cool place for 1 month.
[Music]
One month later,
I already have GE orange peel
fertilizer.
[Music]
I took 4 tablespoons of GE orange peel.
Mix 2 L of water.
[Music]
First method,
use a GE orange peel to thoroughly wipe
the top and bottom of the leaf.
[Music]
Orange peels contain essential oils that
after incubation will help repel insects
very effectively.
[Music]
helps leaves photosynthesize and create
chlorophyll better.
[Music]
Do this one to two times a month to
protect orchids and keep the leaves
green.
[Music]
Second method.
Applying this fertilizer to the roots
one to two times per month helps provide
organic substances such as humic acid,
fulvic acid, and enhance water retention
in orchid growing media.
[Music]
Orange peel also contains many important
minerals such as potassium, magnesium,
calcium, and trace elements.
[Music]
GE fertilizer helps orchids grow
strongly and increase flower production.
[Music]
GE fertilizer helps improve the ability
of plants to absorb nutrients.
helping orchids make better use of
available nutrients in the environment.
[Music]
Let's see the results.
The flower color is more vibrant than
usual.
[Music]
Orchids bloom many flowers on the same
tree, but do not fall.
[Music]
Flowers bloom continuously from season
to season all year round.
[Music]
The flowers stay on the branches for a
long time before fading.
[Music]
Thank you for watching the video. Good
luck and see you in the next videos.
Welcome to my channel.
In this video, I share the method of
recovering weak orchids, helping them
quickly take root and grow strongly.
[Music]
If you haven't subscribed to the channel
yet, please subscribe to support me and
not miss any orchid care tips.
Let's get started.
I picked up a rotten orchid that someone
had thrown away.
Please comment to me which country you
are watching the video from.
It's great that we can chat together
from all over the world.
[Music]
All the roots have rotted.
Which country are you watching this
video from? Please comment and let me
know.
Uh it's wonderful that we can connect
and chat with each other from all around
the world.
[Music]
This original part has completely
rotted, so it can no longer be used.
[Music]
Wash orchid branches with water.
Then take one clove of garlic and mince
it.
[Music]
Garlic has antibacterial and antifungal
properties helping to prevent common
diseases in orchids such as mold and
harmful bacteria.
[Music]
Uh, garlic contains allisonin, um, a
compound that stimulates plant root
growth, which is especially helpful when
orchids are recovering from a period of
flower loss or a weakened plant.
[Music]
Antioxidants in garlic help strengthen
the orchid's resistance, helping the
plant stay healthy and and grow better
in a caring environment.
[Music]
Add 500 ml of water and soak for 30
minutes, letting the flour nutrition
completely dissolve in water.
[Music]
After
30 minutes,
[Music]
wiping orchid branches with garlic water
helps disinfect and eliminate fungal
diseases.
[Music]
If you encounter any difficulties during
the orchid growing process, don't
hesitate to comment. I am always ready
to support you so you can grow healthy
orchids and bloom lots of flowers.
[Music]
Then soak the orchid branches in garlic
water for 10 minutes. This helps
stimulate root and chute growth.
[Music]
10 minutes later.
because this orchid has many scars from
previous insect bites. So, I waited a
day for the orchid to dry completely
before planting it.
[Music]
One day later,
I recycle sponges as orchid nursery
tools.
[Music]
Soaking the sponge in garlic water for
20 minutes Helps disinfect and kill
fungus.
[Music]
20 minutes later.
Insert the orchid stem into the sponge
and place it in the vase.
[Music]
Pour some water into the jar and change
it every time it gets dirty.
[Music]
Spray moisturizer every 3 days and place
it in a cool, well-lit place.
[Music]
5 weeks later,
the roots have grown very healthy.
[Music]
The roots have grown very healthy.
How do you see how to restore your weak
orchids? Please write a comment to let
me know your opinion.
[Music]
I planted it in a pot so the orchid
could grow better.
[Music]
If you find the video interesting,
please like and share so more people
know this tip.
[Music]
Water orchids regularly to keep them
moist.
[Music]
Thank you for watching the video. Good
luck and see you in the next videos.
[Music]
Hi everybody.
In this video, I share how to care for
orchids to help them grow quickly and
flower many times in the same year.
You see, my orchids new flowers always
grow after old ones fall. So, my orchids
bloom all year round from branch to
branch.
[Music]
The flowers bloom for a long time before
dropping their petals and can stay on
the branches for up to 6 months.
Um, please comment to me which country
you are watching the video from.
It's great that we can chat together
from all over the world.
Many flowers grow on the same tree.
[Music]
New roots grow a lot to help absorb
nutrients best.
[Music]
Chubby flower buds.
Help flowers bloom long on branches.
[Music]
brilliant flowers.
How to make fertilizer as follows. Use
one small carrot weighing about 30 g.
[Music]
Cut into small pieces.
Add one liter of filtered water.
[Music]
puree.
Filter out residue.
[Music]
Add one liter of filtered water.
Then use cotton to soak carrot juice and
wipe both the top and bottom sides of
the leaves.
[Music]
This method helps repel insects and open
the stamata. The orchids will
photosynthesize and exchange nutrients
better.
[Music]
At the same time, orchids also absorb
some nutrients through the leaves,
helping keep the leaves green.
[Music]
If you haven't subscribed to the channel
yet, please subscribe to support me and
not miss any orchid care tips.
[Music]
Second way,
water this carrot for orchids.
Carrot juice is a good source of
nutrients for orchids, including
vitamins and minerals like betaarotene,
potassium, magnesium, and phosphorus.
[Music]
Uh when the carrot juice is poured into
the orchid pot, it provides nutrients to
the orchids and helps to promote their
health.
In addition, carrot juice is also
acidic, which helps regulate the pH of
the potted soil and enhances the
orchid's ability to absorb nutrients.
You can soak the orchid pot in this
carrot juice for 20 minutes.
[Music]
Do this one two times a month.
Third way.
[Music]
Mist moisturizing carrot juice for
orchids by spraying both the top and
bottom of the leaves. This helps wash
away dirt and eliminate insects on your
orchids. The nutrients in carrot juice
support orchid health, helping them
thrive and bloom beautifully.
[Music]
However, be careful not to overwater
with carrot juice as it can clog the
water channels in the orchid.
Avoid spraying directly on the flowers
as this can cause them to fall off
quickly.
I hope this video helps you take better
care of your orchids at home and
encourages them to bloom easily. Um, if
you find it helpful and interesting,
please like, share, and subscribe to
support my channel. Thank you.
Hi everybody.
to give you more options for taking care
of your orchids at home using organic
fertilizer. In this video, I continue to
share methods for making natural
fertilizer from everyday kitchen
ingredients you can find in your home.
Subscribe to the video so you don't miss
any tips on my channel.
Number
one,
to make this fertilizer, you need
apples.
[Music]
Apples contain potassium, an important
mineral for orchid growth.
[Music]
Potassium helps orchids develop stronger
leaves, roots, and flowers.
Uh, I took the apple peel and put it in
a bottle.
Soak in boiled water and leave
overnight.
Please comment to me which country
you're watching the video from.
It's great that we can chat together
from all over the world.
[Music]
Number two,
to make this type of fertilizer, you
need more eggshells.
[Music]
If you haven't subscribed to the channel
yet, please subscribe to support me and
not miss any orchid care tips.
[Music]
Soak the eggshells in boiled water and
leave overnight.
[Music]
after one night. Filter the water.
So we have fertilizer from apples and
eggshells.
[Music]
First method,
water this fertilizer solution on the
orchid roots.
[Music]
Eggshells provide natural calcium which
is very good for orchids. They help
orchids stay healthy and increase
resistance.
[Music]
Apple peels contain a lot of phosphorus
which is also an important nutrient for
orchid growth
[Music]
especially during the flowering and
flower development stage.
[Music]
Do this one to two times a month to
supplement nutrition and increase the
orchid's resistance.
[Music]
Second method,
spray this fertilizer on the entire
orchid.
[Music]
This method is similar to using folure
fertilizer.
[Music]
Calcium and eggshells helps orchids stay
healthy and increases their resistance
to pests.
[Music]
Apples contain nitrogen, an essential
nutrient that helps orchids develop
healthy green growth and enhances their
ability to photosynthesize.
[Music]
Do not spray on flowers because wet
flowers will easily fall off.
[Music]
Third method.
Clean the leaf surface with this liquid
fertilizer.
[Music]
The leaf surface will always be clean
and airy.
[Music]
Orchids will photosynthesize better.
Fertilizing regularly, one to two times
a month will help keep the leaves
healthy.
[Music]
Number three,
you can reuse eggshells and apple peels
to make fertilizer again.
[Music]
Let's check out the results together.
This type of fertilizer stimulates
rooting very quickly.
[Music]
After one month of use, you will see
great results.
[Music]
Many flower buds develop and do not
fall.
[Music]
Blooming flowers stay on the branches
for a long time before fading.
[Music]
Flowers can remain on branches for up to
6 months before falling.
[Music]
Hello friends.
Nice to meet you on my channel.
You see here a withered orchid. Maybe
it's because you didn't water it or due
to direct sunlight shining on the
orchid.
[Music]
Um, if you want orchids to be nourished
and grow quickly, please watch this
video carefully.
[Music]
Now I will share this amazing trick with
you.
You need one aloe vera leaf.
[Music]
Which country are you watching the video
from? Please comment below.
It's wonderful that we can chat together
from all around the world.
This aloe vera gel is great for reviving
orchids.
Now apply aloe vera gel on the top and
bottom of the leaf.
[Music]
Aloe vera gel has a very good
moisturizing effect.
[Music]
In addition, aloe vera also contains
vitamins's A, B, and C and minerals such
as nitrogen, phosphorus, and potassium.
[Music]
Uh, do this every 5 days and leave the
orchid pot in a cool place for 3 weeks.
[Music]
Next, take one liter of warm water and
put it in the bottle.
[Music]
Then take one spoon of rice and soak it
in this water for about 30 minutes. Let
the nutrients in the rice completely
dissolve into the water.
[Music]
Chop the remaining aloe vera leaves into
small pieces.
[Music]
Then puree with 300 mm of water.
filter out residue. Then add 2 L of
water at room temperature.
[Music]
After soaking for 30 minutes, filter
this rice water.
[Music]
Mix rice water with aloe vera juice.
So, I ended up with about 3 L of this
wonderful liquid manure solution.
[Music]
Cover the pot with moss to retain
moisture better.
[Music]
Now you use the solution to water the
orchid every 5 days.
[Music]
Soak the orchid pot in this water for 2
hours.
After soaking for 2 hours, remember to
lift the orchid pot and place it in a
cool place to let the orchid recover.
[Music]
Two weeks later,
Fertilize after 2 weeks for fresher
orchid leaves.
[Music]
New roots develop very well.
Many new roots are growing.
[Music]
new roots will help transport water and
nutrients from the roots to the stem.
If the leaves are provided with enough
water and nutrients from the roots, the
leaves will gradually become lush again.
[Music]
One month later,
you see the leaves are very fresh.
[Music]
And the orchid grows a new leaf.
after the next two months,
the orchid has grown two branches, two
buds.
[Music]
But the leaves at the base have turned
yellow. So I will cut off these yellow
leaves.
[Music]
uh instinctively when an orchid buds, if
the plant lacks nutrients, the the base
leaves will turn yellow and fall off to
provide nutrients for the buds to
develop.
Now I need to supplement the orchid's
nutrition by taking three spoons of
rice.
[Music]
Uh then soak in 2 L of water at room
temperature
[Music]
and wait 30 minutes for the nutrients to
completely dissolve in water before
using.
[Music]
30 minutes later,
add 3 tablesp of milk.
[Music]
Rice water and milk are excellent
sources of nutrients for orchids to
grow.
[Music]
Now you water the orchid with this
solution once a week to help the orchid
recover quickly.
[Music]
After
the next one month,
after three to four times of applying
liquid fertilizer from milk and rice
water. The orchid had many roots.
[Music]
Hope the video will help you a lot.
If you like the video, remember to hit
like, share, and subscribe to support
me.
Uh, thank you for watching the video.
Wish you luck and see you in the next
videos.
[Music]
Welcome to my channel.
Today I share with you an amazing
organic fertilizer and anyone can do it
easily.
Just one to two ripe bananas and the
orchid garden will bloom all kinds of
flowers.
Now I will revive this orchid with new
[Music]
Um, you've seen this orchid lose all its
flowers, leaving only withered branches.
And here are the withered orchids that
have been revived with lots of new
flowers.
Step one.
[Music]
Cut off the withers.
Apply toothpaste on the cut.
[Music]
Don't throw away banana peels when
eating bananas.
[Music]
Don't throw away banana peels when
eating bananas.
[Music]
Clip the banana peel to to the place
where the flower buds can grow
[Music]
and note to remove after 6 hours.
This helps to create the right moisture,
provide essential nutrients and
stimulate flower sprouts.
[Music]
Do this once a week.
Step two,
use a banana peel to wipe the top and
bottom of the leaves. This helps
eliminate insects, fungi, bacteria
hiding on orchid leaves and at the same
time provides a part of nutrients
through the leaves for orchids.
[Music]
This method also helps the orchid plant
to be protected and not be affected by
yellowing or rotten leaves.
[Music]
After wiping you will see green leaves.
Orchids will photosynthesize eyes better
to increase resistance.
[Music]
Step three,
one liter of water.
[Music]
Leave in a cool and dark place for one
day.
[Music]
After one day,
banana juice is darker.
[Music]
Use this absorbent cotton.
Clip a cotton ball where the flower buds
can grow
and note to remove after 6 hours.
Uh this helps to to create the right
moisture, provide essential nutrients
and stimulate flower sprouts.
Do this once a week.
Step four.
[Music]
Normally after 3 to 4 weeks, flower buds
will be formed and develop like this.
Um, with a flower sprout this big,
there's no need to sandwich banana peels
with cotton balls.
[Music]
You will be surprised how amazing this
is.
[Music]
Don't forget to subscribe. Subscribe to
see my next videos.
[Music]
Sty.
Add water to make 2 L. Water this banana
for orchids once every 2 to 3 weeks.
Banana peel is rich in potassium,
phosphorus, and essential vitamins.
Will promote the growth of orchid roots.
In particular, the potassium in banana
peels stimulates flowering very well.
[Music]
In addition, you need to combine using
other organic fertilizers for orchids
like manure made from soybeans, peas,
fish poop as I shared.
[Music]
Hope this sharing content will help you
in taking better care of orchids at
home.
Um, if you find the video interesting,
don't forget to like, share, and
subscribe to support my channel.
Welcome to my channel
uh to help you have many choices when
caring for orchids at home with organic
fertilizer. In this video, I continue to
share new methods.
In addition to the English voiceover, we
have now created voiceovers in French,
German, Italian, Spanish, Portuguese,
Hindi, Japanese, and Indonesian to help
you listen to and understand the video
content more easily.
Open the video and click on settings,
the gear icon to select the appropriate
audio language.
Now, let's get started.
To make this type of organic fertilizer,
you need black tea or tea grounds.
[Music]
I use 3 teaspoons of black tea.
Add one liter of boiled water.
[Music]
Incubate until the water cools.
After the water cools, filter to remove
sediment.
If you haven't subscribe to the channel
yet, please click the subscribe button
to support me and never miss any orchid
growing tips. It's wonderful to have you
along for the journey.
[Music]
[Applause]
Add water to make 5 L of black tea
solution.
[Music]
Next, add 1 teaspoon of baking soda.
First method,
[Music]
water this fertilizer solution on the
orchid roots.
[Music]
Black tea contains many minerals and
organic substances that help provide
nutrition for orchids.
[Music]
It contains nitrogen, potassium, and
phosphorus, important nutritional
factors for orchid growth.
[Music]
Please comment to me which country you
are watching the video from. It's great
that we can chat together from all over
the world.
[Music]
Baking soda, bicarbonate soda, has the
ability to increase the pH level in
orchid pots.
[Music]
Um, this is helpful in reducing acidity
if you use too much chemical fertilizer.
[Music]
Baking soda has the ability to kill
insects and fungi that are harmful to
plants.
[Music]
second method.
Spray this fertilizer on the entire
orchid.
[Music]
This method is similar to using folure
fertilizer.
[Music]
You can use it as a natural pesticide to
protect orchids from insects and
diseases.
[Music]
third method.
Clean the leaf surface with this
fertilizer solution.
[Music]
The leaf surface will always be clean
and the stomata will not be clogged.
[Music]
Orchids will photosynthesize better.
Join us to see the results when caring
for orchids with this natural
fertilizer.
[Music]
Uh plant roots are protected and
supplemented with nutrients so they grow
very healthily.
[Music]
will help orchids absorb the most
nutrients.
[Music]
Because they are provided with enough
nutrition, the flowers bloom more
brilliantly.
Many flowers bloom on the same branch.
[Music]
If you find the video helpful, please
hit like, share it to reach more people,
and don't forget to subscribe to the
channel to support me.
[Music]
The flowers stay on the branches for a
long time before fading.
Thank you for watching the video.
Wishing you luck and success in