Hello everyone. Today I will share five
simple ways to revive weak orchids so
they always stay healthy and bloom
brilliantly right at home.
Is your orchid struggling? Don't worry.
With these simple tips, you can
completely help them revive and bloom
brilliantly right at home.
[Music]
So, let's get started.
Look at this orchid. It's quite weak
with soft, wrinkled leaves, as if it
needs a boost of energy to revive.
In this video, I will guide you step by
step on how to care for and restore the
plant, helping it become healthy again
and bloom brilliantly right at home.
The first step is to check the
substrate, old fertilizer, and the
orchid's roots so you can understand
what the plant needs to revive.
Look at this substrate. It's very dry
and needs immediate care for the orchid
to recover.
[Music]
The old inorganic fertilizer granules
mixed in this substrate also need to be
removed as they can damage the orchid's
roots.
[Music]
Next, check the orchid's roots to see if
they are healthy.
[Music]
At the bottom of the pot, there are
quite a few leftover inorganic
fertilizer granules. It seems this
orchid doesn't do well with inorganic
fertilizer when cared for at home.
Many roots are damaged, so we need to
cut away all the hollow and harmed
roots. Um, when an orchid's roots are
injured, bacteria, mold, or viruses can
invade and harm the plant if not treated
promptly.
[Music]
Removing these damaged roots helps
prevent disease from spreading to other
parts of the plant, protecting the
overall health of the orchid.
Leave only the fresh firm roots like
these. These roots will help the plant
recover well.
Next, cut away all the damaged leaves so
the plant can focus on nourishing the
healthy parts.
[Music]
Damaged orchid leaves can become
breeding grounds for bacteria, mold, or
viruses. Therefore, removing them helps
prevent disease from spreading to other
parts of the plant, protecting the
overall health of the orchid.
[Music]
Damaged leaves force the orchid to
expend a lot of energy, reducing its
growth potential. Removing them helps
the plant focus on nurturing new,
healthier leaves.
[Music]
After the flowers fade, the old stems no
longer contribute nutrients. Removing
them helps the orchid save energy and
focus on developing roots, leaves, and
other parts.
[Music]
The next step is to fertilize the orchid
to help it recover. But first, soak the
wilted plant in water for about 1 hour
so the roots get enough moisture,
helping the plant absorb the fertilizer
more effectively.
To prepare the fertilizer, first take
500 ml of water in a clean cup.
[Music]
Then add/ teaspoon of sugar to the
water. It's best to use brown sugar
because it provides extra minerals for
the orchid.
[Music]
Uh after soaking the plant in water for
1 hour, take it out and dip the wilted
leaves into the sugar water for about 20
minutes, helping the leaves absorb
nutrients and recover better.
Sugar helps wilted leaves recover faster
by providing the necessary energy and
nutrients, aiding cell regeneration and
making the leaves healthy.
Additionally, the sugar water helps the
wilted plant reduce stress, allowing the
leaves and roots to recover effectively.
[Music]
The next step is to make fertilizer to
promote root growth. Take one teaspoon
of oatmeal and put it into a clean cup.
Next, add 1 teasp of brewer's yeast or
baking yeast to the mixture.
Next, pour 500 ml of warm water. Stir
well and wait about 20 minutes for the
fertilizer to be ready for the roots.
[Music]
After fermenting for about 20 minutes,
strain out the residue to get the clear
fertilizer solution.
[Music]
Gently take the orchid out and uh dip
the entire root system into this
fertilizer solution for about 20
minutes. This helps stimulate strong
root growth while preparing the orchid
to absorb the necessary nutrients for
recovery and leaf nourishment.
[Music]
Uh after soaking the roots for 20
minutes, take the orchid out to prepare
it for planting.
[Music]
If there is still water on the leaves,
gently blot it all off.
Avoid leaving water on the leaves as it
can cause leaf rot or create an
environment for mold to grow. This helps
the orchid maintain optimal health when
planted in the new substrate.
[Music]
Then plant the orchid in a pot so it can
grow in an outdoor environment.
I use moss as the substrate for planting
because it retains moisture well,
creating an ideal environment for the
orchid to recover quickly and grow
healthily.
Which country are you watching this
video from? Leave a comment for me. It's
wonderful that we can connect and chat
together from all around the world.
If you haven't subscribed to the channel
yet, click the subscribe button to
support me and don't miss any orchid
growing tips. It's wonderful to have you
along.
[Music]
Then mix these two solutions together
and use it to water directly onto the
substrate and roots. This helps the
roots fully absorb nutrients while
providing the necessary moisture for the
orchid to recover quickly.
[Music]
Apply this liquid fertilizer directly to
the orchid pot and repeat after 10 days.
Maintaining a regular fertilizing
schedule helps the roots and leaves
fully absorb nutrients, promoting quick
recovery and healthy growth.
This liquid fertilizer will strongly and
rapidly stimulate root growth, helping
the orchid absorb nutrients effectively,
thereby nourishing new healthy leaves
and roots.
[Music]
You can also use the remaining liquid
fertilizer to feed other orchids. This
is an effective way to provide
nutrients, helping multiple plants grow
healthily and bloom brilliantly.
[Music]
Looking at the orchids cared for with
natural fertilizer, you can see many new
healthy roots growing while the leaves
are shiny and firm. This is the result
of proper and consistent care.
[Music]
each time you care for your orchids.
Soak the pot in the fertilizer solution
for about 20 minutes and then take it
out. After that, place the orchid pot in
a well-lit area and maintain liquid
fertilization every 10 days. This care
method helps the plant absorb nutrients
well, promotes strong root growth, and
keeps leaves and flowers vibrant and
healthy.
[Music]
And here is the result. After one month
of care, many new healthy roots have
grown, creating a strong foundation for
the orchid to recover its wilted leaves.
[Music]
These new roots will absorb water and
nutrients effectively, helping the
wilted leaves recover quickly and become
healthier.
[Music]
Next, continue applying this liquid
fertilizer regularly every 10 days. This
ensures the roots, leaves, and flowers
receive enough nutrients, helping the
orchid grow healthily and bloom
brilliantly.
[Music]
Um, additionally, you can also use other
types of natural fertilizers to care for
orchids. Uh, this not only provides
nutrients but also helps the plants grow
safely with shiny green leaves and
brilliant blooms.
[Music]
And here is the result after the next 3
months. You can see the orchid has fully
recovered, growing strongly with healthy
roots and shiny, firm green leaves.
You can see that not only has the orchid
recovered, but it has also grown two new
flower stems. Very plump and healthy,
promising brilliant blooms soon.
Uh, what do you think about how I
revived this small orchid? Don't
hesitate to leave a comment and share
your thoughts. I'm eager to hear your
feedback and experiences.
[Music]
Take care of your orchid with all the
love and attention you give it. And in
return, you will be rewarded with
brilliant flowers, a healthy plant, and
full of vitality.
When you spend time and pay attention to
every little detail, the orchid senses
that love and responds with brilliant,
healthy, and vibrant flowers.
Orchids are not only beautiful plants,
but also a testament to love, patience,
and meticulous care. Each blooming
flower reflects the dedication and
affection you give to the plant.
[Music]
Let your orchids grow in an environment
full of care and love and you will see
that they not only become strong but
also bloom beautifully and brilliantly.