[Music]
welcome to my
channel if you have an orchid after
blooming like
[Music]
this which country are you watching the
video from please leave a comment for me
it's wonderful that we can chat with
each other from all around the
[Music]
world cut off wilted flower
stems uh this helps nutrients no longer
concentrate on wilted flower branches
[Music]
and the rot from the flower stem will
not spread down the
stem please comment to me which country
you are watching the video from it's
great that we can chat together from all
over the
world then remove all yellow leaves
[Music]
if you haven't subscribed to the channel
yet please click the Subscribe button to
support me and not miss any Orchid
growing
tips it's great to have
company uh cut off rotten leaves so the
rot doesn't spread to other leaves
[Music]
and this is is a weak Orchid its leaves
wither cut off wilted branches yellow
leaves and damaged roots
[Music]
then sprinkle cinnamon powder on the cut
to help it heal quickly
[Music]
cinnamon has antibacterial and
antiseptic properties that help Cuts
prevent further rot and heal quickly
[Music]
um then leave it for one day without
watering to let the cut heal
[Music]
completely this is a potato including
potato
[Music]
Sprouts potato Sprouts contain a lot of
oxin a plant growth stimulant
this will stimulate weak orchids to grow
strongly especially roots and
[Music]
chots then peel and use the potato peels
as fertilizer for the
[Music]
orchids potato peels contain many
vitamins and minerals providing
nutrients for PL
[Music]
plants cut the potato skin into small
pieces
[Music]
then put all the potato peels into a
glass
[Music]
jar add 1 liter of boiled water
then incubate for one day so that the
flour nutrients can completely dissolve
into the
water one day later
[Music]
filter this potato juice
add 1 liter of
[Music]
water method one
water your orchid with this
water potato sprouts and potato peels
contain some plant hormones such as oxin
which helps uh stimulate root growth
[Music]
water each Orchid pot
thoroughly apply every 2
[Music]
weeks after watering for about 3 to 4
weeks the weak Orchid will grow new
roots
soaking the roots in this water for 20
minutes helps the roots absorb nutrients
better method two
[Music]
use this water to thoroughly wipe the
top and bottom of the
leaves this helps remove dirt insects
and fungal diseases residing on the
leaves that harm the
Orchid create favorable conditions for
orchids to photosynthesize light to
create
[Music]
chlorophyll helps orchids grow and
increase resistance to fungal
[Music]
diseases thanks to that your orchid
leaves will always be lush green and
sturdy
[Music]
this is a spider nest so it needs to be
removed immediately from the Orchid
[Music]
if you encounter any difficulties during
the Orchid growing process don't
hesitate to comment I am always ready to
support you so you can grow healthy
orchids and Bloom lots of
flowers in addition to the English dub
we've now created dubs in French German
Italian Spanish Portuguese Japanese
Hindi and Indonesian to help you hear
and understand the content videos are
easier to listen to the language open
the video and click settings gear icon
to select the appropriate audio
[Music]
language um this is a mbug speci species
that harms orchids if cleaned regularly
mbgs will be
[Music]
eliminated fertilize one to two times a
month to protect orchids
[Music]
and then you pour the remaining water
into the spray
[Music]
bottle method three spray this water on
the entire orchid
potato peels and potato Sprouts
decompose and provide organic matter to
the soil improving soil structure and
[Music]
moisture certain compounds in potato
Sprouts help fight fungi and bacteria
protecting orchids from
[Music]
disease nutrients and potato Sprouts
help keep leaves green and healthy
promoting photosynthesis
[Music]
helps improve soil structure enhance
water holding capacity helping orchid
leaves Stay Green and
[Music]
healthy do it twice a month and can
combine with other organic fertilizers
as I shared
[Music]
results after 3
weeks after only 3 weeks this weak
orchid has developed a very strong root
system
[Music]
this orchid has Greener and stronger
leaves and grow many new roots
[Music]
this orchid's Roots grow very large and
healthy
[Music]
when the roots are strong they will
absorb nutrients
[Music]
easily and if you provide enough
fertilizer as I instruct and keep the
Orchid in diffused
sunlight make sure the orchids will
Bloom and the flowers will stay on the
branches for a long time before fading
hope you will like the
[Music]
video wishing you luck and success in
life
[Music]