It's a pleasure to welcome you to the
happiness garden where we take care of
flowers together and spread joy through
their
blooms. Growing orchids that always
display vibrant colors and produce many
blooms is something every orchid lover
wishes
[Music]
for. However, to help the plant grow
quickly and develop a truly strong root
system, today I want to share with you a
completely new type of
[Music]
fertilizer. And I will also guide you on
simple but effective care methods that
that help orchids grow quickly and
always shine with many beautiful fresh
flowers.
The flowers will last longer on the
stem, helping the orchids remain
vibrant, color fast, and may even bloom
year round, bringing lasting beauty to
your
[Music]
garden. Let's get
started. To make natural fertilizer, use
rice, a familiar ingredient that is rich
in vitamin B and many essential
minerals, helping orchids grow quickly
and stay healthy.
Use 3 tablespoons of rice to start. This
is the right amount to create an
effective fertilizer mixture for your
orchid. Then add the rice to one liter
of water to begin the process of
extracting nutrients from the rice for
your
[Music]
orchid. And let this mixture sit for 2
hours to give the nutrients in the rice
time to dissolve into the water.
[Music]
The next ingredient to make the
fertilizer is pure ground
coffee. Coffee contains many valuable
nutrients that help orchids grow healthy
and produce more vibrant
blooms. Uh, put one teaspoon of pure
coffee into a cup to prepare the
fertilizer mixture for the
[Music]
orchid. Pour.5 L of boiled water over
the coffee to extract the nutrients.
[Music]
And please wait for the coffee mixture
to cool completely before using it to
ensure the safety of your
orchid. For orchids that have finished
blooming, you should cut off the old
flower stems to help the plant focus
nutrients on nurturing new shoots and
growing stronger.
[Music]
Wilted or deformed flowers should also
be removed.
[Music]
This creates conditions for the plant to
focus nutrients on nurturing and
developing healthier new
[Music]
buds. Leave a comment uh to let me know
which country you're watching the video
from. It's wonderful that we can connect
and and chat together from all around
the
world. Uh if you haven't subscribed to
the channel yet, please hit the
subscribe button to support me and not
miss any orchid growing tips. It's truly
wonderful to have you along on this
journey.
Then trim off any yellow or wilted
leaves to keep the plant clean, well
ventilated, and reduce the risk of pests
and diseases.
[Music]
We need to observe the of the orchid
regularly. When the tip of the leaf
turns yellow like this, it's a sign that
the plant may be lacking water or
nitrogen, which is essential for its
growth.
[Music]
In this case, we need to water
adequately and apply fertilizer properly
to help the orchid recover and grow
healthy again.
[Music]
For an orchid to grow lush and have
always healthy leaves, before
fertilizing, you need to water the plant
thoroughly
[Music]
enough. And this is very important. It
will help the roots develop and allow
the fertilizers to be absorbed very
effectively. After soaking for 2 hours,
strain out the residue to collect the
clear, nutrient-rich rice water used as
fertilizer for the plant.
[Music]
Bye.
Then strain out the coffee grounds and
mix the coffee solution with the rice
water solution to create a nutrientrich
natural fertilizer mixture for the
orchids.
[Music]
Step one, use a soft cloth to soak up
the fertilizer mixture made from the
coffee solution and rice water. Then
gently wipe the orchid leaves to provide
nutrients directly and help the leaves
become healthier.
Be sure to wipe both the top and
underside of the leaves thoroughly to
ensure the nutrients are evenly absorbed
and to remove dust, helping the orchid
leaves absorb better and grow healthier.
[Music]
The fertilizer mixture not only provides
nutrients, but also cleans the leaf
surface, removes dust, and prevents the
growth of harmful bacteria and
fungi. As a result, the orchid can avoid
many diseases and maintain long-lasting
vitality.
[Music]
When wiping the leaves, the fertilizer
mixture creates a natural protective
layer on the leaf surface, helping to
retain moisture and reduce water loss.
[Music]
This is especially important during dry
weather days, helping the orchid leaves
stay fresh and not wilted.
When the leaves are clean and nourished,
the process of absorbing light and
converting energy happens more
efficiently, thereby promoting better
nutrient synthesis and healthy growth of
the plant.
[Music]
Step two, pour the prepared fertilizer
mixture into a spray bottle to easily
spray it evenly onto the orchid, helping
the nutrients penetrate deeply into
every part of the plant.
[Music]
Then spray the mixture evenly over the
entire orchid from the leaves and stem
to the roots to ensure the plant
receives all the necessary nutrients for
comprehensive
growth. After wiping the leaves, spray
this mixture onto the plant to wash away
any remaining dirt.
Spraying the mixture helps stimulate gas
exchange on the leaves, creating
favorable conditions for the plant to
breathe and absorb nutrients more
effectively, thereby promoting the
overall growth of the
[Music]
orchid. When sprayed evenly on the
plant, the mixture also helps strengthen
its natural resistance, enabling the
orchid to withstand negative
environmental impacts such as
temperature changes or minor pests.
After that, I dilute the mixture by
adding water at a 1:1 ratio to make the
solution gentler, allowing the plant to
absorb the nutrients without shocking
the orchid's delicate root system.
[Music]
Step three, water this diluted mixture
directly into each orchid pot, allowing
the roots to slowly absorb the nutrients
and promoting strong growth from the
base.
Watering with this mixture provides a
rich source of nutrients directly to the
roots, encouraging them to grow quickly,
strongly, and spread throughout the pot,
thereby enhancing the plant's ability to
absorb water and nutrients.
[Music]
Nutrients from coffee and rice water
help improve the structure of the
potting medium, making it looser and
more airrated, creating ideal conditions
for orchid roots to breathe and grow
sustainably.
This mixture also stimulates the growth
of beneficial microorganisms in the
growing medium, supporting the
decomposition of organic matter and
enhancing metabolic activity in the
plant's living environment.
[Music]
Then soak the orchid pot in this mixture
for about 20 minutes to allow the roots
time to fully absorb the nutrients,
helping the plant recover quickly and
grow
[Music]
stronger. After soaking for 20 minutes,
gently remove the orchid pot from the
mixture to prevent water logging and
prepare for the next care step.
Step four, use a soft cloth to gently
blot dry any water remaining on the
leaves and in the leaf crevices to
prevent water accumulation that could
harm the orchid.
Blotting off the standing water helps
prevent the growth of mold and
disease-causing bacteria, thereby
keeping the orchid leaves clean and
healthy. Removing standing water also
helps prevent the leaves from rotting or
being damaged due to prolonged exposure
to a moist environment, keeping the
plant healthy and vibrant for
sustainable growth.
Step five, sprinkle cinnamon powder on
the cuts of the flower stems to prevent
the growth of bacteria and fungi,
helping the wounds heal quickly and
keeping the orchid healthier.
[Music]
Now here is the result after 2 weeks of
care. Uh you can clearly see the orchid
has started to develop many new healthy
roots signaling recovery and good growth
after the care process.
[Music]
New roots help the orchid increase its
ability to absorb water and nutrients
from the soil, creating a strong
foundation for the plant to grow healthy
and produce more beautiful flowers.
[Music]
And here are the orchids that I have
regularly cared for using this natural
[Music]
fertilizer. You can easily notice their
roots growing very vigorously, creating
the best conditions for the plants to
grow and bloom regularly.
[Music]
If you care for your orchids with all
the love you have for plants, you will
feel the plant's magical response.
Strong, healthy roots, lush green
leaves, and brilliant blooms like a
meaningful gift for your
soul. Blooming orchids help you feel
relaxed, bring gentle joy, and brighten
your living space with their vibrant
natural
beauty. I hope you enjoyed this video.
If you found it helpful, don't forget to
hit the like button and subscribe to the
channel so you won't miss the next tips
on how to care for orchids naturally and
simply.