hello
everyone after the orchid has bloomed
what should we do to help it grow and
Bloom
continuously in this video I'll show you
step-by-step instructions to ensure your
orchids stay healthy and Bloom
regularly let's get
started to make fertilizer for this
Orchid I need about 10 eggshells
uh eggshells are a natural source of
calcium which helps improve soil
structure boost root development and
prevent diseases in
orchids using eggshells as fertilizer
helps orchids recover quickly after
blooming stimulating continuous and
healthy
flowering which country are you watching
videos from please comment for
me uh it's great that we can chat
together from all over the
world you need to dry the eggshells and
then grind them into powder
then put the eggshell powder into the
jar next bananas are a very good choice
as fertilizer for orchids
take one banana peel and cut it into
small
pieces banana peels are rich in
potassium and minerals which help
stimulate flowering and promote quick
recovery for orchids after Bluing
using banana peels as fertilizer ensures
consistent and healthy
blooming add 1 liter of boiling water
cover and leave overnight to let the
nutrients mix into the
water next I use oatmeal to make natural
fertilizer
take three teaspoons of
oatmeal add 1 liter of water at room
temperature cover and leave overnight to
let the nutrient mix into the
water this is an orchid I bought at an
industrial orchid garden and has
finished blooming
uh to care for the plant to continue
flowering I first need to cut off the
damaged leaves
then cut off the old flower
stems if you haven't subscribed to the
Channel Please Subscribe and support me
it's amazing to have you along for the
journey and supporting
me then use coffee powder to apply to
the cut to help the wound heal quickly
leave it overnight for the cut to heal
completely
after one
night stir well so that the nutrients
dissolve into the water
filter out eggshells and banana
[Music]
peels step one
use soft cotton to wipe the leaves to
help keep them
cleaner wiping leaves helps remove dust
debris and bacteria from Leaf surfaces
helping orchid leaves breathe better and
absorb light more effectively
wiping leaves helps enhance
photosynthesis because clean leaves
absorb light better and can metabolize
energy more efficiently
wiping leaves with this water helps
reduce the risk of mold bacterial
diseases because clean Leaf surfaces
limit the environment for harmful
pathogens to grow
step
two pour this water into a spray bottle
and spray your
orchid spraying water infused with
banana peels and eggshells provides
nutrients for orchids boosting their
resistance promoting quick recovery
after blooming and ensuring continuous
flowering thoroughly spray both the top
and bottom of the
leaves when sprayed on leaves liquid
fertilizer helps orchids absorb
nutrients more easily and enhance root
development
[Music]
when sprayed on leaves liquid fertilizer
helps orchids absorb nutrients more
easily and enhance root
[Music]
development will create a synthetic
liquid fertilizer solution that is very
good for orchids to recover after
flowering
step
three water this liquid fertilizer for
orchid
[Music]
pots watering with a liquid fertilizer
made from banana peels eggshells and
oatmeal boosts nutrients enhances
resistance promotes quick recovery and
ensures continuous blooming for
orchids uh soak the Orchid pot for 20
minutes so the Orchid can absorb the
most nutrients
after soaking for about 20 minutes take
it out take it out and place the Orchid
pot in a place with plenty of
light step
four water droplets on leaves can create
a favorable environment for mold and
bacteria to
grow wiping off water helps reduce the
risk of infection
wiping off the water helps the stomata
stay open and function
better and do the above four steps every
10 to 15
days remember no matter how good the
fertilizer is if the Orchid lacks light
growth and cannot photosynthesize it
will still be stunted and grow slowly
therefore place the Orchid in a location
with sufficient light for Healthy
Growth results after 50
days you can see the roots and leaves of
the Orchid growing very
quickly the leaves are also stronger and
glossier and also grew two new flower
buds
oh the roots in the Orchid pot grow so
well
new roots are an important factor in
helping orchids grow healthily and
sustainably throughout their life
cycle for
um now I plant it in a larger pot so the
Orchid grows
healthier as a growing medium I use
crushed pine bark to help aate the roots
but still retain the necessary moisture
after planting take care of it like
other normal
orchids take care of your Orchids with
all the love and dedication you have for
nature because every leaf and every
flower bud is a testament to the effort
and heart you put into
it thank you for watching and supporting
my channel