Welcome to Happiness Garden. [music]
Denrobium orchids are a famous species
known for their bright and graceful
flowers. Even from dried, withered
orchid stems that seemed lifeless, you
can still bring about the miracle of
revival.
[music] If you own Denrobium orchids
like these, don't rush to throw them
away because they still have the chance
to grow strongly. Let me guide you on
how to revive them in a simple, quick,
and [music] highly effective way so you
can enjoy the beauty of fresh young
shoots right before your eyes. [music]
First, carefully cut off all roots that
are damaged or rotted. This helps the
[music] plant focus its energy on the
healthy parts, creating conditions for
new roots to grow [music] strongly.
When you remove the weak roots, you are
paving the way for a vibrant revival of
the orchid.
After cutting off the damaged roots,
gently rinse all the remaining roots
under [music] a light stream of water.
This helps remove dirt and bacteria,
leaving the orchid clean and ready for
the next step of revival.
Next, take [music] a 2.5 mg B1 vitamin
tablet and dissolve it in 300 ml of
water to create [music] a root
stimulating solution. This solution will
help awaken the vitality within the
young roots, promoting [music] their
fast and healthy growth.
[music]
>> [music]
>> After preparing the solution, [music]
soak the orchid roots for about 20 to 30
minutes. This time is enough for the B1
vitamin to penetrate deeply into [music]
the roots, stimulating their growth and
preparing them for a strong revival.
After soaking, gently take the [music]
orchid plant out and blot all the water
on the stem. This helps prevent excess
moisture and prepares [music] the plant
for planting.
[music]
Next, I reuse used plastic cups,
recycling them into convenient planting
[music] containers. These cups help
create an ideal environment, stimulating
the roots and young shoots to grow
faster from the withered orchid stems.
This way, you save resources while
effectively caring for the plant, giving
each young chute a chance to revive.
>> [music]
[music]
>> After placing the orchid stem into the
planting container, add clean water just
enough so that the water level lightly
touches the older part of the plant
stem.
Next, [music]
place the planting pot in a cool, airy
spot with an ideal temperature of 20 to
30° C. [music]
This environments, the young orchid
grows steadily without heat shock or
wilting. When the plant is cared for
under suitable conditions, [music]
each young root will grow strong, ready
for the next stage of revival.
And here are the results after one month
of recovery.
You can see that from the old withered
orchids, the dormant buds have now
awakened and begun to sprout healthily.
This change shows that with love and
proper care, even stems that seemed
lifeless can miraculously revive.
[music]
Although the shoots are still small, you
can see that their roots are developing
quite strongly. This is a great sign
showing that the orchid is absorbing
nutrients and preparing for the next
stage of growth.
Next, I replace the clean water and
continue planting so that the young
orchid has the best conditions for
growth. Maintaining a [music] clean and
sufficiently moist environment helps the
young roots grow strongly while
stimulating the orchid shoots to expand
and become healthier.
[music]
And here are the results after 2 months
of recovery.
>> [music]
[music]
>> You [music] can see that the young
orchids growing from the mother stem
have now become much larger with fresh
green leaves [music] and strong root
development.
This progress is clear evidence that
with the right method and been a bit of
pence, even orchid stems that seemed
lifeless can experience a remarkable
revival.
What do you think about the way I
revived this young orchid? Don't
hesitate to leave a comment and share
your thoughts. I'm really eager to hear
your feedback and experiences. [music]
>> [music]
>> Um, if you encounter [music] difficulty
uh difficulties during the orchid
growing process, don't hesitate to
comment. Uh, I'm always ready to support
you so that you can grow healthy orchids
that bloom abundantly.
>> [music]
>> Once the orchids have become healthy, I
transfer them into new pots, helping the
plants adapt better to the natural
environment outside.
[music]
This creates conditions for the orchid
roots to anchor firmly and the leaves to
grow lushly, preparing for the flowering
stage in the future. [music]
When the plant is placed in a suitable
environment, you will see its vitality
spreading strongly with each young chute
maturing into vibrant flowers.
Each time you revive an orchid, you are
not only bringing a small living being
back to life, but also experiencing joy
and patience in every step of care.
Gradually, you will build a garden full
of different orchid varieties blooming
together in vibrant colors. When you see
each flower unfold, you will understand
that the love and care given to orchids
bring [music] the most wonderful
rewards.
[music]
[music] Remember, each orchid you care
for gives you an opportunity to
experience patience, love, and joy from
nature. Even stems that seemed withered
[music] can be miraculously revived.
Revived with your dedicated hands and
heart. So don't hesitate to try. [music]
Don't hesitate to care because every
effort you make will be rewarded with
healthy young shoots and [music] vibrant
flowers.
[music]
Keep sewing joy, spreading vitality, and
creating a garden you can be proud of,
where each orchid tells its own story.
>> [music]
>> And that is the story of the journey to
revive orchids that seem lifeless. Each
orchid you care for not [music] only
grows but also brings joy, patience, and
pride to yourself.
Believe that with [music] love and
dedication, you can turn any stem into
healthy young shoots and vibrant
flowers. Keep spreading joy, caring for
each [music] orchid, and transform your
garden into a place full of life, color,
and happiness.
[music]
Thank you so much for watching. I truly
appreciate your [music] time and
support. Don't forget to like,
subscribe, and share if you enjoyed this
video. Wishing you a wonderful day
filled with joy and blooming orchids.
[music]
See you in the next video.
Hello everyone. [music] It's wonderful
to see you again in a new video on the
Happiness Garden channel where we share
our love for nature together.
[music] Orchids are famous for their
lasting beauty. Their blooms can open
and stay on the stem for a long time.
[music]
And with proper care, the plant will
continue to gift you with one blooming
season after another.
That's why so many people on this
[music] planet grow orchids.
However, many beginners still struggle
to get their [music] Phelinopsis orchids
to bloom abundantly. If you're still
trying to figure it out, watch this
video [music] to the end. A wonderful
secret is waiting for you to discover.
If you haven't subscribed to the channel
yet, please [music] hit the subscribe
button to support me and never miss any
orchid growing tips. It's truly
wonderful to have you with me.
Let's get started.
First of all, the placement of the
orchid pot plays a very important role.
A spot with gentle light and good air
circulation will help the plant absorb
nutrients better and grow healthily.
Orchids need light for photosynthesis,
but they can't tolerate harsh direct
sunlight. The ideal spot is on a window
sill with a sheer curtain or under a
light shade structure made especially
for orchids.
Next, I'll share [snorts] with you a
simple yet highly effective way to make
organic [music] fertilizer for orchids.
With just a few familiar ingredients,
you'll help your plant grow strong roots
and bloom more beautifully.
All you need is three tablespoons of
cooked rice, a familiar ingredient
that's packed with nutrients [music] for
your plant.
Then grind the rice into a fine powder.
>> [music]
>> Next, put the rice. powder into a clean
jar.
Next, I need to prepare a fresh aloe
vera leaf, an ingredient that helps
boost the plant's resistance.
Then, slice the aloe vera leaf into thin
pieces.
Put the aloe vera slices into the jar
with the rice powder you prepared
earlier.
Next, pour one liter of boiling water
into the jar to dissolve the nutrients
from the [music] rice and aloe vera.
Wrap a cloth around the jar to retain
heat. Then [music] let it sit until the
water cools completely.
Once the water is cooled, strain out the
residue and keep the clear,
nutrient-rich liquid.
In addition to the English voice over,
we have now created versions in French,
German, Italian, Portuguese, Japanese,
Hindi, Dutch, Polish, Korean, [music]
and Indonesian to help you listen and
understand the content more easily. To
hear your preferred language, open the
video and click on settings, the gear
[music] icon, to select the appropriate
audio language.
[music] Then add clean water to the
filtered liquid until you have about 3 L
of fertilizer solution.
Leave me a comment and let me know
[music] which country you're watching
from. It's wonderful that we can connect
and chat uh from all around the world.
Method one, pour the solution into a
spray bottle and mist it directly onto
the orchid's leaves [music] and roots.
Spray the solution evenly on both the
top and underside of the leaves as well
as the roots to help the plant absorb it
most effectively.
About 30 minutes after spraying, if
there's still water on the leaves,
gently blot the excess with a soft cloth
from the surface and [music] between the
leaves.
This helps prevent leaf rot and keeps
the [music] plant healthy.
>> [music]
[music]
>> Just apply this method once every two
weeks and you'll see your orchid stay
lush.
>> [music]
>> and full of life like this.
Method two, you use the solution to
water directly onto the roots and
growing medium, [music] helping to
deliver nutrients from below.
Um, this method allows the roots to
naturally absorb nutrients, [music]
stimulating the plant to grow vigorously
from the base to the top.
Rice water is rich in vitamins and
minerals that nourish healthy roots,
while aloe vera has antibacterial
properties [music] and boosts the
plant's resistance.
Combining both helps orchids thrive
[music] overall, encouraging fast root
growth, lush green leaves, and
long-lasting blooms.
You can choose method one, method
[music] two, or combine both for the
best results. Just apply it regularly
twice a month and your orchid will stay
healthy and bloom [music] beautifully.
And don't forget to place your orchid
pot in a spot with gentle [music]
sunlight so the plant can
photosynthesize and absorb nutrients
more effectively.
Uh and here is the result after 1 month
of care. You can see the plant has grown
many new roots full of vitality. [music]
Uh, a healthy root system helps the
plant absorb water and nutrients more
efficiently, leading to vigorous growth
and long-lasting blooms.
That's why roots are often compared to
the heart of an orchid. Because if the
roots are healthy, the plant will
thrive, grow strong, and bloom
beautifully. [music]
A healthy root system not only keeps the
plant stable, but is also the key to
beautiful and long-lasting orchid
blooms.
Um, what do you think about the way I
take care of these little orchids?
Don't hesitate to leave a comment and
share your thoughts. I'd love to hear
your feedback and experiences.
>> [music]
[music]
>> The orchids in my garden cared for with
natural fertilizer always bloom
vibrantly, full of [music] life, and
last a long time.
Natural fertilizers usually work more
slowly than synthetic ones, but once the
plant absorbs them, the growth will be
sustainable and strong from the roots
all the way to the blooms.
That's why the blooms can stay on the
stem for a very long time. Some flowers
even last up to 6 months before they
start to fade.
>> [music]
>> If you face any difficulties while
growing orchids, don't hesitate to leave
a comment. [music] I'm always here to
help you grow healthy orchids that bloom
abundantly.
[music]
I hope you enjoy this video. If you find
it helpful, don't forget to like and
subscribe to the channel so you won't
miss future tips on caring for orchids
naturally [music] and simply.
Thank you for watching until the end of
the video. Wishing you joy, good health,
[music] and lots of beautiful blooming
orchids. See you in the next video.