Welcome to Happiness Garden, where every
leaf and every petal tells us a gentle
story of love for nature and care from
the heart.
Let's discover together the wonders that
come from the smallest things in this
garden.
After buying an orchid and enjoying its
blooms, the plant often starts to
decline. Yellowing leaves, weak roots,
and a tired look.
Sadly, many people throw it away too
soon, not knowing there's still a strong
life force inside waiting to be revived.
[Music]
Many orchids here have been discarded
wastefully.
[Music]
This orchid, although weakened, still
has fresh green leaves, a sign that it's
alive. So, I decided to take it home to
care for and revive it, hoping to bring
it back to full strength.
[Music]
We need to gently remove the old growing
medium, which may hold dust and
bacteria, and repot the orchid into a
new container to give it a better
environment to grow.
This helps the roots breathe and absorb
nutrients and water more effectively,
supporting the recovery process.
[Music]
After removing all the old growing
medium, we trim away all the damaged
roots, those that are rotten or no
longer able to absorb water and
nutrients.
This helps the plant focus its energy on
growing new healthy roots, increasing
its chances of recovery and healthy
growth.
[Music]
Next, we cut off the dry flower spikes
and old weak stems.
[Music]
This helps the plant save energy and
focus nutrients on its healthy leaves
and roots, promoting new growth and
preparing for more vibrant blooms in the
future.
Next, we remove the wilted and yellow
leaves as they no longer perform
photosynthesis well and may harbor
harmful bacteria.
This keeps the plant clean and allows it
to focus nutrients on healthy leaves,
supporting recovery and growth.
Next, we rinse the entire orchid
thoroughly with clean water to remove
dust, bacteria, and impurities from the
leaves, roots, and stem.
[Applause]
This step creates a clean environment,
reduces the risk of infection, and helps
the plant absorb nutrients more
effectively during recovery.
[Music]
Next, I sterilize the moss used as the
orchid growing medium.
This step is crucial to eliminate
bacteria, mold, and harmful agents that
might exist in the moss, creating a
clean and safe environment for the
orchid roots to grow strong.
I soak the moss in hot water to
sterilize it, effectively removing
bacteria, mold, and insects that may be
hidden inside.
[Music]
I soak the moss in hot water to
sterilize it, effectively removing
bacteria, mold, and insects that may be
hidden inside.
Next, we prepare a natural fertilizer to
restore the orchid's health.
Take one liter of clean water as the
base to dissolve the fertilizer
ingredients.
[Music]
Here is the banana extract, GE banana,
that I made 3 weeks ago.
It is a natural fertilizer rich in
nutrients, helping stimulate strong
growth from roots to leaves while also
promoting recovery after the plant has
weakened.
[Music]
Take 50 ml of banana extract and mix it
into one liter of clean water. This
ratio creates a balanced fertilizer
solution, providing enough nutrients for
the orchid to absorb effectively without
causing irritation or damage during
recovery.
[Music]
You can refer to the video tutorial on
how to make banana extract GE banana via
the link in the description of this
video.
[Music]
Next, soak the entire orchid in the
banana extract fertilizer solution for
about 20 minutes.
[Music]
This allows the plant to absorb
nutrients directly and deeply,
supporting faster recovery and boosting
its resilience.
While waiting, I recycle old plastic
cups to make recovery pots for the
orchids.
This is an economical and eco-friendly
way also providing good erration and
drainage for the roots to grow strong.
[Music]
after soaking the orchid for about 20
minutes. Remember to gently remove the
plant.
Use a soft cloth to gently pat dry the
water droplets on the leaves and between
the leaf folds.
This helps prevent prolonged moisture,
reducing the risk of mold and leaf
diseases while keeping the plant clean
and healthy.
[Music]
Once the water has fully cooled, take
out the moss and prepare it for
repotting the orchid.
[Music]
The clean sterilized moss provides an
ideal environment helping the orchid
roots grow strong and the plant recover
faster.
[Music]
Next, plant the orchid in the pot using
the sterilized moss as the growing
medium.
[Music]
Gently place the roots into the moss,
making sure they have good contact with
the medium without being too tightly
packed to allow proper air flow and
encourage healthy root growth.
[Music]
After planting, from now on, water the
orchid once every 10 days with the
diluted banana GE solution.
This regular watering helps provide
nutrients to the plant regularly,
supporting healthy root growth and green
leaves during recovery.
Just about 5 tablespoons of the diluted
banana GE solution is enough for each
watering.
This moderate amount allows the plant to
absorb nutrients effectively without
causing overwatering or wasting
fertilizer.
Then place the orchid pot in a spot with
gentle sunlight, good air circulation,
and protection from heavy rain.
Soft morning or late afternoon light
helps the plant photosynthesize better,
supporting recovery and growth without
burning the leaves.
[Music]
Um, put put the remaining fertilizer
mixture into a spray bottle and mist it
onto the orchids that are currently
blooming.
[Music]
This method delivers nutrients directly
to the leaves and flowers, promoting
healthy growth and enhancing the
longevity and vibrancy of the blooms.
[Music]
The natural potassium content in the
banana extract, GE, helps the orchid
petals last longer, potentially keeping
the flowers fresh for up to 6 months.
Now, I invite you to join me in seeing
the results after 3 weeks of orchid
recovery.
Oh, can you see the new white root
growing inside the orchid pot?
Let's check the roots inside the orchid
pot together.
[Music]
Wow. You can see the orchid has grown
many new roots, which shows the plant is
recovering very well and ready for the
next strong growth phase.
These new roots increase its ability to
absorb water and nutrients, bringing
vibrant life to the plant.
[Music]
How do you find the way to restore your
weak orchid? Please write a comment to
let me know your opinion.
If you find the content interesting and
meaningful, don't forget to like, share.
so that many people know and subscribe
to the channel to support me. Thank you
for always accompanying me.
[Music]
Once the orchid has developed many new
roots, I transplanted into a new pot
filled with pine bark as the growing
medium.
Pine bark improves irerration and
drainage, creating an ideal environment
for the roots to grow stronger, helping
the plant become healthier and ready for
vibrant blooming cycles ahead.
[Music]
If you haven't subscribed to the channel
yet, please hit the subscribe button to
support me and not miss any orchid
growing tips. Um, it's great to have you
along.
After planting, we prepare natural
fertilizer to care for the orchid.
To make natural fertilizer, I take I
take 1 tbsp of wheat flour diluted in
one liter of water.
This mixture provides gentle nutrients
and helps stimulate beneficial
microorganisms in the growing medium,
contributing to the orchid's health
naturally and effectively.
[Music]
After mixing, strain out the sediment so
the solution becomes clear and can
penetrate the growing medium and roots
more easily.
This helps the natural fertilizer work
most effectively without clogging or
harming the orchid.
Then apply this fertilizer twice a month
to provide consistent nut nutrients for
the orchid.
Regular feeding helps the plant grow
steadily, boosts its resistance, and
prepares it well for future blooming
cycles.
[Music]
Then place the orchid pot in a spot with
gentle sunlight so the plant can
photosynthesize. Only with good
photosynthesis can the orchid absorb
nutrients effectively.
[Music]
And here is the result after 5 months of
recovery.
You can see that the orchid has grown
vigorously with many new roots growing
and the leaves are greener and shinier
than before.
[Music]
Especially the orchid has bloomed with
new flowers. A wonderful achievement
after a journey of patient and loving
care.
[Music]
This moment brings not only joy but also
motivation to keep nurturing our love
for orchids.
[Music]
Uh, thank you for joining me on this
orchid recovery journey.
I hope these tips help you care for, and
cherish your orchids even more.
[Music]
Don't forget to like, share, and
subscribe so you won't miss upcoming
helpful videos. See you next time.
Welcome to the happiness garden.
In this video, I continue to share a new
method for making organic fertilizer for
orchids. It helps orchids grow
comprehensively and bloom abundantly.
[Music]
Let's get started.
To make this fertilizer, I need tobacco.
[Music]
Only one cigarette is enough.
Tobacco contains nicotine, which has
antifungal effects, helping protect
plants from some fungal diseases.
[Music]
Nicotine has insecticidal effects. It
can cause suffocation or paralysis in
insects upon contact.
[Music]
The smell of tobacco makes some insects
like aphids and thris avoid coming near
the plant.
[Music]
Leave a comment to let me know which
country you're watching the video from.
It's wonderful that we can chat with
each other from all around the world.
[Music]
Put the tobacco into the jar.
Then add one liter of boiling water.
[Music]
Next, we need a banana.
Any type of banana can be used to make
natural fertilizer.
[Music]
Take one ripe banana and cut it into
thin slices.
[Music]
Bananas are rich in potassium and
phosphorus, which are important
nutrients that help orchids grow well,
bloom, root, and increase resistance.
[Music]
Then soak the banana in the previously
prepared tobacco water.
[Music]
Then close the lid. Let it sit and wait
for the water to cool.
After two hours, the water has cooled.
[Music]
Strain this water.
dilute with one liter of water.
Method one.
When the roots turn silvery white like
this, water the orchid with this liquid
fertilizer solution.
[Music]
Bananas also provide organic matter and
enzymes that help improve soil fertility
and the growth of beneficial
microorganisms.
[Music]
Uh, the tobacco soaking water has
antifungal properties and repels
insects, helping protect the plant roots
from diseases.
[Music]
Water the orchid with this liquid
fertilizer one, two, two times per month
or combine it with other organic
fertilizers as I have shared on the
channel.
Your orchid will absorb more nutrients.
[Music]
Soak the orchid pot in this water for
about 20 minutes so the roots can absorb
more nutrients and be protected from
fungal diseases.
Method two,
use a soft cotton ball to soak up this
liquid fertilizer solution. Then gently
wipe it onto the leaves.
Wipe thoroughly on both the top and
bottom surfaces of the leaves.
Uh, wiping the leaves helps remove dust
and enhances photosynthesis, allowing
the plant to absorb light better.
Uh, the combination of tobacco and
banana helps stimulate the plant's
natural immune system, helping to fight
diseases and insects.
[Music]
A wiping provides some micronutrients
and can support plant health.
[Music]
Doing this one to two times a month will
be very good for your orchid.
method three.
Um, if you have a large number of orchid
pots, you can put the solution into a
spray bottle and spray the entire orchid
plants.
Spray thoroughly on both the top and
bottom sides of the leaves.
[Music]
spray on the aerial roots and on the
orchid growing medium.
This method is similar to using folure
fertilizer and base watering,
but you should not spray it on the
hours.
[Music]
Because when flowers get wet, they tend
to wilt and drop their petals.
[Music]
After soaking for 20 minutes, uh, take
the orchid pot out and place it in a
spot with plenty of diffused light so
the orchid can photosynthesize.
[Music]
I continue to recycle the banana peel
and tobacco ashes into fertilizer for
the next time.
[Music]
Put it into a glass jar.
Then add one teaspoon of yeast.
[Music]
stir well.
Close
the bottle and place it in a cool place.
After 3 weeks, you will have GE
fertilizer that is very good for orchids
to bloom.
[Music]
The result after 3 weeks,
even the weakest orchid species has
developed very strong roots.
[Music]
The potassium content helps the orchids
bloom more and more.
[Music]
The flowers on the branch last a long
time before wilting.
[Music]
Orchid flowers can be kept on the branch
for up to 6 months before the petals
wilt.
Take care of your orchid with all the
love you have for plants, and you will
be rewarded with the enchanting
fragrance and the wonderful beauty of
the orchid flowers.
I hope you will like the video. Please
leave me a comment.
[Music]
If you haven't subscribed yet, please
subscribe to support me.
Thank you all for watching the video.
May God always bless you.
[Music]
Wishing you luck and success in life.