Welcome everyone to my channel. Today I
want to explore with you a simple but
truly effective way to help an orchid
suffering from rot recover quickly.
Even though the plant may look weak on
the outside, as long as we take care of
it properly, it can still come back
strong and continue to grow beautifully.
[Music]
Um, you can see that all the leaves of
the plant have become soft and rotten,
turning dark brown. At first glance,
anyone might think that this plant can
no longer be saved. But don't give up,
because with a little patience and the
right care, miracles can still happen.
Leave a comment and let me know which
country you're watching from. It's
wonderful that we can connect and share
with each other from all around the
world.
If you haven't subscribed yet, hit the
subscribe button to support me and make
sure you don't miss any orchid growing
tips. It's wonderful to have you along
for the journey.
Um, the tip of the flower stem is still
fresh and healthy, so I decided to keep
this part to try propagating it by
cutting.
Next, I gently cut off all the roots
that were damaged, rotten, or dried out.
This step is very important because if
we keep the unhealthy roots, they can
spread disease to the healthy parts of
the plant.
Although the orchid has decayed quite a
lot, fortunately, there are still a few
fresh and healthy roots left.
These roots will be the hope for the
plant to continue absorbing nutrients
and begin its journey of revival.
Now I will rinse the entire plant with
water to remove all the rotten parts and
any residues that could cause fungal
disease.
To start the recovery process, I first
use a fresh aloe vera leaf.
Next, I add two sprouted garlic cloves.
Sprouted garlic contains a very high
amount of natural oxin, a growth hormone
that helps stimulate the development of
roots and new shoots. Thanks to that,
the orchid will recover quickly, become
stronger, and soon burst with new life.
[Music]
If you don't have sprouted garlic, you
can completely replace it with regular
garlic. Although the amount of oxin in
regular garlic is slightly lower, it
still has excellent antibacterial
properties and effectively supports the
plant's recovery.
[Music]
Then I add one liter of water to the
aloe vera and garlic.
Next, I put everything into a blender
and blend it until smooth. This way, the
nutrients from the aloe vera and garlic
will completely mix into the water.
After blending, I strain out the residue
to obtain a clear and smooth solution.
This helps the helps the nutrients
absorb more quickly into the roots and
prevents residue from accumulating in
the plant's growing medium.
After that, I gently place the orchid
into the mixture and soak it for about
20 minutes. When
I reuse an old plastic bottle to make a
tool that helps the orchid revive. This
recycling not only creates a humid and
airy environment that helps the plant
recover faster, but also contributes a
small part to reducing environmental
pollution. A simple action, yet it
brings great meaning to both nature and
our own garden.
[Music]
After that, I wash the growing container
container thoroughly to remove all
remaining dirt and bacteria.
[Music]
Next, I make a few small ventilation
holes around the sides of the growing
pot. These holes help improve air
circulation, keep the roots well
airrated, and prevent water stagnation
that could cause root rot.
[Music]
For the growing medium, I choose
carefully sterilized pine bark. Pine
bark helps retain just the right amount
of moisture, provides good irration, and
creates an ideal environment for orchid
roots to grow.
[Music]
After planting, place the orchid pot in
a cool and well ventilated area avoiding
direct sunlight. Let the plant rest for
about a week without watering.
During this time, the dry pine bark will
naturally absorb a small amount of
moisture from the air, keeping the
orchid roots airy, preventing water
logging and stopping further root rot.
[Music]
After one week, gently take the orchid
pot out to check the condition of the
plant.
[Music]
At this point, if the roots look dry and
stronger, you can start watering lightly
to keep the orchid moist.
Providing moderate moisture will help
the new roots continue to grow and the
plant gradually regain its vitality.
[Music]
about once every 5 days. Simply mist the
growing medium and orchid roots lightly
to maintain stable humidity.
Place the orchid pot in a very cool and
airy spot, avoiding direct sunlight and
strong winds.
And here's the result after 3 weeks of
consistent care.
[Music]
You can clearly see that the orchid has
started to sprout a very healthy new
growth, showing that the revival process
is going well. The small daily efforts
have now brought a promising result for
for our garden.
Not only that, the plant's new roots
have also started to grow and
Continue
misting lightly to maintain moisture
regularly about once every 5 days. At
the same time, always keep the orchid
pot in a cool, airy spot away from
strong sunlight and wind so the plant
can recover gradually and grow
healthily.
[Music]
And here is the result after the
following two months of care.
You can see that from an orchid that was
almost completely rotted, it has now
fully recovered and grown into a
healthy, vibrant new plant. The patient
step-by-step process has brought about
this wonderful outcome.
[Music]
With this semi-hydroponic orchid
propagation method, you can clearly see
the results from the first few weeks.
The orchid roots grow strongly. The
young plant develops healthily and the
revival process happens faster compared
to traditional methods.
Each small plant revived today will
contribute to creating a vibrant and
lively natural scene in the future.
You just need to care for each plant one
at a time. Patiently observe and follow
the steps correctly. Gradually you will
have a garden full of vibrant orchids
with all the beautiful colors just like
my garden.
I hope you enjoy this video. If you find
it helpful, don't forget to hit like and
subscribe to the channel so you won't
miss future tips on caring for orchids
in a natural and simple way.
Thank you so much for watching. I truly
appreciate your time and support. Don't
forget to like, subscribe, and share if
you enjoyed this video. Wishing you a
wonderful day filled with joy and
blooming orchids. See you in the next
video.
[Music]