Welcome to Happiness Garden
channel. In this video, I share how to
grow it to grow
[Music]
fast. When I just bought orchids, we
remove all this
moss. Uh because these orchid pots are
grown in an industrial environment
controlled by temperature, humidity, and
uh ideal for orchids.
But when brought back, the environment
has changed, making these roots
susceptible to rot. Therefore, you
should cut off damaged
roots. Please comment to me which
country you are watching the video from.
It's great that we can chat together
from all over the
world. Then watch the roots.
[Music]
Taking advantage of used plastic
bottles, I recycled them into hydroponic
orchid pots.
[Music]
This method of planting will not require
watering, but will still help orchids
grow very healthily and produce more
beautiful and vibrant
[Music]
flowers. Recycling plastic bottles to
make orchid pots is not only a great way
to repurpose used materials, uh, but
also helps protect the environment. This
way we reduce plastic waste while
creating unique and sustainable orchid
[Music]
pots. If you haven't subscribed to the
channel yet, please click the subscribe
button to support me and not miss any
orchid growing tips. It's great to have
company.
I need to wash the plastic bottle to
make sure it's clean from fungi and
bacteria that are harmful to the orchid.
[Music]
Using the drill bit, we'll cut out the
positions here.
[Music]
This part will be used as an orchid
pot. The rest is for water
[Music]
storage. Using a glass jar on the bottom
will help the roots not absorb too much
water.
[Music]
Put the orchid
in. Put terracotta seeds around the pot.
grown in a semi-hydroponic environment,
often in contact with water. So, we use
breathable terracotta beads as the
[Music]
best. If it's breathable, it's very
rarely rotten. And after planting, the
roots will grow very fast.
[Music]
So, I've finished
planting. You water the potted
plants. We only water once. next time
you don't need to water
[Music]
anymore. With this simple planting
method, you save a lot of time to take
care
[Music]
of. With this planting method, you will
let the water level cover part of the
bottom of the pot.
[Music]
The water will absorb itself, helping to
maintain the moisture in the growing
medium. We will not need to water
[Music]
anymore. When the water in the container
is empty, remember to add more water to
keep the growing medium in a moist
[Music]
state. And this is the orchid. I planted
it using this method. You can see it
grows very
quickly. The flowers are durable and
have many flower stems on the same
[Music]
branch. And I also grow this orchid
using the semihydroponic method using
pine bark. When it flowers, it has
vibrant colors and stays fresh
[Music]
longer. Uh, growing semi-hydroponic
orchids, the moisture is always
wellmaintained. The roots will grow very
quickly. A strong root system will help
the plant perform metabolism and absorb
organic fertilizer and water very well.
Uh, with this simple planting method, we
will get orchids that grow
faster. I hope this video provides
useful information to help you take
great care of your orchids at home. If
you found it helpful, don't forget to
like, share it so more people can learn,
too, and subscribe to the channel to
stay connected with me. Thank you for
watching, wishing you a wonderful day,
and see you in the next videos.
[Music]
Welcome to my channel
uh to help you have many choices when
caring for orchids at home with organic
fertilizer. In this video, I continue to
share new
[Music]
methods. Please subscribe to the video
so you don't miss any tips on my
channel.
Now, let's get
started. To make this organic
fertilizer, you need coffee or coffee
[Music]
grounds. I use three teaspoons.
Add one liter of boiled water.
[Music]
Incubate until cool.
after the water cools. Filter to remove
residue.
[Music]
Add water to make 5 L of coffee
solution.
[Music]
Next, add one teaspoon of baking soda.
first method.
[Music]
Water this fertilizer solution on the
orchid
[Music]
roots. Coffee contains many minerals and
organic matter helps provide orchid
nutrition.
[Music]
It contains nitrogen, potassium, and
phosphorus, important nutritional
elements for orchid growth.
[Music]
Uh, baking soda bicarbonate soda has the
ability to increase the pH level in
orchid pots. This is helpful in reducing
acidity if you use too much chemical
fertilizer.
[Music]
Baking soda has the ability to kill
insects and fungi that damage plants.
[Music]
Second method.
Spray this fertilizer on the entire
[Music]
orchid. This method is similar to using
folure fertilizer.
[Music]
[Applause]
You can use it as a natural pesticide to
protect orchids from insects and
diseases.
[Music]
third
method. Clean the leaf surface with this
fertilizer solution.
[Music]
The leaf surface will always be clean
and an airy with stamata. Orchids will
photosynthesize better.
[Music]
Thank you.
Please see the
[Music]
results. Please see the results.
Uh because of enough nutrition, the
flowers bloom more brilliantly.
[Music]
Many flowers bloom on the same branch.
The flowers stay on the branches for a
long time before
[Music]
fading. Thank you for watching the
video. Wish you luck and success in
life. Thank you for watching the video.
Wish you luck and success in life.