Welcome to my channel. I am very happy
to have you here with me sharing the
love for taking care of orchids.
If you want your orchids to grow well
and bloom year round with vibrant
colors, take care to promote strong root
development. That way, the plant will
absorb more nutrients. In this video, I
will share simple, easy to do, but very
effective steps to achieve that. Please
watch the video carefully so you don't
miss any important tips.
[Music]
To make natural fertilizer for orchids
yourself, you only need one banana. You
can use either a green or a ripe one.
The banana will provide plenty of
nutrients to help the plant stay healthy
and bloom more easily.
Slice the banana into very thin pieces
uh so the nutrients dissolve more easily
during fermentation. allowing the
natural fertilizer to break down faster
and be absorbed better by the plant.
[Music]
Please comment and let me know which
country you are watching this video
from. It's wonderful that we can connect
and chat together from all around the
world.
Then put the sliced banana into a clean
glass jar to start the fertilizer
fermentation process.
Next, pour about four cups of water into
the jar, which is equivalent to one
liter.
To help the fermentation process happen
faster and prevent the banana from
spoiling, I add a little beer to the
mixture.
[Music]
Add about 6 tablesp of beer, equivalent
to around 100 mm, to help the mixture
ferment effectively and maintain a
pleasant fragrance.
[Music]
and finally add 1 tbsp of honey to
provide extra nutrients and stimulate a
better fermentation process.
[Music]
Uh, if you haven't subscribed to the
channel yet, please hit the subscribe
button to support me and not miss any
orchid growing tips. It's wonderful to
have you along on this journey.
[Music]
On the jar lid, make a small ventilation
hole so that the gas produced during
fermentation can escape, preventing the
jar from bursting.
Then place the jar in a cool, airy spot
for about 2 to 3 weeks for the mixture
to ferment completely and be ready to
use.
And here's the result. After about 2
weeks of fermentation, the banana has
completely softened, ensuring the
nutrients are fully dissolved and ready
to be used as fertilizer for orchids.
[Music]
Simply take 3 tablespoons of this
fermented banana mixture and mix it with
four cups of water, equivalent to about
one liter, and you will have a natural
fertilizer solution for your orchids.
[Music]
Method one, fertilize the orchid roots
directly with the liquid solution made
from fermented bananas, helping the
roots stay strong and absorb nutrients
more effectively.
Simply water each orchid pot with about
10 tablespoons of this solution, which
is enough to ensure the plant receives
sufficient nutrients without any waste.
[Music]
The fermented banana solution also
provides plenty of natural vitamins and
minerals, helping the orchids leaves and
flowers stay fresh and glossy while
keeping the flower colors vibrant for
longer. This is a natural, safe, yet
effective way to care for orchids.
[Music]
Um, liquid fertilizer made from
fermented bananas helps orchid roots
grow strong, firm, and healthy. When the
roots are healthy, the plant can absorb
more nutrients from the soil or growing
medium, thereby increasing vitality and
the ability to bloom consistently year
round.
[Music]
Using liquid fertilizer from fermented
bananas also helps improve the structure
of the soil or orchid growing medium,
making the environment around the roots
more loose and airy. This not only
supports root development but also
prevents root rot or fungal diseases.
[Music]
Additionally, the fermented banana
mixture stimulates the growth of
beneficial microorganisms in the soil,
creating a biological balance and
promoting the natural breakdown of
nutrients. As a result, the orchid
absorbs nutrients more effectively and
remains healthy for a long time.
Method two,
you can put the fermented banana mixture
into a spray bottle and spray it
directly onto the orchid's leaves and
flowers. This method helps the plant
absorb nutrients quickly through the
leaves while keeping the leaf surface
clean and glossy, contributing to
longerlasting blooms.
[Music]
Spraying liquid fertilizer made from
fermented bananas directly onto the
leaves helps the orchid absorb essential
nutrients quickly, improves
photosynthesis, and increases the
plant's vitality. When the leaves are
healthy, the plant grows more balanced,
and has a better ability to bloom
consistently.
[Music]
Uh when sprayed on the leaves, the
fermented banana mixture also stimulates
the growth of beneficial microorganisms
on the leaf surface, creating a natural
protective layer against pests and mold.
As a result, the orchid becomes
healthier and the risk of disease is
minimized.
[Music]
But you should not spray this solution
directly onto the flowers because when
the flowers get wet, they can easily
drop, reducing their lifespan.
[Music]
Next, if you want the orchid leaves to
stay glossy and firm, take half a lemon,
squeeze out the juice, and prepare to
mix it into the leaf care solution.
[Music]
Then dilute the lemon juice in about 3 L
of water to create a gentle solution
that is safe for the orchid leaves while
still helping them stay glossy and
healthy.
[Music]
Next, use a soft cloth soaked in the
diluted lemon juice solution and gently
wipe both the top and underside of the
orchid leaves, helping them stay clean,
glossy, and better absorb nutrients.
Lemon has antibacterial and antiseptic
properties, effectively eliminating
harmful fungi and insects. At the same
time, um, wiping the leaves with the
lemon solution adds vitamins, helping
the orchid leaves stay healthy, glossy,
and grow well.
Thanks to being cleaned and nourished,
the orchid leaves can perform
photosynthesis better, helping the plant
store more energy to develop roots, new
leaves, and prepare for the next
blooming cycles.
And so with just a few simple steps, you
have completed caring for the orchid
leaves using diluted lemon water. The
leaves are clean, glossy, protected,
protected, and supplied with essential
vitamins, creating a solid foundation
for the plant to grow strongly and bloom
beautifully in the future.
And here is the result. You can see that
the orchid leaves are well protected,
always fresh, glossy, and healthy.
Besides staying fresh, the leaves also
become firmer, helping the plant
withstand light sunlight and
environmental factors while providing a
solid foundation for the orchid to grow
well. and lounge grid.
[Music]
The newly developed roots are very
strong, thick, and firm, helping the
plant absorb more nutrients, thereby
promoting overall growth and preparing
for upcoming flower buds.
These healthy roots also help the plant
anchor firmly to the growing medium,
providing stability and reducing the
risk of falling or damage, creating a
solid foundation for the long-term
growth of the orchid.
[Music]
And so with strong roots, the orchid
will absorb nutrients optimally, grow
balanced from roots to leaves, and be
ready for the next vibrant blooms. This
is the essential foundation for the
orchid to stay healthy, and bloom
consistently.
[Music]
The potassium in bananas helps orchids
resist drought very effectively. Thanks
to potassium, water is transported
better from the roots to the stems,
leaves, and flowers, helping the blooms
last longer, maintain vibrant colors,
and reduce the risk of wilting or
premature fading.
Potassium also stimulates the orchid to
produce more flower buds, helping the
plant bloom consistently and increasing
the number of flowers on each spike.
[Music]
With this very simple care method, you
can confidently grow and care for
orchids at home, ensuring the plant
stays healthy, the leaves remain glossy,
and the flowers bloom vibrantly all year
round.
I hope you enjoy this video. If you find
it helpful, don't forget to subscribe to
the channel and share it so more people
can learn how to care for orchids
naturally.
Thank you for watching. Wishing you a
wonderful day. And may your orchids
always stay fresh, green, and bloom
beautifully.