Welcome to the Happiness Garden, where
we explore the beauty of nature together
and find joy in every moment of plant
care.
If you love orchids and wish to
propagate and care for your orchids so
they grow strong, lush, and bloom all
year round, then this is the video for
you.
If you haven't subscribed yet, please
hit the subscribe button to support me
and never miss any helpful orchid
growing tips. It's truly wonderful to
have you along on this journey. Let's
get started.
This is an orchid that has finished
blooming and I bought it at a very low
price to restore, propagate, and help it
bloom again in future seasons.
After orchids finish blooming, they
usually have been through quite a long
period, so we need to carefully check
their roots and repot them to help the
plant grow healthier.
[Music]
Uh you can see that because the orchid
pot has been used for a long time, mold
has appeared on the growing medium which
negatively affects the plant's growth.
[Music]
If this situation is left untreated for
too long, it will cause root rot and
weaken the orchid, even risking the
plant's death.
[Music]
uh we need to remove all the moldy
growing medium and replace it with fresh
clean medium to provide the best
conditions for root growth.
Um next we will cut away all the damaged
roots to prevent disease spread and help
the plant recover faster.
[Music]
The spots where the flower buds have
bloomed cannot bloom again and will not
develop into kiki baby plants.
Uh these two nodes haven't bloomed yet,
so we can stimulate them to grow into
kiki baby plants or produce new flower
buds.
Um, that's why I cut off the spent
flower nodes so the nutrients won't be
scattered and can focus on supporting
the potential growth of Kiki baby
plants.
Next, I prepare a natural fertilizer to
help restore the orchid and stimulate
the growth of Kiki kegi baby plants on
the orchid cutting.
[Music]
Take 3 tablespoons of oat flour as the
main ingredient to provide natural
nutrients for the orchid.
Add one liter of water to the oat flour
to dissolve it and create a natural
fertilizer mixture.
Cover the container and wait for 2 hours
to allow the nutrients from the oat
flour to fully dissolve into the water.
[Music]
Next, sprinkle turmeric powder on the
cut surface of the orchid cutting to
prevent bacteria and promote faster
healing.
[Music]
After 2 hours, strain out the sediment
to collect the clear liquid, which will
be used as The natural fertilizer for
the orchid,
oat flour contains many natural vitamins
and minerals that provide essential
nutrients, stimulating orchid roots to
grow stronger and healthier.
The antioxidants in oat flour help boost
the plant's resistance, keeping orchid
leaves green and promoting healthy
growth.
[Music]
Then add one teaspoon of honey into the
solution to boost nutrients and
stimulate the orchid's growth.
Honey has natural antibacterial
properties that help prevent the growth
of bacteria and fungi on cuts,
protecting the orchid from infections.
Then add three vitamin B1 tablets into
the mixture to enhance nutrient
absorption and stimulate stronger orchid
root growth.
[Music]
Then use this mixture to soak the orchid
roots for about 20 minutes, helping to
disinfect and stimulate faster root
growth.
While waiting, I prepare stakes to
secure the orchid after planting,
helping the plant stand firm and grow
more steadily.
Please comment to me which country you
are watching the video from. It's great
that we can chat together from all over
the world.
In addition to English dubbing, we have
now created French, German, Italian,
Spanish, Portuguese, Japanese, Hindi,
and Indonesian. and dubbing to help you
listen and understand the content
easily.
[Music]
To listen to the language, open the
video and click settings gear icon to
select the appropriate audio language.
[Music]
Next, plant the orchid into a new pot
with fresh, nutrient-rich growing medium
to support better growth.
I choose crushed pine bark as the
growing medium because it provides good
drainage, retains moderate moisture, and
creates a well ventilated environment
for healthy orchid root growth.
Using stakes to secure the orchid after
planting prevents the plant from shaking
uh thus protecting the new roots from
damage or negative impact.
[Music]
Then water the orchid with this natural
fertilizer mixture to provide essential
nutrients and maintain moisture in the
growing medium after planting.
[Music]
From now on, use this mixture to water
or spray the entire orchid about two to
three times a month, helping the plant
stay healthy and grow well.
[Music]
When sprayed, the mixture supplies
nutrients directly through the leaves
and the growing medium, allowing the
orchid to absorb faster and develop more
fully.
[Music]
The spraying process also helps wash
away dust and fungal pathogens on the
leaves, keeping the orchid cleaner and
healthier.
[Music]
Uh after spraying, use a soft cloth to
wipe off the water droplets on the
leaves to prevent mold growth and
protect the orchid from damage.
Next, I peel off the protective layer
covering the dormant buds on the stem
cutting, which helps the buds better
access air and nutrients, thereby
promoting faster growth.
[Music]
Then I use aloe vera leaves to stimulate
the growth of kiki baby plants from the
orchid. stem cutting. Thanks to the
natural hormones and nutrients in aloe
vera.
[Music]
Extract the aloe vera gel because it
provides moisture, nutrients, and
natural hormones that support the rapid
and healthy growth of kiki buds.
[Music]
Then apply or press aloe vera gel onto
the dormant kiki bud for about 30
minutes, allowing the nutrients to
absorb into the plant tissue and
stimulate the bud to awaken and begin
growing.
[Music]
Uh then wait about 30 minutes and take
cotton balls soaked in aloe vera gel out
of the sleeping orchid buds.
After 30 minutes, remove the cotton.
After that, if you place the orchid pot
in a cool and humid area, the dormant
bud will grow into a kiki plantlet.
However, if you place it in a sunnier
spot, the dormant bud will develop into
a flower bud.
And here are the results after 5 weeks.
Um, you can see that the roots have
grown very strong, indicating that the
orchid is recovering well and absorbing
nutrients effectively.
[Music]
When the roots are healthy, they help
the orchid absorb water and nutrients
more efficiently, leading to strong
growth, new leaves, new shoots, and an
easier blooming in the next season.
The leaves have also become glossier and
plumper, showing that the plant is in a
healthy and vigorous growth state.
[Music]
And you can clearly see that the dormant
bud has developed into a kiki orchid
plantlet, proving that the stimulation
method is completely effective and safe
for the orchid.
If you find this content helpful and
meaningful, don't forget to like and
share. so more people can discover it
and subscribe to support the channel.
Thank you for always being with me.
[Music]
Uh after that, I continue to care for
the orchid using fertilizer made from
oat solution, honey, and vitamin B1.
Watering or spraying two to three times
a month to keep the plant healthy and
growing well.
[Music]
And here are the results after 10 weeks.
You can see that the Kiki baby plant
from the stem cutting has grown very
strong with fresh robust roots proving
the effectiveness of the care method we
applied.
When the kiki baby plant on the stem
cutting is sturdy and has strong roots,
we can completely separate and replant
the baby orchid to help it grow better
and stronger.
[Music]
Now I separate the baby plant to replant
it individually, creating favorable
conditions for strong growth in an
environment with better controlled
light, humidity, and nutrients.
[Music]
I choose pine bark chips as the main
growing medium for the baby orchid
because it provides good arration,
retains moderate moisture, and supports
healthy root development. time.
[Music]
I spread a thin layer of moss on top to
retain moisture and create a soft
environment, helping protect the young
roots of the baby orchid for better
growth.
When planting in the pot, we only need
to place the orchid cutting from the
stem on top of the moss layer without
burying the roots under the medium,
which helps avoid damaging the young
roots and creates better conditions for
new root growth.
[Music]
Then, water the orchid to keep it moist.
Only when new roots grow and firmly
attach to the medium should you start
fertilizing, allowing the plant to
absorb nutrients more effectively.
If you care for them patiently,
gradually you will have a beautiful
orchid garden filled filled with lush
plants blooming all year round, bringing
joy and relaxation every day.
I hope this video will be very helpful
to you in caring for orchids at home,
helping the plants grow healthy and
bloom beautifully.
If you find the content meaningful and
helpful, don't forget to like and share
so more people can discover it and
subscribe to support my channel. Thank
you for always being with me.
Welcome everyone to my garden.
Um, I'm really happy to see you again in
this video.
Today, we'll continue exploring a
wonderful organic fertilizer for
orchids.
This fertilizer not only helps the
orchids grow strong, but also encourages
them to bloom all year round.
Let's dive into the details together.
To make this fertilizer, I need onions.
Onions contain essential nutrients such
as nitrogen, phosphorus, and potassium,
which help the plant grow strong.
[Music]
The sulfur compounds in onions have
antibacterial and antifungal properties,
helping protect orchids from common
diseases.
[Music]
Onion extract helps stimulate the growth
of new roots, allowing orchids to
thrive.
[Music]
Put the onion into a jar.
Please comment to me which country you
are watching the video from. It's great
that we can chat together from all over
the world.
[Music]
Add one liter of boiled water.
[Applause]
[Music]
Then incubate and wait overnight.
after one night.
[Music]
The onion peel juice I leave overnight
will look like this.
Now I open this and filter it. I will
just use the onion juice. We do not use
the onions.
[Music]
Add one liter of water.
Step one.
In the first method, I put onion juice
in a spray bottle.
[Music]
and spray on orchid leaves as
fertilizer.
[Music]
We will fertilize orchids from the
leaves and roots by spraying both the
top and bottom parts.
[Music]
Spray the top and bottom of the leaves
thoroughly.
and spray onto aerial roots to help
deliver nutrients directly to the aerial
roots.
When the substrate is dry and the roots
are silvery white, spray immediately.
Uh onion soak water contains many
vitamins and minerals providing
nutrition for the plant from leaves to
roots.
[Music]
Spraying on leaves enhances
photosynthesis, keeping the leaves green
and healthy.
After spraying water on the orchid
leaves, if it's sunny, you need to wipe
off any water droplets left on the
leaves.
Uh because the water droplets on the
leaves can create a magnifying effect
under the sunlight leading to leaf burn.
Water accumulation on leaves can foster
the growth of fungi and bacteria,
increasing the likelihood of disease.
[Music]
Water on leaves can obstruct
photosynthesis.
Wiping it off allows leaves to transpire
and absorb light more effectively.
[Music]
Cleaning off water helps the leaves dry
faster, keeping the plant healthy and
avoiding issues related to excessive
humidity.
[Music]
If you haven't subscribed to the channel
yet, please hit the subscribe button to
support me and not miss any orchid
growing tips. It's wonderful to have you
as a companion.
[Music]
Step two,
water each orchid pot with this liquid
fertilizer.
[Music]
This natural fertilizer contains
essential vitamins and minerals that
help orchids grow healthily.
[Music]
The compounds in onions have
antibacterial and antifungal properties
protecting orchids from diseases.
[Music]
Onion soak water can stimulate root
growth, helping the plant absorb water
and nutrients more effectively.
[Music]
Watering with onion liquid helps keep
leaves greener and enhances
photosynthesis.
It helps the plant combat environmental
stress such as high temperatures or low
humidity.
It helps retain moisture in the soil and
improves fertility creating favorable
conditions for root development.
Uh it enhances the activity of
beneficial microorganisms in the soil
improving the overall health of the
plant.
[Music]
It is best to soak the orchid pot in
this water for about 20 minutes.
After soaking for 20 minutes, take the
orchid pot out and place it in a place
with enough light.
[Music]
Then place the pot in a spot with gentle
sunlight so the plant can
photosynthesize, allowing the natural
fertilizer to work at its best.
Orchids typically need about 50 to 70%
natural light as too much direct
sunlight can scorch the leaves.
A good place to place the orchid pot is
a spot with moderate wind flow, which
will help reduce excessive humidity and
prevent fungal diseases very well.
You can place the pot near a window or a
place with a light breeze.
[Music]
Now, let's take a look at the results.
After caring for the orchids with the
natural fertilizer,
[Music]
the leaves will grow vibrant, thick, and
healthy. They will have bright colors
and and will not turn yellow or scorch
due to appropriate light and humidity.
[Music]
The roots will develop robustly and
evenly with adequate moisture and
nutrients. The roots will have a shiny
appearance and will not rot or
deteriorate.
If you encounter any difficulties during
the orchid growing process, don't
hesitate to comment and let me know. I'm
always ready to support you so that you
can grow healthy orchids and have them
bloom abundantly.
[Music]
proper care and ideal environmental
conditions will stimulate bud formation.
[Music]
The buds will be strong and capable of
developing into flowers.
[Music]
How do you find the way to revive weak
orchids and care for your orchids?
Please leave your comments and
suggestions to let me know.
[Music]
If you find the content useful and
meaningful, don't forget to like, share
it so more people can see, and subscribe
to the channel to support me. Thank you
for always being with me.
[Music]
The flowers will bloom evenly, last
longer, and display vibrant colors.
When placed correctly, orchid flowers
will be less likely to drop and will
have a longer blooming period.
[Music]
Take care of your orchids with all the
love you have for plants and you will be
rewarded.
[Music]
Orchids are sensitive beings that
respond positively to dedicated care.
When you invest your time and effort in
nurturing them, um, you not only help
the plants grow strong, but also get to
enjoy beautiful blooms, symbolizing the
love and patience you have put in. Let
your love shine through every orchid
pot.
[Music]
Thank you for watching today's video.
I hope the information about how to care
for and water orchids with liquid
fertilizer helps you have healthy and
vibrant orchid pots.
If you found the video helpful, don't
forget to like and subscribe to the
channel for more gardening tips.
See you in the next video.