Welcome to the happiness garden. In
today's video, I will guide you on how
to make a new natural fertilizer that
helps orchids grow strong from roots to
leaves and continuously show off
brilliant flowers. Let's explore the
secret to caring for orchids so the
plants are always healthy and keep
blooming non-stop.
To make natural fertilizer, the first
ingredient I need to prepare is garlic.
A simple ingredient, but but rich in
valuable nutrients that help stimulate
healthy growth for orchid plants.
[Music]
You only need a small clove of garlic
and mince it very finely to maximize the
essence from the garlic for this natural
fertilizer.
[Music]
Uh, if you haven't subscribed to the
channel yet, please press the subscribe
button to support me and not miss any
orchid growing tips. It's wonderful to
have you along.
[Music]
Besides English narration, we have now
created versions narrated in French,
German, Italian, Spanish, Portuguese,
Japanese, Hindi, Dutch, Polish, Korean,
and Indonesian to help you listen to and
understand the content more easily.
Um, to listen to a language, open the
video and click on settings, the gear
icon to select the appropriate audio
language.
Please comment and let me know which
country you are watching the video from.
It's wonderful that we can chat together
from all around the world.
[Music]
After mincing the garlic, put it into a
clean cup and then mix it with one liter
of water.
[Music]
Uh the next ingredient I need to prepare
is molasses. uh a natural nutrient rich
in minerals that helps nourish and
stimulate orchid plants to grow
healthier.
[Music]
You only need to add one teaspoon of
molasses into the solution. Just enough
to provide energy and nutrients to help
the orchid grow vigorously.
[Music]
Stir the mixture well then and cover it
and place it in a cool airy place for 1
day uh so the nutrients can blend and
work best for the natural fertilizer.
[Music]
After one day, stir the solution well
once again. Then filter out the sediment
to get the clear, pure liquid to use as
fertilizer for the orchid plants.
[Music]
Next, dilute the filtered solution with
another one L of water, creating 2 L of
complete natural fertilizer mixture,
ready to care for and nourish your
orchid plants.
[Music]
Method one, use a soft cloth to evenly
soak up this liquid fertilizer mixture.
Then gently and thoroughly wipe both the
top and underside of the orchid leaves
to help the nutrients absorb deeply.
Wiping the leaves helps remove dust and
bacteria stuck on the leaf surface uh
thereby creating better conditions for
the leaves to breathe and increasing
photosynthesis, helping the plant grow
healthier every day.
The natural fertilizer mixture
penetrates through the leaf surface,
directly supplying essential nutrients,
helping the leaves become shiny and
enhancing the plant's resistance against
pests and harmful environmental factors.
[Music]
Uh through the regular leaf wiping
process, you can also easily detect
early signs of abnormalities such as
disease spots or pests, helping you
promptly handle them and keep your
orchid plants in the best condition.
[Music]
You should wipe the leaves with this
fertilizer mixture about one to two
times per month. Doing this regularly
will help the orchid plants consistently
receive nutrients and keep the leaves
clean, thereby supporting healthy growth
and regular blooming.
[Music]
Method two, put the prepared fertilizer
mixture into a spray bottle, making it
easier and more even to spray the
fertilizer over the entire orchid plant.
[Music]
Then gently spray evenly over the entire
orchid plant from leaves to stem,
allowing the nutrients to penetrate
deeply and nourish the plant
comprehensively.
Don't forget to also spray onto the
roots and the growing medium around the
plant, helping stimulate healthy root
development and improve the living
environment for the orchid.
Spraying the fertilizer mixture helps
nutrients cover the entire surface of
the plant from leaves to roots, creating
conditions for the plant to absorb
quickly and effectively, thereby
promoting comprehensive growth and
increasing vitality for the orchid.
[Music]
When sprayed onto the growing medium and
roots, the mixture also helps improve
the plant's living environment,
stimulates strong root growth, increases
the ability to absorb water and
nutrients, helping the orchid grow
sustainably and bloom more regularly.
[Music]
Method three, use the diluted fertilizer
mixture to water directly at the base
and roots of the orchid plant, helping
supply nutrients deep inside, stimulate
healthy root growth, and enable the
plant to absorb nutrients optimally.
Watering with this mixture helps
maintain moisture and nutrient balance
in the growing medium, creating a
favorable environment for orchid roots
to develop sustainably, contributing to
overall plant health and regular
blooming ability.
Watering the fertilizer mixture directly
onto the roots provides essential
nutrients right where the plant absorbs
most of its nourishment, thereby
promoting strong root growth and
improving the ability to absorb water as
well as necessary minerals for the
plant.
After watering, you can soak the entire
orchid pot in this fertilizer solution
for about 20 minutes, helping the
nutrients penetrate deeply into the
roots and growing medium, supporting the
plant to absorb more effectively and
stimulating comprehensive growth.
[Music]
Uh while waiting for the soak, gently
use a dry cloth to wipe off any water
droplets remaining on the leaf surfaces
and in the leaf crevices. This method
helps prevent prolonged moisture,
reduces the risk of fungal diseases, and
keeps the leaves always dry, shiny, and
healthy.
[Music]
After soaking for 20 minutes, gently
take the orchid out and place it in a
spot with gentle sunlight. This mild
light helps the plant photosynthesize
effectively there, thereby maximizing
nutrient absorption from the fertilizer
mixture, helping the orchid grow healthy
and bloom more brilliantly.
And here is the orchid after being cared
for with natural fertilizer made from
garlic combined with fermented molasses.
Uh a simple method but with clear
effective results.
First are the leaves. You can see they
are lush green, firm and thick, which
indicates that the orchid is being
supplied with sufficient nutrients, is
healthy, and has good resistance to
external factors.
[Music]
Next are the roots. You can easily
notice that both the roots inside the
pot and the aerial roots are growing
very strong and healthy. Proof of
effective nutrient absorption and the
ideal living environment that the plant
is being cared for.
[Music]
Uh when the root system is healthy, the
orchid will absorb water and nutrients
optimally, thereby promoting the plant's
comprehensive growth, helping the leaves
stay lush green and the flowers bloom
more regularly.
[Music]
Therefore, roots are often compared to
the heart of the orchid, playing the
most important role in nurturing and
sustaining the life of the entire plant,
determining the health and beauty of
every single flower.
[Music]
When cared for with this natural
fertilizer, the flower spikes on the
orchid also become plumper and healthier
than usual, signaling a brilliant and
longlasting blooming season approaching.
[Music]
The flowers when blooming have larger,
softer petals and vibrant, bright
colors, looking like beautiful
butterflies gently resting on the
branches, creating a truly lively and
energetic scene.
[Music]
Thanks to that, your garden will always
be filled with fresh, colorful flowers,
attracting every gaze and bringing a
feeling of peace and happiness every
time you look at them. This is the
well-deserved reward for your dedicated
and patient care of the orchid plants.
And and more importantly, using natural
fertilizer made from garlic and molasses
not only helps the plants stay healthy
and bloom brilliantly, but is also safe,
environmentally friendly, and cost
effective compared to chemical
fertilizers. This is a sustainable
choice for both orchid growers and
nature.
[Music]
I hope with this natural fertilizer
recipe, you will easily care for and
revive your beloved orchid plants. Don't
forget to do it regularly and patiently
to see clear changes in every leaf,
chute, root, and flower.
I hope you will like this video. If you
find it useful, don't forget to hit like
and subscribe to the channel so you
won't miss the next shares on how to
care for orchids naturally and simply.
[Music]
Thank you so much for watching the video
and supporting the channel. Goodbye and
wishing you always happiness and good
health along with the brilliant orchids
in your garden.