Welcome to my channel.
If you have an orchid with yellow leaves
and weak roots, don't miss this video.
First, remove all the yellow leaves and
any dead roots.
[Music]
Um, let me know where you're from.
Let me create subtitles in your
country's language so we can communicate
more easily.
[Music]
Then use small pieces of pine bark to
replant this orchid.
If you haven't subscribe to the channel
yet, click the subscribe button to
support me.
[Music]
Spread a layer of moss over the surface
of the orchid pot to help retain
moisture better.
[Music]
Take 2 tbsps of vinegar.
mix 4 L of water with the vinegar.
[Music]
Step one, clean the orchid leaves with
this water.
[Music]
Vinegar water helps remove lime deposits
and dirt from the leaves, allowing them
to photosynthesize more effectively in
sunlight. It also kills harmful insects
that often hide on the underside of
leaves such as red spidermitites, leaf
hoppers, aphids, and thris.
[Music]
If you don't understand, don't hesitate
to leave a comment so we can help you.
[Music]
Doing this one to two times a month will
keep your orchid leaves green and
prevent leaf diseases.
[Music]
Then take one teaspoon of sugar and mix
it with the vinegar water.
[Music]
Step two, pour the solution over the
orchid roots.
Vinegar combined with sugar helps
stimulate root growth very quickly and
effectively.
Uh, vinegar helps eliminate pests
harmful to orchid roots while sugar
provides nutrients and creates an
environment for beneficial
microorganisms to thrive around the
roots.
[Music]
Soak in this solution for about 30
minutes.
[Music]
Then take it out and place it in a spot
with gentle sunlight so the orchid can
photosynthesize and grow well.
[Music]
Use the remaining mixture to water other
healthy orchids, helping them grow and
enhance their resistance to pests and
diseases.
[Music]
Do this twice a month with this solution
for your orchids.
[Music]
One month later,
after just one month, the orchid has
grown many new roots.
[Music]
These new roots will absorb water and
nutrients most effectively, helping the
orchid grow quickly.
[Music]
I hope this video content will help you
learn how to care for orchids at home.
Thank you for watching. Wishing you good
health and good luck in taking care of
your orchids at home.
Welcome to part two of this video.
[Music]
[Applause]
Rice is a common and highly effective
organic fertilizer for plants. So in
this video I will show you two methods
to make orchid fertilizer using rice.
[Music]
Method one.
Take 3 tablesp of rice.
[Music]
Grind it into a fine powder.
Add one liter of boiling water.
[Music]
cover it and wait for it to cool down.
Filter out the residue.
[Music]
Dilute it with 2 L of water.
Now use this water to water your
orchids.
Rice contains many nutrients such as
potassium, phosphorus, and protein,
which are essential for the growth of
orchids.
Therefore, rice washing water helps the
plants grow healthily and enhances their
resistance to pests and diseases.
[Music]
Rice washing water helps boost the
activity of beneficial microorganisms in
the orchids growing medium, thereby
protecting the roots and making it
easier for them to absorb nutrients.
Doing this once a month will help your
orchids grow healthily.
[Music]
And of course, it will also bloom a lot.
Uh, the microorganisms in the orchid's
growing medium help protect the roots
from rotting.
When the roots grow, they absorb
nutrients that make the flowers more
beautiful, allowing them to stay in
bloom for a long time before their
petals wither.
[Music]
Regular
care in this way will ensure the leaves
receive enough nutrients allowing them
to grow very green.
[Music]
Method do.
When cooking rice, we usually rinse the
rice. From now on, don't rush to pour
this rice water down the drain.
Filter this rice washing water and let
it settle.
[Music]
After it has settled, filter 100 mm of
the water from the top.
[Music]
Dilute it with 200 ml of regular water.
Pour this rice washing water into a
spray bottle.
[Music]
Use this water to spray evenly on the
surface of the orchid leaves.
The vitamin B1 in rice washing water
helps stimulate the conversion of
nutrients, especially harmful elements
like manganesees, iron, and copper into
more easily absorbed forms.
[Music]
Vitamin B1 helps strengthen the orchid's
immune system, enabling the plant to
resist pests and other environmental
stressors.
[Music]
For the rice water that has settled at
the bottom, I filter out the residue,
[Applause]
then dilute it with an additional 2 L of
water.
[Music]
And I use this water to water my
orchids.
We also do this once a month just like
the first method I shared at the
beginning of the video.
Additionally, you can combine other
organic fertilizers to ensure your
orchids receive all the necessary
nutrients.
Thank you for watching the video.
Wishing you all the best and much
success.
Welcome to my channel.
In this video, I continue to share a new
way to make organic fertilizer for
orchids. Helps orchids grow healthily
and bloom continuously all year round.
If you haven't subscribed to the channel
yet, please click the subscribe button
to support me and not miss any orchid
growing tips.
It's great to have company.
[Music]
Let's get started.
After buying the orchid, the orchid has
finished blooming and entered the
withering stage of the flower branch.
Don't rush to throw it away. Um, let me
share how they can grow and continue to
bloom.
[Music]
First you need to remove all wilted
petals.
[Music]
Then throw away this old plastic orchid
pot.
Then cut off all damaged roots.
[Music]
This helps the roots branch quickly and
not rot.
In addition to the English dub, we've
now created dubs in French, German,
Italian, Spanish, Portuguese, Japanese,
Hindi, and Indonesian to help you hear
and understand the content. Videos are
easier.
When transplanted to a new pot, these
branched roots will grow very strongly.
[Music]
But if we don't replant it in a new pot,
the roots will rot very quickly. So,
cut off damaged leaves.
Please comment to me which country you
are watching the video from. It's great
that we can chat together from all over
the world.
If you encounter any difficulties during
the orchid growing process, don't
hesitate to comment. I am always ready
to support you so you can grow healthy
orchids and bloom lots of flowers.
Then take one onion
and take its shell.
[Music]
Onion peels contain many antioxidants
and antibacterial compounds which help
strengthen orchids resistance and
protect them from diseases.
When onion peels decompose, they provide
nutrients such as potassium, calcium,
and magnesium, helping plants grow
healthily.
Put all the onion skins in the jar.
[Music]
Add one liter of boiled water. About
four cups of water.
Then take 3 tablespoon of oatmeal.
[Music]
Oats contain many nutrients including
vitamins, minerals, and proteins, which
help provide nutrition for orchids.
Oats have good moisture retention
ability, helping to maintain moisture in
orchid soil, especially on hot days.
Incubate and wait until the water cools.
[Music]
Now take one teaspoon of baking soda.
Add one liter of water, about four cups.
Baking soda has antifungal properties,
helping to prevent common fungal
diseases in orchids such as mold.
Then pour the baking soda solution in to
soak.
Use a soft cotton pad to thoroughly wipe
the top and bottom of the leaves with
baking soda solution.
Baking soda solution has antifungal
properties, helping to prevent the
development of fungal diseases on orchid
leaves.
Wiping leaves helps remove dirt and
impurities, helping leaves absorb light
better, thereby promoting
photosynthesis.
[Music]
Soak orchid roots in this water for 20
minutes.
[Music]
30 minutes later.
After soaking for 20 minutes, take the
orchid out and plant it in a new pot.
[Music]
Planted with deep pine bark. Helps
moisturize better.
after the water cools.
[Music]
Filter out residue.
Add one liter of water.
[Music]
The nutrients in the onion skin will
penetrate the leaves, helping the plant
absorb more necessary minerals.
[Music]
Wiping leaves with onion peel water
helps remove dirt and impurities,
cleaning the leaf surface for more
effective photosynthesis.
[Music]
From now on, do this once a month to
protect orchid leaves.
Then use this water to water the
orchids.
[Music]
As onion skin decomposes, it provides
nutrients such as potassium, calcium,
and magnesium, which help the plant grow
healthily.
[Music]
Onion peels have the ability to retain
moisture, helping to maintain moisture
in orchid soil, which is essential for
root growth.
[Music]
Soak in this water for 20 minutes.
Or you can also put this water in a
spray bottle.
[Music]
Then spray the entire orchid.
This method is similar to folure
fertilization for orchids.
[Music]
After soaking for 20 minutes, take the
orchid pot out and place it in a place
with light sunlight for the orchid to
photosynthesize.
[Music]
results after one month.
Orchid branches continue to flower.
[Music]
The petals are very thick and beautiful.
Brilliant colors.
[Music]
The roots grow healthily.
Um, healthy roots help plants absorb
water and essential nutrients from the
environment, ensuring good growth.
[Music]
Roots play an important role in
regulating the plant's humidity,
preventing orchids from drying out or
root rot.
[Music]
Roots also produce hormones that help
promote plant growth, including
flowering and new leaves.
[Music]
The leaves also become greener and
glossier.
[Music]
Um, this proves proves that the orchid
is in a very healthy period.
Take care of your orchids with all the
love you have for plants
and you'll be rewarded with beautiful
flowers that you you take care of
yourself.
I hope this video will be an inspiration
and helpful for you in taking care of
your beloved orchids at home. If you
find this content interesting, don't
forget to hit the subscribe button so
you won't miss out on more helpful tips.
Thank you for watching the video. I ask
God to bless