Welcome to the happiness garden. Today I
will continue to share with you a new
natural fertilizer method that is simple
but effective. I hope this recipe will
give you more options to take care of
your orchid pots so they stay healthy
and always bloom beautifully at home.
When you have a small orchid from a
nursery pot or are about to repot a
mature orchid, the first step is to
check the growing medium. If the medium
is too old, decomposed, or retains
moisture poorly, you should remove it
completely. But if the medium is still
good, we just need to treat it for
reuse. For this young orchid, the medium
is still in good condition. So, I will
treat and keep the old medium.
[Music]
Um to treat the old growing medium,
prepare about one liter of clean water
to mix a natural disinfectant solution.
[Music]
Next, add 1 teasp of baking soda into
the prepared 1 L of water. Baking soda
is a natural disinfectant that gently
sterilizes the growing medium while
remaining safe for the roots. Stir well
until the baking soda is completely
dissolved in the water.
[Music]
If you haven't subscribed to the channel
yet, please click the subscribe button
to support me and not miss any orchid
growing tips. It's wonderful to have you
along.
[Music]
After preparing the baking soda
solution, gently dip the orchid's leaves
into it. For a small orchid, dipping for
about 10 to 20 seconds is enough. For a
mature orchid, you can soak the leaves
for a few minutes to increase the
disinfecting and disease preventing
effect.
[Music]
After treating the leaves, continue
soaking the orchid roots and growing
medium in the prepared baking soda
solution.
Soaking for about 20 minutes will help
eliminate remaining bacteria, mold, and
insects while creating a safe condition
for the plant to grow after repotting.
After treating the old growing medium
and orchid roots, we also need to treat
the new growing medium before placing
the plant in the pot. This step is very
important to eliminate potential fungal
diseases in the new medium and help the
orchid adapt better to the new growing
environment.
[Music]
The new growing medium needs to be
soaked in the baking soda solution for
about 20 minutes before use.
[Music]
After soaking the growing medium for 20
minutes, take it out and place it in a
well ventilated area to drain. The
surface of the medium should be dry, but
it should still retain internal moisture
to help prevent the orchid from going
into shock when planted in the new pot.
While waiting for the growing medium to
drain, uh, gently take the orchid out to
prepare for repotting into the new pot.
When planting orchids, you should choose
a pot with drainage holes at the bottom.
This is very important to prevent water
logging, keeping the orchid roots well
arrated and healthy.
First, place a few pieces of foam at the
bottom of the pot to improve drainage
and prevent the growing medium from
becoming compacted. Then, add a thin
layer of the medium on top to prepare
for placing the orchid in.
[Music]
Next, gently place the orchid in the
center of the pot.
Then, fill the growing medium around the
roots, pressing just enough to keep the
plant stable while still allowing the
roots enough space to breathe and grow.
[Music]
After filling in the growing medium,
gently tap the sides of the pot to help
the medium settle into the gaps around
the roots. This helps the plant stay
firm and stable in the pot, creating
good conditions for even root
development.
[Music]
Finally, you can spread a bit of dried
moss on the surface of the growing
medium. This moss layer helps lightly
retain moisture on the pot's surface and
creates a stable environment for the
plant to recover after repotting.
[Music]
After repotting, place the orchid pot in
a cool, wellventilated area away from
sunlight for a few hours to let the
plants stabilize before applying natural
fertilizer.
[Music]
To make today's natural fertilizer, I
continue using rice, but in a completely
different way. I hope this method will
give you another new option for taking
care of orchids at home.
[Music]
Put the rice in a pan and toast it over
low heat. Stir evenly until the rice
turns golden and releases a light aroma.
This is an important step to activate
the the nutrients in the rice, making
them easier for the plant to absorb.
Toasted rice differs from regular rice
in that after toasting, the nutrients in
the rice are activated and more easily
dissolved when mixed with water. As a
result, the orchid can absorb nutrients
better, especially during the recovery
and root development stage.
After toasting, transfer the rice to a
plate and let it cool completely.
Letting it cool helps preserve the rice
better so you can use it multiple times
while maintaining its quality and
distinctive aroma.
Put one spoonful of toasted rice into a
clean bottle. Then pour in about 1 L of
boiling water. The high temperature will
help extract the nutrients from the
toasted rice, creating a natural
fertilizer solution rich in energy for
the orchid.
[Music]
After pouring in the boiling water,
close the lid and let it sit until the
solution cools completely. Keeping the
lid on helps retain the full nutrients
and natural aroma of the toasted rice
during the soaking process.
[Music]
Once the solution has cooled, stir it
well and then strain out the residue.
Straining helps make the solution
clearer and cleaner, preventing clogging
during watering and allowing the plant
to absorb nutrients more effectively.
[Music]
Um, in addition to the English
voiceover, we've now created versions in
French, German, Italian, Spanish,
Portuguese, Japanese, Hindi, Dutch,
Polish, Korean, and Indonesian to help
you listen and understand the content
more easily.
To listen in your preferred language,
open the video and click on settings,
the gear icon, to select the appropriate
audio language.
[Music]
Leave me a comment letting me know which
country you're watching from. It's
wonderful that we can connect and chat
with each other from all around the
world.
Then use this mixture to water the
orchid directly. The solution made from
toasted rice will gently provide energy
and help the roots absorb nutrients
naturally and safely.
You only need to use this mixture twice
a month. Regular use will help your
orchid grow strong with firm roots,
green leaves, and readiness for the next
blooming cycles.
You can also soak the orchid pot in this
mixture for about 20 minutes. This
method allows the roots to absorb
nutrients more deeply while also
soothing the plant after repotting or
during its recovery period.
The leftover solution can be poured into
a spray bottle for easy use on your
orchid.
[Music]
Then lightly spray it on the leaves and
roots of other orchids in the garden to
help them absorb nutrients better while
also maintaining moisture and boosting
their natural resistance.
Spraying the toasted rice mixture will
provide a gentle amount of nutrients to
the orchid. As a result, the leaves
become greener, the roots grow stronger,
and the plant recovers more easily after
periods of stress.
In addition, the thin mist from the
solution helps retain moisture on the
surface of the leaves. This is
especially useful during dry weather or
when growing orchids in low humidity
environments.
[Music]
You only need to spray this mixture tur
twice a month. Regular use provides just
the right amount of nutrients, avoiding
excess while maintaining steady vitality
and natural beauty.
[Music]
Uh after soaking the orchid pot for 20
minutes, gently take the plant out and
place it in a spot with soft sunlight.
The gentle light helps the plant dry
naturally while also supporting
photosynthesis and recovery after
feeding.
And here's the result after 2 weeks. You
can see that the once small and weak
orchid has now clearly recovered and is
growing day by day. With a little
patience and a little love, your orchid
will always respond with fresh, vibrant
life.
[Music]
The roots have also become slightly
stronger, whiter, and are beginning to
cling to the new growing medium. This is
a positive sign that the plant is
gradually adapting and thriving in its
new environment.
[Music]
I will continue fertilizing this young
orchid twice a month regularly and
gently. Such consistent care will help
the plant absorb nutrients better and
grow steadily from roots to leaves. With
just a bit of patience and love for the
plant, you'll soon see the difference.
[Music]
Applying this mixture helps stimulate
strong root growth and enhances nutrient
absorption. When the root system is
healthy, the orchid will quickly
stabilize in the new growing medium and
begin to form new leaf shoots. This is a
vital foundation for the plant to
continue growing and prepare for the
next blooming cycles.
[Music]
After soaking for about 20 minutes, take
the orchid pot out and place it in a
spot with gentle indirect sunlight. At
this stage, the plant is absorbing
nutrients, so it needs a calm
environment with enough light to recover
and develop new roots.
And here is the result after the next 3
months. You can see the orchid has
clearly matured.
[Music]
From a tiny seedling, it has now
developed a strong root system, lush
green leaves, and is full of vitality.
Every stage of care has contributed to
this impressive transformation.
[Music]
And the special thing is that you can
see the orchid has produced two new
flower spikes, strong and full of
energy. This is a sign that the plant
has not only recovered well, but is also
ready to enter a new blooming cycle. A
welldeserved result for the the patience
and consistent care over the past
months.
[Music]
I continue fertilizing the orchid with
toasted rice regularly every 2 weeks.
This cyclical way of adding natural
nutrients helps the plant stay healthy,
grow steadily, and get ready for the
next blooming season. A simple yet
effective method that you can easily
apply at home.
[Music]
Please leave me a comment letting me
know which country you are watching the
video from. It's wonderful that we can
chat together from all around the world.
[Music]
After moistening the growing medium,
soak the entire orchid pot in this
mixture for about 20 minutes.
[Music]
Then place the orchid pot in a spot with
gentle light and good air flow. Soft
sunlight at this stage is very important
as it helps stimulate bud formation and
prepares the plant to bloom. A well-lit
environment will allow the orchid to
thrive at its best.
[Music]
And here is the result after the next
one month. You can see the two flower
spikes have started to bloom
beautifully, vibrant and full of life.
>> Each flower is proof of the persistent
and proper care, a well-deserved reward
for the love you have given to the
orchid.
[Music]
Thanks to this fertilizer, the petals
become softer and have more vibrant
colors than usual.
The natural nutrients deeply penetrate,
helping the orchid flowers maintain
freshness for a long time, highlighting
the plant's natural beauty and strong
vitality.
Uh, what do you think about how I care
for this young orchid? Don't hesitate to
leave a comment and share your thoughts.
I'm really looking forward to hearing
your feedback and experiences.
[Music]
If you encounter any difficulties during
the orchid growing process, don't
hesitate to comment for me. I'm always
ready to support you so you can grow
healthy orchids that bloom abundantly.
[Music]
I hope you will enjoy this video. If you
find it helpful, don't forget to hit
like and subscribe to the channel so you
won't miss the upcoming shares on how to
care for orchids naturally and simply.
[Music]