Welcome to my little channel where we
care for nature with love and patience.
Wishing you a peaceful day full of
inspiration.
In today's video, I continue to share
with you a new type of organic
fertilizer easy to make at home that
helps care for orchids to grow fully
from roots, stems, and leaves to flowers
all year round.
That's my helper. How do you like it?
[Music]
Let's get started.
Uh, this is the orchid I just bought.
Uh, when the delivery person brought it
and opened the package, the petals had
already wilted.
[Music]
the the surface of the leaves still has
a layer of mineral residue. It's
probably a mix of minerals and
pesticides sprayed from their industrial
orchid garden.
[Music]
Upon checking the roots, I found mold
and many rotting roots.
Which country are you watching this
video from? Leave a comment and let me
know where you are. It's amazing that we
can connect with each other from all
around the world.
[Music]
Cut off all the damaged roots.
Damaged roots are often home to harmful
fungi and bacteria. Removing them helps
reduce the risk of spreading disease to
the plant.
Then remove the old growing medium.
[Music]
The old growing medium may contain
harmful fungi, bacteria, or parasites.
Removing it helps reduce the risk of
spreading disease to the plant.
[Music]
Just keep a small amount of moss to
prevent the plant from going into shock
during repotting.
Then remove the wilted flowers.
[Music]
Wilted flowers absorb nutrients and
energy from the plant. Uh removing them
allows the plant to focus on growing new
blooms and healthy leaves.
[Music]
Then take 1 tbsp of baking soda.
Add one liter of water.
[Music]
Then gently place the orchid pot into
the container.
Pour in the baking soda solution and let
it soak. This helps clean the roots,
relax them, and improve nutrient
absorption.
[Music]
This will help eliminate fungal diseases
and insects that cause root rot.
[Music]
Then use a soft cotton pad to wipe the
leaves with the baking soda solution.
[Music]
Baking soda has antifungal properties
helping to prevent the growth of harmful
fungi and bacteria on the leaves and
roots.
[Music]
When you wipe the leaves with the baking
soda solution, it's not just about
cleaning. You're also removing dust,
mineral residue, and leftover
pesticides, allowing the leaves to
breathe better and absorb light more
effectively.
[Music]
Next, soak the orchid roots in this
solution for about 30 minutes. This is
the ideal time for a deep clean and
gentle mineral absorption.
[Music]
Do you have a cucumber?
Uh, every time I eat cucumber, I usually
peel it and never throw the skin away
because this peel is a wonderful
ingredient for making natural fertilizer
for orchids. It's both convenient and
nutrient-rich.
[Music]
Cucumber peel contains many minerals and
vitamins which help provide nutrients
for the plant and support its growth.
[Music]
Cut the peel of one cucumber into small
pieces.
In addition to the English voiceover,
we've also created versions in French,
German, Italian, Spanish, Portuguese,
Japanese, Hindi, Dutch, Polish, Korean,
and Indonesian to help you listen and
understand the content more easily.
To hear your preferred language, open
the video and click on settings, the
gear icon, to select the appropriate
audio language.
put them into a container and add one
liter of boiling water.
Leave a comment and let me know which
country you're watching from. It's truly
wonderful that we can can connect and
chat from all around the world.
Add 3 tablesp of rice into the
container.
[Music]
Rice, especially rice water, contains
many essential vitamins and minerals for
plant growth, such as nitrogen,
phosphorus, and potassium.
Then wait for the water to cool down
before using it.
After soaking for 30 minutes in the
baking soda solution, we repot the
orchid into a new pot.
Using chopped pine bark for planting
helps retain moisture while still
allowing good air flow for the roots.
[Music]
A new pot is usually larger, giving the
plant more space for root growth, which
in turn improves its overall
development.
[Music]
Once the water has cooled, strain it to
remove any residue.
[Music]
Dilute it with one liter of water to
make a total of 2 L of natural
fertilizer mixture.
Then water your orchid with this mixture
two to three times a month.
[Music]
Watering with this mixture also helps
gently moisturize the growing medium and
orchid leaves while providing natural
enzymes that keep the leaves cleaner,
boost photosynthesis, and make the
orchid flowers more vibrant and
longerlasting.
[Music]
Then soak a soft cotton pad in this
water and gently wipe the entire leaf.
[Music]
Cucumber juice is rich in vitamin C and
minerals which help nourish the leaves
and enhance the overall health of the
plant.
[Music]
Cucumber war has moisturizing properties
helping to soothe the leaves and provide
the necessary hydration for the plant.
Then place it in a spot with plenty of
indirect light so the orchid can
photosynthesize.
[Music]
And here is the result after 3 weeks.
You can see many new healthy roots
growing.
[Music]
New healthy roots help form a better
root network, improving drainage and
arration in the growing medium.
And you can see the leaves have become
greener and stronger.
[Music]
Uh the flowers will last longer, not
only staying fresh, but also blooming
with new ones. A sweet response from
nature to your gentle care.
Uh, what do you think about the way I
revived this little orchid? Feel free to
leave a comment and share your thoughts.
I'd love to hear your feedback and
experiences.
Uh, if you face any difficulties while
growing orchids, don't hesitate to leave
a comment. I'm always here to support
you so you can grow healthy orchids that
bloom beautifully.
Um, other orchids cared for with this
method also have healthy root systems.
[Music]
And the leaves have become glossy green.
Uh, take care of your orchid with all
the love you have for plants because
that very love will bloom through every
green leaf and every vibrant petal.
[Music]
and you'll feel fulfilled as you enjoy
and admire the beautiful orchids grown
by your own hands.
Hope you enjoy this video. If you find
it helpful, don't forget to hit like and
subscribe so you won't miss the next
tips on how to care for orchids
naturally and easily.
[Music]
Um, thank you for joining me today.
Wishing you happiness always with your
beautiful orchids. See you in the next
video.