welcome to my
channel to help you have many options
when caring for orchids at home with
organic fertilizer to help you have many
options when caring for orchids at home
with organic
fertilizer helps develop new choots
flowers bloom profusely and last long in
this video I continue to share new
methods
[Music]
to make this fertilizer I reuse rice
water when cooking
[Music]
rice you can use 200 g of rice like me
or more which is also very good
[Music]
after washing the rice cover tightly and
leave in a cool place for 24 hours
[Music]
next I used about 10 G of fresh
ginger ginger has the ability to
stimulate plant growth helping orchids
grow strongly and produce more leaves
and flowers
[Music]
after mincing soak in 1 liter of boiled
water and place in a cool place for 24
hours
[Music]
24 hours later
only deant the Clear Water
[Music]
above I do not use this cloudy water
first method clean the leaf surface with
this Liquid Fertilizer
[Music]
the leaf surface will always be clean
and the stamata will be clear orchids
will photosynthesize
[Music]
better if applied regularly you will not
encounter this problem
leaves will always be
[Music]
green second method spray this
fertilizer on the entire orchid
[Music]
minerals contained in ginger and
fermented rice water will help stimulate
rooting and shoot growth very
well do this once a month to supplement
nutrition and increase the orcas the
orchid's
resistance third method now take this
liquid fertilizer mixture and water it
on the Orchid roots
[Music]
fertilizer from Ginger and naturally
fermented rice water rice water helps
supplement nutrients and amino acids
that are beneficial for orchid growth
[Music]
especially helps stimulate germination
and rooting extremely
[Music]
quickly 1 month
later Roots begin to sprout
[Music]
after 2
month the fruits grow very healthily
helping the Orchid absorb the most
[Music]
nutrients after the next two months
many buds
[Music]
develop new sprouts grow very strong and
grow quickly
[Music]
after the next 3
months blue many flowers
[Music]
the flower color is more vibrant than
usual the flowers stay on the branches
for a long time before
[Music]
fading um if you find this video
meaningful please share it so more
people know about this
[Music]
video and don't forget to subscribe to
the channel so you don't miss any tips
on my
[Music]
channel if you encounter any
difficulties during the Orchid growing
process don't hesitate to comment I am
always ready to support you so you can
grow healthy orchids and Bloom lots of
flowers uh in addition to the English
dub we've now created dubs in French
German Italian Spanish Portuguese
Japanese Hindi and Indonesian to help
you hear and understand the content
videos are easier um to listen to the
language open the video and click
settings gear icon to select the
appropriate audio language
welcome to my
Channel today I will show you how to
revive a rotten Orchid like
[Music]
this when the orchid has withered all
the leaves and only the stem and Roots
do not rush to throw it away
[Music]
where are you watching the video from
please leave a comment and let me
[Music]
know it's amazing that we can chat
together from all around the
world uh here the branches are still
fresh
my video features voiceovers in six
languages English French German Spanish
Portuguese and Italian additionally I
have subtitles in various other
languages around the world for you to
choose
from I will remove all wilted and rotten
leaves
[Music]
and I remove all the broken
Roots um if you haven't subscribed to
the channel yet please hit the subscribe
button to support
[Music]
me I keep only the fresh roots that are
left
[Music]
over I cut off the flower stock so that
the Orchid can concentrate nutrients for
the new Sprout to grow
rinse with
[Music]
water apply melted candle solution to
the cut to prevent water from seeping
into the tree
[Music]
use three cloves of garlic and
mince soak G garlic and 1 L of water at
room
temperature incubate for one
[Music]
day at the same time spread in a cool
place for one
[Music]
day one day after
filter out
[Music]
residue soak Orchid branches in garlic
water for 20 minutes
[Music]
the rest of the water I will spray on
other orchids to help protect the Orchid
from insects and fungi at the same time
garlic juice also stimulates the
development of roots and Flower sprouts
very well
[Music]
20 minutes after
after soaking for 30 minutes
plant using pine bark or dry pmus Stone
to plant will help absorb moisture in
the roots making the Orchid roots not
[Music]
rot put in a cool place for 1 week
without watering
[Music]
one week
later from now on water the Orchid to
keep it
moist then place it in a place with
light sunlight the best temperature is
20 to 25° C
[Music]
regularly spray moisture to spread life
and revive
faster 2 weeks after
[Music]
use 3 mm of GE Ginger water mixed with 1
liter of water
[Music]
um GE ginger juice is considered an
organic fertilizer that helps to
stimulate plant growth very
[Music]
well water this G Ginger every 10 days
continue to place the plant in a place
with light
sunlight uh cover with a clear vented
plastic container and wait for the plant
to
revive 1 month
later the root system is very welld
developed when the roots are strong like
this you can fertilize the Orchid with
Organic ferti ier like I shared on the
channel uh to help the Orchid grow
healthier hope this sharing content will
help you in resurrecting weak orchids to
grow
again if you find it interesting
remember to like share and subscribe so
that my channel can soon reach 10
million
[Music]
subscribers um the video I have created
many subtitles you you can choose the
appropriate language to understand my
sharing
[Music]