I am very happy to welcome everyone to
my channel where we explore natural
beauty and inspiring plant care methods
together. Today I want to share with you
an interesting way to grow orchids. No
need to water yet the flowers can still
bloom brightly all year round. This is a
simple and creative solution especially
helpful for those who love orchids but
don't have much time to care for them
everyday.
Let's get started. This is a small
orchid that I bought from a local flower
shop. Although the plant is small, it is
growing very healthily and vibrantly.
To apply the method of growing orchids
without watering, the first step is to
remove all the old growing medium,
especially the moss.
Moss retains moisture very well, which
will prevent the plant from growing
properly using this method.
The next step is to cut off any damaged
or dry roots. This is important because
unhealthy roots not only reduce the
plant's ability to absorb neut
nutrients, but can also cause diseases.
Removing them will help the orchid grow
stronger, creating a solid foundation
for growing using the no watering
method.
[Music]
To ensure the orchid doesn't rot during
the growing process, I use baking soda
to treat the cuts on the roots.
Baking soda helps kill bacteria and
fungi, preventing the formation of
pathogens while creating a clean
environment for the roots to grow.
Just half a teaspoon of baking soda is
enough.
Then mix it with.5 L of water.
Um, after preparing the baking soda
solution, soak the orchid in it for
about 10 minutes.
Soaking the plant helps disinfect
effectively, ensuring that the roots are
protected from bacteria and mold before
planting.
This is an important step that helps the
orchid stay healthy and grow well
throughout the care process.
[Music]
Next, I prepare rice to make a natural
fertilizer that helps stimulate the
rapid growth of the orchid after
planting.
Take one tablespoon of rice and soak it
in 0.5 L of water. This mixture will
provide essential nutrients to help the
orchid grow healthily.
Um, it's best to let the mixture soak
for about 10 to 30 minutes. This helps
the nutrients in the rice dissolve into
the water, creating a nutrient-rich
natural fertilizer for the plant.
While waiting, I will recycle plastic
bottle caps to make a no watering orchid
pot.
While waiting, I will recycle plastic
bottle caps to make a no watering orchid
pot.
Uh, this is a great way to combine plant
care and protecting our planet.
Please pay attention and follow along
with me.
Let me know in the comments which
country you're watching this video from.
Um, it's amazing that we can chat
together from all over the world.
And if you haven't subscribed to the
channel yet, click the subscribe button
to support me and never miss any orchid
care tips. It's wonderful to have you as
a companion.
Then we need to wash the plastic bottle
to remove any dirt or impurities left.
This will help ensure a clean growing
environment, allowing the orchid to
thrive without issues related to
bacteria or mold.
In addition to the English voiceover, we
have now created voiceovers in French,
German, Italian, Spanish, Portuguese,
Japanese, Hindi, and Indonesian to help
you listen to and understand the content
more easily.
[Music]
To listen in your preferred language,
open the video and click on settings,
the gear icon to select the audio
language.
[Music]
Then create a hole in in the bottle cap
just like I did.
[Music]
and make a hole in the body of the
plastic bottle just like I
[Music]
After soaking for about 10 minutes, we
stir well to dissolve the rice water
into the liquid.
Then strain out the remaining residue to
keep only the pure rice water solution
ready for watering the orchids.
[Music]
Then take the orchid out and check it
carefully one more time.
[Music]
I noticed a bruise on the leaf, so I
need to cut it off immediately to
prevent it from spreading to the healthy
parts of the plant.
Removing the damaged parts will help the
orchid focus its energy on growing and
keep the entire plant healthy.
[Music]
Then soak the orchid in the rice water
solution for about 10 minutes.
This will help the roots absorb natural
nutrients from the rice, stimulate
recovery, and promote growth after
repotting.
This is a simple but very effective step
to boost the plant's vitality.
[Music]
Uh while waiting, I proceed to make the
wick in preparation for the no water
orchid planting method.
Uh a wick is a string with excellent
water absorption ability, helping to
maintain moisture for the orchid's roots
without the need for direct watering.
Please pay attention and follow my
instructions.
[Music]
When you place the wick in the pot, it
will water from the bottom and provide
it to the plant steadily.
[Music]
Now we will proceed to Plant the orchid
in the no water pot.
[Music]
Before planting the orchid, we need to
soak up any excess water on the leaves
and between the leaf crevices.
Use a soft cloth or paper towel to
gently dry these areas, preventing the
orchid from rotting during the planting
process.
[Music]
When planting the orchid, we connect the
wick to the roots to ensure that water
is drawn up from the bottom of the pot
to the roots.
Then insert the growing medium such as
pine bark chips around the roots to
retain moisture and create space for the
roots to develop.
This growing medium helps the orchid
stay stable and grow strong in the no
water planting environment.
After
planting, we only need to water once to
allow the growing medium and wick to
absorb enough moisture.
Then you only need to change the water
when it becomes dirty. This helps keep
the orchid healthy without the need for
frequent watering while also preventing
root rot.
The wick will act as a bridge, allowing
water to be drawn up from the bottom of
the pot to the roots. This way, the
orchid will always receive the necessary
moisture naturally without the need for
direct watering.
After planting, we wait for about a week
to allow the orchid roots to stabilize
in the new environment.
Once the roots are settled, you can
start fertilizing the orchid to support
its growth.
[Music]
After a week, I start fertilizing the
orchid with rice water.
Take 1 tbsp of rice, then mix it with
one liter of water and stir well.
[Music]
After the rice has soaked, strain the
rice water to use as fertilizer for the
orchid.
Rice water contains many natural
nutrients that help stimulate the growth
of the orchid's roots, leaves, and
flowers.
After preparing the rice water, soak the
orchid pot in this solution for about 20
minutes.
Soaking the plant in rice water allows
the roots to absorb nutrients gradually.
Uh each month you only need to soak the
orchid pot in rice water twice.
Soaking the plant in rice water allows
the roots to absorb nutrients gradually.
This helps maintain healthy growth for
the orchid without the need for frequent
watering.
After soaking the orchid pot in rice
water for 20 minutes, remove the pot and
wait for the rice water to drain
completely before placing the pot into
the water container.
Uh then remove the pot and place it in a
spot with indirect sunlight. Note that
good fertilizer and the right planting
method will only be effective if the
orchid receives enough sunlight.
If there is a lack of sunlight, the
orchid will not grow well and the
fertilizer will not work at its full
potential.
And now let's take a look at the
results. After 2 months,
[Music]
the orchid has grown strong with clean
white roots and shiny green leaves.
[Music]
What do you think about the way I
revived this little orchid? Don't
hesitate to leave a comment and share
your thoughts. I'd love to hear your
feedback and experiences.
If you face any difficulties while
growing your orchid, don't hesitate to
leave a comment. I'm always here to
support you so you can grow healthy
orchids that bloom beautifully.
[Music]
The most wonderful part is that the
flowers have bloomed beautifully full of
vitality.
[Music]
It's hard to believe that with such a
simple and natural method, we can help a
small orchid recover and bloom so
beautifully.
[Music]
I hope you enjoy this video. If you find
it helpful, don't forget to like and
subscribe to the channel so you won't
miss the next tips on how to care for
orchids naturally and simply.
[Music]
I always pray for God's blessings upon
all of you and your loved ones.
[Music]
Hello everyone. Today I will continue
sharing how to care for orchids.
[Music]
After the orchid has finished blooming,
what should we do to help it grow and
bloom continuously?
[Music]
In this video, I will guide you step by
step to ensure your orchids stay healthy
and bloom regularly.
Let's get started.
[Music]
This is the orchid I bought at the
industrial orchid garden.
[Music]
One month after I bought it, all the
flowers fell off.
[Music]
To care for it to continue flowering, I
first need to cut off the old flower
stems.
[Music]
Then I sprinkle coffee over the cut.
Coffee contains some compounds with
antibacterial and antifungal properties,
helping to prevent infection at the cut.
[Music]
This is crucial because cuts on the
plant can provide an opportunity for
bacteria and fungi to enter,
[Music]
then cut off damaged roots.
Uh, cutting off damaged roots helps the
orchid recover quickly, stops the spread
of disease, and saves energy for the
plant.
[Music]
Then leave overnight for the cut to dry
completely.
[Music]
to make fertilizer to take care of this
orchid. I need potatoes.
[Music]
Take about 30 g of potatoes and cut them
into small pieces.
Potatoes contain nutrients like
potassium, phosphorus, and vitamin C,
which help promote the growth of
orchids.
Compounds in potatoes help improve the
development of the root system, allowing
orchids to absorb water and nutrients
more effectively.
[Music]
And then put the chopped potatoes into
the jar.
And to make this fertilizer, I need one
more aloe vera leaf.
[Music]
Aloe vera when used as fertilizer for
orchids provides vitamins, minerals, and
natural enzymes stimulating the growth
of roots and leaves.
Put in jar.
[Music]
Add one liter of water at room
temperature.
Cover and leave overnight.
[Music]
After one night,
Stir well so that the nutrients dissolve
into the water.
Then filter out the residue.
Step one,
water your orchid with this liquid
fertilizer solution.
Aloe vera provides vitamins and natural
enzymes, while potatoes add minerals
like potassium and phosphorus, helping
the orchid grow robustly.
This combination helps encourage the
orchid to bloom regularly and for a
longer period, thanks to the nutrients
that support the blooming process.
After watering, soak the orchid pot in
this water for about 20 minutes.
[Music]
Step two,
you choose this water into a spray
bottle.
Aloe vera and potatoes provide vitamins,
minerals, and enzymes, helping the
orchid absorb nutrients quickly through
its leaves and stem.
[Music]
You spray the solution on the top and
bottom of the leaves.
When sprayed on the leaves, liquid
fertilizer helps orchids absorb
nutrients more easily and enhances the
development of the root system.
Step three,
use soft cotton to wipe the leaves to
help keep them cleaner.
Um, wiping the leaves helps remove dust,
debris, and bacteria from the leaf
surface, allowing the orchid leaves to
breathe better and absorb light more
effectively.
Wiping the leaves helps enhance
photosynthesis because clean leaves
absorb light better and can convert
energy more efficiently.
[Music]
Wiping the leaves with water helps
reduce the risk of mold.
[Music]
um and bacterial diseases because a
clean leaf surface limits the
environment for harmful pathogens to
grow.
[Music]
Step four,
spray the entire orchid again with this
water to help wash away dirt and mold.
[Music]
Step five,
water droplets on the leaves can create
a favorable environment for mold and
bacteria to grow.
[Music]
Wiping off the water helps reduce the
risk of infection.
[Music]
Water droplets can block the stamata on
the leaves, reducing gas exchange and
affecting photosynthesis.
[Music]
Uh, wiping off the water helps the
stamata stay open and function better.
[Music]
Keeping the leaves dry prevents the
orchid from staying wet for too long,
helping to avoid diseases related to
excessive moisture and enhancing its
resistance.
After soaking for 20 minutes, take it
out and place the orchid pot in a place
with plenty of light.
And do the above five steps every 10 to
15 days.
[Music]
results. After 3 weeks,
you can see the orchid's roots and
leaves growing very quickly.
[Music]
Please.
Wow, the roots in the orchid pot are
growing so well.
New roots are a crucial factor in
helping orchids grow healthy and
sustainably throughout their life cycle.
[Music]
That's right.
Now I plant it in a larger pot so the
orchid grows healthier.
As a growing medium, I use crushed pine
bark to help the roots stay airy but
still retain the necessary moisture.
[Music]
Water the orchid to grow.
Take care of your orchids with all the
love and dedication you have for nature.
As every leaf and every flower bud is a
testament to the effort and heart you
put into it.
[Music]
Thank you for watching and supporting my
channel.