Welcome to the happiness garden where we
explore the gentle beauty of nature and
the secrets of orchid care in a simple
yet loving way. Each video is a small
journey that helps you connect more
closely with the world of vibrant petals
and the wonders of greenery.
In this video, I will share with you a
completely new way to make organic
fertilizer that's easy to prepare at
home.
[Music]
This fertilizer not only helps orchids
grow strong from roots to leaves, but
can also stimulate them to bloom all
year round naturally and sustainably.
[Music]
When the orchid has been grown in a pot
for a long time, its roots become dense
and no longer have enough space to
spread. This causes the plant to grow
slowly, makes it difficult for new roots
to emerge, and affects the overall
development of the plant.
Orchid leaves gradually lose their
vibrant green color when they are not
provided with the necessary nutrients.
Instead, they may turn pale yellow,
become dull, or develop unusual spots,
indicating that the plant is weakening.
[Music]
Therefore, after about 1 to two years,
uh we should repot the orchid to allow
the roots to grow more freely and absorb
nutrients more effectively. This is an
important step to help the plant recover
and continue growing healthily.
[Music]
As you can see, due to the cramped space
in the pot, many roots have started to
deteriorate. They are pressed tightly
together, unable to breathe properly,
and gradually rot, directly affecting
the overall health of the plant.
[Music]
after carefully inspecting the root
system, we need to gently cut off all
the damaged, mushy, or brittle roots.
This will help the plant avoid
infections and focus on nourishing the
remaining healthy roots.
In addition to the English voiceover, we
have now created versions in French,
German, Italian, Spanish, Portuguese,
Japanese, Hindi, Dutch, Polish, Korean,
and Indonesian to help you listen and
understand the content more easily.
[Music]
To listen in your preferred language,
open the video and click on settings,
the gear icon, to select the appropriate
audio language.
[Music]
Leave a comment and let me know which
country you're watching the video from.
It's wonderful that we can connect and
chat from all around the world.
[Music]
In addition to treating the roots, we
should also remove the yellowed leaves
to prevent the spread of disease and and
help the plant focus on nourishing the
healthy foliage.
[Music]
We need to completely remove the old
growing medium, especially any remaining
moss and foam from the seedling stage.
These materials retain moisture for too
long, which can easily cause water
logging and root rot if not replaced in
time.
[Music]
If you haven't subscribed to the channel
yet, uh please hit the subscribe button
to support me and never miss any orchid
growing tips. It's truly wonderful to
have you with me.
[Music]
Then prepare about 2 L of water to treat
fungal diseases and clean the growing
medium before replanting.
This step helps eliminate any remaining
bacteria and harmful fungi, creating a
safe environment for new roots to grow.
Next, I prepare a lemon. You can use
either green or yellow lemon. Lemon has
natural antibacterial properties and is
very effective for cleaning the roots
and growing medium before repotting.
[Music]
Take half a lemon and squeeze out the
juice. Then mix it into the water you
prepared earlier.
[Music]
This mixture will gently disinfect and
naturally protect the orchid roots from
harmful fungi.
[Music]
Then pour the lemon water mixture over
the roots and soak them for about 20
minutes.
[Music]
Uh this amount of time is enough for
gentle cleansing, helping to remove
bacteria and harmful fungi from the
roots without damaging the plant.
[Music]
While waiting for the roots to soak, you
can use a soft cloth dipped in the
diluted lemon water mixture to gently
wipe both the upper and lower surfaces
of the leaves.
[Music]
This helps remove dust, bacteria, and
even insect eggs if present, keeping the
leaves clean, healthy, and shiny.
[Music]
When the leaves are clean, the plant
absorbs light more effectively and grows
more vigorously.
[Music]
In addition, diluted lemon water also
helps repel certain small insects like
aphids and mold due to its mild acidity.
This is a safe and natural way to
protect your orchid without harming the
surrounding environment.
[Music]
Next, place the growing medium into the
pot and pour the remaining diluted lemon
water over it to soak for about 20
minutes.
This helps disinfect the growing medium
before planting, removing any remaining
bacteria, mold, and harmful insects.
[Music]
After soaking for about 20 minutes, take
the growing medium out and let it drain.
[Music]
When the growing medium is clean and
slightly dry, go ahead and plant the
orchid into the new pot.
[Music]
When repotting, you should gently
arrange the roots neatly, pointing them
downward. This will help the plant
anchor more easily into the new growing
medium and grow more steadily after
repotting.
[Music]
Gently use your hands to fill the
growing medium around the roots. Make
sure to fill all the gaps without
packing it too tightly so the roots have
enough air and can grow easily.
[Music]
After filling in the growing medium,
gently tap the sides of the pot to help
the medium settle evenly and fill the
gaps between the roots. This helps the
plant stay upright without damaging the
roots.
[Music]
After repotting, we will prepare a
natural fertilizer to help the orchid
recover quickly.
[Music]
First, take one liter of clean water and
pour it into a cup or container. This
will be the base liquid to mix the
natural fertilizer ingredients that will
help the orchid recover.
[Music]
The first ingredient is molasses.
Add about 1 teaspoon of molasses to the
prepared cup of water.
[Music]
Molasses provides a natural source of
energy, helps stimulate beneficial
microorganisms, and supports the plant
in absorbing nutrients more effectively.
[Music]
The second ingredient is fish protein
that has been fermented with probiotics
for over 12 months.
Add about one spoonful of fish protein
to the mixture. This type of fish
protein is rich in nutrients, especially
organic nitrogen and amino acids, which
help the plant recover quickly, develop
strong roots, and grow vigorously.
[Music]
Method one, pour the natural fertilizer
mixture into a spray bottle and shake
gently to mix it well before spraying it
on the orchid.
Then spray directly onto the underside
of the leaves and around the base of the
plant in the early morning or late
afternoon. This method helps the plant
absorb nutrients quickly through the
leaves.
Spraying fertilizer on the leaves
provides nutrients directly through the
leaf surface where the plant can absorb
them quickly.
This is especially effective during the
plant's recovery period after repotting
or when the roots are not yet actively
functioning.
Evenly spraying the entire plant also
helps boost its resistance thanks to the
beneficial microorganisms in the fish
protein and molasses. They support the
plant in fighting off harmful fungi and
pests naturally without the need for
chemicals.
[Music]
Method two, you can use this fertilizer
mixture to water directly at the base of
the plant, allowing it to soak evenly
into the roots and growing medium.
[Music]
When watering, just use about 10
tablespoons of the mixture per orchid
pot. This moderate amount helps the
roots absorb well without becoming water
logged, while also preventing waste of
the natural fertilizer.
[Music]
This method allows the nutrients to
penetrate deeply, nourishing the roots
from within and stimulating the plant to
recover quickly after repotting.
[Music]
You should apply this watering method
about twice a month to give the plant
enough time to absorb the nutrients and
recover.
[Music]
Um, after watering or spraying, use a
soft cloth to gently wipe off any
remaining fertilizer on the surface of
the leaves and in the leaf crevices.
[Music]
This helps keep the leaves dry and well
ventilated, preventing water buildup
that could cause leaf rot or promote
mold growth.
[Music]
When using fish protein fertilizer, you
need to mix it in the correct ratio and
avoid applying it too frequently as the
high nutrient content can cause root
burn or buildup in the growing medium.
Also, it's best to water or spray in the
early morning or late afternoon for
optimal absorption.
[Music]
And don't forget to place the orchid pot
in a spot with gentle cool sunlight.
Soft light in the morning or late
afternoon will help the plant
photosynthesize better without burning
the leaves, supporting its recovery
after repotting.
You can pour the remaining fertilizer
mixture into a spray bottle and use it
to care for other orchid pots in your
garden.
This natural fertilizer mixture is
especially suitable for spraying on
orchids that are in the recovery stage
or about to bloom.
Uh this is when the plant needs plenty
of nutrients to develop roots and store
energy.
[Music]
Uh, this is when the plant needs plenty
of nutrients to develop roots and store
energy.
And here are the orchid pots after 1
month of being cared for with this
natural fertilizer.
You can see that the orchid has
developed many new healthy roots,
proving that the plant is recovering
well and preparing for its next stage of
growth.
This is the result of proper care and
using the right natural fertilizer.
[Music]
Healthy roots help the plant absorb
water and nutrients more effectively
while also boosting its resistance to
pests and adverse environmental
conditions.
[Music]
When the roots are healthy and absorb
enough water and nutrients, the leaves
also become lush green, glossy, and grow
more vigorously. This is a clear sign
that the orchid is in a good growth
state.
[Music]
Healthy roots and leaves are the
important foundation for the orchid to
produce beautiful and long-lasting
flowers.
Uh when the plant has a strong
foundation, the flowers will bloom more
brilliantly and stay on the stem longer.
[Music]
Thanks to good health from the roots and
leaves, orchid flowers can stay on the
stem for up to 6 months before beginning
to fade, bringing lasting beauty to your
space.
[Music]
Um, when the orchid is healthy, it also
produces flowers with more vibrant
colors, thicker petals, and a glossier
appearance. This is a wonderful result
of natural and consistent care.
[Music]
Long lasting blooms not only beautify
your living space, but also show that
the plant is in perfect balance with
nutrition, moisture, and light. A
healthy orchid pot brings joy that lasts
for many months.
What do you think about the way I care
for the little orchids in my garden?
Don't hesitate to leave a comment and
share your thoughts. I'd love to hear
your feedback and experiences.
If you find the content helpful and
meaningful, don't forget to like, share
so more people can see it and subscribe
to support me. Thank you for always
being with me.
[Music]