Hello everyone. Welcome to Happiness
Garden.
Today I will share with you an amazing
tip to help your orchids not only grow
vigorously but also bloom beautifully
all year round.
[Music]
This is a method to make natural, safe,
and effective fertilizer using simple
ingredients from your kitchen.
If you love orchids and want to care for
them properly, let's get started
together.
Uh to make this natural fertilizer, I
first used oranges because they contain
many nutrients that are very good for
orchids.
[Music]
Peel the skin off one orange.
Orange peels are rich in nutrients like
vitamin C, citric acid, and natural
essential oils, which help stimulate
orchid root growth, boost resistance,
and create a favorable environment for
better nutrient absorption.
Put the orange peel into a blender.
Next, I need bananas to make the natural
fertilizer.
[Music]
Banana peels are rich in potassium,
phosphorus, and other essential minerals
which help orchids grow robustly,
stimulate root development, and enhance
flowering.
[Music]
Put the banana peel into a blender.
Add 300 ml of water to the blender.
Which country are you watching this
video from? Leave a comment below to let
me know.
Blend the mixture until smooth and
blend.
Pour the mixture into a jar.
Add 700 ml of water to the mixture.
[Music]
Next, add one teaspoon of baker's yeast
to promote fermentation, creating a
fermented GE mixture that is very
beneficial for orchids.
[Music]
If you haven't subscribed yet, please
hit subscribe to support me and stay
updated with all the new videos from
Happiness Garden.
Then leave it in a cool, well ventilated
place for 3 weeks to create a wonderful
fermented GE mixture for your orchids.
[Music]
After 3 weeks, the GE mixture is ready.
The mixture has a mild, pleasant
beer-like aroma and a white frothy layer
on top, which indicates that it is good
and ready to use.
[Music]
Take two tablespoons about 50 ml of the
mixture.
For this mixture, after opening the lid,
you can store it in the refrigerator for
up to 3 months.
Then dilute it with one liter of water
to create a natural fertilizer that is
very beneficial for your orchids.
[Music]
This is a young orchid plant. You can
propagate it from seeds by using flower
stems or purchase it from e-commerce
platforms.
Uh before transplanting it into a larger
pot, you need to check and remove any
rotten roots and damaged leaves.
Step one, soak the orchid roots in this
mixture for about 10 to 20 minutes.
This helps stimulate the growth of new
roots and allows the orchid to absorb
additional nutrients more effectively.
[Music]
Step two, use a soft cotton ball to soak
the mixture and gently wipe both the top
and bottom sides of the leaves
thoroughly.
Uh this helps remove dust, harmful fungi
and pests from orchids while also
providing nutrition through the leaves.
Step three, transplant it into a larger
pot to allow the orchid to grow better
and faster.
I plant using pine bark to help retain
moisture and provide better irerration
for the orchid roots to grow well.
On top of the orchid pot, I sprinkle a
little moss to help retain moisture and
create a natural environment conducive
to healthy growth.
[Music]
Step four. From now on, water this
mixture for your orchid once every 10
days to provide nutrients through the
roots.
If you haven't subscribed yet, please
hit subscribe to support me and stay
updated with all the new videos from
Happiness Garden.
[Music]
Step five, wipe off any excess mixture
or water that has collected in the
crevices of the leaves to prevent the
orchid from rotting due to overwatering.
[Music]
Then place the orchid pot in a spot with
gentle sunlight to allow photosynthesis,
which will help the orchid grow well.
[Music]
Results. After 10 days,
the orchid has developed many new young
roots, indicating that it is growing
healthily and effectively, absorbing
nutrients from the mixture.
[Music]
Uh when the orchid absorbs sufficient
nutrients and underos photosynthesis
with adequate sunlight, its leaves will
become greener, shinier, and stronger
than before.
Then I continue to water this fertilizer
mixture at the base of the orchid to
help the plant absorb additional
nutrients and grow healthily.
Remember to apply this mixture once
every 10 days. On regular days, if the
growing medium is dry, you only need to
water with plain water.
And then soak this mixture and continue
wiping both the top and bottom sides of
the leaves to remove dust, fungi, pests,
and provide nutrition through the
leaves.
Then I place the orchid pot in a in a
spot with gentle sunlight.
This allows the orchid to
photosynthesize effectively, synthesize
nutrients, and promote the plant's
growth from roots to leaves.
[Music]
results. After the next two months,
the root system has developed stronger
and healthier.
The orchid has developed larger,
thicker, and sturdier leaves.
This demonstrates the incredible
effectiveness of the natural fertilizer,
promoting the orchid's robust and
healthy growth from roots to leaves.
I continue to water this natural
fertilizer mixture on the orchid every
10 days to support its growth and
prepare it for the next stage of bud
development.
I need to clean the leaves by thoroughly
wiping this mixture on both the top and
bottom surfaces to remove dust, insects,
and fungi, ensuring the orchid's health
and protection.
After cleaning the leaves, I will water
this mixture onto the roots to provide
essential nutrients and boost the
orchid's overall health from the base.
After watering the roots with the
mixture, I continue to place the orchid
pot in a spot with gentle sunlight to
allow the plant to photosynthesize
effectively and absorb nutrients
optimally.
[Music]
um results. After the next 3 months,
the orchid has produced three new flower
spikes, which proves that the care and
nutrients have been effective, helping
the plant to thrive and prepare for a
promising new blooming season.
As you can see, the leaves are growing
very well with large thick leaves, which
indicates that the orchid is absorbing
adequate nutrients and is in its
healthiest state to continue growing and
bloom.
With this simple method, you can easily
care for your orchids at home
effectively and achieve amazing results.
[Music]
Uh, I will continue to care for my
orchids using this natural fertilizer
mixture to keep them healthy and
thriving.
Uh, I hope this video provides valuable
information and helps you succeed in
caring for your orchids.
Uh, I hope this video provides valuable
information and helps you succeed in
caring for your orchids.
Uh, if you find this video enjoyable and
helpful, don't forget to hit like,
share, and subscribe to support me and
stay tuned for more videos on Happiness
Garden.
Wishing you all success in caring for
your orchids and having many joyful days
ahead.
Goodbye and see you in the next video.
Hello everyone.
[Music]
Today we will explore how to make
natural fertilizer to help revive and
promote the growth of orchids after they
bloom.
Did you know that proper care will
ensure your orchids bloom beautifully in
the next season?
Let's discover some simple ingredients
and an easy process to keep your orchids
healthy and thriving.
[Music]
Let's get started.
The old orchid branches have all
bloomed.
[Music]
After flowering, orchids often become
weak because they've spent a lot of
energy to bloom. So, we need to restore
them so that they can continue to bloom
strongly the next flowering season.
Cut off all old flower stems.
[Music]
When cutting off old flower branches,
the plant will focus its energy on
growing new branches and leaves, helping
the plant become healthier.
[Music]
Then cut off damaged leaves.
Damaged leaves can harbor bacteria and
fungi. Pruning helps reduce the risk of
spreading disease to the tree.
[Music]
Removing damaged leaves helps the plant
focus its energy on healthy parts,
thereby growing better.
[Music]
Then cut off all damaged roots.
Damaged roots can be a breeding ground
for bacteria and fungi causing harm to
the plant. Excision helps stop the
spread of the disease.
Healthy roots are important for plants
to absorb water and nutrients.
Removing damaged roots helps the plant
focus on growing new and healthier
roots.
From which country are you watching my
video? Please comment for me.
[Music]
Ginger is not only a familiar spice in
the kitchen, but also a miracle medicine
for your orchids.
[Music]
With antibacterial, antifungal, and
growth stimulating properties, ginger
helps orchids restore health, promotes
root and leaf growth while enhancing
resistance to harmful factors.
Uh, take about 10 g of ginger and cut it
into small slices.
My maids. Do you like them?
Then put it in a jar.
[Music]
Add four cups of boiling water, about
one liter.
Close the lid and wait for the water to
cool.
[Music]
Next, I need oatmeal.
Take 3 tablesp of oatmeal.
[Music]
Add four cups of boiling water, about
one liter.
[Music]
Close the lid and wait for the water to
cool.
Two hours later.
[Music]
filter out ginger residue.
Step one, clean the leaves with ginger.
juice.
By wiping the leaves, you help remove
dirt and impurities from the leaf
surface, making it easier for the plant
to photosynthesize.
[Music]
Ginger water contains compounds that are
beneficial to plant health, helping to
enhance growth and recovery.
Ginger has natural antibacterial
properties. Wiping leaves with ginger
juice helps reduce the risk of bacterial
and fungal infections.
[Music]
Come on. Come on.
When leaves are clean, plants are better
able to absorb sunlight, thereby
promoting photosynthesis.
[Music]
Uh then you put this water into a spray
bottle.
[Music]
Step two, spray this water on the entire
orchid.
Spraying ginger water on the leaves
helps increase humidity, especially in
economical conditions, helping the plant
not to wither.
Ginger water helps plants increase their
resistance to harmful agents such as
pests and adverse environments.
Then mix the two types of water together
to form liquid fertilizer.
Uh, ginger and oats both contain many
nutrients necessary for plant growth,
helping the plant recover quickly after
blooming.
[Music]
Step three, water this mixture into each
orchid pot to help supplement nutrients
through the roots very effectively.
[Music]
This mixture helps stimulate the growth
of roots and leaves, creating conditions
for plants to grow healthier.
Compounds in ginger have antibacterial
and antifungal properties, helping to
protect plants from diseases and
increase resistance.
[Music]
The remaining liquid fertilizer you use
to water other orchid pots is also very
good.
[Music]
This will help the orchid grow and bloom
faster.
[Music]
Oats help improve soil structure, retain
moisture better, thereby supporting the
development of the root system.
[Music]
After watering, soak the orchid pot in
this water for about 20 minutes so that
the roots can absorb more nutrients.
[Music]
Soaking orchid pots in this water will
kill insects and fungi in the growing
medium.
Have you found insects crawling out of
orchid pots?
[Music]
After soaking for 20 minutes, take the
orchid pot out and place it in a place
with lots of scattered light.
Scattered light helps plants
photosynthesize effectively without
burning leaves, thereby providing energy
for growth.
On normal days when you see the growing
medium is dry, you just need to water or
spray the orchid with water regularly.
The oat and ginger fertilizer I just
shared should only be applied every 10
to 15 days.
[Music]
Results
after 16 days.
[Music]
Orchids develop many new roots.
New roots help the plant absorb water
and nutrients needed for growth,
especially during the recovery period
after flowering.
[Music]
Healthy roots help orchids be more
resistant to harmful agents such as
pests and harsh environmental
conditions.
[Music]
New root formation often signals that
the plant is in active growth. um which
is important for flowering in the
following season.
[Music]
Healthy roots support leaf growth
thereby helping plants perform
photosynthesis more effectively.
[Music]
Uh, this orchid I fertilized with this
fertilizer has now taken root and is
very healthy.
[Music]
Uh the same thing happens in this potted
orchid. The root system develops to the
point where the leaves are very green
and shiny.
[Music]
Uh, new roots also play an important
role in maintaining moisture for the
plant, preventing it from drying out.
Care for your orchids with passion and
devotion to nature, and you will receive
brilliant flowers, the result of your
own loving hands.
[Music]
Let each flower branch become a symbol
of your care and dedication.
Thank you for taking the time to watch
this video. If you find the information
useful, don't forget to press the
subscribe button and turn on
notifications so you don't miss the next
videos.
Please support our channel by sharing
and leaving your comments below the
video.
Your support is the greatest motivation
for us to continue to bring more
interesting knowledge. Thank you very
much.