[Music]
Welcome to my channel where we share our
passion for orchid care and enjoy the
gentle beauty that nature offers.
You can see this orchid has yellowed
leaves and a rotting base. Many people
think it's dead and quickly throw it
away, but the truth might surprise you.
Now, let's see how I revived this orchid
that seemed beyond hope. You'll witness
a miracle born from the simplest things.
First, I will remove all the yellow
leaves that have been infected by fungus
to prevent the disease from spreading
and to help the plant recover more
easily.
Next, I will cut off the old withered
flower spikes along with the rotting
roots so the plant no longer has to
waste energy on dead parts and can focus
on recovering.
[Music]
After that, I will gently remove all the
infected leaf sheets as this is where
fungi and bacteria often hide and
continue to harm the plant if not
treated in time.
[Music]
Leave a comment and let me know which
country you're watching from. It's
wonderful that we can connect and share
with each other from all around the
world.
To begin the recovery process for the
orchid, I prepare about 20 g of onion, a
familiar kitchen ingredient, but one
that has strong antibacterial properties
and supports the plant's growth from
within.
Then I add about 600 ml of water to
blend with the onion, helping to release
the essential nutrients needed for the
plant's recovery process.
Bulbs and sprouts, especially onions,
contain many essential minerals,
vitamins, and amino acids that play a
vital role in nourishing the roots,
stimulating growth, and boosting the
plant's resistance.
Then place the orchid into this mixture
and soak it for about 20 minutes so the
nutrients can deeply penetrate the
roots, helping to cleanse pathogens and
stimulate a more effective recovery
process.
After soaking for about 20 minutes, take
the orchid out and hang it in a cool,
airy place to let it dry naturally,
which helps prevent fungal infections
uh and creates the best conditions for
the roots to start recovering.
[Music]
While waiting for the plant to dry, I
reuse a used plastic bottle and turn it
into an orchid pot. A simple,
cost-effective, and environmentally
friendly method.
[Music]
If you haven't subscribed yet, please
hit the subscribe button to support me
and never miss any orchid growing tips.
It's truly wonderful to have you along
on this journey.
[Music]
I make an extra drainage hole at a fixed
position so that when growing the orchid
in a semi-hydroponic style, the water
level in the pot stays stable and
doesn't rise too high, which could lead
to root rot.
Then I continue to make several small
holes around the sides of the bottle to
ensure the roots stay well ventilated,
reduce water stagnation, and help the
plant grow more healthily.
[Music]
Uh with just a few simple steps, you now
have a convenient recycled orchid pot
that saves money and also helps protect
the environment.
I use crushed pine bark to grow orchids.
It's an ideal growing medium because it
retains moisture well, drains quickly,
and provides a well ventilated
environment for healthy root
development.
[Music]
I use clear plastic wrap to create a
sealed cover like a mini greenhouse.
This method helps retain moisture and
maintain a stable temperature, creating
ideal conditions for the orchid to
recover more quickly.
[Music]
After planting, you can reuse the onion
juice mixture used for soaking to
lightly water the roots and growing
medium. This helps with antibacterial
protection, stimulates root growth, and
boosts the orchid's ability to recover.
[Music]
After watering, soak the plant for about
5 minutes. Then you should discard the
excess onion water to avoid water
accumulation in the pot, which helps
reduce the risk of mold and root rot.
[Music]
You only need to mist with clean water
about once every 5 days, just enough to
maintain light humidity for the plant
without soaking the growing medium,
allowing the orchid roots to develop in
a well ventilated environment.
Place the orchid pot in a cool spot with
gentle light and good airflow. Now, all
you need is patience. The orchid will
gradually recover and soon return to its
healthy state.
And here is the result after 3 weeks.
[Music]
When the orchid loses its crown, meaning
the main growing tip is no longer
present, the plant immediately activates
its regeneration mechanism by developing
a new growth point. And those are
exactly the two young shoots you see
here.
Continue
misting with clean water every 5 days to
maintain gentle humidity, creating ideal
conditions for the roots and new shoots
to grow strong and healthy.
[Music]
And here is the result after 3 months.
From an orchid that seemed beyond
saving, it has now made a strong
comeback with two baby orchids growing
from the mother stem, each with healthy
roots and vibrant green leaves full of
life.
[Music]
From now on, to help the orchid continue
growing healthily, I use unsweetened
fresh milk. As a natural care method, it
not only provides nutrients, but also
helps boost the plant's resistance.
[Music]
I mix one spoon of unsweetened fresh
milk with two spoons of clean water to
create a diluted solution that is easy
for the orchid to absorb and safe for
its roots when applied.
[Music]
I use a cotton ball soaked in the
diluted milk solution and gently wipe
both the top and underside of the
leaves. This method not only helps clean
off dust but also supports the removal
of insects, fungi, and harmful bacteria
on the leaf surface.
When the stamata on the leaf surface are
cleaned, they open up, allowing the
orchid to photosynthesize more
effectively. As a result, the plant
absorbs nutrients better and the leaves
become healthier, greener, and full of
vitality.
Uh, I hope this video content provides
you with helpful knowledge making orchid
care at home easier and more effective.
I hope you'll enjoy this video. If you
find it helpful, don't forget to like
and subscribe to the channel so you
won't miss miss upcoming tips on natural
and simple orchid care.
Don't forget to turn on the notification
bell so you won't miss future videos
where I'll continue sharing many helpful
and natural tips for easy orchid care at
home.
Thank you for watching until the end of
the video. Wishing you joy, patience,
and success on your journey of caring
for your beloved orchids. See you in the
next videos. Goodbye.
[Music]
Welcome to the little garden full of
joy. Let's explore the beauty of
orchids.
If your orchids become weak or fail to
bloom due to improper care, don't worry.
Improve their environment, provide
proper nutrition, and adjust watering.
With patience, they will recover and
bloom again.
Let's get started.
This is an orchid infected with leaf rot
caused by a fungus.
[Music]
We need to separate the diseased plant
from other orchids.
Now I will share how to restore this
this rotten orchid with only one leaf
left.
[Music]
cut off all damaged roots.
If you haven't subscribed to the channel
yet, please click the subscribe button
to support me and not miss any orchid
growing tips. It's great to have
company.
[Music]
Leave fresh roots like this.
Then rinse with water.
[Music]
In addition to the English dub, we've
now created dubs in French, German,
Spanish, Spanish, Portuguese, Japanese,
Hindi, and Indonesian to help you hear
and understand the content more easily.
[Music]
Oh, this leaf also falls.
Watch me restore this leafless orchid.
[Music]
Cut off all rotten parts of the orchid
stem.
This will help prevent the orchid stem
from rotting further.
[Music]
Then sprinkle cinnamon powder on the cut
to help the wound heal quickly.
[Music]
Cinnamon powder has very good
antibacterial and antiseptic properties.
[Music]
Then place in a cool place for 2 hours
to let the cut dry completely.
[Music]
Take one clove of garlic and mince it.
Garlic contains allisonin, a substance
with powerful antibacterial and
antifungal effects. Helps prevent
diseases and infections in orchids.
[Music]
Add 500 ml of water at room temperature.
Cover and leave for 2 hours so that the
garlic's nutrients are completely
dissolved in the water.
[Music]
After 2 hours, filter out the residue to
get garlic juice.
[Music]
After seeing that the cut has dried,
soak the orchid roots in garlic water
for 10 minutes.
[Music]
This helps to disinfect the orchid,
preventing rot while also stimulating
its growth and quick recovery.
[Music]
After soaking for 10 minutes, take the
orchid out and plant it in a new pot to
help it help it recover and grow faster.
[Music]
Use sterilized dry moss to grow plants.
Dry moss will absorb moisture and help
the cut heal completely.
[Music]
Then leave it in a cool place and do not
water it for 1 week to let the cut heal
completely.
This garlic water is used to water other
orchids in the garden.
[Music]
Nutrients found in garlic, such as
calcium, potassium, and selenium, help
stimulate the growth of orchid roots,
helping the plant recover quickly.
[Music]
Do this every two weeks to increase the
orchid's resistance and supplement
nutrients for the orchid.
[Music]
Garlic also has the effect of repelling
insects. So, it helps protect plant
leaves.
[Music]
After one week, we start watering the
orchids again.
[Music]
Then use recycled plastic bottles to
create a miniature greenhouse to grow
orchids.
[Music]
Spray water every time the growing
medium and orchid are dry.
[Music]
Cover and place in a cool, well-lit
place.
[Music]
Results after one month.
You can see a new baby orchid being
revived from the trunk of an old dying
orchid.
New roots also grow a lot, which will
help the baby orchids grow faster.
From a bare orchid stem, an extremely
healthy baby orchid has now been
revived.
[Music]
When the root system is strong, we
fertilize it to help the orchid grow
faster.
[Music]
Take 1/2 teaspoon of flour.
Add 500 ml of room temperature water,
about 2 cups.
Using wheat flour helps stimulate the
growth of beneficial microorganisms in
orchid pots, helping increase the
plant's ability to absorb water and
nutrients.
Wait 1 hour before using to fertilize
orchids.
[Music]
One hour later.
Filter out residue.
[Music]
Then water this mixture every 2 weeks.
Continue
[Music]
[Applause]
to cover and place in a cool place with
enough light.
[Music]
results after 2 months.
>> Uh the baby orchids have grown and
developed very healthily.
[Music]
The root system grows very healthy.
Leaves are green and sturdy.
[Music]
Continue using fertilizer from wheat
flour to water the orchids.
[Music]
Wheat flour contains a lot of
carbohydrates which serves as food for
beneficial microorganisms in the soil or
orchid growing medium.
[Music]
Um these microorganisms help improve
soil structure, enhance the ability to
decompose organic substances and help
plants absorb nutrients better.
[Music]
results. After 3 months,
the orchid has grown stronger and
produced buds.
[Music]
growing roots help the orchid absorb
nutrients best.
[Music]
The leaves are green and strong.
This leaf has a rot disease, so it must
be removed immediately.
[Music]
Continue
to use wheat flour fertilizer to water
the orchids every 2 weeks.
[Music]
Results after 4 months.
from the bare orchid stem. It has now
revived and grown into a mature orchid.
[Music]
The flowers bloom brightly and
beautifully.
[Music]
If you find the video meaningful, please
like and share so more people know.
[Music]
And don't forget to subscribe to the
channel to help my channel reach 10
million subscriptions soon.
[Music]
Thank you for watching and supporting my
channel.
[Music]
Wishing you success and joy in life.
Goodbye and see you again in the next
videos.