Welcome to my
channel. If you have a wilted orchid
like this, don't rush to throw it
[Music]
away. Um, now I share how to recover
quickly with natural fertilizers.
[Music]
Please remove inorganic fertilizers and
damaged roots.
[Music]
Because the roots do not rot, I keep the
old planting material to help the orchid
recover
[Music]
quickly and remove all yellow and rotten
leaves.
[Music]
Which country are you watching videos
from? Please comment for me.
[Music]
Uh, it's great that we can chat together
from all over the world.
[Music]
If you haven't subscribed yet, please
subscribe to support me and to not miss
any orchid growing tips.
[Music]
Now you need to soak the entire orchid
in water at room temperature for 1 hour.
This helps to quickly restore wilted
roots and
leaves. Awaken the ability of fresh
roots and leaves to absorb
[Music]
water. Place in a cool place for 1 hour.
Now you take 1/3 teaspoon of sugar.
[Music]
mix with 500 mm of water at room
temperature.
[Music]
Then take 500 ml of warm
water. Add 1 teaspoon of dry yeast.
Yeast used to make bread.
[Music]
Wait 1 hour for the yeast to develop
before using it as
fertilizer. After soaking for 1 hour,
take the orchid out.
[Music]
Then soak the leaves in sugar water for
30 minutes.
[Music]
After soaking for 30 minutes, take the
orchid out.
[Music]
Nutrients and sugar penetrate the
leaves, helping wilted leaves recover
[Music]
quickly. Now mix the sugar water with
the dry yeast solution.
[Music]
Uh this will create a natural fertilizer
that will stimulate strong rooting and
plant recovery.
[Music]
Soak the orchid root in this water for
30 minutes will help stimulate rooting
extremely quickly.
[Music]
The remaining liquid fertilizer is used
to water orchid pots.
[Music]
Water each orchid pot with 10
tablespoons. This fertilizer helps
stimulate root growth. A strong root
system will help the orchid absorb
nutrients best.
[Music]
Doing this one to two times a month will
be very good for the orchid.
[Music]
Water the orchid roots with this
microbial fertilizer solution.
Beneficial microorganisms will grow in
the orchid pot. Helps protect orchid
roots from rot caused by fungi and
[Music]
bacteria. This type of fertilizer also
helps balance the pH level in orchid
pots. help stimulate orchid roots to
grow and not be damaged by
[Music]
acid. After soaking for 30 minutes, take
the orchid out.
[Music]
The roots have become juicier and
greener. I use pine bark to grow
orchids.
[Music]
Cover the surface of the orchid pot with
a little moss.
helps retain moisture
[Music]
better. Then apply this microbial
fertilizer to the orchids every 2
weeks. Uh we'll create beneficial
organisms in the growing environment and
stimulate orchid roots.
Uh on weekdays you just need to spray
mist to keep it moist and water when the
substrate is
[Music]
dry. Then place the orchid pot in a cool
place with enough light for the orchid
to recover.
[Music]
results after one
month. After only one month, orchid
roots have grown a lot and are healthy.
[Music]
Um, these new roots will help the orchid
absorb nutrients and water
[Music]
best. And gradually the leaves will
become fresh again.
[Music]
Take 1/5 teaspoon of sugar.
[Applause]
[Music]
and take 1/5 teaspoon of dry
yeast. Mix with 300 mm warm water.
[Music]
and wait until the water cools to room
temperature. Then use this microbial
fertilizer to water every 2 weeks.
[Music]
This type of fertilizer is especially
good for weak, stunted orchids with
underdeveloped roots because it does not
shock weak orchids like chemical
[Music]
fertilizers. Um, placing it in a place
with light sunlight will be best for
orchids.
After the next one month,
um the orchid has completely recovered.
[Music]
The leaves are normal green and thick.
The roots are very fat and have many new
roots.
[Music]
Hope the video will help you a
lot. If you find it interesting, please
like, share, and subscribe to my support
channel. Thank you for
watching. Good luck and see you in the
next videos.