welcome to my
channnel when you buy an orchid or
someone gives it to
[Music]
you um you need to do the following
leave the Orchid in a cool place for a
few hours to let it adapt to the new
climate if you haven't subscribed to the
channel yet uh please support me by
pressing the Subscribe button and
ringing the bell to stay updated and not
miss any Orchid growing
tips if the growing medium is moss or
small wood chips it is is only suitable
for industrial Orchid
[Music]
Gardens because Moss retains a lot of
moisture many plant roots rot due to
water
[Music]
logging which country are you watching
videos from please comment for
[Music]
me it's it's great that we can chat
together from all over the
world the humidity was too high so the
leaves were also infected with black
mold
[Music]
uh therefore you need to remove all Moss
or old growing
[Music]
medium because this type of substrate is
only suitable for industrial Orchid
Gardens that can control special
humidity
[Music]
then you cut off all day damaged
roots in addition to the English
voiceover my channel also offers
voiceovers in French German Italian
Spanish and
Portuguese you can go to the settings to
choose the voiceover in the language
that suits
[Music]
you how to select the audio language on
YouTube One open the video and click on
settings the gear icon two select
subtitles CC three click on audio and
choose the language you want English
France Deutch Italiano espanol or
Portuguese then you cut off all damaged
roots
[Music]
then you take one aloe vera leaf
and take a clove of garlic
[Music]
put all the aloe vera and garlic in a
jar and soak it with 2 L of
[Music]
water put all the aloe vera and garlic
in a jar and soak it with 2 L of water
[Music]
30 minutes
later soak the roots in this solution
for 30
[Music]
minutes garlic and aloe vera help
stimulate root growth and effectively
fight harmful insects and fungi
[Music]
spraying this Solution on the entire
Orchid will help repel insects eliminate
fungal diseases and keep the leaves
green
[Music]
then clean the black mold stains with
this
[Music]
solution uh this helps prevent orchids
from recurring mold for
[Music]
now I recycle used plastic containers to
make Orchid pots
[Music]
I put a layer of pmus on the bottom of
the Orchid
[Applause]
[Music]
pot this helps keep the bottom of the
Orchid pot clear so the roots don't get
water logged
[Music]
for the top I use dried Pine bark as a
growing
[Music]
medium and mix in some dry moss
when planting cushion the substrate
tightly so that the roots do not move
[Music]
insert the Flower Branch into the right
position to help prevent the Orchid from
shaking
[Music]
after planting let it dry for 5 days
before
watering that is the wonderful thing I
want to share with you in part one of
the video and don't rush to leave the
video because part two will make it more
interesting for you with how to care for
orchids to help them bloom all year
round
[Music]
welcome to part two of this video on
Happy Garden Channel happiness Garden
Channel specializes in Sharing tips for
caring for orchids using natural
fertilizers promoting sustainable growth
abundant blooms and Environmental
Protection if you love orchids as much
as I do subscribe to my channel to
support me and never miss any
tips today I'm sharing how to make a
natural fertilizer from garlic that's
both simple and effective for your
orchids
[Music]
I just need a clove of
garlic garlic promotes harmonious growth
and Lush long- lasting flowering of
[Music]
orchids it repels most pests and kill
spores of fungi viruses and bacteria
[Music]
substances in garlic water strengthen
the immune system of
[Music]
orchids I pour crushed garlic with 1
liter of hot water
[Music]
and this is turmeric powder with rich in
vitamins and minerals potassium calcium
magnesium sodium phosphorus iron
manganese copper selenium and zinc
increases plant resistance to fungi and
diseases while stimulating growth and
flowering
[Music]
uh incubate until the water cools so
that the nutrients from the garlic and
turmeric starch are completely dissolved
in the water
[Music]
after the water cools we filter it to
remove sediment
[Music]
fertilizer for orchids must be carefully
filtered so that organic fragments do
not rot in the
substrate guys please write a comment
letting me know which country you're
watching my video from the of
fence it's great to know that we can
communicate
worldwide for
[Music]
uh to know if it's time to water orchids
I look at the color of the
roots when the Orchid Roots have a light
silver color it's time to water the
Orchid
if the roots are bright green you should
wait until the roots turn pale silver
before
[Music]
watering if you water when the roots are
still green The Roots will easily become
water logged and cause root rot
[Music]
My Maids are tired and
sleeping and the cat seems to be hunting
down the that are destroying my
orchids orchids grown in pots with
drainage
holes I water this one to two times a
month soak the roots in this water for
about 20 minutes to help the roots
absorb nutrients
best um the finished infusion for
orchids helps strengthen the immune
system promotes the development of the
root system
[Music]
this water is also very good when
sprayed on
Orchids spraying your Orchids with
garlic and turmeric water will protect
them from
diseases pests and boost their immune
system
[Music]
spray the entire Orchid from leaves to
Roots but you should not water the
flowers because wet flowers will quickly
fall off
do it one to two times a
month if you have a very humid climate
orchids are susceptible to Leaf base
rot to prevent orchids from rotting at
the base of the leaves you can use
cotton balls to protect them
[Music]
now spray the cotton with garlic and
turmeric
water and spray it on your orchids to
protect them from diseases pests and
boost the immune system
leave the cotton there for 20 minutes
then remove it
[Music]
then you take the Clear Water above
if you don't have access to spraying
orchids you can wipe the leaves with a
cotton pad soaked in this
[Music]
water will help remove mineral salts
still attached to the leaf
[Music]
surface helps orchid leaves avoid
burning when exposed to the
sunlight uh this not only clears the
dust but also provides them with
nutrients and protects them from
diseases and
pests thoroughly wipe both the top and
bottom of the leaf
do this one or two times a
[Music]
month uh it is enough to keep the Orchid
in this water for 20 minutes
[Music]
soaked in this water The Roots will
change from Silver to purple blue like
this
[Music]
then place the Orchid pot in a warm
place with lots of diffused light so the
Orchid will grow quickly
[Music]
after 20 minutes remove the cotton ball
and place the Orchid pot in a warm place
with lots of diffused
[Music]
light
result um the leaves are always green
and shiny like this
the roots are green large and
healthy thanks to the clean Leaf surface
orchid leaves photosynthesize
[Music]
better when orchids have enough light
for photosynthesis they will always be
healthier than
usual thanks to this care the Orchid
produces many
[Music]
flowers vibrant flower colors
orchids bloom all year round flowering
very long and
[Music]
boldly hope you like this video
thank you for viewing good luck and
success in life
[Music]