Welcome to the happiness
garden. In this video, I continue to
share a new method for making organic
fertilizer for orchids. It helps orchids
grow comprehensively and bloom
[Music]
abundantly. Let's get started.
To make this fertilizer, I need
tobacco. Only one cigarette is
[Music]
enough. Tobacco contains nicotine, which
has antifungal effects, helping protect
plants from some fungal diseases.
[Music]
Nicotine has insecttoidal effects. It
can cause suffocation or paralysis in
insects upon
[Music]
contact. The smell of tobacco makes some
insects like aphids and thris avoid
coming near the plant.
[Music]
Leave a comment to let me know which
country you're watching the video from.
It's wonderful that we can chat with
each other from all around the
[Music]
world. Put the tobacco into the
jar. Then add one liter of boiling
water.
[Music]
Next, we need a
banana. Any type of banana can be used
to make natural
[Music]
fertilizer. Take one ripe banana and cut
it into thin slices.
[Music]
Bananas are rich in potassium and
phosphorus, which are important
nutrients that help orchids grow well,
bloom, root, and increase resistance.
[Music]
Then soak the banana in the previously
prepared tobacco water.
[Music]
Then close the lid, let it sit, and wait
for the water to
cool. After 2 hours, the water has
cooled.
[Music]
Strain this water.
Dilute with one liter of water.
method
one. When the roots turn silvery white
like this, water the orchid with this
liquid fertilizer solution.
[Music]
Bananas also provide organic matter and
enzymes that help improve soil fertility
and the growth of beneficial
microorganisms.
[Music]
Uh, the tobacco soaking water has
antifungal properties and repels
insects, helping protect the plant roots
from
[Music]
diseases. Water the orchid with this
liquid fertilizer one, two, two times
per month.
or combine it with other organic
fertilizers as I have shared on the
channel.
Your orchid will absorb more
[Music]
nutrients. Soak the orchid pot in this
water for about 20 minutes so the roots
can absorb more nutrients and be
protected from fungal diseases.
Method
two, use a soft cotton ball to soak up
this liquid fertilizer solution. Then
gently wipe it onto the
leaves. Wipe thoroughly on both the top
and bottom surfaces of the leaves.
Uh, wiping the leaves helps remove dust
and enhances photosynthesis, allowing
the plant to absorb light
better. Uh, the combination of tobacco
and banana helps stimulate the plant's
natural immune system, helping to fight
diseases and insects.
[Music]
A wiping provides some micronutrients
and can support plant health.
[Music]
Doing this one to two times a month will
be very good for your orchid.
Method three,
um, if you have a large number of orchid
pots, you can put the solution into a
spray bottle and spray the entire orchid
plants.
Spray thoroughly on both the top and
bottom sides of the leaves.
[Music]
Spray on the aerial roots and on the
orchid growing
medium. This method is similar to using
folure fertilizer and base
watering, but you should not spray it on
the flowers.
[Music]
Because when flowers get wet, they tend
to wilt and drop their petals.
[Music]
After soaking for 20 minutes, uh, take
the orchid pot out and place it in a
spot with plenty of diffused light so
the orchid can photosynthesize.
[Music]
I continue to recycle the banana peel
and tobacco ashes into fertilizer for
the next
[Music]
time. Put it into a glass jar.
Then add one teaspoon of yeast.
[Music]
stir well.
Close the bottle and place it in a cool
place. After 3 weeks, you will have GE
fertilizer that is very good for orchids
to
[Music]
bloom. The result after 3 weeks.
Even the weakest orchid species has
developed very strong roots.
[Music]
The potassium content helps the orchids
bloom more and
[Music]
more. The flowers on the branch last a
long time before wilting.
[Music]
orchid flowers can be kept on the branch
for up to 6 months before the petals
wilt.
Take care of your orchid with all the
love you have for plants and you will be
rewarded with the enchanting fragrance
and the wonderful beauty of the orchid
flowers.
I hope you will like the video. Please
leave me a
[Music]
comment. If you haven't subscribed yet,
please subscribe to support me.
Thank you all for watching the
video. May God always bless
[Music]
you. Wishing you luck and success in
life.
[Music]