Welcome to my
garden. Today I continue sharing how to
revive weak orchids after blooming using
natural fertilizer, helping them keep
growing and bloom vigorously in the next
flowering
season. This is the orchid after it has
finished blooming for the previous
season. It continues to produce new buds
from the old flower spike, but the plant
has become weakened.
[Music]
Its leaves became soft and wilted,
looking so pitiful. That's why I bought
this orchid from a local orchid shop at
a negligible clearance price to bring it
home and revive
it. First, I need to remove the old
plastic pot to check the root system and
repot the
orchid. We need to check if the roots
are damaged by gently squeezing them.
If the roots feel firm, they are still
healthy. But if they are soft, it means
they have rotted and need to be removed
[Music]
immediately. We only cut off the damaged
roots while keeping the healthy ones.
[Music]
I found that only a few roots are
damaged and need to be removed. Most of
the roots are still healthy.
[Music]
Uh by cutting off the rotting, decayed
or damaged roots, you help stop the
spread of diseases and prevent the plant
from getting infected with fungi or
bacteria.
Moreover, this helps the plant focus its
energy on developing new roots, thereby
improving its ability to absorb water
and nutrients.
[Music]
Next, trim off the damaged leaves to
help the orchid avoid the spread of
diseases, mold, and
bacteria. Damaged or rotten leaves will
reduce the plant's ability to
photosynthesize, affecting its growth
and overall health.
By removing them, the plant will focus
its energy on nourishing the healthier
parts, helping it grow stronger and
better able to withstand external
factors. Next, trim off the wilted
flower spikes that no longer have the
ability to bloom. This helps the orchid
save energy and nutrients without having
to nourish the ineffective flower
spikes.
This will stimulate the plant to develop
new flower buds in the next season.
Additionally, removing the wilted flower
spikes also helps the orchid stay neat
and reduces the risk of disease.
[Music]
After removing the damaged parts of the
plant, you can use aloe vera to help
revive the wilted
orchid. Aloe vera has soothing and
antibacterial properties which help
protect the cuts and promote the healing
process. Additionally, aloe vera gel
retains moisture well, helping the
wilted orchid recover quickly.
You just need to cut a fresh aloe vera
leaf, extract the gel inside, and apply
it to the cuts on the plant and the
wilted leaves. This will help the orchid
recover quickly, reduce stress, and
encourage new growth.
Please leave a comment letting me know
which country you're watching from. It's
amazing that we can chat together from
all around the world.
You can apply aloe vera gel to the
wilted leaves every 2 days depending on
the plant's condition. If the orchid is
recovering well, you can reduce the
frequency to once every 5 days.
After applying the aloe vera gel to the
plant, you can put the remaining part of
the aloe vera leaf into a blender. Add
about 0.3 L of water and blend it until
smooth. If you haven't subscribed yet,
please hit the subscribe button to
support me and never miss any orchid
care tips. It's wonderful to have you as
a companion on this journey.
[Music]
[Applause]
Uh after blending, you should strain out
the pulp as the residue in the aloe vera
gel can clog the root system or make it
difficult for the plant to absorb
nutrients from the water.
Straining the pulp will make the
solution smooth, easy to absorb, and
safe for the plant. This also helps
prevent leaves and roots from getting
clogged with insoluble substances,
allowing the orchid to recover more
effectively. After straining the pulp,
you can dilute the aloe vera solution
with one liter of water. Diluting it
makes the solution gentler, ensuring it
doesn't harm the orchid.
After diluting the aloe vera solution,
soak the orchid's roots in this mixture
for about 15 to 20 minutes.
Soaking the roots helps the plant absorb
nutrients from the aloe vera while also
enhancing its ability to recover and
develop new
roots. Note that you shouldn't soak the
roots for too long as it could harm
them.
After soaking the roots, you can use a
soft cloth to soak up the aloe vera
solution and gently wipe both the top
and bottom of the orchid's leaves,
especially the wilted ones.
Uh this helps provide nutrients to the
leaves while also cleaning the leaf
surface, making it easier for the plant
to absorb the nutrients from the aloe
vera
[Music]
gel. And this helps provide nutrients to
the leaves while also cleaning the leaf
surface, allowing the plant to easily
absorb the nutrients from the aloe vera
gel.
[Music]
After wiping the leaves, take the
remaining aloe vera solution and put
into a spray bottle. Gently spray it on
the other orchids in your garden. It
will be very beneficial for them as
well. This misting will help provide
consistent moisture to the plant while
delivering aloe vera nutrients to every
part of the orchid.
Spray a light mist avoiding overwetting
to prevent the plant from rotting or
becoming water logged. This is a great
way to help the orchid recover and grow
healthily.
Applying this once a week is
[Music]
enough. After misting the entire plant,
continue watering the orchid's roots
with the aloe vera
solution. Gently water around the base
and roots of the plant, ensuring that
the mixture is evenly absorbed into the
roots.
This helps provide additional nutrients
to the roots and stimulates the healthy
growth of the plant.
[Music]
You should also apply this once a week
and avoid overwatering to prevent the
plant from becoming water logged,
especially if the orchid hasn't fully
recovered yet.
[Music]
After watering, you should use a soft
cloth to gently blot off any water
droplets remaining on the leaves and in
between the leaf
[Music]
joints. This helps prevent leaf rot and
reduces the growth of mold, especially
in damp areas like the spaces between
the leaves.
Gently blotting the water helps prevent
excess moisture, ensuring the orchid's
leaves dry and stay more
ventilated. By following these steps for
your orchid, you'll notice the leaves
will stay vibrant, strong, and healthy.
The plant will grow better, absorb light
more easily, and provide energy for
photosynthesis. This is a great way to
care for your orchid, helping it stay
fresh and
strong. After soaking the wilted orchid
roots in the aloe vera solution for
about 20 minutes, I proceed to plant the
orchid in a new
pot. After soaking the wilted orchid
roots in the aloe vera solution for
about 20 minutes, I proceed to plant the
orchid in a new
pot. When planting, carefully place the
orchid in the center of the pot,
adjusting the roots so that they are
comfortable and not bent. Then, gently
cover the roots with the growing medium
to keep the plant stable in the pot.
After planting the orchid, I take some
moss and spread it evenly around the rim
of the
pot. The moss will help retain moisture
for the plant while creating a natural
layer that keeps the growing medium
stable.
Additionally, the moss helps minimize
rapid water evaporation, maintaining
moisture for the plant and creating a
cool environment that aids in faster
recovery and better
growth. After planting the orchid, you
should place it in a well ventilated
area and avoid watering for 1 day,
allowing the cut to dry and heal
quickly.
Next, you can take one tablespoon of
rice to make fertilizer for the weak
orchid. Rice contains many nutrients
such as starch and vitamins, which help
provide energy to the plant, especially
during the recovery phase.
Uh place the rice in one liter of room
temperature water and soak it for 1 day
to allow the nutrients to dissolve into
the water. Then use this solution to
water the orchid.
[Music]
Uh the the natural fertilizer from rice
helps the plant develop strong roots,
allowing the wilted orchid to recover
quickly and regain its vitality.
After soaking the rice for one day,
filter out the rice
water. Rice water contains many
beneficial nutrients for the plant, such
as vitamin B and minerals, which help
stimulate the growth of the orchid's
roots and leaves.
After filtering, I use this rice water
to gently water around the base of the
plant, helping the orchid recover and
grow
better. However, make sure the orchid
pot has drainage holes to prevent water
logging, which can lead to root rot.
You only need to water the orchid with
rice water once a
week. Then take this mixture and put it
into a spray bottle, gently spraying it
on the wilted
orchid. Spraying mist helps provide
nutrients to the leaves and stimulates
the plant's recovery. Specifically,
spraying on the leaves helps retain
moisture and nourish the
plant. Uh, make sure to spray a light
layer and avoid overspraying to prevent
the plant from becoming too
wet. Applying this method once a week
will help the orchid recover and grow
stronger.
After spraying the rice water on the
orchid, you should gently blot the
excess water on the leaves and in
between the leaf joints with a soft
cloth. This helps prevent water from
accumulating, which could lead to rot or
mold. This helps prevent leaf rot and
mold, especially in damp areas like the
leaf joints. Gently blotting the water
allows the leaves to dry off, ensuring
good air flow while preventing excess
moisture that could harm the
plant. After completing all the care
steps, you should you should place the
orchid pot in a location with gentle
sunlight, avoiding direct harsh sunlight
as it can cause the leaves to
burn. Now, let's take a look at the
results after 10 days of recovery and
see how it turned out.
As you can see, the orchid has started
to
bloom. The fact that the flowers are
blooming again is a clear sign that the
plant has received enough nutrients and
is is in the right environment to
thrive. As you can see, the leaves of
the orchid have become lush again, and
there are no more signs of wilting as
before. This is clear evidence that the
plant has recovered very well after the
care process.
[Music]
When the leaves are fresh and strong
again, it not only helps the plant
absorb light effectively, but also
protects it from harmful
elements. With the recovery method,
using natural fertilizers from aloe vera
and rice, my orchid will surely grow
strong and continue to bloom in the
upcoming period.
And this is also a wilted orchid I had
revived earlier. Now after 3 months, it
has fully
recovered. After blooming, it is now
continuing to produce many new flower
spikes.
[Music]
Uh, with this simple method, you can
absolutely take care of your orchids at
home using a natural fertilizer made
from familiar, easy to find ingredients
right in your own kitchen.
Uh, I hope this video brings you lots of
helpful tips and inspiration to take
even better care of your
[Music]
orchids. Take care of your orchid with
all the love you have for plants. And
you will be rewarded with vibrant blooms
that brighten up your garden, bringing
you daily relaxation and
joy. Thank you for watching the video. I
wish you a wonderful day and hope to see
you in the next videos. Goodbye and see
you soon.