Hello everyone. Today, to give you more
options for caring for orchids right at
home and to help the plants grow healthy
and bloom all year round, I will
continue to share how to make natural
fertilizer from familiar ingredients in
your kitchen.
And if you haven't subscribed to the
channel yet, please click the subscribe
button to support me and not miss any
orchid care tips. It's wonderful to have
you along.
Now, let's start exploring together to
see how simple ingredients in the
kitchen can turn into a secret for
growing healthy orchids and making them
bloom brilliantly.
To make the fertilizer, you only need
two bananas. And when you eat the
bananas, don't rush to throw away the
peels. Keep them to turn into natural
fertilizer, helping your orchids grow
healthy and bloom brilliantly.
Banana peels contain many beneficial
nutrients that help plants grow
stronger. They are rich in potassium,
calcium, magnesium along with other
trace minerals which help improve root
health and stimulate the blooming
process of orchids.
The potassium in banana peels helps
plants enhance their disease resistance
while also helping orchids withstand
unfavorable environmental conditions so
the plants remain healthy and ready for
brilliant blooms.
The calcium and magnesium in banana
peels help plants absorb nutrients more
easily while also promoting the
development of strong and healthy roots,
creating a solid foundation for orchids
to grow and bloom brilliantly.
[Music]
Next, you should cut the banana peels
into small pieces. This helps the
nutrients dissolve easily in water
during the fermentation, allowing the
orchids to overcome faster and grow
healthy, preparing for brilliant blooms.
After
[Music]
cutting them into small pieces. Put the
banana peels into a clean jar. This
helps the fermentation process take
place safely without bacteria or fungi
spoiling the nutrients.
[Music]
The next ingredient is oats. You only
need three teaspoons. Oats will provide
additional nutrients, helping orchids
grow comprehensively and healthier.
[Music]
Now add one liter of water to the jar to
ferment the banana peels with the oats.
This helps the nutrients from both
ingredients dissolve completely,
creating a nutrient-rich natural
fertilizer solution ready for the
orchids to absorb.
[Music]
Um, after adding the water, cover the
jar and let it ferment overnight. This
helps the nutrients from the banana
peels and oats dissolve completely into
the water, creating a nutrient-rich
natural fertilizer solution ready to
nourish healthy orchids.
After one night, stir the solution well.
This helps the nutrients dissolve
evenly, ensuring the orchids absorb the
nutrients most effectively.
[Music]
Next, strain out the residue from the
solution. This helps the solution become
clearer and penetrate the growing medium
more easily, ensuring the orchids absorb
the nutrients quickly and effectively.
After straining out the residue, add one
liter of water. This helps dilute the
solution to a safe level for orchid
roots while ensuring the nutrients are
evenly absorbed, nourishing healthy
plant growth.
[Music]
Step one, pour this liquid fertilizer
mixture into a spray bottle. This makes
it easy to spray the solution onto the
growing medium or directly onto the
orchid roots, ensuring the orchids
absorb the nutrients evenly and
effectively.
[Music]
When spraying the solution onto the
leaves and stems, the nutrients are
absorbed directly, helping increase the
plant's resistance, making the orchids
healthier and uh better able to
withstand pests and harsh environmental
conditions.
When spraying onto the roots and growing
medium, the solution delivers nutrients
deep into the root system, promoting
strong root development, allowing the
plant to absorb water and nutrients more
effectively, preparing for brilliant
blooms.
Spraying the solution over the entire
plant and growing medium also helps
balance moisture, creating an ideal
environment for orchids to grow, thereby
promoting regular blooming and making
the flowers bloom more brilliantly.
Step two, water the liquid fertilizer
mixture directly onto the roots and
growing medium. This helps the nutrients
penetrate deeply into the root system,
ensuring the orchids absorb sufficient
nutrients to grow healthy and prepare
for brilliant blooms.
Uh when watering the roots and growing
medium, the solution delivers nutrients
directly to the root system, helping the
roots grow strong and firm and absorb
water and minerals more effectively,
allowing the orchids to grow healthy and
prepare for brilliant blooms.
The natural nutrients from banana peels
and oats help improve the overall health
of the plant. increasing its resistance
to diseases and environmental stress,
helping the orchid stay vibrant even
when light or humidity conditions
change.
Watering with this solution also helps
balance moisture in the growing medium,
creating an ideal environment for
beneficial microorganisms to thrive,
thereby supporting the natural breakdown
of nutrients and nourishing the orchids.
[Applause]
Step three. After spraying or watering,
if water remains on the leaves, gently
wipe with a soft cloth. This helps
prevent leaf rot or mold while keeping
the orchid leaves dry, clean, and
healthy.
Fungi and bacterial diseases often
thrive in a moist environment,
especially on the young leaves of
orchids. When water accumulates on the
leaves, it creates an ideal condition
for fungi and bacteria to grow, which
can harm the health and flowers of the
orchids.
[Music]
To prevent fungi and bacteria from
growing after watering or spraying, you
should dry the young leaves with a soft
cloth while ensuring the orchids are
placed in a well ventilated area with
gentle light. This helps the leaves dry
quickly, prevents diseases, and keeps
the orchids healthy.
[Music]
Water that accumulates on the leaves is
also an ideal environment for moss and
algae to thrive. Moss and algae not only
reduce the plant's aesthetic beauty, but
can also harm the health of the orchids
if they grow excessively. Therefore,
wiping off the water after watering or
spraying helps prevent this problem
effectively.
It's best to fertilize and water the
plants in the morning or late afternoon
when the temperature and light are
gentle. This helps the plants absorb
nutrients effectively while avoiding
leaf burn or stress from intense
sunlight.
[Music]
After that, soak the orchid pot in this
solution for about 20 minutes. This
amount of time is enough for the roots
to absorb water and nutrients optimally.
After 20 minutes, take the orchid pot
out and place it in a spot with with
plenty of natural light. This helps the
plant photosynthesize effectively and
convert nutrients into energy for
growth.
[Music]
After about 3 weeks, you will start to
see a noticeable change. The orchid
leaves become shiny, thick and firm.
This shows that the plant is absorbing
the nutrients from the natural
fertilizer well and recovering strongly
from within.
[Music]
You will also see new roots starting to
grow. The root system remains healthy,
bright white, and not rotten. This is a
great sign that the orchid is growing
steadily and getting ready for the next
blooming season.
[Music]
Uh, healthy roots help the plant absorb
water and nutrients from the growing
medium more effectively, providing the
necessary energy for the growth of
leaves, stems, and flowers. A strong
root system also helps the orchid resist
diseases and adapt well to harsh
environmental conditions.
[Music]
Healthy roots help the plant absorb
water and nutrients from the growing
medium more effectively, providing the
necessary energy for the growth of
leaves, stems, and flowers. A strong
root system also helps the orchid resist
diseases and adapt well to harsh
environmental conditions.
[Music]
A healthy root system is the foundation
for a strong and thriving orchid and it
is also a sign that the plant is being
cared for properly. Therefore, always
observe and nurture the roots well
because the roots are the heart of the
orchid.
[Music]
When orchids have a healthy root system,
their flowers have bright colors, a
symmetrical shape, and are not deformed.
[Music]
The flowers will bloom together, vibrant
and longlasting, as if wanting to
preserve their beauty forever in your
garden.
Thanks to proper care, the plant will
produce many buds and bloom all at once,
bringing a vibrant and lively beauty.
From the those tiny young shoots, the
flower buds will bloom together,
bringing vibrant beauty and happiness to
your space.
[Music]
I hope you enjoy this video. If you find
it helpful, don't forget to like and
subscribe to the channel so you won't
miss the next tips on how to care for
orchids naturally and simply.
Thank you so much for watching. I truly
appreciate your time and support. Don't
forget to like, subscribe, and share if
you enjoyed this video. Wishing you a
wonderful day filled with joy and
blooming orchids. See you again in the
next
[Music]