[Music]
Welcome to my channel. I share helpful
tips for growing and caring for
orchids. Today I will share the simplest
way to help your orchids grow strong
roots and bloom beautifully at
[Music]
home. Uh if you haven't subscribed yet,
please click the subscribe button to
support me and never miss any orchid
tips. It's great to have you with
me. If your orchid has wilted soft
leaves like this, don't throw it away.
This video will show you how to revive
it
quickly. First, we need to check the
roots and the growing medium to find the
cause of the orchid's wilting.
[Music]
We remove all the damaged
roots. Removing all the damaged roots
helps the orchid get rid of dead parts,
prevents harmful bacteria and fungi,
allowing the plant to recover faster and
grow healthier and stronger.
[Music]
Next, rinse the orchid with water to
remove dirt and impurities.
[Music]
Uh, please comment to me which country
you are watching the video from. It's
great that we can chat together from all
over the world.
[Music]
Next, take one spoon of cinnamon powder.
Mix with 0.5 L of boiling water.
[Music]
Cover and let it steep until the water
cools, allowing the nutrients and
minerals from the cinnamon powder to
dissolve into the water.
[Music]
Um once the water has fully cooled,
strain out all the residue to get a
clear, clean solution.
[Music]
Next, dilute the mixture with half a
liter of clean water to ensure
effectiveness and safety for your
orchid.
[Music]
Next, soak your orchid in the cinnamon
water solution for about 20 minutes to
allow nutrients penetrate deeply and uh
provide effective antibacterial
[Music]
benefits. While waiting, I repurpose an
old plastic cup to create a nursery pot
for the orchid.
[Music]
We need to make drainage holes at the
bottom of the pot to prevent water
logging.
[Music]
Uh after soaking the orchid in the
cinnamon water mixture for about 20
minutes, gently take the plant
out. Then use a soft cloth to wipe off
all the remaining water, helping to
prevent the orchid from rotting.
[Music]
These are the pebbles.
[Applause]
[Music]
Next, soak the pebbles in cinnamon water
for about 15 minutes to disinfect them,
ensuring the orchid growing medium stays
clean and safe.
[Music]
The next growing medium is construction
sand. Sand is an ideal orchid growing
medium that provides excellent drainage,
prevents water logging, and keeps the
roots healthy.
[Music]
Then soak the sand in cinnamon water for
about 15 minutes. This helps sterilize
the orchid growing medium, reducing
harmful molds and bacteria.
[Music]
Cinnamon water also stimulates orchid
roots to grow stronger, creating a
favorable environment for the plant to
absorb nutrients effectively.
[Music]
After soaking for about 15 minutes, we
take out the stones and sand to plant
the orchids. This ensures the medium is
clean and ready to provide a solid
foundation for the orchid roots to grow.
[Music]
Then we place the stones at the bottom
of the orchid pot to improve drainage,
helping the orchid roots avoid water
logging and grow healthier.
[Music]
for construction sand as the growing
medium. After soaking in cinnamon water,
we need to rinse it several times with
water to remove any remaining mud and
soil, making the medium cleaner and more
airrated for the orchid roots. All
right.
[Music]
Then we plant the orchid into the pot,
carefully placing it to avoid damaging
the roots and ensuring the plant stands
firmly on the prepared
medium. When planting with construction
sand, the medium consistently maintains
appropriate moisture levels, helping
weak orchids quickly develop new roots
and grow healthier.
[Music]
After planting, place the orchid pot in
a well ventilated area, avoiding strong
winds and allowing only gentle sunlight,
helping the plant adapt well and grow
steadily.
[Music]
And now here are the results after 3
weeks of recovering the orchid with
wilted
leaves. Uh you can see the orchid has
grown a new leaf which indicates that
the plant is recovering well and
beginning to grow again after the care
period.
[Music]
Now let's check the roots together to
see how they are
developing. We just need to gently pour
water and the sand will naturally flow
down through the drainage holes at the
bottom of the pot.
[Music]
Wow, you can see many new roots growing
from the stem buried in the moist sand.
This shows that the growing medium
provides an ideal environment for the
orchid to develop new roots and recover
quickly.
[Music]
How do you feel about my method of
reviving weak orchids? Please leave a
comment and share your feedback with me.
I'm eager to learn from you.
[Music]
The new roots will help the wilted
orchid recover quickly, regain vitality,
and grow back after a week
[Music]
period. As new roots grow, the orchid
can absorb water and nutrients more
effectively, contributing to a complete
recovery process.
The growth of new roots also creates a
strong foundation for the orchid to
develop longterm and bloom regularly in
the future.
Rooting weak orchids in sand stimulates
quick new root growth, but we should
avoid keeping them in sand for too long
as it can cause root rot and damage due
to poor air circulation.
[Music]
Therefore, you need to plant the orchid
into a new pot using mediums like pine
bark chips, pummus, or moss to ensure
better irerration and healthy root
growth.
[Music]
Yummy. Yummy. Yummy.
After planting, you need to secure the
orchid stem to a ST to keep the plant
stable, reduce movement from wind or
handling, which helps the roots firmly
attach to the medium and grow stronger.
[Music]
If you are busy, you can use slowrelease
fertilizer designed for
orchids. Um, this type of fertilizer
gradually supplies nutrients over a long
period, saving you care time while
ensuring healthy orchid growth.
[Music]
However, if you're not too busy, I
recommend using natural fertilizers.
These are environmentally friendly and
help orchids grow well and sustainably
over
time. After planting, you need to water
and maintain moisture for the orchid.
[Music]
Depending on the weather conditions, I
usually water the orchid once every one
to two weeks to ensure the plant is
neither too dry nor water logged.
[Music]
After watering, place the orchid pot in
a spot with gentle sunlight to allow the
orchid to
photosynthesize, helping the plant
produce energy and grow
[Music]
healthier. After watering, place the
orchid pot in a spot with gentle
sunlight to allow the orchid to
photosynthesize, helping the plant
produce energy and grow healthier.
Uh the leaves have fully recovered and
become glossy green, showing that the
orchid is healthy and thriving after
careful
[Music]
care. The roots have developed strongly,
enabling the orchid to absorb nutrients
and water efficiently, providing a solid
foundation for long-term growth.
The petals are large and vividly
colored, highlighting the orchid's
elegant beauty and vibrant vitality
after the recovery process.
[Music]
Uh with this simple planting method,
anyone can easily revive and care for
orchids at home, keeping them healthy
and blooming
beautifully. I hope you enjoy this
video. If you find it helpful, please
like and subscribe to the channel so you
don't miss upcoming tips on caring for
orchids naturally and
easily. If you face any difficulties
during the orchid growing process, don't
hesitate to leave a comment. I'm always
ready to support you so you can grow
healthy orchids that bloom
beautifully. Thank you so much for
watching. Wishing you a wonderful day
filled with joy and blooming orchids.
[Music]