Welcome to the happiness garden, where
every leaf and every flower tells you a
gentle story of love and life.
In this video, I continue sharing with
you how to make natural fertilizer,
gentle yet highly effective to help
revive your orchid after it has finished
blooming so it can keep growing strong
and bloom again like a radiant gift from
nature.
[Music]
Let's get started. This is an orchid
that people once thought was dead and
thrown away, but I picked it up because
I believe that with just a little hope
and gentle care, it could come back to
life and bloom once again.
First, you need to gently remove the
yellow and damaged leaves because they
no longer contribute to the plant's life
and only hinder its natural recovery
process.
[Music]
Next, trim off the withered flower
spikes because once they've lost their
original beauty, they should be removed
so the plant can focus on nourishing its
roots and leaves, preparing for a
vibrant new blooming season.
Leave a comment and let me know which
country you're watching from. It's
wonderful that we can connect and share
with each other from all around the
world.
The damaged roots, the hollow ones that
can no longer absorb water and nutrients
need to be cut off.
This is like helping the plant let go of
its burdens so it can focus its energy
on nurturing the healthy parts.
Cutting off the damaged roots also helps
the plant avoid the risk of rot
spreading to healthy roots while
creating the right conditions for new
roots to grow stronger from within.
[Music]
Then take a small lemon, squeeze out the
juice, and dilute it with clean water to
create a natural disinfecting solution.
Either yellow lemon or green lime works
just fine.
If you haven't subscribed yet, please
hit the subscribe button to support me
and never miss any orchid growing tips.
It's truly wonderful to have you along
on this journey.
Dilute it with about one liter of clean
water to create a natural disinfecting
solution.
[Music]
After mixing, use the solution to
disinfect the entire orchid from the
root. roots and stems to any cuts or
rotting spots.
[Music]
The natural lemon solution will gently
disinfect, prevent bacteria and fungi
from spreading and protect the plant
during its recovery phase.
Additionally, lemon juice contains many
beneficial minerals and vitamins that
offer natural antibacterial properties
and stimulate cell recovery. As a
result, the orchid is not only cleansed
but also energized to revive and grow
stronger.
[Music]
You can also use this mixture to soak
the entire root system and growing
medium. This helps deeply cleanse from
within, eliminate hidden pathogens in
the old medium, and protect the roots
from infection during the recovery
process.
[Music]
After watering the roots and growing
medium thoroughly, soak the entire
orchid pot in the solution for about 20
to 30 minutes.
This amount of time is enough for the
mixture to penetrate deeply and cleanse
effectively, helping to eliminate any
remaining bacteria, mold, and harmful
agents.
While waiting for the orchid to soak,
you can you can prepare another natural
ingredient, a small aloe vera leaf.
Simply
slice the aloe vera leaf into thin
pieces so that its nutrients can easily
dissolve during soaking.
This simple method helps retain the
maximum amount of gel in the leaf,
providing gentle yet highly effective
recovery benefits for the plant's roots.
Uh this succulent leaf will be used to
make a natural fertilizer helping to soo
the roots, promote cell regeneration and
support faster recovery after pruning.
[Music]
After slicing the aloe vera thinly,
place the pieces into a clean jar.
[Music]
Then pour about one liter of clean water
into the jar to soak the aloe vera
slices. As they soak, the nutrients from
the aloe will gradually dissolve,
creating a natural solution that soothes
the roots and stimulates the plant's
growth.
[Music]
Close the jar and let it sit for about 1
hour. This resting time allows the
nutrients from the aloe to gradually
infuse into the water, creating a gentle
yet revitalizing mixture, ready to
nourish the recovering roots of your
orchid.
Uh after soaking for about 30 minutes,
gently remove the orchid pot from the
solution.
At this point, the roots have been
thoroughly cleansed and disinfected,
ready for the next step in the recovery
journey.
[Music]
Next, gently apply aloe vera gel to both
the upper and lower surfaces of the
leaves.
[Music]
Um, this thin layer of gel will help
soothe the leaf surface, enhance
moisture, and create a natural
protective barrier against bacteria and
pests during the recovery period.
[Music]
After applying, let the plant rest for
about 30 minutes to allow the aloe vera
gel to fully absorb and for the cut
areas to dry out.
[Music]
After soaking for about 1 hour, strain
out the aloe vera residue and keep only
the clear liquid.
[Music]
This is a natural, nutrient-rich
solution full of minerals and moisture,
perfect for caring for the freshly
cleaned roots and leaves of of the
orchid.
[Music]
Next, pour the filtered aloe vera
solution into a clean spray bottle.
Then, spray it evenly over the entire
orchid from the roots and stem to both
the upper and lower sides of the leaves.
Uh this fine mist will help provide
moisture, soothe the plant and support a
gentle natural recovery.
[Music]
You can also use this solution to water
the roots directly. The nutrients in
aloe vera will penetrate deeply,
soothing the cut areas, stimulating new
root growth, and boosting the plant's
resistance during the recovery phase.
After watering, continue soaking the
orchid pot in this solution for about 20
minutes. This method allows the roots to
fully absorb the nutrients from the aloe
vera, supporting the recovery process
and encouraging the healthy growth of
new roots.
After that, gently take the orchid pot
out and place it in a spot with gentle
sunlight and good air circulation. The
soft light will help the plant recover
naturally and stimulate the
photosynthesis process.
[Music]
And here is the result after 3 weeks of
patient care.
[Music]
You can see a new chute has awakened,
emerging from the leaf axle and getting
ready to grow like a gentle response
from nature to the steadfast love and
care you've given the plant.
[Music]
I continue caring for the plant by
applying natural fertilizer made from
aloe vera once every 2 weeks.
[Music]
I water this aloe vera mixture directly
onto the roots, helping to provide
moisture and essential nutrients to
stimulate the growth of new, stronger
roots. Day by day.
[Music]
I use a soft cloth, gently soak it with
the aloe vera mixture and wipe it evenly
over the leaf surfaces.
This simple method helps clean off dust,
provide natural moisture to the leaves,
and create a gentle protective barrier
against pests and diseases.
[Music]
After that, Don't forget to place the
orchid pot in a spot with gentle
sunlight and fresh air. The soft light
will help the plant continue
photosynthesizing, recover more
effectively, and soon reveal the first
signs of new life.
And here is the result after another
month.
You can see many new roots have grown
healthy, white, and full of vitality.
[Music]
From the tiny initial chute, a young
orchid has now emerged from the mother
plant. A beautiful testament to the
miraculous recovery journey made
possible by the simple wonders of
nature.
[Music]
These new roots will help the plant
absorb water and nutrients more
efficiently, providing a strong
foundation for long-term growth. With a
healthy root system, the orchid will
continue to thrive, grow lushly, and be
ready for a vibrant blooming season
ahead.
Um, the leaves of the mature orchid are
gradually turning greener, thicker, and
sturdier. This is a sign that the plant
is recovering well and beginning to
store energy for continued growth. Uh
from the roots and stem to each
individual leaf subscal
[Music]
fertilizer made from aloe vera.
Once the root system has grown strong
and stable, you can also alternate with
other natural fertilizers such as rice
water or oat soaking water.
These gentle nutrients will boost the
orchid's overall growth and help it get
ready for the next blooming season.
Don't forget to wipe the leaves
regularly to keep them free from dust,
well ventilated, and better able to
photosynthesize.
This is a small but very important step
to keep the plant healthy and full of
vitality.
[Music]
After that, place the orchid pot in a
spot with gentle sunlight and good air
flow. A calm, well-lit environment will
help the plant continue its recovery,
maintain energy, and get ready for new
shoots and flower buds in the near
future.
[Music]
And here is the result after 11 weeks
since the beginning of the recovery.
You can see the young orchid has grown
noticeably larger with leaves that are
firm and vibrantly green.
This shows that the plant is growing
strong from within thanks to your
patient care and the natural nutrients
you've lovingly provided.
[Music]
And here is the result after 25 weeks
since the beginning of the recovery.
As you can see, the orchid is now in
full bloom. These beautiful flowers are
not only a gift from nature, but also a
sweet reward for the gentle and
persistent care you've given throughout
the recovery journey.
[Music]
From a pot of orchid that once seemed
discarded, it has now become a beautiful
testament to resilient life and the
patient love you've given to nature.
[Music]
As long as you stay patient and care
with all your heart, the plant will
always find a way to revive and bloom
beautifully, like a gentle gift from
nature to a heart that knows how to
love.
[Music]
I hope you enjoyed this video. If you
found it helpful, don't forget to like
and subscribe so you won't miss the next
tips on how to care for orchids
naturally and simply.
[Music]
What do you think about the way I
revived this little orchid? Uh, don't
hesitate to leave a comment and share
your thoughts. I'd love to hear your
feedback and experiences.
If you face any difficulties while
growing orchids, don't hesitate to leave
a comment. I'm always here to support
you so you can grow healthy orchids that
bloom beautifully.
In addition to the English voiceover, we
have now created versions in French,
German, Italian, Spanish, Portuguese,
Japanese, Hindi, Dutch, Polish, Korean,
and Indonesian to help you listen and
understand the content more easily.
To listen to the language, open the
video and click on settings, the gear
icon to select the appropriate audio
language.
[Music]
Thank you so much for watching. I hope
this little story brings you more
inspiration and confidence to keep
nurturing the beautiful gifts of nature.
See you in the next video.