Welcome to the happiness garden. In
today's video, I will share with you a
natural fertilizer that is easy to make
but brings amazing results. This is the
secret to helping orchids grow stronger
everyday with healthy roots, green
leaves, and especially vibrant blooms
all year round. Each drop of this
fertilizer not only nourishes the plant,
but also carries the love and patience
of the grower. So, let's begin the
journey of caring for orchids in a
natural, gentle, yet truly inspiring
way.
[Music]
The first ingredient to make this
fertilizer is eggshells. You only need
about four to five eggshells washed
clean to remove any remaining egg white.
Though small, eggshells contain a lot of
calcium, an essential nutrient that
helps orchid roots grow strong and
resist pests and diseases. By making use
of simple ingredients like these, we not
only take good care of our plants, but
also help protect the environment around
us.
[Music]
After washing, dry the eggshells under
sunlight until they are completely dry.
[Music]
Sunlight not only makes the shells more
brittle and easier to crush, but also
kills bacteria and mold that could harm
the plants.
[Music]
After the eggshells are completely dry,
crush them into small pieces. You can
use a mortar and pestle or a blender as
long as the shells are ground into fine
powder or small fragments.
Please comment and let me know which
country you're watching from. It's
wonderful that we can connect and chat
with each other from all around the
world.
[Music]
[Applause]
And if you haven't subscribed yet,
please hit the subscribe button to
support me and not miss any orchid
growing tips. It's wonderful to have you
along for the journey.
Method one is very simple. You just need
to sprinkle about one spoonful of the
crushed eggshell powder over the surface
of the orchid pot.
This thin layer of powder will slowly
dissolve each time you water the plant,
providing calcium in a natural and safe
way. It's a slow release but effective
method that helps orchid roots absorb
nutrients steadily and encourages
healthy growth, resulting in
longerlasting and more beautiful blooms
over time.
[Music]
Another wonderful benefit of sprinkling
eggshell powder is that it helps
neutralize the acidity in the growing
medium. When the orchid's environment
becomes too acidic, the roots have
difficulty absorbing nutrients. The
eggshell powder gently balances the pH
level, creating ideal conditions for the
roots to grow strong and absorb
nutrients more effectively.
In addition, eggshell powder helps
prevent snails and other small insects
as the sharp fragments of the shells
keep them from crawling near. This is a
natural and safe way to protect your
orchids from being eaten without using
chemical pesticides. As a result, you
not only keep your plants healthy, but
also maintain a green, clean, and
eco-friendly garden.
[Music]
Method two, put the crushed eggshells
into a clean jar to make a liquid
fertilizer. This method allows the
minerals in the eggshells, especially
calcium, to dissolve more easily and be
absorbed by the plant more quickly.
[Music]
Next, pour about 100 ml of Coca-Cola
into the jar. It may sound unusual, but
Coca-Cola contains sugar and a small
amount of acid that helps break down the
minerals in the eggshells more quickly.
When combined, this mixture creates a
nutrient-rich natural fertilizer that
orchids can easily absorb, helping them
grow stronger and healthier. This is a
simple yet surprisingly effective secret
for your orchid pots.
You can see that right after pouring in
the Coca-Cola, a reaction begins to
occur. Tiny bubbles start to appear.
This is a sign that the acid in the
Coca-Cola is dissolving the calcium from
the eggshells.
[Music]
The next ingredient is rice. It's a
familiar ingredient, but but provides
excellent nutrients for orchids,
especially vitamin B and natural
minerals.
Now add about 2 tablespoons of rice.
This amount is just enough to provide
the necessary nutrients without making
the mixture too thick or causing it to
ferment too quickly.
When the rice is soaked together with
the eggshell and Coca-Cola mixture, the
vitamins and minerals in the rice are
released, turning the solution into a
natural energy richch fertilizer for
orchids.
After stirring the mixture well, cover
it and let it sit for about 2 days.
During this time, the ingredients will
gradually blend together, creating a
lightly fermented, nutrient-rich
solution.
[Music]
After fermenting for 2 days, strain the
mixture to separate the liquid and
discard the residue. Uh the liquid
obtained at this stage is rich in easily
absorbed minerals and vitamins which are
excellent for the growth of orchid roots
and leaves.
[Music]
Dilute the solution with about 2 L of
clean water. This step is very important
because if the mixture is too
concentrated, the orchid roots may get
shocked or slightly burned. When
properly diluted, the fertilizer becomes
gentler, allowing the plant to easily
absorb the nutrients and grow healthily.
Then use a soft cloth soaked in this
mixture and gently wipe both the upper
and lower surfaces of the leaves.
When you wipe the leaves with this
liquid fertilizer mixture, the dust and
mold on the leaf surface are completely
removed. Clean leaves help the stomata
function more efficiently, enhancing gas
exchange and photosynthesis. As a
result, the plant absorbs light better,
grows stronger, and stays naturally
green and vibrant.
[Music]
The mixture made from rice, eggshells,
and Coca-Cola is rich in vitamins,
minerals, and calcium. When applied to
the leaves, the plant absorbs part of
these nutrients directly.
This is a quick and effective way to
provide extra nourishment, helping
orchid leaves stay glossy, thick,
healthy, and preventing yellowing caused
by nutrient deficiencies.
[Music]
Thanks to the minerals and mild acids in
Coca-Cola, this solution can inhibit the
growth of harmful bacteria and fungi on
the leaf surface.
When used regularly, orchids develop
stronger resistance, reducing the risk
of leaf rot or brown spots and keeping
the plant healthy and vibrant all year
round.
Um, healthy leaves are the foundation
for more consistent and longlasting
blooms.
When nourished with this natural
fertilizer mixture, the orchid leaves
absorb nutrients effectively, supporting
the process of bud formation and flower
development. The blooms will have
brighter colors and last longer,
bringing vibrant beauty to your garden.
[Music]
You can also pour this mixture directly
onto the roots and growing medium. This
method allows the nutrients to penetrate
deeply, nourishing the root system and
stimulating new root growth. When the
roots are strong, the plant absorbs
water and nutrients more efficiently,
resulting in greener leaves and more
vibrant blooms. It's a simple yet
sustainable method that nourishes your
orchid from root to tip.
[Music]
Calcium from the eggshells strengthens
the roots while the nutrients from the
rice support cell regeneration.
As a result, orchid roots grow
vigorously, absorb water and minerals
more efficiently, and keep the plant
lush and full of vitality.
Uh this solution not only nourishes the
roots but also helps balance the pH in
the growing medium reducing mold and
harmful bacteria. When the root
environment is improved, the orchid
grows more steadily and and can more
easily form new flower buds.
After watering, you can also soak the
orchid pot in this fertilizer mixture
for about 20 minutes. During the soaking
process, the minerals will deeply
penetrate each small root, helping the
plant grow faster.
Alternatively, you can put the mixture
into a spray bottle and mist it onto the
leaves and roots of the orchid.
[Music]
This method helps the fertilizer
solution distribute evenly, quickly,
reaching the gaps between leaves, stems,
and small roots that regular watering
can't reach. Gentle spraying provides
nutrients uniformly to the plant while
also keeping the leaves clean and bright
and allowing the roots to absorb more
effectively.
It's a convenient technique, especially
suitable for hanging orchid pots or
those with many stems, offering
comprehensive care in a gentle way.
[Music]
When you spray the liquid fertilizer
mixture made from rice, eggshells, and
Coca-Cola onto the roots and growing
medium, the minerals and vitamins are
evenly distributed and quickly absorbed
into every root gap.
This helps the roots absorb nutrients
more effectively while creating a
natural protective layer against mold
and harmful bacteria in the growing
medium. As a result, the orchid grows
strong from the roots with sturdy roots,
lush green leaves, and evenly blooming,
long-lasting flowers.
After soaking for about 20 minutes,
gently remove the orchid pot from the
mixture.
[Music]
If there is still water on the leaves
after soaking, use a soft cloth to blot
it all dry. This helps prevent the
leaves from becoming water logged or
moldy while keeping the leaf surface dry
and clean. When the leaves are dry and
airy, the plant absorbs nutrients more
effectively. The roots stay healthy and
the flowers bloom brightly, full of
vitality.
[Music]
You will see that the orchid leaves
become noticeably glossy, thick, and
sturdy. This change shows that the
nutrients from the rice, eggshells, and
Coca-Cola mixture have been effectively
absorbed, nourishing both the leaves and
roots. When the leaves are healthy, the
plant has a strong foundation for
consistent and longlasting blooms,
bringing a garden full of life and
vibrant colors.
What do you think about the results of
how I've cared for these small orchids?
Don't hesitate to leave a comment and
share your thoughts. I'm really looking
forward to hearing your feedback and
experiences.
[Music]
Uh the root system also becomes denser,
stronger, and more robust. These sturdy
roots help the plant absorb water and
nutrients optimally while keeping the
orchid pot stable in the growing medium.
Not only do the old roots become strong,
but the orchid also develops many new
roots. These young roots are a clear
sign that the plant is recovering and
full of vitality.
[Music]
The aerial roots also grow vigorously,
extending long and strong
with both old and new roots as well as
aerial roots. All growing well, the
orchid can absorb water and nutrients to
the fullest, ensuring vitality from root
to tip. When the roots are strong,
leaves are green, and flowers bloom
brightly, you will see your orchid full
of energy and developing sustainably
over time.
And you can also see the flower buds
becoming noticeably bigger and plumper.
This shows that the orchid is being
fully nourished from roots to leaves,
allowing the buds to develop healthily
in preparation for vibrant blooms.
[Music]
When the buds are plump and healthy, the
flowers will bloom large with even
colors and long-lasting petals, bringing
vibrant beauty to your garden.
When the flowers bloom, the petals are
large, the colors vibrant, and the stems
soft, lasting longer on the plant. This
is the result of careful care with the
natural fertilizer mixture, allowing the
plant to fully absorb nutrients from
roots to leaves. Healthy flowers are not
only beautiful, but also longasting,
bringing joy and happiness every time
you admire a lively orchid garden.
[Music]
Note that although this fertilizer is
very beneficial, you should only use it
once a month. Regular monthly watering
helps improve the growing medium and
provide necessary nutrients to the plant
without causing harm. If too much
Coca-Cola is used, the acid in the
solution can accumulate and be harmful
to the roots, making them weak or
damaged. Therefore, consider the timing
and dosage carefully to ensure your
orchid grows strong, lasts long, and
blooms beautifully.
I hope you enjoyed this video. If you
find it helpful, don't forget to like to
like and subscribe so you won't miss
future tips on caring for orchids
naturally and easily. Thank you so much
for taking the time to watch and
accompany us in our happiness garden.