[Music]
welcome to my channel
if not treated promptly rot will spread
to other trees very
quickly this route is rotten so it
should be thrown
[Music]
away this Leaf is still fresh so it can
be
[Music]
restored remove all rotten
leaves uh please comment to me which
country you are watching the video from
it's great that we can chat together
from all over the
[Music]
world then rinse with water this helps
the tree recover
[Music]
faster and this method will remove dirt
and insects still attached to these
leaves
[Music]
helps orchids even though they only have
one leaf can revive Vive faster and
easier
[Music]
cutting extra to avoid crushing the stem
will help prevent the Orchid from
rotting
[Music]
further if you haven't subscribed to the
channel yet please subscribe to support
me and not miss any orchid care tips
[Music]
I use coffee as a natural fertilizer to
help orchids recover
quickly take one
[Music]
teaspoon add 2 cups of boiling water
if you encounter any difficulties during
the Orchid growing process don't
hesitate to comment I am always ready to
support you so you can grow healthy
orchids and Bloom lots of
[Music]
flowers um wait until it cool tools
before using it as
[Music]
fertilizer after cooling filter to
remove
[Music]
residue coffee will be very good and
help orchids grow very quickly
[Music]
in addition to the US English language I
have added voiceovers in French German
Italian Spanish Portuguese Japanese
Hindi and Indonesian to help you hear
and understand the video content easier
please click on the settings on the
video to select the appropriate language
[Music]
use soft cotton pads wipe the leaves
again and add nutrients through the
leaves and eliminate insects and fungi
helps orchid leaves recover will not be
infected with insects and fungi
[Music]
that
put the leaves here and then add this
coffee
[Music]
water leave for about 30 minutes to help
the plant regenerate Roots very
quickly and use the remaining coffee
water put in spray bottle
[Music]
spraying directly on the Orchid will
help the Orchid grow
quickly and remember to spray under the
leaves to prevent insect growth
[Music]
um you should apply this method every 2
weeks or water Orchid Roots every 2
weeks
[Music]
this is a great way to provide nutrients
to orchids through the
[Music]
roots you can see that orchids cared for
by this method have very healthy roots
[Music]
a strong root system will help the
Orchid absorb the most
[Music]
nutrients when absorbing enough
nutrients the plant will always be
healthy and Bloom many
[Music]
flowers the flower color is bright and
stays on the branch for a long time
before fading
[Music]
the mineral and nitrogen content in
coffee helps leaves Stay Green and
strong potassium in coffee helps flour
buds not fall off before
[Music]
blooming after 30 minutes take the
leaves out and wipe dry
[Music]
use one clove of garlic garlic has very
good antibacterial and antiseptic
properties
[Music]
because garlic has good antibacterial
properties it is very effective in
preventing Orchid
[Music]
rot then leave it in a cool dry place
for one day so that the cut will dry and
the orchid leaves will recover
quickly then take advantage of recycled
plastic boxes into Orchid growing tools
please cut like I do
[Music]
take a cotton pad and place it here
cotton will help absorb water better
[Music]
put the leaf
in then pour in filtered
water then cut the orchid leaves into
the
[Music]
box adjust the water level so that it
does not touch the base of the
[Music]
plant and remember to add water when you
feel like you're running out of
[Music]
water cover and place in a cool well-lit
place
[Music]
with this method you will not need to
spray mist to keep the leaves
[Music]
moist and this is the result after the
next month the orchid has recovered and
grown healthy roots
[Music]
the orchid has grown a new
leaf with these methods you need to be
patient because with orchids there will
always be fast plants and slow plants so
when implementing these methods we need
to be
[Music]
persistent and The Roots have grown very
well I planted it in a new pot so the
orchids could grow in the outside
environment
[Music]
planting with pine bark will help the
roots always breathe so the Orchid will
not
rot I always share many ways for you to
easily choose what are the most suitable
and simplest
[Music]
ways add a little Moss to the surface of
the Orchid pot to help retain moisture
better
[Music]
after planting water and keep the
orchids
[Music]
moist I have created many subtitles for
you to view and choose from which
subtitle is suitable
[Music]
hope it will always help you a
lot don't forget to like share and
subscribe to the channel and press the
Bell to conveniently follow
[Music]
thank you for
watching goodbye and see you again wish
you always success