welcome to my
channel if you have an orchid after
flowering like this uh don't rush to
throw it
[Music]
away please pay attention and follow me
to recover and help the orchids bloom
again
[Music]
remove old growing medium
uh when the Moss is green like this it
proves that the humidity in the Orchid
pot is very suitable uh so I only
removed part of the old substrate so the
roots could grow faster
[Music]
if the growing medium is dark green or
viscous it means the humidity is too
high easily rotting the Orchid
Roots if you haven't subscribed to the
channel yet please click the subscribe
button to support me and don't miss any
Orchid growing tips truly great
[Music]
company please comment to me which
country you are watching the video from
it's great that we can chat together
from all over the
[Music]
world cut off all damaged
roots in addition to the English dub
we've now created dubs in French German
Italian Spanish Portuguese Japanese
Hindi and Indonesian to help you hear
and understand the content more
[Music]
easily cutting off wilted flower
branches will help the Orchid quickly
recover and quickly produce new flower
branches
[Music]
these black spots are caused by fungal
growth that rots The
[Music]
Roots when there is too much moisture
fungi will grow and cause root rot
[Music]
upon closer inspection I saw fungal
disease thriving inside the sub
[Music]
straight um therefore it is necessary to
remove all old planting material so that
the fungus does not spread further
[Music]
if you encounter any difficulties during
the Orchid growing process don't
hesitate to comment I am always ready to
support you so you can grow healthy
orchids and Bloom lots of flowers
[Music]
then rinse with water helps eliminate
some fungal diseases
[Music]
then leave in a cool place for 2 hours
to
drain next make fertilizer for
orchids take one spoon of oatmeal
[Music]
add 500 mL boiled water about 2
cups uh wait until it cools before using
it as
[Music]
fertilizer take one spoon of dry yeast
adding 2 cups of warm water about 500 mL
of warm water helps the yeast grow
[Music]
better be careful not to use hot water
because it will kill the microorganisms
in the
[Music]
yeast wait 1 hour for the yeast to
develop before using it as
fertilizer 1 hour later
[Music]
filter the oatmeal solution
uh mix the yeast solution with the
oatmeal
[Music]
solution add 1 lit of room temperature
water about 4
[Music]
cups then soak the Orchid roots in this
solution for 30 minutes
[Applause]
[Music]
minutes beneficial microorganisms in the
yeast will protect the roots from
rot and vitamins and minerals and Oats
help stimulate rapid
[Music]
rooting the remaining solution is used
to fertilize other orchids in the garden
this fertilizer helps stimulate root
growth a strong root system will help
orchids absorb nutrients best
[Music]
um you can see that my orchid pots have
developed very healthy
[Music]
Roots this fertilizer also contains a
large amount of natural potassium to
help bloom more and flowers last
longer apply this liquid fertilizer to
orchids every 2 weeks for Healthy
[Music]
Growth uh after soaking for 30 minutes
take the Orchid out and plant it in a
new pot
[Music]
um I plant with pine bark which helps
drain water quickly and has appropriate
moisture so it doesn't cause root rot
[Music]
for
after planting apply this liquid
fertilizer to the orchids every 2 weeks
[Music]
place the Orchid pot in a place with
light sunlight so that the Orchid can
photosynthesize and and the Orchid will
grow
[Music]
faster on weekdays when the foundation
is dry you just need to spray mist to
keep it
moist or watering to keep the substrate
moist will help the roots take root
quickly
[Music]
when growing orchids always follow the
principle of the substrate is moist but
not wet which will be good for your
[Music]
orchids results after 1
month after only 1 month Orchid Roots
have grown many and
[Music]
healthy leaves become
stronger these new Roots will help the
Orchid absorb nutrients and water best
[Music]
um when the leaves and Roots grow
healthy like this the Orchid will
quickly produce new flower branches
[Music]
uh hope the video will help you a
lot if you find it interesting please
like share and subscribe to support my
[Music]
channel thank you for watching the
video wish you luck and see you in the
next videos
[Music]