welcome to happiness
Garden this is where I share how to care
for and revive orchids using natural
methods and organic
fertilizers uh let's make your orchids
healthy and Bloom more beautifully than
ever if you have a wilted Orchid like
this one don't throw it away just
yet in this video I'll share how to
revive it and help it grow strong again
this Orchid wasn't cared for properly
after blooming causing it to weaken and
become stunted without timely recovery
the Orchid might
[Music]
die first cut off all the damaged roots
to help the Orchid recover
better um in addition to the English
voiceover we have now created voiceovers
in French German Italian Spanish and
Portuguese to help you listen to and
understand the video content more
[Music]
easily how to select the audio language
on YouTube One open the video and click
on settings the gear icon two select
subtitles CC three click on audio and
choose the language you want English
France deut Italiano espanol or
Portuguese
[Music]
next trim off the damaged leaves so the
Orchid can focus on growing
[Music]
this node hasn't bloomed yet so we can
stimulate it to grow into a baby
cakey for nodes that have already
bloomed and branches that are wilted
trim them off so the plant can focus on
[Music]
growth next rinse the Orchid thoroughly
with water to remove dirt and bacteria
which country are you watching this
video from leave a comment and let me
know it's amazing that we can chat
together from all around the world
next take an aloe vera leaf to make a
natural fertilizer that helps retain
moisture and quickly revive wilted
orchids
then add about 10 G of Ginger to the
mixture to boost the orchid's
recovery add 400 m of water
then blend the mixture in a blender to
create a smooth solution
[Music]
finally strain the mixture to ensure
there are no organic residues left in
the
solution add one more liter of water to
create a very effective natural
fertilizer mix for orchids
then pour this mixture over the wilted
Orchid to help it recover
quickly this mixture helps revive wilted
leaves by providing essential nutrients
and moisture it also stimulates new root
growth and Cakey development thanks to
the Natural compounds in aloe vera and
ginger making the Orchid healthier and
stronger next use a soft cotton pad to
soak up the mixture and place it on the
unopened flower node to stimulate cakey
growth
then soak the Orchid in this mixture for
about 20 minutes to allow the plant to
absorb the nutrients
effectively after soaking for 20 minutes
take the Orchid
[Music]
out remove the cotton pad from the node
to allow the Orchid to continue growing
without staying too wet for too long
sprinkle cinnamon powder on the cut to
help with antibacterial protection and
prevent
infection then wipe off any remaining
mixture on the leaves to prevent them
from rotting
take
if you haven't subscribed yet please hit
the Subscribe button to support me thank
you so
much then I plant the it in a larger pot
to give it more space for better
growth I plant the Orchid using pine
bark chips to ensure good drainage and
provide an ideal environment for root
growth if you haven't subscribed to the
channel yet please subscribe to support
me and not miss any orchid care
[Music]
tips uh add a layer of moss on top to
help retain moisture better for the
Orchid
[Music]
after planting water the Orchid with
this mixture once every two weeks to
help it grow healthy
on regular days if the growing medium
feels dry simply water or miss the
Orchid to maintain
[Music]
moisture then place the Orchid pot in a
spot with gentle light avoiding direct
sunlight to help the plant grow
well make sure the area is well
ventilated as
well after 1 month your orchid will
begin to recover the leaves will become
Greener new Roots will begin to grow and
even the kakei will have developed
[Music]
after 1 month the orchid has grown a new
shoot at the tip showing that the
recovery and growth process is going
very well
the cakei on the stem is growing very
plump and healthy showing that the
Orchid is recovering well and growing
strong
[Music]
continue watering the Orchid with the
aloe vera and ginger mixture once every
2 weeks to maintain Healthy Growth
[Music]
then place the Orchid pot in a spot with
gentle light avoiding direct sunlight to
help the plant grow
[Music]
well after the next 3 months the orchid
has grown strong with many new Roots
fresh green leaves and the kakei is
starting to grow bigger
the Orchid now looks very healthy and is
preparing to
[Music]
bloom for
these two leaves have turned yellow and
wilted and cannot be revived so I will
remove them from the Orchid to allow the
plant to focus on developing new healthy
leaves for
the kakei growing on this flower stem
has strong roots so I will cut it and
plant it in a new pot to continue
growing separating the Ki and planting
it allows the mother Orchid to focus its
nutrients on developing healthier leaves
and Roots while reducing the furk and
the kakei
I plant the Ki in a new pot using pine
bark to ensure the plant has good air
flow and drainage
[Music]
continue watering the Orchid with the
aloe vera and ginger mixture once every
2 weeks to maintain Healthy Growth
[Music]
then place the Orchid pot in a spot with
gentle light avoiding direct sunlight to
help the plant grow well make sure the
area is well ventilated as as
[Music]
well results after 1
month healthy roots and many new flower
branches the mother Orchid grew strongly
with many fresh green leaves healthy
roots and many new flower branches
the baby Ki has taken roote and is
thriving in its new pot ready to
continue growing and blooming
take care of your Orchids with all the
love you have for plants and you will be
rewarded with beautiful vibrant flowers
and fresh healthy leaves
your orchid will grow strong and bring
joy to you every
day thank you for
watching uh take good care of your
orchids and don't forget to subscribe to
the channel to not miss the next
videos wishing you a wonderful day and
see you in the next videos