Hello orchid lovers. Welcome to the
happiness garden
channel. Today I will show you how to
make natural fertilizer that is both
simple and
[Music]
effective. This fertilizer will help
your orchids grow sustainably and bloom
for a longer time.
[Music]
Now, let's get
started. This orchid has finished
blooming. If not properly cared for, the
plant can become stunted and grow
slowly. So, post-flowering care is very
important to help the plant recover and
prepare for the next blooming cycle.
[Music]
First remove all damaged, rotting or
dried
[Music]
roots. This will allow the orchid to
focus its energy on healthy parts for
growth.
This process also helps stimulate the
plant to grow new roots and prepares it
for the next growth
[Music]
cycle. After removing damaged roots, we
will proceed to cut off all unhealthy
leaves.
[Music]
Next, cut off the old flower stems so
the plant can focus its energy on
growing new roots and
leaves. Old flower stems usually no
longer have the ability to grow and can
cause the plant to waste energy if left
attached.
[Music]
Sprinkle a layer of cinnamon powder onto
the cut areas to disinfect and prevent
infection.
Next, leave it overnight without
watering to allow the cuts to heal
completely.
[Music]
Now take one spoonful of cinnamon powder
and add it to a jar to prepare a natural
[Music]
fertilizer. Mix the cinnamon powder with
one liter of boiling water to create a
natural fertilizer solution.
Cover the lid and let it sit overnight
to ensure the nutrients from the
cinnamon powder are fully dissolved in
the
water. The second ingredient I use is
breadcrumbs, which are rich in nutrients
and great for the growth of orchids.
[Music]
mix one liter of warm water with 2 tsp
of breadcrumbs to create a natural
nutrient solution.
Let it sit overnight to ensure the
nutrients from the breadcrumbs are fully
dissolved in the
[Music]
water. After one night, strain out the
residue to obtain clean and clear
cinnamon water.
[Music]
Uh, what country are you watching this
video from? Leave a comment to let me
know.
It's so wonderful that we can connect
and chat with each other from all over
the world.
[Music]
Step one, use a soft cotton pad soaked
in the cinnamon water and gently wipe
the top and bottom surfaces of the
leaves. This method helps eliminate
fungi, pests, and harmful insects from
the plant.
This method also cleans the leaves,
allowing them to photosynthesize more
effectively, which improves the plant's
overall nutrient exchange.
If you haven't subscribed yet, click the
subscribe button to support my channel.
Step two, pour this cinnamon water
solution into a spray bottle.
Then spray the solution over the entire
orchid to remove dust, mold, and any
pests clinging to the plant.
This method also stimulates the plant's
natural resistance, helping it grow
stronger and better withstand diseases.
Step three, use a soft cloth to wipe off
any excess water from the leaves to
prevent mold and bacterial growth.
Wiping off water helps the leaves dry
quickly, improving the plant's ability
to photosynthesize and exchange
nutrients. Reduces the risk of the
orchid getting sick due to prolonged
damp conditions.
[Music]
Uh, step four, add a thin layer of moss
on the surface of the orchid pot to to
retain moisture and create a better
growing environment for the
[Music]
plant. This moss layer also helps
maintain moisture balance and prevents
the plant from losing water too quickly
in dry conditions.
[Music]
Now I mix the cinnamon water solution
with the breadcrumbs water solution
together.
[Music]
After mixing, we will have a natural
nutrient solution that is excellent for
the growth of orchids.
[Music]
Step five. From now on, water this
mixture on your orchids once every 10
[Music]
days. This solution stimulates the
growth of new roots, allowing the plant
to absorb nutrients more effectively.
encourages the growth of new shoots and
flowers, allowing the orchid to bloom
for a longer
[Music]
period. After watering, you should soak
the orchid pot in this mixture for about
20 minutes to get the best results.
[Music]
You can use the leftover mixture to
water other regular orchids as well. It
will be very beneficial for their growth
too.
[Music]
Um, this solution is very beneficial,
but you should only water the plant
every 10 to 15 days to avoid
overfeeding.
[Music]
After watering, soak the base of the
orchid pot in this mixture for about 20
minutes.
[Music]
Then take the orchid pot out and place
it in a spot with gentle sunlight to
allow the plant to photosynthesize well,
improving nutrient exchange.
[Applause]
[Music]
Uh keep in mind uh this fertilizer is
very beneficial but without sufficient
sunlight the plant won't be able to
synthesize nutrients effectively.
[Music]
uh the results after 10
days. Can you see the new leaves have
grown longer than before which shows
that the plant is growing very
[Music]
well. New roots have also grown quite a
lot which will help the orchid recover
and grow vigorously in the coming time.
[Music]
And you can see the leaves have become
stronger and greener, which is a sign
that the orchid is growing healthily.
I will continue to water this natural
fertilizer mixture on the plant every 10
days to ensure the orchid grows
[Music]
sustainably on regular days. If the
potting medium is dry or the environment
is too dry, you should simply water or
mist lightly to maintain humidity for
the
orchid. After that, remember to place
the pot in a spot with gentle sunlight
to allow the orchid to photosynthesize
effectively.
[Music]
the results after the next 45
days. You can see that the new leaves
have grown longer and are healthy.
And two new flower stalks have emerged,
promising another vibrant blooming
season ahead.
Uh the leaves have become stronger and
grown exceptionally well after being
cared for with this natural fertilizer
mixture.
Uh the roots have grown out of the
orchid pot which is a sign that the
orchid is growing very vigorously.
[Music]
Um, with other orchids, when cared for
with this natural fertilizer mixture,
they also develop many new flower stocks
and healthy new
roots. I hope this video provides you
with useful information. If you find it
helpful and interesting, don't forget to
support me by liking, sharing, and
subscribing to the
channel. Uh, care for your orchids with
love and dedication, and you will be
rewarded with vibrant blooms and the
pure joy of connecting with nature.
Thank you for watching. I wish you
success in taking care of your orchids
and see you in the next videos. Goodbye.