hello
everyone today we will discover how to
create a natural fertilizer that will
Revitalize and promote the growth of all
[Music]
orchids uh comprehensive development
from roots stems leaves and
[Music]
orchids let's get
started do you have chamomile and grass
tea chrysanthemums contain many vitamins
and minerals providing a rich source of
nutrition for
[Music]
orchids the ingredients in chrysanthemum
help strengthen the plant's resistance
and prevent
diseases nutrition from chrysanthemums
also promotes orchids to more and more
[Music]
beautifully take three packs of
chrysanthemum and lemongrass tea and put
them in a
jar then add 1 liter of boiled water
[Music]
then close the lid and wait for the
water to
[Music]
cool next I need garlic to make
fertilizer for orchids
[Music]
take three cloves of garlic and cut them
into small
[Music]
slices garlic contains allisin a
compound with antibacterial and
antifungal properties that helps protect
orchids from common
diseases nutrition from garlic helps
improve plants resistance helping them
better cope with environmental
conditions and pests
[Music]
then put it in the
jar and add 1 liter of
water which country are you watching
videos from please comment
me it's great that we can chat together
from all over the world
wait 2 hours for nutrients to dissolve
in water before using as
[Music]
fertilizer after 2 hours
filter the garlic water
[Music]
method
one use a soft cotton to soak the garlic
water and thoroughly wipe the top and
bottom of the
leaves garlic juice contains allisin
which helps kill harmful bacteria and
fungi protecting leaves from disease
wiping leaves helps remove dirt creating
conditions for leaves to photosynthesize
more
effectively um the smell of garlic helps
repel insects and pests protecting
plants from Attack
using garlic water helps improve the
plant's natural resistance making
orchids
healthier therefore wiping orchid leaves
with garlic water water is a natural and
effective way to care for and protect
the
plant which country are you watching
videos from please comment and let me
know um it's nice that we can chat
together from all over the world
um do this one to two times a month to
protect your orchids
[Music]
after the water cools mix the two types
of water
together method
two water the Orchid roots with this
Liquid Fertilizer
Allison in garlic helps kill fungi and
bacteria harmful to
Roots garlic strengthens plants
resistance helping Roots grow
healthfully
compounds in garlic promote root growth
helping plants absorb nutrients
better chrysanthemum and lemongrass tea
contain many vitamins and minerals
necessary for root growth
[Music]
essential oils from lemongrass and
compounds in crysanthemum help protect
plants from
diseases the scent from lemongrass
creates a pleasant environment for the
plant
[Music]
after watering soak the Orchid pot in
this water for about 20 minutes to let
the roots absorb nutrients
[Music]
method
three or you can also put this water in
a spray bottle
then spray the entire
Orchid Allison in garlic and compounds
in chrysanthemum help protect plants
from diseases
nutritious ingredients help plants grow
healthily and resist
[Music]
stress the essential oil in lemongrass
has the effect of repelling insects and
protecting plants from pests
spraying both leaves and Orchid Roots is
good spraying both leaves and Orchid
Roots is good
but you should not spray this water on
[Music]
flowers water wets flower petals
creating conditions for fungi and
bacteria to grow leading to flower rot
[Music]
after soaking for 20 minutes take the
Orchid pot out and place it in a place
with lots of scattered
light scattered light provides enough
energy for photosynthesis without
causing Leaf burn helping plants absorb
nutrients better
[Music]
results after 3 weeks of caring for
orchids with this liquid
fertilizer green leaves are shiny and
sturdy
[Music]
this green color is due to the archid
photosynthesizing a lot of light so it's
very
[Music]
hard many new Roots grow
uh new Roots also play an important role
in maintaining moisture for the plant
preventing it from drying
[Music]
out the the new Roots help the Orchid
firmly adhere to the substrate or
surface keeping the plant from falling
over new Roots also create relationships
with microorganisms in the soil helping
the plant absorb nutrients better
[Music]
uh new root growth is often a sign that
the plant is growing healthily and is
ready for
flowering uh new Roots help the plant
adapt to its living environment
searching for moisture and nutrients in
different
[Music]
areas care for your Orchids with passion
and Devotion to
Nature you will receive brilliant
flowers that are the result of your own
Loving
[Music]
Hands Let each flower become a symbol of
your care and
dedication thank you for taking the time
to watch this video
if you find the information useful then
don't forget to click the Subscribe
button and turn on notifications so you
don't miss the next
[Music]
videos please support our Channel by
sharing and leaving your comments below
the
video your support is is the greatest
motivation for us to continue to bring
more interesting knowledge thanks a lot