Welcome to Happiness Garden, where we
together explore the gentle beauty of
nature and the love for orchid petals.
Today I want to share with you how to
care for orchids using natural
fertilizer, a simple yet effective
method that helps orchids bloom multiple
times a year. As a result, your home
will always be filled with the colors
and gentle fragrance of nature.
Uh, the orchid petals after falling
leave a quiet emptiness on the branch,
marking the time when the orchid begins
to weaken. During the blooming period,
the plant puts all its strength into
nurturing each petal, gradually
depleting the energy stored in its stem,
roots, and leaves.
We need to cut off the entire old orchid
branch. This helps the plant focus its
nutrients on nurturing healthy new
shoots while also stimulating the growth
of new roots, preparing for a more
brilliant next blooming season.
[Music]
If you haven't subscribe to the channel
yet, please press the subscribe button
to support me and not miss any orchid
growing tips. It's wonderful to have you
along.
[Music]
Leave a comment and let me know which
country you're watching from. It's
amazing that we can chat with each other
from all around the world.
[Music]
To make natural fertilizer, the first
ingredient I use is eggshells. Eggshells
are rich in calcium, which helps orchid
roots grow strong and also improves soil
quality, creating favorable conditions
for the plant to absorb nutrients more
effectively.
Take two cleaned eggshells. Then crush
them by hand and put them into a small
jar.
[Music]
The next ingredient I use is rice
because rice contains vitamins,
minerals, and a small amount of starch,
all of which are beneficial for orchid
root development.
Take three tablespoons of rice and add
them to the prepared eggshells. Then
pour in about.5 L of boiling water.
[Music]
Um, the high temperature will help
release nutrients from the rice and
eggshells, creating a nutrient-rich brew
for the orchid.
Close the jar and let the solution cool
naturally. This process helps the
nutrients fully dissolve, ready to
nourish your orchid.
[Music]
After the water cools, stir the solution
well so that the nutrients blend
completely, ensuring the natural
fertilizer works at its best when used
for the orchid.
[Music]
Then we proceed to filter out the
sediment. This helps make the fertilizer
solution clear and easier to absorb into
the soil when watering the plant.
[Music]
Next, dilute the solution with water at
a ratio of one part solution to one part
water. This helps make the fertilizer
not too concentrated, safe, and easier
for the orchid to absorb.
[Music]
Step one, use a soft cloth to soak up
the fertilizer mixture. Then, gently
wipe both the top and bottom surfaces of
the orchid leaves thoroughly.
[Music]
This method helps remove dust stuck on
the leaves while also supporting the
leaves in absorbing nutrients better,
contributing to keeping the plant
healthy.
[Music]
Additionally, this method helps remove
insects and fungal diseases attached to
the leaves, keeping the orchid clean and
healthy.
[Music]
This is a way to help the leaves
directly absorb nutrients, thereby
nourishing the orchid to be healthy and
develop better every day.
[Music]
Note to wipe thoroughly the underside of
the leaves because this is where many
stamata concentrate, helping the leaves
exchange gases and absorb nutrients most
effectively.
Um the underside of the leaves does not
directly receive sunlight. So it is
often where insects and fungal diseases
tend to gather. Therefore thoroughly
wiping this part is very important to
keep the plant healthy.
[Music]
You should perform this method one to
two times a month to keep the orchid
leaves clean and help the plant absorb
nutrients most effectively.
[Music]
Step two, use the diluted fertilizer
mixture to water each orchid pot
directly, helping the plant absorb
nutrients from the soil effectively.
Doing this once every 2 weeks is enough.
[Music]
We water the roots and growing medium,
helping supply nutrients directly to
where the plant absorbs best, promoting
healthy growth from within.
When you water this mixture onto the
roots and growing medium, it helps
loosen the soil, creating conditions for
the roots to exchange gases well and
absorb nutrients more effectively.
This mixture provides plenty of calcium
and minerals that help orchid roots grow
strong, enabling the plant to absorb
water and nutrients better.
[Music]
Uh, the nutrients in the mixture help
the plant produce new shoots faster,
creating a foundation for future
blooming seasons that are more beautiful
and longlasting.
Step three, put the diluted fertilizer
mixture into a spray bottle. Then spray
evenly onto the orchid leaves,
especially the underside of the leaves,
so the nutrients penetrate deeply and
help the plant become healthier.
Um, when spraying the fertilizer mixture
onto the leaves, the minerals and
vitamins from the eggshells and rice are
absorbed directly through the leaf
surface.
This helps the orchid leaves become
greener and healthier while also
supporting the photosynthesis process
effectively, contributing to enhancing
the plant's vitality.
[Music]
Spraying the mixture onto the leaves not
only provides nutrients but also helps
clean the layer of dust remaining on the
leaves after we wipe them.
[Music]
Additionally, the solution helps reduce
the presence of harmful insects, keeping
the orchid leaves clean and well
ventilated, creating a good environment
for the plant to thrive.
[Music]
Step four. After spraying, use a soft
cloth to gently wipe off any remaining
water on the leaf surface and between
the leaf folds to prevent mold and keep
the leaves well ventilated.
When water remains on the leaves under
sunlight, the droplets can act like
lenses, increasing the risk of leaf
burn.
Wiping off the remaining water helps
prevent this issue, keeping the leaf
surface green and protected from damage
caused by strong light.
[Music]
Wiping the leaves with a soft cloth
after spraying not only helps clean
them, but also gently massages the leaf
surface, supporting deeper absorption of
nutrients.
As a result, the orchid can fully
benefit from the natural fertilizer
mixture.
After finishing the care routine,
remember to place the orchid pot in a
spot with gentle sunlight and good
ventilation. Light is an essential
factor for photosynthesis, which allows
the orchid to absorb and fully convert
nutrients from the fertilizer, helping
the plant recover quickly and grow
stronger each day.
And here is the result after 6 weeks.
You can see the orchid has recovered
strongly with roots developing well.
that
the orchid continues to develop new
flower spikes, promising a brilliant
blooming season ahead.
These new roots will help the orchid
absorb more nutrients, enhancing
stability and vitality throughout its
growth process.
[Music]
You can also see orchid leaves become
greener and sturdier, proving the
plant's improving health.
[Music]
Uh, this orchid pot is the same. Many
new roots have grown and new flower buds
are developing strongly, signaling a
beautiful blooming season is
approaching.
[Music]
Um, the calcium in the eggshells along
with the minerals in the rice water help
stimulate the growth of many new roots,
proving that the natural fertilizer
mixture is very effective.
[Music]
Uh, rice water also helps improve the
plant's health by providing natural
vitamins and enzymes, supporting growth
and fighting pests.
[Music]
With just a few simple steps, we can
care for orchids at home, helping them
stay healthy and bloom brilliantly all
year round.
[Music]
Uh, how do you find my method of
restoring the orchid after the petals
fall? Please leave your comments and
share your thoughts with me.
[Music]
If you encounter any difficulties during
the orchid growing process, don't
hesitate to comment. I'm always ready to
support you so you can grow healthy
orchids that bloom abundantly.
Um, as long as you persist in daily
care, gradually you will have a happy
garden like mine filled with brilliant
flowers.
I hope you will like this video. If you
find it helpful, don't forget to hit the
like button on the video
and subscribe to the channel so you
don't miss the next shares about how to
care for orchids naturally and simply.
[Music]
Thank you for watching the video.
Wishing you joy and success in caring
for your beloved orchid plants.