Hello everyone. It's great to see you on
my channel.
Today I will share how to restore an
orchid suffering from leaf rot so that
it can recover and grow quickly.
If you haven't subscribed to my channel
yet, please subscribe to support me and
and uh not miss any orchid tips on my
channel.
So, let's get started.
You can see that this orchid which was
growing healthily suddenly has some
rotting leaves in the middle of its
stem.
When you encounter an orchid with with
this type of rot, the first thing you
need to do is isolate it from the garden
to prevent the disease from spreading to
other plants.
The cause of this leaf rot in the orchid
is bacteria which leads to orchid soft
rot disease.
In just a few hours, they can make the
orchid leaves become soft, mushy, and
necrotic.
[Music]
If not treated quickly, the rot will
spread to other leaves, down the stem,
and to the roots, causing the orchid to
die rapidly.
After isolating it from the garden, we
proceed to clean up and remove the
rotten parts from the orchid.
[Music]
At the same time, I trim off all dry
branches and roots. Um, this helps the
orchid focus its nutrients on the
healthy parts and stimulates stronger
new root growth.
[Music]
At the same time, removing the withered
parts also helps the plant stay well
ventilated, reducing the risk of fungal
infections and pests.
[Music]
Please comment and let me know which
country you are watching the video from.
It's amazing that we can chat together
from all over the world.
[Music]
In addition to the English dub, we've
now created dubs in French, German,
Italian, Spanish, Portuguese, Japanese,
Hindi, and Indonesian to help you hear
and understand the content more easily.
[Music]
This is cinnamon powder. Cinnamon has
strong antibacterial and antifungal
properties, helping to prevent the
spread of rot in orchids.
[Music]
I take one spoonful of cinnamon powder
and mix it with four cups of boiled
water, about one liter.
[Music]
Then we stir it well, cover it, and wait
until the water cools down before using
it.
[Music]
After the water cools down, we filter
out the residue to obtain the clear
liquid. Squid.
[Music]
If not filtered properly, cinnamon
powder can stick to the leaves and
roots, hindering the plant's respiration
or creating a humid environment that
promotes fungal growth.
Additionally, well-filtered cinnamon
water allows the solution to penetrate
wounds more effectively, enhancing its
antibacterial properties and aiding the
plant's recovery.
Step one, soak a cotton pad in the
cinnamon water mixture and gently wipe
both the upper and lower surfaces of the
leaves.
Cinnamon water helps eliminate bacteria
and fungi on the leaf surface,
preventing diseases such as leaf spots
and soft rot.
The scent of cinnamon repels harmful
insects such as aphids and thris,
helping to protect orchid leaves from
attacks.
[Music]
Removing dirt helps the leaves absorb
light better, enhancing photosynthesis
and promoting healthy plant growth.
[Music]
Thanks to its natural antibacterial
properties, cinnamon water helps orchids
become stronger and more resistant to
unfavorable environmental conditions.
If the plant is healthy, wipe the leaves
once a month to prevent diseases and
improve light absorption.
[Music]
Uh if the plant shows signs of disease,
increase to twice a month to help
eliminate bacteria and speed up
recovery.
[Music]
Note, wipe in the morning or late
afternoon using a soft cloth to avoid
scratching the leaves, allowing the
plant to absorb the natural nutrients
from cinnamon effectively.
[Music]
Step two, pour the cinnamon water into a
spray bottle.
If you encounter any difficulties while
growing orchids, don't hesitate to leave
a comment. I'm always ready to help you
grow healthy orchids with plenty of
beautiful blooms.
Then I spray this cinnamon water onto
the rotting area to clean it. This helps
the wound dry faster and reduces the
humid environment where bacteria and
fungi can thrive.
When the rotting area is cleaned and
dried, the plant will recover more
easily, develop healthy new tissue, and
stimulate tissue regeneration.
Then spray it on the orchid leaves. This
helps clean them and support
photosynthesis by removing dust,
allowing the plant to absorb light
better and promoting growth.
The antibacterial and antifungal
properties of cinnamon water help
prevent the growth of harmful bacteria
and fungi on the leaf surface, reducing
the risk of diseases such as leaf spots
and soft rot.
If the plant is healthy, spray once a
month to prevent diseases and boost its
resistance.
Uh, if the plant shows signs of fungal
disease or pests, spray twice a month to
help eliminate bacteria, fight fungi,
and provide better protection for the
plant.
[Music]
Step three, dry the water on the leaf
joints and surfaces to prevent water
accumulation, reducing the risk of
fungal diseases and soft rot.
[Music]
Use a soft cloth or cotton pad to gently
absorb the moisture, especially in the
leaf joints where water tends to
accumulate.
[Music]
Keep the plant in a well ventilated area
to allow the leaves to dry quickly and
prevent prolonged humidity.
[Music]
Carefully check the base of the leaves
as this is where bacteria and fungi can
easily develop if if water remains.
[Music]
This step helps keep the orchid dry,
healthy, and better able to absorb
nutrients.
[Music]
Then take two cups of cinnamon water,
about 0.5 L.
[Music]
Dilute it with two cups of filtered
water, about 0.5 L.
[Music]
This is beer. Some microorganisms in
beer can help balance the substrate
environment, supporting the plant's
better recovery.
Mix in 5 tablespoons of beer.
When using beer for orchids, it should
be diluted with water as I've instructed
to avoid overloading the plant with
nutrients or causing excessive
fermentation.
[Music]
Step four, water the orchid pot with the
cinnamon and beer mixture to help the
orchid recover faster and grow
healthier.
[Music]
When watering, slowly pour the mixture
around the base of the plant, avoiding
direct contact with the leaves and crown
to prevent water accumulation.
[Music]
Water in the morning or late afternoon
to help the plant absorb nutrients
better and prevent fermentation due to
high temperatures.
[Music]
This mixture provides nutrients from
beer, stimulating root growth and aiding
in faster recovery.
This mixture also improves the growing
medium by introducing beneficial
microorganisms from beer, helping the
plant absorb nutrients more effectively.
After watering, let the roots soak in
this mixture for about 20 minutes to
enhance the recovery effect.
[Music]
After soaking, take the orchid pot out
and place it in a well ventilated area
with gentle sunlight to enhance
photosynthesis and boost recovery.
[Music]
Now, let's take a look at the results
after 3 weeks of caring for and
restoring the rotting orchid.
You can see that new roots have started
to grow from the previously rotting
area. This is a wonderful sign that the
orchid has recovered and is continuing
to thrive.
You can also see that the leaves are
greener and firmer, which proves that
the plant has absorbed enough nutrients
and regained its vitality.
[Music]
And here is another orchid that I also
restored using this method. As you can
see, from the roots to the leaves, it is
thriving after the recovery phase.
[Music]
The growing medium is dry and well
ventilated with no unusual odors. This
indicates that the environment has
improved, reducing the risk of fungal
diseases.
[Music]
And here is the orchid I cared for and
restored using this method 3 months ago.
Now look at its roots. So strong and
healthy, right?
With this simple method, you can easily
restore rotten orchids at home. Right.
With a little patience and the right
approach, your orchid will quickly
recover, grow new roots, turn lush green
again, and may even bloom soon.
Keep caring for and loving your orchids,
and you will be rewarded with wonderful
results. Wishing you success.
What do you think about my method for
reviving weak orchids? Leave a comment
and share your thoughts with me.
If you find this content helpful and
meaningful, don't forget to like, share
so more people can benefit and subscribe
to support my channel. Thank you for
always being with me.
I always pray for God's blessings upon
all of you. For now, goodbye and see you
in the next videos.
[Music]