Hello everyone. Today I will share a
great way to revive wilted orchids,
helping them grow strong and bloom
[Music]
beautifully. Let's explore together.
These are orchids that people have
thrown away.
[Music]
This orchid is dead so it cannot be
revived. This plant is also dead so it
cannot be revived.
[Music]
This orchid is wilted but still alive.
So I decided to bring it home to revive
it.
[Music]
You need to check the roots and cut off
all the damaged
[Music]
ones. Cutting them off helps stop the
spread of bacteria, mold, and other
diseases. After cutting, the orchid will
focus its energy on the healthy roots,
helping the plant grow better.
[Music]
Then cut off the old orchid flower
spikes and withered leaf stalks to help
the plant focus its energy on developing
new parts, including fresh flower spikes
and
leaves. When the flowers have faded,
faded, or the leaf stalks become dry and
wilted, cutting them off not only makes
the plant look tidier, but also prevents
the spread of diseases. This helps the
orchid bloom more vigorously and grow
healthier in the next season.
[Music]
Then soaking the wilted orchid in water
for about 1 hour is a simple yet
effective method to help the plant
recover. This provides moisture to the
roots, making it easier for them to
absorb water and nutrients.
Soaking the orchid also helps remove any
toxins or dirt that may be present on
the roots, creating a better environment
for the plant to recover quickly and
grow
[Music]
healthier. Take a/ teaspoon of sugar.
add it to one liter of
water. Sugar helps revive wilted orchids
by providing an easy source of energy
for the plant. Uh when the orchid is
wilted, it may lack energy due to the
roots not functioning effectively or
being
damaged.
Remember to stir well to ensure the
sugar completely dissolves in the
water. Take one liter of
water and add 3 teaspoon of breadcrumbs.
Breadcrumbs can help the orchid quickly
recover and develop roots due to the
nutritional components they contain such
as vitamins and vitamins and minerals.
When soaked in water, they create a
solution that provides beneficial
nutrients, giving energy to the plant.
In particular, breadcrumbs can stimulate
the growth of beneficial bacteria in the
soil, improving the root environment and
promoting the development of new roots.
[Music]
After soaking for 1 hour, remove the
orchid.
[Music]
Then immerse the wilted leaves in the
diluted sugar water for about 20
minutes.
[Music]
The sugar water provides energy to the
leaves, helping them absorb nutrients
and moisture more effectively. This
process also stimulates cell
regeneration, aiding in the rapid
recovery of the leaves.
[Music]
Then remove it and wipe off any excess
water from the
[Music]
orchid. What country are you watching
the video from? Please leave a comment
for me.
It's so fun that we can chat together
from all around the world.
[Music]
Now let's mix the diluted sugar solution
with the breadcrumb soaking solution.
This solution provides energy from sugar
and nutrients from the breadcrumbs,
helping the plant recover
quickly. The sugar provides
carbohydrates, giving the plant extra
energy, while the breadcrumbs supply
vitamins and minerals, stimulating the
growth of roots and leaves.
[Music]
Then soak the orchid roots in this
combined solution for about 20 minutes.
You need to be careful and soak for a
short time to avoid rotting the roots or
affecting them with too much sugar
residue.
The leftover mixed solution from soaking
the orchid roots can be used to
fertilize other orchids, providing
additional nutrients and energy. The
vitamins, minerals, and carbohydrates
from the sugar and breadcrumbs support
the growth of orchids very well.
[Music]
This fertilizer stimulates flower growth
very effectively. As you can see, this
orchid has developed four new flower
spikes.
[Music]
And as you can see, this orchid of mine
has very well-developed roots after
using this liquid fertilizer.
[Music]
After applying this liquid fertilizer,
soak the roots for about 20 minutes to
allow the orchid to absorb the water and
nutrients
effectively. Then take the orchid pot
out and place it in a location with
plenty of light, but avoid direct
sunlight.
To protect the plant, you should place
the orchid in areas with indirect light
or shade, especially during the intense
midday
sun. After soaking for 20 minutes,
remove the wilted
orchid. You can see that the orchid
roots have become fresher and greener
after soaking in this mixed solution for
20 minutes.
Now I'm planting the orchid in a new pot
to make the recovery process
[Music]
easier. Uh I use spagnum moss as the
growing medium for the orchid to help
retain
moisture. Spagnum moss is an excellent
growing medium because it can hold water
for a long time and creates a stable,
humid environment for the orchid roots
to grow.
[Music]
[Applause]
From now on, you should wa water the
orchid with the mixed solution of sugar
and breadcrumbs once a week.
[Music]
Sugar provides energy for the plant,
helping to stimulate the growth of roots
and leaves. And while breadcrumbs supply
the vitamins and minerals necessary for
the plant's healthy
[Music]
[Applause]
development. The result after 3 weeks.
As you can see, many new roots have
[Music]
developed. When the wilted orchid leaves
are revived and new roots start to grow,
it is a sign that the plant is gradually
recovering. The new roots will help the
plant absorb water and nutrients better
while also providing energy for the
growth of leaves and flowers.
At this point, you can continue to care
for the plant by ensuring it receives
enough light, moisture, and appropriate
fertilization so the orchid can grow
strong and bloom beautifully.
[Music]
I continue to fertilize this orchid with
the liquid fertilizer made from sugar
and breadcrumbs once a week.
[Music]
the result after the next 2
months. Uh, as you can see, the orchid
has recovered and grown very healthily.
The leaves have recovered and are no
longer
[Music]
wilted. The roots are plump and healthy.
And the orchid has produced two new
flower spikes.
[Music]
Give all your love and care to your
orchids and you will be rewarded with
beautiful blooms like a healing remedy
that banishes all worries, bringing joy
and peace to your
soul. I hope you enjoyed this video.
Don't forget to like, subscribe to the
channel, and stay tuned for more helpful
videos. Goodbye, and see you in the next
video. I picked up a rotten orchid that
someone had thrown away.
[Music]
All the roots have rotted.
Which country are you watching this
video from? Please comment and let me
know. Uh it's wonderful that we can
connect and chat with each other from
all around the world.
[Music]
This original part has completely
rotted, so it can no longer be
[Music]
used. Wash orchid branches with water.
Then take one clove of garlic and mince
it.
[Music]
Add 500 ml of water and soak for 30
minutes, letting the flour nutrition
completely dissolve in water.
[Music]
After 30
minutes, wiping orchid branches with
garlic water helps disinfect and
eliminate fungal diseases.
[Music]
Then soak the orchid branches in garlic
water for 10 minutes. This helps
stimulate root and chute growth.
[Music]
10 minutes later.
Because this orchid has many scars from
previous insect bites. So I waited a day
for the orchid to dry completely before
planting it.
[Music]
One day
later, I recycle sponges as orchid
nursery
[Music]
tools. All
right.
[Music]
Soaking the sponge in garlic water for
20 minutes helps disinfect and kill
fungus.
[Music]
20 minutes
later. Insert the orchid stem into the
sponge and place it in the vase.
[Music]
Pour some water into the jar and change
it every time it gets
[Music]
dirty. Spray moisturizer every 3 days
and place it in a cool, well-lit place.
[Music]
5 weeks
later, the roots have grown very
healthy.
[Music]
The roots have grown very healthy.
I planted it in a pot so the orchid
could grow better.
[Music]
If you find the video interesting,
please like and share so more people
know this tip.
[Music]
Water orchids regularly to keep them
moist. Subscribe to my channel to
support me and don't miss any tricks on
my channel.
[Music]
Welcome to part two of this video. Uh in
part two of this video, I share how to
care for orchids to help them grow and
bloom. You can see that my orchids
always develop new flower stems after
the old flowers have fallen off.
[Music]
So, my orchids bloom all year round,
blooming from branch to
[Music]
branch. The flowers on the stems take a
long time to fall off. They can even
last up to 6 months before the petals
drop.
[Music]
Many flowers grow on the same tree.
New roots grow a lot to help absorb
nutrients
[Music]
best. Chubby flower
buds.
[Music]
Help flowers bloom long on
branches. Brilliant flowers.
[Music]
How to make fertilizer as follows. Use
one small carrot weighing about 30
[Music]
g. Cut into small pieces.
Add one liter of filtered water.
[Music]
Puree.
Filter out residue.
[Music]
Add one liter of filtered water.
Then use cotton to soak carrot juice and
wipe both the top and bottom sides of
the
[Music]
leaves. This method helps repel insects
and open the stamata. The orchids will
photosynthesize and exchange nutrients
better.
[Music]
At the same time, orchids also absorb
some nutrients through the leaves,
helping keep the leaves green.
[Music]
second way.
Water this carrot for
orchids. Carrot juice is a good source
of nutrients for orchids, including
vitamins and minerals like beta
carotene, potassium, magnesium, and
phosphorus.
[Music]
uh when the carrot juice is poured into
the orchid pot, it provides nutrients to
the orchids and helps to promote their
[Music]
health. In addition, carrot juice is
also acidic, which helps regulate the pH
of the potted soil and enhances the
orchid's ability to absorb
nutrients. You can soak the orchid pot
in this carrot juice for 20 minutes.
[Music]
Do this one two times a
month. Third way.
[Music]
Mist moisturizing carrot juice for
orchids by spraying both the top and
bottom of the leaves. This helps wash
away dirt and eliminate insects on your
orchids. The nutrients in carrot juice
support orchid health, helping them
thrive and bloom beautifully.
[Music]
However, be careful not to overwater
with carrot juice as it can clog the
water channels in the
orchid. Avoid spraying directly on the
flowers as this can cause them to fall
off
quickly. I hope this video helps you
take better care of your orchids at home
and encourages them to bloom easily.
Um, if you find it helpful and
interesting, please like, share, and
subscribe to support my
channel. Welcome to part three of
today's
video. To give you more options for
taking care of your orchids at home
using organic fertilizer, in this video,
I continue to share methods for making
natural fertilizer from everyday kitchen
ingredients you can find in your
home.
Subscribe to the video so you don't miss
any tips on my
[Music]
channel. Number
one, to make this fertilizer, you need
apples.
[Music]
Apples contain potassium, an important
mineral for orchid
[Music]
growth. Potassium helps orchids develop
stronger leaves, roots, and flowers.
[Music]
Uh, I took the apple peel and put it in
a
[Music]
bottle. Soak in boiled water and leave
overnight.
[Music]
number
two. To make this type of fertilizer,
you need more eggshells.
[Music]
Soak the eggshells in boiled water and
leave overnight.
[Music]
Leave overnight.
After one night, filter the water.
[Music]
So we have fertiliz filizer from apples
and
[Music]
eggshells. First
method, water this fertilizer solution
on the orchid roots.
[Music]
Eggshells provide natural calcium which
is very good for orchids. They help
orchids stay healthy and increase
resistance.
[Music]
Apple peels contain a lot of phosphorus
which is also an important nutrient for
orchid
growth.
Especially during the flowering and
flower development
[Music]
stage. Do this one to two times a month
to supplement nutrition and increase the
orchid's resistance.
[Music]
Second method.
Spray this fertilizer on the entire
[Music]
orchid. This method is similar to using
folure fertilizer.
[Music]
Calcium and eggshells helps orchids stay
healthy and increases their resistance
to pests.
[Music]
Apples contain nitrogen, an essential
nutrient that helps orchids develop
healthy green growth and enhances their
ability to photosynthesize.
[Music]
Do not spray on flowers because wet
flowers will easily fall off.
[Music]
Third
method. Clean the leaf surface with this
liquid fertilizer.
[Music]
The leaf surface will always be clean
and
[Music]
airy. Orchids will photosynthesize
better.
[Music]
Fertilizing regularly one to two times a
month will help keep the leaves
[Music]
healthy. Number
three, you can reuse eggshells and apple
peels to make fertilizer again.
[Music]
Let's check out the results
together. This type of fertilizer
stimulates rooting very
[Music]
quickly. After one month of use, you
will see great results.
[Music]
Many flower buds develop and do not
fall.
[Music]
Blooming flowers stay on the branches
for a long time before
[Music]
fading. Flowers can remain on branches
for up to 6 months before falling.
[Music]
Thank you for watching the video. Good
luck and see you in the next videos.
[Music]