Welcome to Happiness Garden, where
orchid petals are cared for with love
and gentleness, so that every day is
filled with vitality and joy.
[Applause]
If you have an orchid pot with wilted
leaves like this, don't be quick to
throw it away. In today's video, I will
share with you a simple but effective
way to help the plant recover and
continue to thrive.
[Music]
If you haven't subscribed to the channel
yet, please hit the subscribe button to
support me and not miss any orchid
growing tips. It's wonderful to have you
along.
If you see your orchid pot with wilted
leaves like this, don't be quick to
throw it away because behind that
fragile appearance, the plant still has
a chance to revive and bloom
beautifully.
First, you need to remove all the wilted
leaves, old leaves, and damaged leaves
so the plant can focus its energy on
nourishing the healthy parts.
[Music]
Please comment and let me know which
country you are watching this video
from. It's wonderful that we can connect
and chat together from all around the
world.
[Music]
The next step is to completely cut off
the dried or rotten roots, keeping only
the firm and healthy ones to give the
plant a solid foundation for recovery.
That's my helper. Do you have any pets?
[Music]
Um, next I will cut off this old flower
spike. By removing the old spike, the
plant will no longer waste energy on the
useless part, but instead focus on
nourishing itself to recover faster.
[Music]
Uh, after careful inspection, I noticed
that the top of the plant still has the
potential to grow new leaves. This is a
sign that the plant is still alive and
can recover.
[Music]
After that, place the orchid pot in a
well ventilated spot for one day and
temporarily avoid watering so the cuts
have time to dry and the plant can
stabilize again.
[Music]
After that, take two cloves of garlic.
Garlic has antibacterial and
disinfecting properties and is
especially useful in supporting the
recovery of weak orchids.
Because garlic contains many natural
compounds that help prevent bacteria and
fungal diseases, it becomes a great ally
to protect and restore the orchid.
And now slice the garlic into very thin
pieces so that the nutrients can easily
dissolve and work more effectively.
[Music]
Next, take about 20 g of aloe vera
leaves and cut them into thin slices.
Aloe vera will help provide moisture and
nutrients, supporting the orchid to
recover and grow quickly.
[Music]
Then put all the ingredients into a very
clean jar.
[Music]
Next, add one liter of room temperature
water to the jar, allowing the
ingredients to blend and form a
nourishing solution for the orchid.
Then tightly close the jar and let it
sit for one day, allowing the nutrients
from the garlic and aloe vera to fully
blend.
[Music]
After one day, stir the solution well
and then strain out the solids, keeping
only the clear liquid to use for caring
for the orchid.
[Music]
Step one, use a soft cloth to soak up
this solution and gently wipe both the
top and bottom of the orchid leaves,
helping the nutrients penetrate deeply
and support recovery.
Wiping the leaves with the garlic and
aloe vera mixture helps remove dirt and
bacteria on the leaf surface, reducing
the risk of disease and creating a clean
environment for the leaves to
photosynthesize more effectively.
This mixture also provides moisture and
nutrients directly to the leaves,
helping them become healthy and glossy
and enhancing their ability to absorb
light uh thereby supporting the orchid's
recovery and growth.
Step two, pour the garlic and aloe vera
mixture into a spray bottle, ready for
direct spraying onto the orchid leaves
and roots.
Then evenly spray this mixture onto the
orchid stem, leaves, and roots, helping
to provide nutrients and protect the
plant from bacteria while promoting the
recovery process.
This provides nutrients directly while
also acting as an antibacterial
treatment, supporting the plant to
recover faster and become healthier.
Step three, evenly water the roots and
growing medium with this mixture,
helping to provide nutrients, maintain
moisture, and stimulate strong orchid
root growth.
After watering, you can soak the orchid
pot in this mixture for about 5 to 10
minutes or longer depending on the water
retention of the growing medium so the
roots can absorb maximum nutrients.
[Music]
I recycle a plastic bottle into a simple
tool, helping to concentrate nutrients
and stimulate the orchid roots to grow
faster.
[Music]
Pay close attention and follow each step
I guide you through so the orchid can
recover quickly and become healthy.
[Music]
Then put sterilized dry moss inside the
tool, creating a moist and clean
environment for the orchid roots to grow
faster.
[Applause]
[Music]
After that, water regularly and maintain
moisture, helping the orchid roots grow
evenly and the plant recover faster.
I usually water every 3 to 5 days.
At the same time, misting the leaves
with water keeps the orchid leaves fresh
and supports a faster recovery process.
Then place the orchid pot in a spot with
gentle sunlight, helping the plant
photosynthesize effectively and recover
energy faster.
[Music]
And here are the results. After one
month of care, the orchid leaves have
become sturdy and healthier, and a new
leaf has grown at the top.
[Music]
Now, let's peel off the outer layer to
check the inside and see how the orchid
is growing.
Wow, amazing. You can see new roots
sprouting from the orchid stem. They are
growing very strong and full of
vitality.
[Music]
In this way, this method has stimulated
excellent root growth, helping the
orchid become healthy and ready for the
next blooms.
[Music]
These new roots will help the orchid
absorb nutrients and water more
efficiently, allowing it to grow healthy
and bloom beautifully in the future.
[Music]
Thanks to the roots absorbing more
nutrients, the new leaves at the top
grow strong, while the older leaves also
become greener and sturdier than before.
[Music]
Now I will cut across the orchid stem
just below where the roots grow along
the stem to plant it in a new pot and
help the plant grow more successfully.
[Music]
After that, I apply a little toothpaste
to the cut, helping it heal quickly and
prevent infection.
[Music]
[Applause]
Then plant the orchid section just cut
from the mother stem into a new pot,
giving the plant space to grow and
recover better.
[Music]
The orchid growing medium is made up of
large pine bark and some moss, all
sterilized to provide a clean
environment supporting healthy orchid
growth.
Then carefully place the orchid into the
pot, ensuring the roots are evenly
spread on the growing medium so the
plant grows firmly.
[Music]
After planting, place the orchid pot in
a spot with gentle sunlight, ideally
morning sun from the east, helping the
plant photosynthesize and recover
faster.
[Music]
And here is the orchid pot that was once
rotting. But after applying this method,
the plant has fully recovered and is
growing healthily.
This is the lower part of the stem.
After cutting across the mother stem,
since it no longer has the growth tip, a
new orchid has sprouted from the
horizontal part of the mother stem.
[Music]
And this is the upper part of the mother
plant. It has grown many new leaves and
is very healthy, full of vitality.
[Music]
What do you think about the way I
revived this rotting orchid? Don't
hesitate to leave a comment and share
your thoughts. I'm eager to hear your
feedback and experiences.
By caring for each plant individually,
step by step, over time you will have a
garden full of vibrant orchid blooms.
The patience you show today will bring
abundant joy tomorrow.
Start with each small orchid pot.
Gradually, through years of persistent
care, you will transform your garden
into a paradise full of vibrant orchid
blooms and vitality.
[Music]
I hope you enjoy this video. If you find
it helpful, don't forget to hit like and
subscribe to the channel so you won't
miss future tips on caring for orchids
naturally and easily.