Hello everyone. Welcome to the Happiness
Garden channel.
Today I will share a great tip for
taking care of orchids after the flowers
have faded.
This method is especially effective in
helping wilted or weak orchids recover
and grow quickly.
This Phelinopsis orchid has finished
blooming but became wilted and stunted,
so it was removed.
I picked it up with the hope of reviving
it and helping it grow strong again.
And now I will show you how to revive
it.
Uh if you're interested and haven't
subscribed yet, please hit the subscribe
button to support me and not miss any
orchid care tips. It's wonderful to have
you as a companion on this orchid care
journey.
Thank you so much for watching and
sharing this passion with me.
First, we need to remove the yellowing
and damaged leaves from the orchid. Um,
this helps the plant focus its energy on
healthier parts and prevents diseases
from spreading through the damaged
leaves.
[Music]
Then, we need to check the roots and the
orchid's growing medium as after the
flowers fade, the plant often goes
through a resting phase or prepares for
a new growth cycle.
[Music]
Due to the growing medium too wet, many
of the orchids roots were damaged,
resulting in the plant being unable to
absorb enough water and nutrients.
This caused the orchid's leaves to start
wilting, and the plant became weak.
To fix this issue, we need to remove the
old growing medium and replace it with a
new one, ensuring that the orchid's
environment is well ventilated and not
water logged, allowing the roots to grow
healthily and the plant to recover
quickly.
[Music]
Next, cut off the damaged roots to stop
the growth of fungi and bacteria while
also creating space for new healthy
roots to grow.
Uh, this step not only helps the orchid
recover faster, but also allows the
plant to absorb nutrients better from
the new growing medium.
Next, cut off the wilted flower stalks
to help the plant focus its energy on
developing new leaves and roots rather
than nourishing the spent flower stems.
Next, we wash the orchid with water to
remove dust, fungus residues, bacteria,
or any impurities that could harm the
plant.
Uh, in addition to the English
voiceover, we have now created
voiceovers in French, German, Italian,
Spanish, Portuguese, Japanese, Hindi,
and Indonesian to help you listen and
understand the content more easily.
Uh, to listen in your preferred
language, open the video and click on
click on settings, the gear icon to
select the appropriate audio language.
After washing, wait for the orchid to
dry before moving on to the next step.
[Music]
Next, take one aloe vera leaf to make a
natural fertilizer to revive the orchid.
Aloe vera has antibacterial properties,
helping the orchid recover quickly and
grow healthily.
Put the aloe vera leaf into 300 ml of
water and blend it to create a natural
fertilizer solution.
[Music]
After blending, strain it through a
sieve to remove the coarse fibers,
leaving only the aloe vera gel mixed
with water.
After straining, dilute it with an
additional 0.7 L of water to get one
liter of aloe vera solution.
Next, I add three vitamin B1 tablets to
the aloe vera solution to enhance the
recovery effect for the orchid.
[Music]
Step one, use a soft cloth to soak up
this mixture and gently wipe both the
top and bottom surfaces of the orchid
leaves.
Step one, use a soft cloth to soak up
this mixture and gently wipe both the
top and bottom surfaces of the orchid
leaves.
[Music]
Clean and healthy leaves will
photosynthesize better, supporting the
plant's recovery and growth process.
[Music]
After wiping the leaves, soak the entire
orchid in this mixture for about 20
minutes.
Soaking helps the roots absorb the
maximum nutrients from the aloe vera and
vitamin B1, supporting the stimulation
of new root growth and the recovery of
damaged cells.
During the soaking time, you should
place the plant in a cool area, avoiding
direct sunlight to prevent thermal
shock.
Next, we need to prepare the new growing
medium before planting.
I use pine bark chips for planting
orchids because pine bark chips are
breathable and retain moisture well,
helping the orchid grow healthily.
And I add a little moss to spread on top
of the orchid pot, helping to retain
moisture better and create a breathable
environment for the plant's roots.
Then pour boiling water over the pine
bark chips and soak the moss.
This helps sterilize and remove harmful
impurities while also making the growing
medium sum softer and better at
retaining moisture for the orchid
[Music]
and let me know which country you're
watching the video from. It's amazing
that we can chat together from all
around the world.
[Music]
If you haven't subscribed to the channel
yet, please hit the subscribe button to
support me and not miss any orchid care
tips. It's wonderful to have you have
you as a companion.
[Music]
If you haven't subscribed to the channel
yet, please hit the subscribe button to
support me and not miss any orchid care
tips. It's wonderful to have you have
you as a companion.
This helps prevent water logging and the
growth of mold while also allowing the
plant to dry out and be ready to
continue growing.
[Music]
Use a soft cloth or cotton pad to gently
wipe, ensuring that you don't damage the
leaves or other parts of the plant.
[Music]
After the growing medium has completely
cooled, we can proceed to plant the
orchid into the new pot.
Uh this ensures that the temperature of
the growing medium won't harm the
plant's roots.
[Music]
Gently place the orchid into the pot,
covering the roots with pine bark chips
and moss to stabilize the plant and
prevent it from being loose.
[Music]
Uh, make sure the roots are evenly
covered but not too tightly allowing
them space to grow.
[Music]
Next, spread a layer of moss on top of
the pot. This layer helps retain
moisture in the growing medium inside
the pot and prevents water from
evaporating too quickly.
[Music]
Moss also helps create a breathable
environment for the orchid and adds a
natural aesthetic to your orchid pot.
Then place the orchid pot in a cool,
airy spot for 3 days and avoid watering,
allowing the plant to adapt to the new
environment and recover after being
replanted.
[Music]
Then place the orchid pot in a cool,
airy spot for 3 days and avoid watering,
allowing the plant to adapt to the new
environment and recover after being
replanted.
Uh from now on I will care for the
orchid using the aloe vera and vitamin
B1 liquid fertilizer once every 1 to 2
weeks.
Each time I fertilize, I use a soft
cloth to wipe the leaves, helping to
remove dirt and allowing the leaves to
absorb the nutrients from the fertilizer
more effectively.
[Music]
Gently wiping the leaves also helps the
orchid photosynthesize more effectively
while cleaning off impurities that could
hinder the plant's growth.
Uh then water the roots and growing
medium of the orchid with this mixture.
Make sure that the liquid fertilizer is
evenly distributed around the roots and
throughout the growing medium, helping
the plant absorb nutrients effectively.
Water gently to avoid disturbing the
growing medium and help the orchid
develop steadily.
[Music]
After watering, soak the orchid pot in
this mixture for about 20 minutes.
[Music]
Afterwards, take the orchid pot out and
place it in a spot with gentle sunlight
to allow the orchid to photosynthesize
and help the plant grow healthily.
[Music]
Now, let's take a look at the results
after 3 months of reviving the wilted
orchid.
You can see that the orchid has become
healthy again with strong root growth
and lush green leaves.
Um, although the bottom leaves are still
wilted and soft, once the orchid has a
healthy root system that absorbs enough
water and nutrients, it will gradually
recover and begin to grow again.
[Music]
In addition to recovering wilted leaves,
the orchid has also grown two new
leaves. This is a very positive sign
that the plant is developing well and
adapting successfully to its new
environment.
[Music]
And the newly grown roots are very
healthy, bright white and plump,
indicating that the orchid is recovering
well and is capable of effectively
absorbing both water and nutrients.
[Music]
When the orchid roots grow vigorously,
they provide a strong foundation for the
plant to continue producing new leaves
and prepare for the next blooming cycle.
[Music]
I continue to care for the orchid with
the liquid fertilizer mixture made from
aloe vera and vitamin B1 once every 1 to
two weeks so the orchid maintains its
growth momentum with increasingly
stronger roots, lush green leaves, and
readiness for the next blooming phase.
Regular fertilization helps the plant
receive a gentle yet effective supply of
natural nutrients.
After that, I soak the orchid pot in
this mixture for about 20 minutes to
allow the roots to absorb the nutrients
maximally.
[Music]
Um, after that, take the orchid pot out
and place it in a spot with gentle
sunlight to allow the orchid to
photosynthesize.
[Music]
Now, let's take a look at the results
after 5 months of restoring the wilted
orchid.
[Music]
Uh you can see that the orchid has fully
recovered with lush green leaves, strong
root growth, and especially new leaves
that have sprouted.
[Music]
The new leaves that have sprouted are
usually vibrant, green, and glossy,
showing that the roots are functioning
well and the plant is receiving all the
nutrients it needs.
[Music]
How do you think about my method of
restoring this small orchid plant? Don't
hesitate to leave a comment and share
your opinions. I'm really looking
forward to hearing your suggestions and
experiences.
[Music]
Not only has the wilted leaves fully
recovered, but the orchid has also
produced two new flower spikes with
vibrant blooms, proving that the care
and recovery process has been a complete
success.
These flower spikes are not only
beautiful but also a clear testament to
the patience and love we give to our
orchids.
Uh each time you revive a plant, little
by little, your garden will be filled
with the vibrant colors of blooming
orchids.
Patience and careful care will yield
wonderful results. Not only beautifying
your living space, but also bringing joy
every day as you watch the orchids bloom
and showcase their beauty.
[Music]
If you find the content interesting and
meaningful, don't forget to like, share
it so more people can know and subscribe
to support me. Thank you for always
being with me.
Thank you for watching the video. I
always pray that God blesses all of you.
Goodbye.
Welcome to my garden.
In this video, I continue to share how
to make natural fertilizer to care for
and restore orchids after blooming so
they can keep growing and bloom
vigorously in the next seasons.
If you haven't subscribed to the channel
yet, hit the subscribe button to support
me and never miss any orchid care tips.
It's wonderful to have you along.
Now, let's get started.
This is the orchid after blooming that I
bought from an orchid shop at a
clearance price of just $1 per plant
like this.
[Music]
The orchid is in a state where the
flower spike is withered and the petals
have faded and dried.
[Music]
First, we need to trim off the withered
flower spike. This helps the plant focus
its nutrients on the leaves, roots, and
new shoots instead of sustaining the
faded flowers.
[Music]
Then remove any damaged or rotting
leaves. This helps protect the plant
from fungal infections as decaying or
damaged leaves can harbor fungi,
bacteria, and pests.
[Music]
Next, trim off any damaged or rotting
roots as decaying or damaged roots
create an ideal environment for fungi
and bacteria to grow. But removing them
helps prevent the spread of disease to
other parts of the plant.
[Applause]
[Music]
As you can see, this orchid still has a
fairly healthy root system, but because
it hasn't been watered for a long time,
the plant has become weak, causing the
leaves to wilt significantly.
[Music]
Do you have lemons? We can use either
yellow lemons or green ones.
Take half a lemon and squeeze the juice
into a cup.
Lemon has natural antibacterial
properties helping to prevent the growth
of bacteria and fungi in the growing
medium supporting the orchid in avoiding
issues like root or leaf rot.
[Music]
Then dilute it with one liter of room
temperature water.
[Music]
Make sure to strain out the pulp and
only keep the diluted lemon juice.
[Music]
Please comment and let me know which
country you're watching the video from.
It's wonderful that we can chat together
from all around the world.
[Music]
Then dip the leaves into the diluted
lemon juice for about 1 minute. This
helps disinfect and recover the wilted
orchid more effectively.
Lemon juice is acidic and leaving it on
for too long can damage or burn the
leaves. Therefore, it should only be
dipped gently and quickly.
[Music]
Then wait for 1 minute before removing
it. This will help eliminate fungi and
bacteria more effectively.
[Music]
After gently dipping for about 1 minute,
immediately remove the leaves from the
diluted lemon juice to avoid prolonged
exposure to the acid, which could harm
the leaves.
[Music]
Use a clean soft cloth or paper towel to
gently wipe and blot dry any remaining
moisture on the leaves. This helps
prevent mold or bacteria from developing
due to prolonged dampness.
This method helps protect the orchid
from the negative effects of lemon juice
while also providing the benefits of
antibacterial properties and stimulating
the plant's growth.
Next, we dip the roots into the diluted
lemon juice.
Lemon juice has natural acidic
properties that help disinfect the
roots, preventing the growth of mold and
harmful bacteria, especially in cases
where the roots are rotting or diseased.
Diluted lemon juice helps stimulate the
growth of new roots by creating a
favorable environment for nutrient
absorption, which in turn helps the
plant recover more quickly.
[Music]
Soak the roots in this mixture for about
10 minutes.
[Music]
For planting orchids, I use pine bark
chips as the growing medium.
To limit fungi and diseases, I need to
treat the growing medium for the orchids
before planting.
Then I pour the diluted lemon juice to
soak the orchid growing medium for about
10 minutes.
Diluted lemon juice helps reduce the
growth of mold, one of the causes of
root and leaf rot in orchids. This is
important to keep the growing medium
clean and prevent the development of
fungi.
[Music]
Once the growing medium is treated, the
orchid will face fewer harmful
environmental factors, helping the plant
grow stronger and better resist
diseases.
Then we wait for about 10 minutes before
planting the orchid.
[Music]
After soaking for about 10 minutes, we
proceed to plant the orchid into the new
pot.
[Music]
We take the pine bark out to plant the
orchid into the pot.
[Music]
As you can see, after soaking the roots
in the diluted lemon juice for about 10
minutes, the roots become clean and
fresh again, which helps the orchid's
recovery process happen faster.
Carefully place the orchid into the pot,
making sure the roots are evenly
distributed, not bent or cramped.
[Music]
Avoid pressing the plant too tightly
into the pot as this can damage the
roots and affect the plant's growth.
Simply press the growing medium gently
to ensure the plant stands firm without
being cramped.
[Applause]
After planting, spread a layer of dry
moss over the orchid pot. This helps
protect the roots from direct sunlight,
especially when the plant is newly
potted. It reduces the risk of root burn
and helps the roots develop better.
[Music]
After planting, leave the orchid in a
cool, wellventilated place for a day and
do not water it.
Uh, in the first 24 hours after
planting, the roots need time to adjust
to the new growing medium. If you water
immediately, the medium could become
saturated, creating a favorable
environment for mold and bacteria to
grow, leading to root rot. Not watering
helps minimize this risk.
[Music]
Since the orchid has a healthy root
system, after one day, I proceed to
apply natural fertilizer to stimulate
faster growth.
[Music]
To make natural fertilizer, I take a
slice of fresh potato.
[Music]
Place the potato into a blender.
Add 0.25 L of water and blend until
smooth.
Potatoes are rich in vitamins and
minerals, especially potassium,
phosphorus, and some amino acids. These
nutrients help orchids grow stronger,
stimulate root growth, and assist the
plant in recovering quickly after stress
or weakness.
[Music]
Then strain out the residue. Straining
helps make the fertilizer water clearer,
reducing the risk of bacteria and fungi
growing in the undissolved particles.
This also helps prevent harm to the
orchid.
[Music]
[Applause]
Then dilute it with one liter of water.
This helps reduce the concentration of
nutrients in the fertilizer, preventing
nutrient overload that could damage the
plant's roots. It's a good way to
provide nutrients without overwatering
or overdosing the plant.
[Music]
After preparing the potato mixture, use
a soft cloth to soak up the mixture and
gently wipe both the top and bottom
sides of the orchid's leaves.
The potato mixture contains nutrients
like potassium and vitamins which help
directly nourish the orchid's leaves.
Wiping the leaves helps the plant absorb
these nutrients, promoting strong growth
and improving the overall health of the
orchid.
Then pour the potato mixture into a
spray bottle and mist the entire orchid
plant.
[Music]
Um, the nutrients in the potato help
stimulate the growth of new leaves and
strengthen the root system.
[Music]
Spraying the potato water on the entire
plant provides the orchid with extra
energy to recover after periods of
weakness or stress.
Potatoes have natural antibacterial
properties helping to protect the plant
from mold, bacteria, and common
diseases.
Then water the orchid's roots with the
potato mixture.
Potassium and phosphorus in potatoes
help enhance root growth, particularly
by encouraging strong and widespread
root development.
When the roots are healthy and
well-developed, the plant can easily
absorb enough water and nutrients, which
helps it grow more holistically.
Perform leaf wiping, spraying, and
watering the orchid's roots with the
potato mixture twice a month.
Then place the orchid pot in a location
with gentle sunlight so that the plant
can photosynthesize, allowing the
natural fertilizer to work more
effectively.
Now, let's take a look at the results
after 45 days of care and recovery using
the natural potato fertilizer.
Um, as you can see, the orchid has grown
new leaves and become sturdier with a
shinier, healthier green color.
Not only that, but the orchid has also
grown a new flower spike, which clearly
shows that this natural fertilizer has a
positive effect on the plant's growth.
[Music]
I continue to care for this orchid using
the natural potato fertilizer by
following the steps of watering,
spraying, and wiping the leaves twice a
month.
The potato fertilizer helps the orchid
quickly recover from a weakened state or
nutrient deficiency.
[Music]
The appearance of a new flower spike is
a clear sign that the plant has received
the necessary support and is returning
to a phase of strong growth.
Remember
to place the orchid pot in a spot with
gentle sunlight so the plant can
photosynthesize, allowing the natural
fertilizer to work even better.
Now, let me invite you to see the
results after the next 3 months of care
using the natural fertilizer.
[Music]
As you can see, the leaves have become
much greener, sturdier, and healthier
than before.
And the orchid has even produced
multiple flower spikes at the same time
on the same plant.
[Music]
Wow. There are as many as six flower
spikes growing at the same time, which
proves that the fertilizer is really
effective for recovering and caring for
orchids.
[Music]
Your orchid blooming with six flower
stems at the same time is a clear sign
that the fertilizer has had a strong
effect in revitalizing and taking care
of the plant.
That is a great achievement and proves
that the plant is very healthy and
thriving. These are the reasons why
natural fertilizer has had such
wonderful effects.
[Music]
Give your orchid all the love and care
you would give to a close friend.
[Music]
Don't forget with every bit of love you
give, the plant will reward you with
beautiful blooms and vibrant life.
Um, I hope this video brings great value
to you. If you found it helpful, don't
hesitate to share it with those around
you and don't forget to hit the like
button to support me in continuing to
share interesting and useful content.
Thank you all for taking the time to
watch the video. Wishing you a wonderful
day and see you in the next videos.
[Music]