welcome to my
channel if you have a rotten or damaged
Orchid and you want to restore it
quickly and if you don't want to miss
any Orchid growing tips subscribe to my
Channel
[Music]
today uh this is a rotten Orchid that
everyone threw away I picked it up to
revive it
[Music]
the cause of rot is disease causing
fungi and
[Music]
bacteria I remove all damaged roots and
damaged leaves
[Music]
if you haven't subscribed to the channel
yet please hit the Subscribe button to
support me and not miss any Orchid
growing tips it's great to have you
[Music]
along then rinse with
water in addition to the English dub
we've now created dubs in French German
Italian Spanish Portuguese Japanese
Hindi and Indonesian to help you hear
and understand the content uh videos are
[Music]
easier then hang in a cool place for 2
hours to let the Orchid dry
[Music]
naturally I took one aloe vera
leaf then filter to get aloe vera
[Music]
jelly I cut the rest Into Thin slices
um please comment to me which country
you are watching the video from it's
great that we can chat together from all
over the
[Music]
world then puree with two cups of water
about 500 m
[Music]
then filter out the residue
next I took three spoons of
[Music]
rice add 2 cups of water about 500
mL then leave for 2 hours for the
nutrients to completely dissolve in the
[Music]
Water 2 hours
later take aloe vera jelly and wipe the
leaves
[Music]
this helps wilted orchids recover and
grow very
[Music]
quickly at the same time it also kills
disease causing bacteria and fungi very
effectively
[Music]
mix the two types together
soak the roots in this water for 30
minutes this helps the roots not rot and
grow new Roots very quickly
[Music]
then plant the Orchid in a new pot for
the Orchid to recover
[Music]
covering the pot with a layer of moss
helps retain moisture
[Music]
better from now on water this once a
week
[Music]
we and spray this water on the leaves
once a week
[Music]
place in a light and Airy place so the
Orchid can recover easily
1 month
later the leaves become stronger and a
new Leaf
grows and many new Roots
[Music]
grow how do you find the way to restore
your weak orchid please write a comment
to let me know your
[Music]
opinion these new Roots help absorb
nutrients better so the Orchid will
recover very quickly
[Music]
continue watering this once a
week and continue spraying this water
once a
week um if you encounter any
difficulties in the process of growing
orchids do not hesitate to comment for
me I always ready to support you so that
you can grow healthy orchids and Bloom a
lot of
[Music]
flowers after the next 2
months this Leaf has completely
recovered and become
[Music]
Lush The Roots grow strongly and produce
many new roots
with this simple method the Orchid
recovered completely very
[Music]
quickly thank you for watching the video
please share the video so more people
[Music]
know good luck and see you in the next
videos
[Music]
hello everyone welcome to the happiness
Garden
Channel today I'll share an amazing tip
for taking care of orchids after their
flowers have faded this method is
especially effective for helping wilted
or weak orchids recover and grow
[Music]
quickly this is an orchid that has
already bloomed but became wilted and
stunted so it was
discarded I picked it up with the hope
of Reviving it and helping it grow
strong again let's see how I do
it first trim off the old flower Spike
that has long
withered this helps the plant redirect
nutrients to root and leaf growth
instead of sustaining the dried flower
[Music]
stem next upon checking the roots I
found many in organic fertilizer pellets
in green and
[Music]
gray um this Orchid may have wilted
because the inorganic fertilizer damaged
its roots preventing it from absorbing
water and nutrients which cause the
leaves to wilt therefore we need to
remove these fertilizer pellets and
treat the roots to help the plant
recover
[Music]
the roots are severely damaged and dry
uh this prevents the plant from
absorbing water and nutrients
uh the next step is to trim off the
damaged Roots so the plant can focus on
growing new healthier ones
next rinse the roots thoroughly with
water this removes any remaining dirt
old fertilizer and damaged Parts
preparing the plant for recovery
which country are you watching this
video from leave a comment below and let
me
know I'd love to connect and chat with
all of you from around the
[Music]
world to make natural fertilizer I first
take one teaspoon of honey honey
provides natural nutrients and supports
the plant's growth in a safe and
effective
way dilute the honey in 1 liter of
water this makes the solution lighter
allowing it to easily penetrate the
leaves and roots without causing harm
while effectively providing nutrients
[Music]
next I take one aloe vera leaf as it is
excellent for helping wilted or stunted
orchids recover aloe vera provides
moisture and natural nutrients to help
the plant recover quickly and grow
strong add the aloe vera leaf to about
300 M of
water then blend the aloe vera with a
blender until smooth this ensures the
aloe vera is fully mixed into the water
creating a fine smooth solution that can
easily absorb into the roots and leaves
of the
Orchid strain out any pulp or residue
from the aloe vera
mixture this makes the solution smooth
ensuring it can easily penetrate the
plant without clogging or causing damage
to the roots and leaves
[Music]
place the aloe vera leaf in a cup and
pour the aloe vera water over it letting
it soak for about 20
minutes this method helps provide
moisture and essential nutrients
speeding up the recovery process for
wilted orchids
[Music]
after soaking for 20 minutes remove the
Orchid and wipe off any excess mixture
on the
leaves this helps prevent overwatering
or excess mixture reducing the risk of
leaf or root rot
place the Orchid Roots into the
cup this makes it easy easier to observe
and proceed with the next steps in the
recovery
process now mix the honey with the aloe
vera
mixture and here is vitamin B1 which is
great for recovering ing wilted leaves
and encouraging new root
growth vitamin B1 helps strengthen the
plant's resistance and supports its
quick recovery after stress or
weakness then pour this mixture and soak
the Orchid roots for about 20
minutes this helps provide all the
necessary nutrients and vitamins
accelerating the plant's recovery
[Music]
process after soaking for 20 minutes we
take the Orchid out and plant it into a
new pot
planting it into a new pot provides the
plant with the best conditions to grow
and absorb nutrients from fresh
soil I plant the Orchid using moss to
help retain
moisture Moss is a fantastic natural
material that maintains humidity and
supports the plants quick recovery
[Music]
from now on water the Orchid with the
honey Aloe Vera and Vitamin B1 mixture
once every 10 days this will provide
essential nutrients and moisture
promoting quick recovery and Healthy
Growth
[Music]
on regular days if you notice the
growing medium is dry simply water or
miss the Orchid to maintain
moisture this helps the plant maintain
proper hydration and grow steadily
without needing a special mixture
[Music]
then place the Orchid pot in a spot with
gentle
sunlight gentle sunlight allows the
plant to absorb enough energy for growth
without burning its leaves or causing
damage from excessive
[Music]
Sun you can use any leftover mixture to
to water other regular
orchids this will help stimulate root
growth and promote the development of
new chots improving the overall health
and growth of the
[Music]
plants uh you can see this Orchid of
mine which was cared for using this
method has developed many new chotes and
roots and is now healthy the natural
method using honey Aloe Vera and Vitamin
B1 is truly effective and helps the
plant recover quickly
[Music]
the result after 3 weeks is that the
orchid has developed many new emerging
Roots this is a clear sign that the
plant has recovered
strongly and is now in a Healthy Growth
[Music]
phase if you haven't subscribed yet
please hit the Subscribe button and
support my
channel your support is a great
motivation for me to keep creating more
interesting and helpful
[Music]
videos the orchid has sprouted a new
Leaf
bud this is a great sign that the plant
is recovering well and ready to continue
growing in the future
[Music]
the wilted leaves are much fresher
compared to before the recovery
process this is a clear sign that the
plant has absorbed sufficient nutrients
and is on the path to Healthy Growth
[Music]
I will continue to water this Orchid
with the natural fertilizer mixture of
Honey Aloe Vera and Vitamin B1 once
every 10
days this will help the plant maintain
it health and continue to develop strong
roots and leaves in the future
[Music]
next use a soft cotton pad to soak up
the mixture and gently wipe both the top
and bottom sides of the
leaves this helps provide nutrients
directly to the leaves and remove dirt
promoting better plant health and
[Music]
growth then place the Orchid pot in a
spot with gentle
sunlight remember while fertilizer is
beneficial without sufficient sunlight
the Orchid won't synthesize nutrients
properly leading to stunted
[Music]
growth the result after the next 2
months is that the orchid has grown very
well with many new roots and healthy
leaves the Natural Care method with
honey Aloe Vera and Vitamin B1 has
proven to be highly effective
[Music]
you can see the orchid has grown many
new healthy leaves
and it has also sprouted a new flower
Chute which proves that the orchid has
fully
recovered this is a wonderful sign that
the plant is thriving and ready to bloom
soon care for your orchids with all the
love and tenderness in your heart and
nature will always reward your
efforts every drop of water every moment
of care is a gift that brings life
vibrant blooms and endless
Joy thank you for watching wishing you a
joyful and energetic day goodbye and see
you next time