Welcome to my little garden full of
love, where orchid petals bloom in
vibrant colors and every moment of
caring for the plants is a simple yet
profound joy.
Today I'm back with a new natural
fertilizer recipe. Simple, easy to make,
but very effective to continue the
journey of caring for beautiful orchid
pots with you.
If you haven't subscribed to the channel
yet, please hit the subscribe button to
support me and not miss any orchid
growing tips. It's wonderful to have you
with me.
Let's get started.
This is an orchid that has just finished
blooming after a long and glorious
journey. For the past 6 months, it has
used up all its nutrients to keep
blooming continuously, bringing
incredible beauty. That's why the leaves
are starting to wilt as a sign that the
plant needs to recover and be nourished
again from the roots.
[Music]
First, gently cut off the old flower
spike, the part of the plant that has
completed its blooming mission to help
the orchid focus on nourishing new roots
and leaves.
Next, remove the dry leaves. They no
longer nourish the plant and may cause
disease if left in place.
[Music]
The pine bark growing medium is still
dry, airy, and relatively new, so
there's no need to replace it for now.
The plant can still grow well in this
environment.
[Music]
I'll add a layer of moss on the surface
of the orchid pot to improve moisture
retention as the pine bark medium is
currently quite dry and drains quickly.
[Music]
The moss needs to be properly treated to
remove fungi and dried before placing it
on the pot to ensure the orchid safety
and prevent the spread of pathogens.
[Music]
Leave a comment and let me know which
country you're watching from. It's
wonderful that we can connect and chat
from all around the world.
In addition to the English voiceover,
we've also created versions in French,
German, Italian, Spanish, Portuguese,
Japanese, Hindi, Dutch, Polish, Korean,
and Indonesian to help you listen and
understand the content more easily.
To listen in your preferred language,
open the video and click on settings,
the gear icon, to select the appropriate
audio language.
[Music]
A thick layer of moss covering the pot's
surface will help retain moisture
longer, reduce rapid water evaporation,
and create ideal conditions for the
orchid roots to grow strong and healthy.
[Music]
Uh to make today's natural fertilizer,
I'll use garlic, a familiar ingredient
that's very effective in stimulating
root growth and protecting the plant.
[Music]
Take one clove of garlic, gently peel
it, then cut it into a few slices and
place them in a container, ready for the
next mixing step.
[Music]
After placing the sliced garlic in the
container, add one liter of clean water
to prepare. Prepare for the next step in
the soaking process.
[Music]
The next ingredient I need is molasses.
A great source of nutrients that feeds
beneficial microbes and supports healthy
plant growth.
[Music]
Just one teaspoon of molasses is enough
to activate the natural fermentation
process and provide nutrients for the
plant.
[Music]
Next, blend the garlic directly in the
container to fully release its active
compounds, helping the mixture work more
effectively.
[Applause]
[Music]
Cover the container and leave it
undisturbed for 1 day to allow the
mixture to ferment naturally.
[Music]
After one day, stir the mixture well.
Then strain out the sediment to get a
clear solution.
[Music]
The lightly fermented mixture helps
stimulate strong root growth, provides
nutrients, and boosts the orchid's
resistance after blooming.
[Music]
Uh after straining, add one liter of
water to dilute the solution just right.
Ready to use for orchid care.
[Music]
Method one, pour the mixture into a
spray bottle to mist the leaves and base
of the orchid, helping the plant absorb
nutrients quickly.
[Music]
Then spray the mixture evenly onto the
leaves, stem, and growing medium to
provide comprehensive nutrition for the
plant.
This mixture provides essential natural
nutrients that stimulate the roots and
leaves of the orchid to grow healthy,
thereby enhancing the plant's overall
growth and vitality.
Thanks to the antibacterial compounds in
garlic, spraying the mixture helps
strengthen the plant's ability to resist
pests and harmful bacteria, keeping the
orchid healthy and effectively reducing
diseases.
[Music]
When sprayed on the growing medium, the
mixture helps retain moisture longer and
improves the living environment for the
roots, creating favorable conditions for
the orchid roots to grow well and absorb
nutrients and water more effectively.
[Music]
Method two, water the mixture directly
onto the orchid pot to deliver nutrients
deep into the growing medium, helping
the roots absorb effectively and the
plant grow better.
Watering with this mixture directly adds
nutrients to the growing medium,
stimulating healthy root growth and more
efficient nutrient absorption, enabling
the plant to recover quickly after
blooming.
The natural compounds in garlic combined
with nutrients from molasses create a
favorable environment for beneficial
microbes to thrive, helping balance the
microbial system in the growing medium
and preventing diseases caused by fungi
and bacteria.
[Music]
After watering, you can soak the entire
orchid pot in the mixture for about 10
to 20 minutes to allow nutrients to
penetrate deeply into the roots, helping
the plant recover faster.
[Music]
Um, you can use the remaining mixture in
the spray bottle to mist other orchids
in the garden, helping all the plants be
cared for and grow healthier.
For orchids that are currently blooming,
this mixture helps strengthen their
health, prolong the freshness of the
flowers, and provide nutrients for more
vibrant blooms.
Uh for orchids preparing to bloom, this
mixture stimulates the development of
flower buds, helping flowers open evenly
and beautifully while also boosting the
plant's vitality before the flowering
season.
You only need to use this fertilizer
twice a month to keep your orchids
healthy and blooming regularly.
After soaking for about 10 minutes,
gently wipe off any remaining liquid
fertilizer on the leaves and leaf axles
with a soft cloth to keep the orchid
leaves fresh and prevent prolonged
dampness.
While wiping, you also remove dust,
fungi, and insects still clinging to the
leaves, helping the orchid leaves stay
clean and healthier.
[Music]
Then uh take the orchid pot out and
place it in a well ventilated area with
gentle sunlight to help the plant rec
recover quickly and grow better.
[Music]
Remember, no matter how good the
fertilizer is, if the plant lacks
sunlight, it will struggle to grow
healthy and bloom regularly.
[Music]
And here's the result after 1 month of
care. You can see the orchid leaves have
become much greener and shinier compared
to before.
[Music]
Now let's check the orchid roots to see
how they are doing after the care
process.
[Music]
You can see the new roots growing very
strong, proving that the plant is
recovering well and absorbing nutrients
effectively.
These healthy thick new roots will help
the plant absorb water and nutrients
efficiently, thereby restoring the
wilting leaves.
[Music]
Now I will replant the orchid into the
pot, then continue caring for and
fertilizing it to help the plant grow
stronger.
[Music]
Then I continue caring for the orchid
with the lightly fermented fertilizer
made from garlic. Garlic and molasses,
helping the plant recover quickly and
grow sustainably.
[Music]
Uh you should water this fertilizer
mixture two to three times a month to
keep your orchids healthy and blooming
regularly.
[Music]
Or you can also spray this fertilizer
mixture onto the orchid to provide
nutrients directly to the leaves and
stem.
Additionally, you can alternate using
this mixture with other natural
fertilizers to diversify nutrients and
provide more comprehensive care for your
orchids.
After watering, you can soak the orchid
pot in the mixture for about 10 to 20
minutes to allow nutrients to deeply
penetrate the roots, helping the plant
recover faster.
[Music]
Then take the orchid pot out and place
it in a spot with gentle sunlight to
help the plant absorb light and grow
better.
And here is the result after 3 months.
You can see the orchid has fully
recovered and started to sprout two
fresh new flower spikes.
[Music]
The orchid has begun to grow new leaves,
a clear sign of recovery and healthy
growth.
The leaves near the base are still
wilted, but the leaves above have fully
recovered and many fresh green leaves
are growing at the top. This shows the
plant is recovering well and continuing
to grow strong.
[Music]
The flower buds are plump, signaling a
vibrant blooming season is approaching
soon.
[Music]
Thus, with just a few simple steps and
natural ingredients readily available in
your kitchen, you have created an
excellent fertilizer that helps your
orchids recover and grow strong. Be
patient and loving with your plants, so
your garden will always be vibrant with
colorful blooms and vitality.
[Music]
What do you think about how I revived
this small orchid? Uh, don't hesitate to
leave a comment and share your thoughts.
I'm really eager to hear your feedback
and experiences.
[Music]
As long as you stay patient and pour
your love into these little orchid pots,
over time you'll have a garden or
balcony full of vibrant blooms where
every morning begins with gentle colors,
soft fragrances, and simple joy.
[Music]
I hope you enjoy this video. If you find
it helpful, don't forget to hit like and
subscribe to the channel so you won't
miss future tips on how to care for
orchids naturally and simply.
[Music]
If you encounter any difficulties while
growing orchids, don't hesitate to leave
a comment. I'm always here to support
you so you can grow healthy orchids that
bloom beautifully.
[Music]
Thank you for watching until the end of
the video. Wishing you good health,
happiness, and plenty of orchid pots
blooming beautifully all year round. See
you in the next video.