welcome to the little garden full of joy
let's explore the beauty of
orchids if your orchids become weak or
fail to bloom due to improper care don't
worry improve their environment provide
proper nutrition and adjust watering
with patience they will recover and
Bloom
again let's get
started this is an orchid infected with
Leaf rot caused by a fungus
[Music]
we need to separate the disease plant
from other
orchids now I will share how to restore
this this rotten Orchid with only one
leaf
[Music]
left cut off all damaged roots
if you haven't subscribed to the channel
yet please click the Subscribe button to
support me and not miss any Orchid
growing tips it's great to have
[Music]
company leave fresh Roots like this
then rinse with
[Music]
water in addition to the English dub
we've now created dubs in French German
Espanish Spanish Portuguese Japanese
Hindi and Indonesian to help you hear
and understand the content more easily
[Music]
oh this Leaf also
falls watch me restore this leafless
[Music]
Orchid cut off all rotten parts of the
Orchid stem
this will help prevent the Orchid stem
from rotting further
[Music]
then sprinkle cinnamon powder on the cut
to help the wound heal quickly
[Music]
cinnamon powder has very good
antibacterial and antiseptic
[Music]
properties then place in a cool place
for 2 hours to let the cut dry
[Music]
completely take one clove of garlic and
mince
[Music]
it garlic contains allisin a substance
with powerful antibacterial and
antifungal effects helps prevent
diseases and infections in orchids
[Music]
add 500 M of water at room temperature
cover and leave for 2 hours so that the
Garlic's nutrients are completely
dissolved in the
[Music]
water after 2 hours filter out the
residue to get garlic juice
[Music]
after seeing that the cut has dried soak
the Orchid roots in garlic water for 10
minutes
[Music]
this helps to disinfect the Orchid
preventing rot while also stimulating
its growth and quick
[Music]
recovery after soaking for 10 minutes
take the Orchid out and planted in a new
pot to help it help it recover and grow
[Music]
faster use sterilized dry moss to grow
plants dry moss will absorb moisture and
help the cut heal completely
[Music]
then leave it in a cool place and do not
water it for one week to let the cut
heal
[Music]
completely this garlic water is used to
water other orchids in the
[Music]
garden nutrients found in garlic such as
calcium potassium and selenium help
stimulate the growth of orchid Roots
helping the plant recover
[Music]
quickly do this every 2 weeks to
increase the orchid's resistance and
supplement nutrients for the Orchid
[Music]
garlic also has the effect of repelling
insects so it helps protect plant
[Music]
leaves after 1 week we start watering
the orchids again now
[Music]
then use recycled plastic bottles to
create a miniature Greenhouse to grow
[Music]
orchids spray water every time the
growing medium and Orchid or dry
[Music]
cover and place in a cool well-lit
place results after 1 month
[Music]
you can see a new baby Orchid being
revived from the trunk of an old dying
Orchid new Roots also grow a lot which
will help the baby orchids grow
faster from a bare Orchid stem an
extremely healthy baby orchid has now
been revived
[Music]
when the root system is strong we
fertilize it to help the Orchid grow
[Music]
faster take 1/2 teaspoon of flour
add 500 M of room temperature water
about 2
cups using wheat flour helps stimulate
the growth of beneficial microorganisms
in Orchid pots helping increase the
plant's ability to absorb water and
nutrients wait 1 hour before using to
fertilize orch
[Music]
Kids 1 hour later
filter out
[Music]
residue then water this mixture every 2
weeks
[Music]
[Applause]
continue to cover and place in a cool
place with enough light
[Music]
results after 2
months uh the baby orchids have grown
and developed very
[Music]
healthily the root system grows very
healthy leaves are green and sturdy
[Music]
continue using fertilizer from wheat
flour to water the
[Music]
orchids wheat flour contains a lot of
carbohydrates which serves as food for
beneficial microorganisms in the soil or
Orchid growing
[Music]
medium um these microorganisms help
improve soil structure enhance the
ability to decompose organic substances
and help plants absorb nutrients better
[Music]
results after 3
months the orchid has grown stronger and
produced buds
[Music]
growing Roots help the Orchid absorb
nutrients
[Music]
best the leaves are green and strong
this Leaf has a rot disease so it must
be removed immediately
[Music]
continue to use wheat flour fertilizer
to water the orchids every 2 weeks
[Music]
results after 4
months from the bare Orchid stem it has
now revived and grown into a mature
[Music]
Orchid the flowers bloom brightly and
beautifully if you find the video
meaningful please like and share so more
people know
[Music]
and don't forget to subscribe to the
channel to help my channel reach 10
million subscriptions
[Music]
soon thank you for watching and
supporting my channel
[Music]
wishing you success and joy in
life goodbye and see you again in the
next videos