Welcome to my little garden where orchid
branches begin a new
journey. Today I will show you how to
propagate orchids from cutings. Simple
and effective right at
[Music]
home. This is my orchid. It it has
finished blooming and is ready for
propagation. When the petals fade, it's
the perfect time to start propagating
orchids from cutings.
Cut off any damaged leaves so the plant
can grow
stronger. Cutting off damaged leaves
helps eliminate fungi, prevents the
spread of disease, and keeps the plant
healthy. Next, trim off any damaged
roots to ensure the plant grows well.
[Music]
Uh, trimming off damaged roots helps
prevent mold growth and creates
conditions for new healthy roots to
[Music]
grow. Uh, identifying damaged roots is
simple. If the roots are soft, they are
completely damaged. If the roots are
still firm but have a dark brown color,
it is also a sign of damage.
Please comment and let me know which
country you're watching the video from.
It's amazing that we can chat together
from all over the
[Music]
world. Um, if you haven't subscribed to
the channel yet, please hit the
subscribe button to support me and not
miss any orchid growing tips. It's
wonderful to have you as a companion.
Next, trim off the faded petals. This
helps the plant conserve energy and get
ready for the next blooming cycle or for
producing baby plants on the stem if
properly stimulated.
[Music]
The nodes that have already bloomed will
not bloom again and cannot produce baby
plants for baby from
there. Young nodes like this should not
be used for propagation as the dormant
buds are prone to rotting and damage.
Old nodes like this should also not be
used for propagation as the dormant buds
are very hard to
develop. This node is neither too old
nor too young making it the ideal choice
for propagation from cutings.
Um, peeling off the protective layer of
the dormant bud helps nutrients absorb
better when stimulated, allowing the
baby plant to sprout quickly.
In addition to the English voiceover, uh
we have now created voiceovers in
French, German, Italian, Spanish,
Portuguese, Japanese, Hindi, and
Indonesian to help you listen to and
understand the content more easily. To
listen to the language, open the video
and click settings gear icon to select
the appropriate audio language.
[Music]
For languages without voice over, we
have created subtitles to help you
easily read and understand the
content. Bananas when made into GE gel
enzyme are very effective in orchid
propagation from cutings, helping to
stimulate rapid growth.
Bananas when made into GE gel enzyme are
very effective in orchid propagation
from cutings helping to stimulate rapid
growth. Uh next take a pieces of gin to
make GE which helps enhance growth and
fight diseases during the propagation
process.
Then place the sliced banana and ginger
into a glass or plastic jar to prepare
for making
GE. Make sure the jar is clean so that
when the GE fermentss, uh, the mixture
doesn't spoil and maintains its
quality. Next, add.5 L of water to make
it easier for the mixture to dissolve
and ferment effectively.
[Music]
uh leave some space in the jar so that
when it ferments the GE will produce gas
and allow the fermentation process to
proceed
smoothly. Finally, add about 2 tesp of
honey to boost nutrients and stimulate
the fermentation process.
Stir the mixture well so that the
ingredients blend together and ferment
easily.
Close the lid and place it in a cool,
airy spot for 3 weeks. The mixture will
ferment and turn into a highly effective
GE for orchid propagation from
cutings. This is the GE product I made
earlier. Now all you need to do is take
it out and apply it for orchid
propagation from
cutings. Just take about 20 mil of this
GE and apply it to the orchid cutting.
Dilute the GE with one liter of water to
create an effective orchid propagation
solution. Next, I add vitamin B1 to the
mixture to help stimulate root growth
and enhance the plant's health.
Add three vitamin B1 tablets to the
mixture to enrich it with nutrients,
helping the orchid grow stronger.
[Music]
Step one, use a soft cloth to soak up
the mixture. Then firmly attach it to
the node with the peeled dormant bud to
help the nutrients absorb
effectively. This helps stimulate the
dormant bud to sprout quickly and
develop into a baby orchid plant.
Step two, use a soft cloth to soak up
the mixture and gently wipe both the top
and bottom of the leaves to allow better
nutrient absorption.
[Music]
This mixture helps enhance nutrients and
stimulates strong root
development. Vitamin B1 and the
components in the mixture help the plant
resist diseases and
[Music]
stress. Wiping the leaves helps remove
dirt, creating a shiny surface that
easily absorbs light.
When the leaves are clean and healthy,
the plant will photosynthesize more
efficiently, helping the orchid grow
well. Wiping the leaves with the mixture
helps the plant absorb nutrients through
the leaves more easily, especially when
the plant is young or weak after
blooming.
[Music]
Then transfer the mixture into a spray
bottle for easy application on the
leaves and dormant buds.
Step three, spray this mixture on the
leaves, stem, and roots of the orchid to
provide the plant with complete
nutrients.
Spraying the mixture helps the orchid
recover after pruning or during the
propagation process, promoting quick
recovery and rapid
growth. Spraying helps maintain the
ideal humidity for the orchid,
especially in dry environments.
The mixture when sprayed helps stimulate
rapid root growth, especially when the
plant is in the propagation
stage. Step four, spray the mixture onto
this cotton pad to boost nutrients and
support strong growth of the dormant
bud.
Wait about 20 minutes for the nutrients
to absorb into the dormant bud before
removing the
cotton. The leftover mixture in the
bottle can be used to spray on other
orchids in the garden. It will be very
beneficial for their
growth. For healthy orchids, apply once
or twice a month. For orchids being
stimulated to sprout keakis, apply three
to four times a month for best
results. Step five, water the orchid pot
with this mixture to stimulate the
growth of keis on the
spike. Um, water each pot with about 10
tablespoons to provide enough nutrients
for the
plant. When watering with this mixture,
it will provide nutrients that help the
dormant buds on the flower spike grow
quickly and sprout into
keakis. Watering with this mixture helps
the orchid become healthier, increasing
its ability to endure and thrive during
the propagation
process. Apply this to the orchid three
to four times a month to effectively
stimulate the dormant buds to sprout
into keis.
Step six, use a soft cloth to wipe off
any excess mixture on the leaves and
between the leaf crevices to prevent the
plant from staying too moist for too
long, which can lead to mold.
Step six, use a soft cloth to wipe off
any excess mixture on the leaves and
between the leaf crevices to prevent the
plant from staying too moist for too
long, which can lead to
mold. After about 20 minutes, remove the
cloth from the dormant bud to allow the
nutrients to have fully absorbed into
the plant.
Now let's take a look at the results
after 30 days of
care. You can see that the kei has
sprouted and is quite healthy. Uh
proving that this method is very
effective. Although small, the kei
already has roots showing strong
development right from the early stages.
The mother orchid has also grown many
new roots, proving that this care method
helps the plant grow healthy.
You can also see that the orchid's
leaves have become glossy green, showing
good health and growth after applying
this care method.
[Music]
Uh, I continue to care for the orchid
with the natural fertilizer mix from the
GE product to maintain strong and
sustainable growth.
Now, let's take a look at the results
after 45 days of care with the natural
GE fertilizer.
You can see that the kei on the stem has
grown bigger and healthier, proving that
the care method is very
effective. However, the orchid is still
small and not yet ready to be separated
and replanted into a new pot.
Uh, I continue to care for the orchid
with a natural fertilizer mixture from
GE products to maintain strong and
sustainable growth.
[Music]
Uh, I continue to care for the orchid
with a natural fertilizer mixture from
GE products to maintain strong and
sustainable growth.
You can see that the orchid plant
growing on the stem now has leaves and
roots that are developing very
healthily.
[Music]
Uh, the mother orchid has even grown a
new flower spike, showing that the care
method has really helped the plant grow
strong and healthy.
[Music]
This is the perfect time to cut the
orchid pups from the stem and transplant
them into a new pot, allowing the plants
to thrive even more.
[Music]
Before planting, you should disinfect
the cut area or apply candle wax to the
wound to prevent rotting.
[Music]
I hope this video will be helpful to you
in caring for and propagating orchids at
home.
What do you think about my method of
propagating orchids from stems? Please
leave your feedback and suggestions in
the
[Music]
comments. If you encounter any
difficulties during the orchid growing
process, don't hesitate to comment and
let me know. I'm always here to support
you so you can grow healthy orchids and
enjoy many beautiful
[Music]
blooms. If you find the content helpful
and meaningful, don't forget to like,
share so more people can benefit and
subscribe to support my channel. Thank
you for always being with me.
Thank you for watching the video. I
always pray that God blesses all of you.
Goodbye and see you in the next videos.