Welcome to the Happiness Garden channel.
In today's video, I will continue to
share a new method that helps blooms
that have already opened to revive and
bloom again. You will see that with just
a few simple steps, your orchid [music]
can still maintain its vitality and
brilliant beauty after each flowering.
Uh if [music] you haven't subscribed to
the channel yet, click the subscribe
button to support me and not miss any
orchid growing tips. It's wonderful to
have you along.
[music]
So, let's start exploring together right
now.
These [music] are the blooms after the
petals have fallen. You can see that the
plant still retains its vitality inside,
and we can definitely [music] help it
revive.
The buds on the branch that haven't
bloomed are still sleeping [music]
inside and can definitely be awakened to
bloom again if you know how to care for
them.
The blooms that have opened should be
removed so that the [music] nutrients
can focus on helping the remaining
sleeping buds grow. In this way, the
plant will have more chances to produce
many new flowers.
Then sprinkle a little cinnamon powder
on the cut, [music] helping the wound
heal quickly because cinnamon has
antibacterial properties and prevents
mold.
Thanks to this, the plant will recover
quickly and focus [music] its nutrients
on the remaining buds to grow.
[music]
Then leave the plant alone for 1 day
without watering until the cut is
completely dry.
>> [music]
>> This helps the wound heal faster and
prevents harmful diseases from entering.
[music] Um to stimulate the orchid to
grow new buds from the dormant eyes on
the branch, I will use a small onion and
cut it into thin slices.
Onions contain growth stimulating
compounds such as oxin, cytoinine, and
many other nutrients, helping the orchid
branch quickly sprout buds. Thanks to
these compounds, the sleeping buds will
be awakened and get ready to bloom
again. [music]
Then place the onion slices into a clean
jar.
[music]
The next ingredient is eggshells. Take
two eggshells that have been dried,
sterilized, and ground into a fine
powder. This eggshell powder will
provide calcium and essential minerals
supporting the orchid to develop healthy
new buds.
[laughter]
[snorts]
Next, add the eggshell powder into the
jar with the onion.
Then pour the mixture into one liter of
boiling water and let [music] it steep
until the water is completely cool. This
process helps extract the nutrients from
the onion and eggshells, creating a
natural nutrient solution for the orchid
branch.
Uh please comment and you know let me
know which country you are watching the
video from. [music]
It's wonderful that we can connect and
chat together from all around the world.
>> [music]
>> Um, when the water has cooled, strain
the mixture to remove the sediment. Only
use the clear solution to water the
orchid [music] branch, ensuring the
nutrients are absorbed effectively by
the plant.
Uh, step one, water this natural
fertilizer mixture directly onto the
roots and growing medium. two to three
times per month. Doing this regularly
will help the plant absorb nutrients
well and stimulate the sleeping buds to
grow vigorously.
Step two, put the mixture into a spray
bottle and spray evenly over all the
roots, stem, and leaves of the plant.
Um, this method helps the nutrients
penetrate [music] evenly, nourishing the
plant from the inside out and supporting
the sleeping buds to [music] grow
quickly.
Spray the mixture gently, allowing the
solution to soak evenly throughout the
plant. Don't forget to spray [music]
both the top and underside of the leaves
so the nutrients are absorbed optimally.
Do this two to three times per month to
directly supplement [music] nutrients
through the leaves. At the same time,
this method also helps repel harmful
insects and increases the plant's
resistance [music] to pests and
diseases.
Step three, [music] wrap cotton around
the sleeping buds. Then spray the
natural fertilizer mixture directly onto
the cotton to stimulate [music]
blooming. This method helps concentrate
the nutrients on the buds, increasing
the chances [music] of them bursting
into vibrant flowers.
[music]
>> [music]
>> Now spray the fertilizer mixture onto
these cotton pieces. The solution will
soak into the sleeping buds, softening
and awakening them, [music] preparing
for the blooming process.
Do this two to three times per month and
keep keep the cotton on the sleeping
buds for about 30 minutes. This helps
the fertilizer mixture [music] penetrate
deep into the buds, stimulating them to
grow and prepare for blooming.
After letting the cotton sit for about
30 minutes, gently remove it.
[music]
At the same time, also take the orchid
pot out of the fertilizer mixture and
place it in a spot with gentle sunlight.
[music] Remember to do this regularly
two to three times per month so the
plant absorbs nutrients well [music] and
the sleeping buds grow vigorously.
[music] And here are the results after 6
weeks of recovery care. You can see many
new flower spikes emerging from the
sleeping buds on the old orchid branch,
proving that this care method is truly
effective.
Looking at these new flower spikes, you
will see that with just a little
patience and love for the plant, all
your care efforts are rewarded. Trust
that your orchid can also revive,
[music] bloom brilliantly, and be full
of vitality after just a few weeks of
proper care.
What do you think about the way I
revived this little orchid? Don't
hesitate to leave a comment and share
your thoughts. I'm very eager to hear
your feedback and experiences.
If you encounter any difficulties in
growing orchids, [music] don't hesitate
to comment. I'm always ready to support
you so you can grow healthy orchids that
bloom abundantly.
[music]
Take care of your orchid with all your
love and patience. Every small effort
brings [music] wonderful results, and
you will be rewarded with vibrant,
healthy flowers right at home. Don't
forget to follow the plant's progress
and enjoy the joy of seeing [music] the
sleeping buds slowly bloom.
I hope [music] you enjoy this video. If
you find it helpful, don't forget to
like and subscribe to the channel so
[music] you won't miss future tips on
caring for orchids naturally and easily.
Thank you all for watching. Goodbye and
wishing [music] you a beautiful day full
of joy and vibrant orchid blooms. See
you in [music] the next video.
Welcome to part two of today's video on
the Happiness Garden channel.
In this video, I will share a simple way
[music] to help a sick orchid recover
quickly while also stimulating the plant
to produce many keis at the same time.
Thanks to that, in one orchid pot,
[music] you will see many young plants
growing together, bringing a brilliant
blooming season with lots of [music]
flowers.
Let's get started.
This is an [music] orchid suffering from
rot mainly caused by the attack of fungi
and bacteria [music] which damage and
weaken the leaves.
If rot is not treated in time, [music]
it will quickly spread and can cause the
entire orchid to die.
>> [music]
>> Uh please comment and let me know which
country you are watching the video from.
It's wonderful that we can connect and
chat [music] from all over the world.
The rotten parts after being removed
[music] need to be carefully disinfected
or destroyed far from the garden to
avoid spreading to other plants.
>> [music]
>> Um, I need to check the roots because
when an orchid rots, it is often due to
water logging in the roots, [music]
which causes root suffocation and
gradual weakening of the plant.
[music]
It is necessary to cut off all the
damaged roots, helping the orchid avoid
the spread of pathogens [music]
and creating conditions for new healthy
roots to grow.
If you [music] haven't subscribed to the
channel yet, click the subscribe button
to support me and not miss any orchid
growing tips. It's wonderful to have you
along for the journey.
After that, [music] wash the orchid
thoroughly with water to completely
remove any remaining bacteria and fungi.
>> [music]
>> Next, prepare four cups of water,
approximately one liter, to proceed with
the next care step for the orchid.
Then [music] add five tablets of vitamin
B1, each 2.5 mg. Vitamin B1 helps the
orchid recover quickly, stimulates new
root growth, and [music] boosts
resistance.
[music]
Next, take an aloe vera leaf and cut it
into thin slices. Aloe vera is rich in
nutrients, very good for restoring weak
orchids and helping the roots grow
quickly.
>> [music]
>> Add the aloe vera slices together with
the vitamin B1 to create a nutrient
mixture that helps the orchid recover
quickly and stimulates root growth.
Then wait about 30 minutes for the
nutrients to fully dissolve in the
water, ready for [music] the next care
step for the orchid.
>> [music]
>> Then strain the water to remove the
residue, keeping [music] only the
nutrient-rich solution for the orchid.
Then use this solution to soak the
orchid's roots for about 20 minutes,
helping [music] the roots absorb
nutrients, recover quite quickly, and
stimulate healthy growth.
[music]
I chose crushed pine bark as the growing
medium because it helps maintain just
the right moisture and [music] ensures
good drainage for the orchid.
Then [music] gently place the orchid
into the growing medium, keeping the
roots comfortable and free from bending
or damage.
The white beads are resin beads used in
hydroponic [music] gardening. When mixed
with crushed pine bark, they help
increase irration for the orchid [music]
roots.
Finally, add a thin layer of moss on top
to retain moisture and create a good
environment for the orchid roots to
grow. [music]
Then take [music] cotton balls and soak
them in the vitamin B1 and aloe vera
mixture. Then use them to wrap the
orchid's [music] roots, helping retain
moisture and allowing the roots to
absorb nutrients and recover quickly.
>> [music]
[music]
>> Wrap for one day and then remove. This
helps stimulate the roots and new shoots
to grow quickly. [music]
Then pour the nutrient mixture into a
spray bottle for easy application onto
the orchid.
From now on, spray this solution onto
the leaves, roots, and growing medium of
the orchid once a week to help the plant
stay healthy and [music] grow well.
Or you can also pour this mixture
directly onto the roots and growing
[music] medium, helping the orchid
absorb nutrients faster and grow
healthily.
[music]
>> [music]
>> Then place the orchid pot in a cool area
with sufficient light, allowing the
plant to stabilize and adapt well to the
new [music] environment.
[music]
After one day, remove the cotton from
the orchid's roots, allowing the roots
to continue growing normally.
[music]
Then take a transparent plastic [music]
box and place it over the plant like a
mini greenhouse to retain moisture and
protect the young [music] orchid.
Uh place the orchid pot in a cool, airy
[music] spot with gentle sunlight,
preferably morning eastacing sun, so the
plant can photosynthesize effectively
[music]
and synthesize nutrients well.
Continue spraying the aloe vera and
vitamin B1 mixture onto the plant once a
week to help the orchid grow healthily
and recover quickly.
Or you can pour this mixture directly
onto the orchid [music] once a week,
helping the plant absorb nutrients and
grow healthily.
Remember to place the orchid pot in a
spot with [music] gentle sunlight so the
plant can photosynthesize well and
absorb plenty of nutrients, helping the
roots and leaves [music] grow healthily.
And here is the result. After 1 month of
care and recovery using the vitamin B1
and aloe vera mixture, [music] the
orchid grows healthily and blooms
beautifully.
You can see that the orchid has grown
two shoots on [music] both sides which
shows that the plant is recovering well
and growing vigorously.
[music]
Continue spraying the aloe vera and
vitamin B1 mixture [music] onto the
plants a week to maintain healthy
growth.
Or you can pour this mixture directly
onto the roots and growing medium,
[music] helping the orchid absorb
nutrients quickly and grow healthily.
And remember to place the orchid [music]
pot in a spot with gentle sunlight so
the plant can photosynthesize well and
absorb nutrients effectively.
And here is the result after another
month.
You can see that two young orchids
growing from the mother plant are
developing healthily, but they have not
rooted yet. Therefore, continued care is
needed for the young plants to grow
roots [music] and develop stably.
Continue pouring the aloe vera and
vitamin B1 mixture [music] once a week
to help to help the young orchids grow
healthily and develop roots faster.
Or you can spray this mixture onto the
entire orchid once a week, helping the
plant absorb [music] nutrients and grow
evenly.
[music]
And remember to place the orchid pot in
a spot with gentle sunlight. You can use
a specialized orchid sunshade net to
protect the plant and enable effective
photosynthesis.
[music]
And here is the result after the next 2
months.
You can see that the orchid has
developed healthy roots, stems, [music]
and leaves, which indicates.
You can also see the orchid is producing
new flower spikes, promising a brilliant
blooming season ahead.
>> [music]
>> The leaves have become green and sturdy,
which shows that the fertilizer and
nutrients are working effectively,
[music] helping the orchid stay healthy.
When you care for an orchid with all the
love you have for plants, it will not
disappoint [music] you. The plant will
reward you with many buds on a single
stem.
[music]
These buds will not fall off and will
soon bloom, bringing fresh and vibrant
flowers.
Thanks to careful and consistent care,
[music] the orchid will grow vigorously
with lush green leaves, strong roots,
and continuously emerging flower [music]
spikes, promising a brilliant blooming
season.
And [music] when there is enough
sunlight, your orchids will bloom all at
once, creating a garden full of vibrant
colors and [music] delightful fragrance.
Every blooming flower is the result of
the love and patience you give to the
plant, turning your garden into a
vibrant [music] and colorful paradise.
And it is these moments that bring joy,
relaxation, and happiness as you see
your orchids grow, bloom, and shine in
the garden.
I hope you enjoy this video. If you find
it helpful, don't forget to like and
subscribe to the channel so you won't
miss future tips on caring for orchids
naturally and easily.
Thank you all for watching. Goodbye. And
I wish you always have healthy orchids
that bloom beautifully and bring lots of
[music] joy to your garden.