hello
everyone today I'm excited to share a
wonderful way to care for your orchids
using natural fertilizer made from
everyday kitchen
[Music]
ingredients this simple trick will help
your orchids grow strong and Bloom
[Music]
longer let's dive into how to make this
easy fertilizer that anyone can
create to create natural fertilizer for
orchids I need one ripe
[Music]
banana cut banana into thin slices
bananas are rich in potassium an
essential mineral that improves plant
Health enhances stress resistance and
stimulates
blooming when bananas decompose they
provide easily absorbable nutrients for
plants promoting rapid growth for
orchids
[Music]
bananas provide food for beneficial
microorganisms in the soil helping
balance the microbial ecosystem and
promoting root
[Music]
growth then you put the bananas in the
jar please comment to me which country
you are watching watching the video from
it's great that we can chat together
from all over the
[Music]
world add 1500 ml warm
water if you haven't subscribed to the
channel yet please subscribe to support
me and not miss any orchid care tips
[Music]
next I use eggshells as
fertilizer eggshells have alkaline
properties that help balance soil pH
creating an ideal environment for
orchids
[Music]
gr eggshells Supply other minerals such
as magnesium and phosphorus which are
essential for plant growth
put 2 tablespoons of eggshell powder
into the
[Music]
jar uh in addition to the English dub
we've now created dubs in French German
Italian Spanish Portuguese Japanese
Hindi and Indonesian to help you hear
and understand the content videos are
easier then been place in a cool place
for 3 weeks to create fermented GE
fertilizer from bananas and eggshells
which is very good for
[Music]
orchids this is a GE product fermented
from bananas and eggshells that I made 3
weeks ago
take 50 m of GE fermentation
[Music]
solution uh a good product after
fermentation must have the aroma of
banana
mix with 2 L of water
[Music]
method
one water this liquid fertilizer into
each Orchid
pot uh this solution delivers a rich
supply of essential nutrients to the
plants including uh potassium from
bananas and calcium from eggshells
promoting Healthy
[Music]
Growth um the nutrients in the solution
encourage the blooming process leading
to more vibrant and longer lasting
flowers the fermented solution enhances
soil fertility creating a conducive
environment for root development and
beneficial
microorganisms do this once every 2
weeks method two
if you have many Orchid pots you can put
this solution in a spray
[Music]
bottle then spray the entire orchid
spraying the solution delivers nutrients
directly to the leaves and other parts
of the plant supporting overall
growth the ingredients in the solution
promote photosynthesis making leaves
Greener and healthier
spraying this solution helps the plant
improve its resilience to harsh
environmental conditions such as heat or
[Music]
drought the fermentation solution
encourages the growth of beneficial
microorganisms on the leaf surface
supporting overall plant health
[Music]
uh the combination of nutrients and
beneficial microorganisms helps reduce
the risk of diseases and pests on the
[Music]
plant with these benefits spraying the
fermented solution from bananas and
eggshells will be an effective method
for caring for and protecting orchids
[Music]
standing water can create a favorable
environment for mold and disease
development especially in humid
conditions
[Music]
wet leaves can reduce the efficiency of
photosynthesis due to light being
reflected or absorbed
[Music]
ineffectively drying them enhances
photosynthesis if the fertilizer
solution contains concentrated nutrients
standing water can lead to Leaf burn
when exposed to direct
[Music]
sunlight um dry leaves allow for better
absorption of nutrients through the leaf
surface
[Music]
wiping off excess water helps maintain
the overall health of the plant avoiding
issues caused by high
humidity uh do this one to two times a
month and you will get great results
uh after soaking for about 20 minutes
take the Orchid pot out and place it in
a place in a place with lots of
scattered light so the Orchid can
photosynthesize well
[Music]
let's see the
results orchid leaves are always sturdy
and shiny green
[Music]
new Roots develop and the root system
remains healthy and rot
[Music]
free strong roots help plants absorb
water and nutrients from the growing
medium effectively
[Music]
a healthy root system helps plants
resist disease and harsh environmental
[Music]
conditions Roots also store energy
supporting the plant through different
stages of growth
[Music]
well-developed Roots facilitate
effective gas exchange enhancing the
plants respiratory ability
[Music]
when orchids have healthy Roots the
flowers have bright colors symmetrical
shapes and are not deformed
flowers will Bloom profusely and
simultaneously without falling
[Music]
prematurely the plant will produce more
flower buds resulting in a greater
number of flowers blooming each
flowering
[Music]
season thank you for watching the video
wishing you luck and success in life