Welcome to the happiness garden, where
we take care of flowers and plants
together and find peace in every green
moment.
In this video, I continue to share how
to make natural fertilizer for orchids,
helping them grow exceptionally and
bloom outstandingly.
Let's get started.
If you haven't subscribed to the channel
yet, please hit the subscribe button to
support me and not miss any orchid
growing tips. It's wonderful to have you
along.
In my hand here is a package of seaweed,
a simple but very nutritious ingredient
for plants.
Seaweed is known as a versatile,
nutritious, and healthy food. And
[Music]
however, few people know that seaweed is
also a wonderful ingredient for making
fertilizer, especially helping orchids
grow healthy.
In this video, we will guide you on how
to use seaweed to make magical
fertilizer, helping orchids grow strong
and bloom all year round.
You only need to use a piece of seaweed
like this.
And add about 15 to 20 g of fresh
ginger.
[Music]
Add one liter of room temperature water
to the mixture.
[Music]
Then blend everything thoroughly.
Then strain out the pulp.
[Music]
Please comment to let me know which
country you are watching the video from.
It it's wonderful that we can chat
together from all around the world.
[Music]
Step one, use a soft cloth to soak up
the mixture. Then gently wipe thoroughly
both the top and bottom of the leaves.
[Music]
ginger has very good antiseptic
properties helping to eliminate fungi
and parasitic insects on orchids.
At the same time, ginger and seaweed
provide many essential minerals that
help plants grow healthy.
[Music]
When you wipe like this, the orchid will
absorb some nutrients through the
leaves, helping the leaves stay green
and lush.
[Music]
Regularly wiping the leaves helps open
the stamata, creating better conditions
for oxygen and carbon dioxide exchange
for the plant.
[Music]
After doing this, the orchid will more
easily synthesize chlorophyll, helping
the leaves stay green and healthy.
[Music]
The leaves will become stronger and
healthier day by day.
You should apply this method to your
orchid once a month to keep the plant
healthy.
Step two,
[Music]
dilute the entire mixture with 2 L of
water before watering.
[Music]
Then water each orchid pot with this
mixture.
[Music]
During watering, you can also soak the
entire orchid pot in this water to help
the roots absorb nutrients better.
[Music]
Seaweed contains many natural nutrients
and minerals such as nitrogen,
phosphorus, and potassium, which are
very good for the development of
orchids.
[Music]
Nitrogen N helps promote the growth of
leaves, shoots, branches, and orchid
roots.
[Music]
Phosphorus P plays an important role in
promoting the development of roots and
flowers.
[Music]
Potassium K helps plants resist water
logging, increase resistance, and reduce
pests and diseases.
[Music]
Seaweed also contains a lot of natural
calcium, CA, which helps strengthen
resistance and develop the skeletal
system for orchids.
[Music]
Seaweed also contains a lot of natural
magnesium, Mg supporting the metabolic
process to help plants grow healthy.
[Music]
Thanks to the abundant nutrients from
seaweed, this fertilizer helps provide
all the necessary nutrients for orchids
to grow healthy.
[Music]
This helps orchids receive sufficient
nutrition, contributing to more abundant
blooms.
The flowers are always more radiant and
retain their color longer on the stem
before wilting.
[Music]
I hope you'll like this video. If you
find it useful, don't forget to hit like
and subscribe to the channel so you
won't miss the next shares on how to
care for orchids naturally and simply.
[Music]
Thank you for watching the video.
Wishing you always happiness and your
orchids always healthy and green.
[Music]
Hello everyone. Thank you for visiting
my garden.
Today, I'm very excited to continue
sharing with you how to propagate
orchids through cutings at home using
very simple ingredients that you can
easily find in your kitchen.
[Music]
If you find this helpful, don't forget
to subscribe to the channel to support
me and to make sure you don't miss any
tips on plant care.
As you can see, this orchid has finished
blooming, and this is the perfect time
for us to start the process of
propagating orchids from cutings.
I will cut across this old flower stem
to begin the process of propagating the
orchid through cutings.
We need to cut neatly to avoid crushing
the cut, creating the best conditions
for the orchid cutting to grow into a
strong, healthy, young plant.
Next, we remove the protective layer
around the dormant bud to help stimulate
it to sprout faster, which will
encourage the young plant to grow strong
and quickly.
[Music]
Next, I take an onion as onions contain
a lot of nutrients and natural compounds
that are great for orchid propagation.
Um, the components in onions, especially
antioxidants and ends, help stimulate
root formation and enhance the growth
potential of the young plant.
[Music]
Onions also help prevent mold and
harmful bacteria, keeping the cutting
healthy throughout the development
process.
I put the onion in here to extract the
onion juice.
[Music]
Please comment and let me know which
country you're watching the video from.
It's so amazing that we can chat
together from all around the world.
Do as I did, then wait for about 10
minutes to allow the onion juice to soak
into the cutting.
[Music]
Uh after soaking the cutting in onion
juice for about 10 minutes, take it out
and let the cut dry naturally for a few
hours.
This helps the cut to heal, reducing the
risk of infection and creating optimal
conditions for root development later
on.
Then apply a special plant glue to the
cut, which helps prevent water from
seeping into the wound. This will
protect the cut from bacteria and mold,
thus preventing rot and allowing the new
plant to grow healthily.
Then place the cutting in a cool well
ventilated area to allow the glue to dry
completely.
This will help the glue dry evenly and
form a solid protective layer preventing
bacterial infection and supporting
better growth of the plant.
While waiting for the glue to dry
completely, take one teaspoon of
cinnamon powder and soak it in one lit
of hot water to treat the growing medium
before inserting the cutting.
Cinnamon powder has antibacterial and
antifungal properties, helping to clean
the growing medium, prevent the growth
of harmful bacteria, and create a safe
environment for the cutting to develop.
[Music]
After the water cools, filter out the
residue to leave only the clear liquid
ready to be used for treating the
growing medium.
This ensures that the growing medium
will not be contaminated with
impurities, providing the best
conditions for the development of orchid
roots.
[Music]
Then soak the dry moss in the cinnamon
water for about 20 minutes. This will
help the moss of absorb nutrients from
the cinnamon water while also
disinfecting it and creating a good
environment for the development of
orchid roots during the rooting process.
[Music]
Then remove the moss and let it drain.
The moss has now been treated and is
ready to be used as a growing medium for
rooting orchid cutings.
I have recycled a plastic bottle to
create a mini greenhouse which helps
speed up speed up the rooting process
and ensures better results for the
orchid cutings. Here I have created
ventilation holes in the plastic bottle
to ensure air flow helping to prevent
excessive moisture buildup.
Uh I also made drainage holes at the
bottom of the plastic bottle to prevent
water from accumulating which could
cause root rot in the cutings.
[Music]
After placing the moss inside, we will
insert the cutting and mist it regularly
to maintain moisture. This helps keep
the humidity stable for the cutting,
creating a favorable environment for
root development and allowing the young
orchid to sprout healthily.
[Music]
Then place the mini greenhouse in a spot
with gentle sunlight and good
ventilation and continue to wait for the
orchid to sprout.
Soft light will help stimulate the
growth process without causing the
cutting to get sunburned or lose
moisture too quickly. Be patient. Those
lovely little sprouts will appear soon.
Now, let's take a look at the results
after 3 weeks of rooting the cutting.
[Music]
As you can see, the dormant bud has now
sprouted. This shows that the cutting
has adapted well to the environment,
absorbed enough nutrients, and has begun
developing into a healthy young plant.
[Music]
I continue to mist regularly and place
the cutting in a spot with gentle
sunlight to maintain ideal conditions.
Uh helping the cutting develop steadily
and allowing the sprout to grow
healthily.
[Music]
Now, let's check the results after 3
months of rooting the cutting.
As you can see, the young orchid has
grown healthily with lush green leaves
that are strong and sturdy.
[Music]
The roots have also developed strongly,
proving that the rooting process was
successful and the orchid is growing
well.
[Music]
Once the roots are strong and the plant
is sturdy, transferring the orchid to a
pot will help it grow better, providing
ample space for the plant to continue
thriving.
[Music]
Now I can transplant the young orchid
into a new pot so it can thrive in an
outdoor environment.
[Music]
I recycle plastic bottles into orchid
pots using the semihydroponic method.
This method helps the orchid receive
sufficient moisture from the water at
the bottom of the pot while keeping the
roots well ventilated and preventing
water logging, creating ideal conditions
for the plant's growth.
[Music]
with this planting method. After
planting, I only need to water once and
change the water when it becomes dirty
in the pot.
The semihydroponic method helps maintain
moisture for the plant without the need
for frequent watering while also
promoting strong and healthy root
development.
The semihydroponic method helps maintain
moisture for the plant without the need
for frequent watering while also
promoting strong and healthy root
development.
[Music]
If you haven't subscribed to the channel
yet, please hit the subscribe button to
support me and not miss any orchid care
tips. It's wonderful to have you along
on this journey of caring for and
propagating orchids.
[Music]
Thank you for watching the video.
Goodbye and see you in the next ones.
Wishing you beautiful and healthy
orchids.