welcome back to happiness
Garden orchids are special plants that
require proper care to thrive and Bloom
beautifully all year
[Music]
round today I'll guide you on how to
make natural fertilizer using simple
easyto find ingredients that you
probably already have at
[Music]
home this method is not only budget
friendly but also incredibly safe for
your plants
let's dive in and get
[Music]
started today I used coffee grounds to
make natural
fertilizer take one cake of coffee
grounds about 20 G
[Music]
the next ingredient I used is eggshells
to make natural
fertilizer take clean dry eggshells and
crush them into small
pieces coffee grounds provide nitrogen
for Lush leaves while eggshells add
calcium to strengthen roots
the mild acidity of coffee grounds pairs
with the alkalinity of eggshells to
create a balanced pH suitable for
orchids
[Music]
put everything in a
jar add 1 liter of boiling
[Music]
water if you haven't subscribed to the
channel yet please click the Subscribe
button to support me and not miss any
Orchid growing
[Music]
tips in addition to the English voice
over we have now created voiceovers in
French German Italian Spanish and
Portuguese to help you listen to and
understand the video content more
easily how to select the audio language
on YouTube One open the video and click
on settings the gear icon two select
subtitles CC three click on audio and
choose the language you want English
France Deutsch Italiano espanol or
Portugese cover the jar and let it steep
until the water cools completely usually
takes one to 2
hours once cooled strain out the solids
and keep the
liquid um I don't watch videos but if
you want to know where your viewers are
watching from feel free to ask them to
share in the
comments it's great that we can chat
together from all over the
[Music]
world add 1 liter of water
step
[Music]
one use a soft cotton pad to gently wipe
the upper and lower sides of the leaves
with this
solution this method will remove dust
helping the plant breathe better by
keeping the stamata
[Music]
open this fertilizer solution helps
prevent certain pests or fungi due to
the mild acidity from the coffee grounds
and minerals found in eggshells
uh wiping the leave leaves help Supply
additional nutrients directly to the
plant especially to weak areas or parts
that show signs of nutrient deficiency
it's good to wipe the leaves with this
solution once every 1 to 2 weeks to
provide nutrients and help the plant
Thrive if you need to clean the leaves
or remove dust you can wipe the leaves
once a week
[Music]
step
two next we put this solution into a
spray bottle and spray it on each Orchid
pot uh shake the spray bottle before use
to ensure the solution is well mixed
lightly spray the solution on both the
top and underside of the leaves avoiding
the flowers to prevent
damage you can also spray around the
roots if accessible
spray the fertilizer solution once a
week or as
needed be sure not to overspray the
plant to avoid water logging
[Music]
step
three water the orchid's growing medium
focusing on the roots and around the
base of the
plant avoid watering directly onto the
leaves or flowers to prevent damage
uh water the Orchid with the fertilizer
solution once a week or as
needed if the solution feels too
concentrated you can dilute it with
water especially if the plant shows
signs of being
sensitive soak the Orchid pot in the
fertilizer solution for about 20 minutes
to allow the roots to absorb enough
water and nutrients
[Music]
after soaking remove the pot from the
solution and allow it to drain before
placing it back in its usual
[Music]
spot step
four after watering or soaking the
Orchid pot in the fertilizer solution
gently use the cloth to absorb any
excess water on the surface of the
leaves both the top and Underside
[Music]
be sure to absorb thoroughly so there is
no water left on the leaves which helps
the plant avoid water logging and allows
it to better absorb the nutrients
[Music]
then place the Orchid pots in a spot
with gentle sunlight to help the orchids
photosynthesize
[Music]
well however avoid direct sunlight
especially the harsh midday Sun as it
can cause Leaf burn heat shock and
stress to the
[Music]
plants results after 1
month uh as you can see the roots have
developed quickly
and are very
[Music]
healthy healthy new Roots promote faster
growth providing a strong foundation for
the plant to bloom and
develop healthy new Roots promote faster
growth providing a strong foundation for
the plant to bloom and develop enhancing
its resilience against harsh
factors you can see that the orchid has
produced many new flower
spikes you see on the same tree four new
flower branches can grow at the same
time for
[Music]
and the leaves also become green shiny
and very strong and healthy
continue to care for your Orchids with
all the love and dedication you have for
nature when you invest your time and
effort the beautiful blooms you receive
will be a wonderful reward a testament
to the patience and Care you've given to
each leaf and
[Music]
root keep keep nurturing them with love
and you'll experience the joy and
satisfaction every time you watch those
orchids bloom bringing Beauty and pride
created by your own
hands hope this video was helpful don't
forget to like comment share and
subscribe for more videos
thanks for watching and supporting the
channel wishing you success with your
orchids see you next time