Hello everyone. Today I will share with
you a simple yet effective way to help
your orchid quickly recover.
If your orchid is wilting, weakened
after blooming, or suffering from
improper care, don't worry. With just a
few gentle steps, it will soon thrive
again as before.
If you have orchids with yellowing or
starting to rot leaves, don't be quick
to throw them away. Uh, take some time
to watch this video carefully and follow
each step. You'll be surprised by the
results this method can bring.
[Music]
Rotten leaves often contain a lot of
harmful fungi and bacteria. Therefore,
the first thing you need to do is
immediately isolate the rotting orchid
from the healthy ones to prevent the
disease from spreading to your entire
orchid garden.
[Music]
You can see a snail hiding in the orchid
pot. Those small bite marks left by the
snail could be the reason why the orchid
is damaged and infected with fungus.
These wounds create favorable conditions
for bacteria and fungi to easily enter
the plant.
[Music]
Next, we need to carefully inspect the
root system. Healthy orchid roots are
usually ivory white or fresh green,
plump, and have good elasticity. If you
see roots that are darkened, mushy, or
have an unusual smell, that's a sign
they are damaged and need to be removed
immediately to prevent the rot from
spreading to the healthy roots.
[Music]
This root system is almost completely
damaged. Most of the roots have become
rotten, discolored, and can no longer
absorb water or nourish the plant. If
not treated in time, the plant will
continue to deteriorate and be very
difficult to recover.
[Music]
Gently cut off all the damaged and
rotten roots. Keep only the fresh, firm,
and light colored roots. These are the
ones still capable of recovering and
sustaining the orchid.
Um, removing the damaged roots is a very
important step as it helps eliminate the
source of disease and creates the
conditions for the plant to begin
regenerating. Use clean, sharp scissors
to neatly trim each rotten root,
avoiding injury to the healthy base of
the plant.
[Music]
Don't forget to cut off the old and
withered flower spike. This helps the
plant conserve energy by not maintaining
a part that no longer serves a purpose,
allowing it to focus on nourishing the
roots and leaves for faster recovery.
[Music]
Leave a comment and let me know which
country you're watching from. It's
wonderful that we can connect and chat
from all around the world.
[Music]
After pruning, rinse the entire orchid
base with water to remove all old soil,
bacteria, fungi, and any remaining
insects. This cleaning step helps
prepare the plant for the recovery
process.
And if you haven't subscribed yet,
please hit the subscribe button to
support me and never miss any orchid
care tips. It's truly wonderful to have
you along on this journey.
[Music]
After rinsing, place the orchid in a
well ventilated area and wait for all
the water to drain off.
[Music]
To make fertilizer that helps the orchid
recover, first prepare one liter of
clean water.
[Music]
Next, add 1 teaspoon of baking soda and
stir well into the one liter of water.
[Music]
Baking soda will provide mild
antibacterial properties.
help prevent fungal infections and
create a clean environment for the
orchid roots to recover more
effectively.
After mixing, soak the orchid base in
the baking soda solution for about 20
minutes. This duration is enough to
gently disinfect, clean the cut areas,
and support the plant in recovering more
quickly.
After mixing, soak the orchid base in
the baking soda solution for about 20
minutes. This duration is enough to
gently disinfect, clean the cut areas,
and support the plant in recovering more
quickly.
[Music]
Pour the baking soda solution over the
dried moss and soak it for about 20
minutes. This will help clean the moss,
reduce fungi and bacteria, and also
soften it, making it easier to use when
planting the orchid.
[Music]
After soaking for 20 minutes, gently
remove the orchid from the solution and
use a soft cloth or clean paper towel to
dry the base.
[Music]
Then light a candle and drip a small
amount of melted wax onto the cut areas.
[Music]
This layer of wax will help seal the
wounds, prevent vent bacteria and fungi
from entering and also keep the plant
from losing moisture during the recovery
process.
[Music]
After soaking, take the moss out and
gently squeeze it to remove excess
water.
At this point, the moss is clean and
soft, ready for replanting the orchid
into its new environment.
[Music]
Choose a pot that fits the size of the
orchid base and has good drainage holes.
This helps prevent water from
accumulating around the roots, reduces
the risk of root rot, and creates
favorable conditions for healthy plant
growth.
[Music]
Gently place the orchid in the center of
the pot. Then cover the base with the
treated moss.
Make sure the roots are in contact with
the moss, but not packed too tightly so
the plant has enough air flow and can
easily grow new roots.
[Music]
After planting, place the orchid pot in
small bowl or tray.
Pour water into the bowl so that the
water level is about 1 cm.
[Music]
This method keeps the moss moist from
the bottom up without water logging the
orchid base, creating ideal conditions
for recovery and new root growth.
[Music]
Then I repurposed a clear plastic bottle
by cutting off the bottom and making a
few ventilation holes. Then uh placed it
over the orchid pot like a mini
greenhouse. This method helps maintain
stable humidity, protects the plant, and
creates ideal conditions for the orchid
to recover in an enclosed yet
wellventilated environment.
[Music]
And here's the result after 6 weeks.
Uh you can see that the orchid has
revived by growing a new baby plant
right on the old stem. A wonderful proof
of patience and proper care.
[Music]
The baby orchid, though still small, has
developed strong roots and firm, vibrant
leaves. This is a sign that the plant is
recovering very well and is ready to
grow in its new environment.
[Music]
What do you think about the way I
revived this little orchid? Don't
hesitate to leave a comment and share
your thoughts. I really look forward to
hearing your feedback and experiences.
Now, let's explore the roots inside the
growing medium to see how they are
developing. This will be an important
part to help you understand the health
and recovery of the orchid.
[Music]
Wow. You can see the new pure white
roots hidden inside the growing medium.
This is a wonderful sign that the orchid
is recovering and growing stronger every
day.
[Music]
These new roots will help the orchid
absorb water and nutrients more
efficiently, thereby boosting its
vitality and promoting the overall
growth of the plant.
The roots are often compared to the
heart of the orchid. Therefore, when the
root system is healthy, the plant will
have enough vitality to grow lush green
leaves, beautiful flowers, and live long
with you.
[Music]
Now, I need to choose a larger pot to
plant the orchid. Selecting the right
pot will give the roots room to grow,
helping the orchids stay healthy and
bloom better.
And I choose shredded pine bark as the
growing medium because it helps protect
the orchid roots, retains moisture well,
and provides good erration, creating
favorable conditions for strong root
development.
[Music]
Gently place the orchid into the new
pot. Then fill in the shredded pine bark
around the roots. Make sure the roots
are secured but still have enough
airflow so the plant stays stable and
continues to grow well.
Gently tap the sides of the pot to help
the pine bark settle evenly around the
roots and make the plant more stable.
This also helps eliminate large air gaps
in the growing medium, creating a stable
environment for root development.
[Music]
And finally, spread a bit of moss on the
surface of the pot. This layer of moss
will help lightly retain moisture on the
surface of the growing medium while also
creating a more natural and cooler
environment for the orchid.
[Music]
After planting, we will prepare a
natural fertilizer to care for the
orchid. The nutrients from the
fertilizer will help the roots quickly
adapt to the new environment and
encourage the plant to grow more
vigorously.
Rice is always the ingredient I
prioritize for making fertilizer because
it is rich in natural nutrients,
especially starch and vitamin B, which
are excellent for the development of
orchid roots and leaves.
Take one spoonful of rice and pour it
into 500 ml of clean water. Then stir
well. Let it sit for about 30 minutes so
the nutrients in the rice can infuse
into the water, creating a natural tonic
for the orchid.
[Music]
Um, after 30 minutes, pour off the clear
water from the top and use it to water
the orchid.
This water contains gentle nutrients
that help stimulate root growth and
support the plant's recovery after
repotting.
You can use this fertilizer twice a
month or alternate it with other natural
fertilizers.
Rotating them will help the orchid
receive a variety of nutrients and grow
more fully.
[Music]
After applying the fertilizer, you can
also soak the orchid pot in the solution
for about 20 minutes. This method helps
the roots absorb nutrients more
effectively, supporting faster recovery
and healthy growth.
[Music]
After that, take the orchid pot out and
place it in a bright, airy spot with
gentle sunlight. The soft light will
help the plant photosynthesize better
without causing shock to the roots or
leaves after care.
[Music]
And here is the result after 3 months.
From an orchid that was almost
completely rotted with only the bare
stem and a few weak roots remaining, it
has now revived into a new baby orchid
growing from that very stem. Now the
young plant is strong with firm, vibrant
leaves full of life.
[Music]
With just a few simple steps and a bit
of patience, you can completely revive
an orchid that seemed to have withered
away. The most important thing is to
always care for it with love and
persistence.
[Music]
If you have a weak or seemingly hopeless
orchid, don't give up too soon. Believe
that with gentle care each day, a
miracle will happen. Every new leaf,
every tender root is a welldeserved
result of the love you've given to the
plant.
Um, as long as you stay patient and care
for each orchid gently and consistently
over time, you'll have a vibrant orchid
garden full of blooming, lively flowers.
Each plant is a journey and every
blossom is a reward for the love you've
given.
I hope you enjoy this video. If you find
it helpful, don't forget to hit like and
subscribe so you won't miss the next
tips on how to care for orchids
naturally and simply.
Thank you for staying with me until the
end of the video. Wishing you joy, good
health, happiness and great success in
growing orchids.