Welcome to my garden where you can find
the simplest and most natural orchid
care tips. Here we explore together how
to help orchids grow healthy, bloom
brightly, and bring joy to your home.
However, to help the plant grow quickly,
and develop a truly healthy root system
today, I want to share with you a
completely new type of fertilizer.
Simple but effective care methods will
help orchids grow quickly and always be
vibrant with many beautiful fresh
flowers. A natural fertilizer easy to
make at home but very effective, helping
the plant grow strongly from roots to
leaves.
Now the flowers will stay fresh longer
on the branch and their colors will
become more vibrant and prominent.
Let's get started. To start making this
natural fertilizer, you just need a
clean bottle and a bit of pure coffee
powder. These simple ingredients will
provide excellent nutrients for your
orchid.
Just one spoon of pure coffee powder is
enough to create a nutrient-rich
mixture.
[Music]
Next, pour in another 500 ml of boiling
water to activate the nutrients in the
coffee powder and create an energy
richch fertilizer for your orchid.
Pure coffee solution contains many
minerals such as potassium, magnesium,
and antioxidants, which help stimulate
root growth, make the leaves shiny
green, increase resistance, and support
even and longlasting blooming. Close the
bottle and let it sit for about 2 hours
to allow the solution to cool down.
Uh the next ingredient you need to
prepare is oatmeal, a natural and
healthy source of starch. Oatmeal
contains micronutrients such as iron,
zinc, magnesium, and B vitamins, which
help nourish healthy roots and support
balanced plant growth. Just one spoon of
oatmeal is enough to provide gentle
nutrients that help orchid roots grow
strong while also nourishing beneficial
microbes in the growing medium.
Pour in another 500 ml of boiling water
to activate the oatmeal and release its
nutrients, creating a simple yet
effective orchid fertilizer mixture.
As it breaks down, oatmeal creates a
carbonrich and moist environment, ideal
for microorganisms that help the plant
absorb nutrients more effectively.
Oatmeal has a mild water retaining
ability, helping to maintain moisture
around the the roots, especially useful
when the plant is recovering.
[Music]
Uh after about 2 hours, the coffee
solution has completely cooled.
You can now strain out the grounds to
obtain the nutrient-rich extract ready
to use for your plant.
Coffee water contains micronutrients
such as potassium, magnesium, and a
small amount of nitrogen, helping the
plant develop strong roots, green
leaves, and long-lasting flowers.
Thanks to natural antioxidants, coffee
water helps boost the plant's
resistance. Especially effective for
weak plants or after repotting.
When used in proper amounts, coffee
water helps maintain a stable pH level
and creates an ideal environment for
root development.
[Music]
Add 500 ml of room temperature water to
dilute the solution, helping the plant
absorb nutrients more safely and
effectively.
Um, coffee gently stimulates growth,
helping orchids sprout new shoots and
develop fresh foliage.
The organic acids in coffee can soften
the growing medium, helping roots absorb
minerals more effectively from the
surrounding environment.
[Music]
Use a soft cloth soaked with the coffee
solution to gently wipe the leaf
surface.
[Music]
Method one, use a soft cloth to gently
wipe both the upper and lower surfaces
of the orchid leaves, helping them
absorb nutrients more effectively.
[Music]
Please leave a comment and let me know
which country you're watching from. It's
truly wonderful that we can connect and
share with each other from all around
the world. All because of our love for
nature and beautiful orchids.
Orchid leaves have tiny pores on both
surfaces, especially on the underside.
When wiped with the coffee solution,
minerals like potassium and magnesium
are absorbed directly into the leaf
tissue, allowing the plant to take them
in faster than through regular watering.
Wiping the leaves helps remove builtup
dust which can hinder the photosynthesis
process. When the leaves are clean, the
plant absorbs light more effectively,
thereby boosting energy production and
supporting more efficient root and
flower development.
[Music]
The coffee solution also contains
natural antioxidants which help make the
leaves shinier and greener when applied.
At the same time, it can help inhibit
some mild fungi on the leaf surface,
keeping the plant clean and healthy.
Especially, the natural nutrients in
coffee when applied directly to the
leaves help boost the plant's
resistance, allowing it to better
withstand weather changes, pests, or
unstable growing conditions.
Regularly wiping orchid leaves keeps the
stamata on the leaf surface clear and
open, creating favorable conditions for
respiration and gas exchange.
[Music]
Um, pour the solution into a spray
bottle. Then spray evenly on both the
upper and lower surfaces of the orchid
leaves to provide direct nutrients.
[Music]
The coffee solution helps clean dust off
the leaves, keeping the leaf surface
clear and improving the photosynthesis
process. As a result, orchid leaves will
stay fresh, vibrant, and naturally
glossy.
[Music]
You can also spray coffee water on your
orchid once or twice a week. This method
helps the leaves stay greener, keeps the
plant naturally hydrated, and stimulates
overall growth from roots to leaves.
After steeping for about 2 hours, stir
the oatmeal solution well to ensure the
nutrients are fully dissolved in the
water.
[Music]
Strain the oatmeal water, then mix it
with the remaining coffee water to
create a natural nutrient blend that
helps the orchid absorb nutrients to to
the fullest.
[Music]
Stir well to combine the two types of
nutrients, creating a uniform solution
rich in micronutrients and easy for the
orchid to absorb.
[Music]
Method two, water the orchid directly at
the base with the coffee and oatmeal
solution to nourish the roots, helping
the plant absorb nutrients from below
effectively and safely.
[Music]
We need to water evenly around the base
and moisten the entire growing medium so
the nutrients can penetrate deeply to
the roots, allowing the plant to
gradually absorb them and grow
sustainably from roots to leaves.
[Music]
You only need to water the plant with
this solution once every 2 weeks to
maintain light moisture, provide
nutrients, and support healthy long-term
growth.
[Music]
For better results, after watering, you
can soak the entire pot in the solution
for about 20 minutes to allow the roots
to absorb the nutrients to the fullest.
[Music]
Soaking the pot provides gentle and
continuous moisture to the roots, which
is especially helpful for plants in
recovery or suffering from dry roots.
the plant can more easily regain
vitality and stabilize its growth.
We can see dirt, residue, or small mold
particles loosening and mixing into the
soaking water, showing that the roots
and growing medium are being gently and
naturally cleaned.
And uh here is the result after 3 weeks.
You can see that the orchids cared for
with the coffee and oatmeal mixture have
shown noticeable changes. Stronger
roots, shiny green leaves, and the plant
looks full of vitality.
[Music]
Many new roots have grown and the older
roots have also lengthened. indicating
that the plant is absorbing nutrients
well and developing healthily and
steadily from within.
[Music]
A healthy root system allows the plant
to absorb water quickly and retain
moisture for longer, which is especially
important during dry seasons or when the
plant is placed in a low humidity
environment.
[Music]
Well-developed roots help the plant
anchor firmly to the growing medium or
pot, keeping it stable and preventing it
from shifting in strong winds or during
handling.
[Music]
A healthy root system is the foundation
of a strong immune system, allowing the
plant to naturally resist pests and
fungal infections without relying
heavily on chemical treatments.
[Music]
Strong roots consistently deliver
nutrients to the stem and leaves, which
stimulates the growth of new shoots and
prepares the plant for continuous
blooming.
[Music]
I hope you enjoyed this video. If you
found it helpful, don't forget to hit
the like button and subscribe to the
channel so you won't miss more simple
and natural orchid care tips coming up
next.
[Music]
Not only are the roots growing
vigorously, but new flower spikes are
also beginning to emerge, signaling a
bright and promising blooming season
ahead.
[Music]
The orchids that are blooming hold their
flowers longer with colors that remain
vibrant and beautiful, while the newly
forming buds are larger and plumper,
getting ready for the arrival of
stunning flower spikes in the near
future.
[Music]
When we care for orchids with love and
patience, the reward is not only vibrant
blooms, but also the joy and a deep
connection with nature.
Thank you so much for joining me.
Wishing you happiness, good health, and
beautiful orchids all year all. See you
in the next videos.
[Music]