[Music]
Welcome to my orchid garden.
If the potting medium is not replaced
after a long time, the orchid roots may
rot and lose their ability to absorb
water and nutrients, which will cause
the plant to become stunted and
gradually
weaken. This orchid of mine is gradually
deteriorating with wilted, lifeless
leaves.
The important thing right now is to
check the potting medium and observe
whether the root system is
[Music]
damaged. Uh please comment and let me
know which country you're watching the
video from. It's wonderful that we can
chat together from all around the world.
[Music]
If you haven't subscribed to the channel
yet, please hit the subscribe button to
support me and not miss any orchid
growing tips. It's amazing to have you
as a
[Music]
companion. Just as I suspected, all the
roots in the potting medium have rotted,
preventing the plant from absorbing
water and nutrients, which has led to
its weakened condition.
[Music]
After checking, the next step is to
remove all the damaged roots so the
plant has a chance to regenerate and
grow again.
Removing the damaged roots helps stop
the spread of diseases. The rotting
roots may contain harmful bacteria or
fungi and if not removed they can spread
to the healthy roots.
[Music]
Secondly, removing the damaged roots
allows the plant to focus on developing
a stronger, healthier root system,
making it easier to absorb water and
nutrients. And removing the damaged
roots helps reduce the risk of rotting
in the potting medium, keeping the
growing environment clean and airy,
which creates the best conditions for
the plant to
thrive. To help the plant recover
better, we need to remove the flower
spike, allowing all the nutrients to
focus on developing new leaves and
roots. After removing the damaged parts,
wash the orchid under running water to
help remove any impurities and clean the
roots.
To ensure the orchid is properly
disinfected, I will use baking soda and
easy defined ingredient that is very
effective in killing
pathogens. Take one teaspoon of baking
soda and mix it with.5 L of water,
stirring well to create the solution for
disinfecting the plant.
[Music]
After mixing, soak the orchid in the
solution for about 5 minutes to help
eliminate pathogens.
To naturally supplement nutrients for
the plant, I use black tea bags, a
gentle and mineral rich way to fertilize
orchids. We use two black tea bags
brewed with one liter of hot water to
create a natural fertilizer solution for
the orchid.
[Music]
Then cover it and let the tea steep.
Once the water has completely cooled, it
will be ready to
use.
[Music]
After the water has completely cooled, I
add vitamin B1 to the solution to help
the plant recover quickly and develop
stronger
[Music]
roots. Add five vitamin B1 tablets and
stir well until they are fully dissolved
in the tea, creating a nourishing
solution for the orchid.
After soaking the plant in the baking
soda solution, Take it out and dry it to
remove any excess water.
[Music]
Then I soak the orchid in the tea and B1
solution for about 20 minutes, helping
the plant absorb nutrients and recover
quickly.
[Music]
I will use the leftover fertilizer to
feed the other orchids in the garden,
helping them maintain their beautiful
flowers longer and supporting their
healthy growth.
[Music]
I will use the leftover fertilizer to
feed the other orchids in the garden,
helping them maintain their beautiful
flowers longer and supporting their
healthy growth.
[Music]
In addition to the English voiceover, we
have now created voiceovers in French,
German, Italian, Spanish, Portuguese,
Japanese, Hindi, and Indonesian to help
you listen to and understand the content
more
easily. For languages without voice
over, we have created subtitles so you
can read and understand the content.
[Music]
Just water each orchid pot with about 10
tablespoons of the fertilizer solution
and it will be enough for the plant to
grow
[Music]
healthily. After watering, you can let
the orchid pot soak in this solution for
about 20 minutes, allowing the plant to
absorb the nutrients from the fertilizer
well.
After removing the orchid pot, place it
in a spot with gentle
[Music]
sunlight. Remember, no matter how good
the fertilizer is, without sunlight, the
orchid cannot grow healthily because
light is essential for the plant to
synthesize nutrients.
[Music]
After soaking the orchid for about 20
minutes, take it out and gently dry it
with a soft cloth. Then proceed to plant
it in a new pot.
[Music]
I choose a pot with drainage holes at
the bottom and use crushed pine bark as
the potting medium to plant the orchid,
helping the plant grow healthily and
preventing water logging.
At the bottom of the pot, I place a
piece of foam to help with better
drainage and use it to anchor the orchid
steak when planting.
[Music]
I use a plastic clip to secure the
orchid to the steak, ensuring the plant
doesn't shift and remain stable in the
pot.
I spread a layer of spagnum moss on the
top of the pot to help retain moisture
for the plant and create a favorable
environment for root development.
From now on, I will water the orch. with
the tea and B1 mixture once a week to
encourage rapid root growth and help the
plant recover quickly.
[Music]
Now, let's take a look at the results
after 1.5 months of caring for and
reviving the wilted orchid.
As you can see, the orchid roots have
developed strongly, proving that the
plant has recovered very well thanks to
the proper care and
nutrition. When the root system is
healthy, the orchid will absorb enough
water and nutrients, helping it recover
quickly and grow normally after a period
of wilting.
[Music]
Additionally, you can see that the
orchid has grown two new leaves, which
is a clear sign that the plant has
recovered very well and is growing
vigorously.
Uh to help the orchid recover, I
continue watering it with the tea and B1
mixture once a week, providing nutrients
for the plant to grow healthily.
Yummy.
[Music]
Now, let's take a look at the perfect
recovery of the orchid after 5 months of
care and
[Music]
restoration. As you can see, the new
leaves have become sturdy and glossy,
which shows that the orchid has fully
recovered and is growing vigorously.
[Music]
As you can see, the new leaves have
become sturdy and glossy, which shows
that the orchid has fully recovered and
is growing vigorously.
[Music]
The roots have also grown large and
healthy, proving that the orchid is
absorbing enough nutrients and
developing
[Music]
steadily. Not only is the root system
and the leaves healthy, but the orchid
has also developed a vibrant flower
spike with many buds and blooms. um
proving that the plant has fully
recovered and is
[Music]
thriving. We have witnessed the entire
recovery journey of this orchid. An
inspiring story of resilience and its
strong ability to bounce
back. From the wilted leaves and weak
roots, the orchid has overcome all
challenges and revived strongly thanks
to meticulous care and the love given to
it. Not only the health of the roots and
leaves, but the orchid also brings a
wonderful transformation by developing
vibrant flower spikes full of buds and
blooms.
This orchid has proven an important
lesson in life. No matter how difficult
the challenges may be, with patience,
proper care, and sufficient nutrition,
recovery and strong growth are
absolutely
possible. Each small change in this
orchid is not only a sign of its
revival, but also a great source of
motivation for us during tough times.
Look at this orchid and remember that no
matter the circumstances, perseverance
and love are the keys to overcoming
challenges and achieving wonderful
results. Um, I hope you enjoy this video
and find a lot of value in the tip
insights I've
shared. And I also hope this video will
inspire many people to care for and
restore their
[Music]
orchids. If you need any support with
orchid care, don't hesitate to leave a
comment and I'll be happy to help.
[Applause]
Wishing you success and looking forward
to seeing you in the next video.
[Music]