Welcome to my little garden where I
share how to care for orchids using
natural and easy to find
[Music]
ingredients. Today I'm sharing a natural
fertilizer that helps keep orchid leaves
shiny and
[Music]
healthy. This fertilizer will help the
orchid roots grow stronger and more
abundantly.
[Music]
the flower buds will appear earlier and
they will also become plump and healthy.
[Music]
This fertilizer also helps multiple
branches grow on the same flower stem,
creating a beautiful and dense flower
[Music]
cluster. In addition, this fertilizer
helps the petals grow larger and stay on
the stem for a long time before
[Music]
wilting. Let's get started.
To make this amazing natural fertilizer
today, I'm using onions, something that
every household has in their
[Music]
kitchen. Onions contain many natural
antibacterial compounds that help
protect orchid roots from fungal
diseases and stimulate strong new root
growth.
[Music]
Um, when you eat onions, save the peels
to use as natural fertilizer. It's very
beneficial for orchids.
[Music]
Take the peel of one onion and put it
into a clean jar.
[Music]
are. Then add one liter of boiling water
to extract the nutrients from the onion
peel.
[Music]
Cover the jar and wait until the water
cools down
completely. Please comment and let me
know which country you're watching this
video from. It's wonderful that we can
chat together from all over the world.
[Music]
Once the water has cooled completely,
stir it well to extract the nutrients
from the onion peel into the water.
Then strain out the solids to keep only
the liquid.
Next, add about 10 milllers of fresh
milk to the
mixture. Fresh milk provides calcium and
protein, helping the orchid grow
stronger with vibrant green leaves and
long-lasting flowers.
In addition, fresh milk has
antibacterial and disinfectant
properties, helping protect the plant
from fungal diseases.
[Music]
Step one, use a soft cloth to soak up
the mixture and gently wipe both the top
and bottom of the
leaves. Wiping the leaves helps remove
dust and impurities, allowing the plant
to absorb light better.
Fresh milk has antibacterial properties
that help prevent fungi and harmful
bacteria from affecting the
plant. Wiping the leaves also helps the
stamata on the leaves to open wider
enhancing the photosynthesis process.
Wiping with this mixture also provides
calcium and protein from the milk,
helping the leaves stay healthy and grow
well. Uh, cleaning the leaves helps the
plant absorb light more efficiently,
promoting growth.
This mixture helps reduce the growth of
pests that harm the
plant. Wiping the leaves helps create a
natural protective layer, making the
leaves glossy and giving the plant a
fresh, vibrant look.
Once a month, you should wipe the leaves
with this mixture one to two times to
help your orchid stay healthy and grow
well. If you haven't subscribed yet,
please hit the subscribe button to
support me and not miss any orchid
growing tips. It's amazing to have you
as a companion.
Step two, spray this mixture on the
leaves, especially the underside where
fungi and pests are more likely to
thrive.
Spraying this mixture is like washing
away dust, mold, and fungi on the leaves
and leaf joints, making the leaves
glossy and keeping the plant
fresh. This mixture has antibacterial
and disinfectant properties, helping
prevent fungal and bacterial diseases on
the
orchid. Fresh milk and onion peels help
prevent pest attacks, protecting the
leaves from harmful factors.
Fresh milk provides calcium and protein,
improving the plant's health and
supporting the growth of leaves and
roots. Once a month, you should spray
this mixture one to two times. The best
time to do this is in the early morning
or late afternoon when the plant is not
exposed to harsh
sunlight. Step three, water the roots
and the orchid growing medium with this
mixture.
Step three, water the roots and the
orchid growing medium with this
mixture. Fresh milk contains calcium and
protein, helping the roots grow stronger
and absorb nutrients more
effectively. This mixture helps
stimulate root growth, making the roots
healthier and more resilient.
[Music]
Onion peel and fresh milk contain
potassium and calcium, two essential
nutrients that help orchids develop
strong, healthy
flowers. Uh you should apply this care
method twice a month, preferably in the
early morning or late afternoon when the
weather is not too hot. At this time,
the plant can easily absorb nutrients
without experiencing heat shock or leaf
burn.
Step four, use a soft cloth to wipe off
any excess water on the leaf surfaces
and in the leaf
joints. Wiping off excess water helps
reduce the risk of leaf rot and soft rot
caused by prolonged
[Music]
moisture. This helps prevent the growth
of fungi and bacteria, protecting the
plant from diseases.
[Music]
When the leaves are dry and well
ventilated, it helps the plant absorb
light better, improving the
photosynthesis
process. Wiping off excess water helps
remove dust and residue, making the
plant look cleaner and more
beautiful. Wellventilated leaves help
the plant absorb nutrients better when
you spray fertilizer or apply it.
Wiping off excess moisture helps reduce
the risk of insects hiding in the moist
leaf
[Music]
joints. Any leftover fertilizer mixture
can be placed in a spray bottle to spray
on other blooming orchids in your
garden.
[Music]
When spraying the fertilizer mixture on
a blooming orchid, it helps stimulate
flower growth, making the flowers bloom
larger and last longer. This allows the
orchid to produce beautiful and
impressive flowers.
The fertilizer mixture also helps
strengthen the flowers, keeping them on
the stem longer without easily falling
off. Uh, this ensures the flowers stay
fresh and last throughout the blooming
process.
Adding nutrients from the fertilizer
helps the flowers have brighter, more
vibrant colors, enhancing the beauty of
the orchid and making the garden more
lively.
[Music]
The fertilizer mixture also supports the
orchid in maintaining its health
throughout the blooming process, helping
the plant withstand stress and grow
strong, ensuring that it continues to
bloom in the following
[Music]
seasons. You should spray the fertilizer
mixture on blooming orchids about 1 to
two times a month. The best time to do
this is in the early morning or late
afternoon when the temperature is not
too high, allowing the plant to absorb
nutrients easily without experiencing
heat
[Music]
shock. Now, let's take a look at the
results after 1 month of using this
fertilizer care routine.
You can clearly see the changes in your
orchid with glossy, healthy leaves,
large, longlasting flowers, and
especially the strong growth of new
roots. The orchid will become healthier,
better able to fight off diseases, and
produce even more beautiful flowers in
the following seasons.
[Music]
The abundant growth of new roots shows
that the orchid has absorbed enough
nutrients from the natural
fertilizer. When the roots are healthy
and strong, the plant will have a solid
foundation to continue growing, allowing
the orchid to absorb enough water and
nutrients to nourish its flowers and
leaves.
The strong growth of the roots is also a
sign of a healthy plant system ready for
the next blooming
cycle. Uh the orchids that were
previously cared for with the natural
fertilizer made from milk and onion
skins have produced more buds which are
healthier, plumper, and stronger.
[Music]
The combination of nutrients from onion
skins and milk helps the orchid develop
strong buds, ensuring they will bloom
evenly and last
longer. The buds are not only plentiful
uh but also plump, showing that the
orchid is healthy and wellnourished,
ready to develop into beautiful flowers.
Multiple branches growing on the same
flower stem is a fantastic result of
using the natural fertilizer made from
milk and onion
skins. This fertilizer provides
essential nutrients that help the orchid
grow vigorously, stimulating a uniform
bloom.
And when the plant receives enough
nutrients, it will develop multiple
flower branches on the same stem,
creating a beautiful and dense bouquet
that adds more charm to your
garden. I hope this video will be very
helpful for you in taking care of
orchids at home.
With these simple yet effective tips and
tricks, you'll be able to create the
best conditions for your orchid to grow
healthy and bloom
beautifully. I wish you success in
caring for and nurturing your beloved
orchids.