Welcome to my channel. If you have an
orchid that looks weak and wilted like
this, don't be discouraged or throw it
away because right now I'm going to
share with you a simple yet very
effective way to revive it using only
natural fertilizer that you can easily
make at home. Let's get started and
you'll be amazed to see your orchid come
back to life so beautifully in just a
short time.
Um, first we need to gently remove all
the yellow and rotten leaves. This helps
the orchid breathe and prevents bacteria
from spreading to the healthy parts.
Next, carefully check the plant's roots
and growing medium.
And we also need to remove any remaining
inorganic fertilizer pellets along with
the old growing medium. Over time, these
pellets can build up salts that burn the
roots and make it hard for the plant to
absorb water. The old medium is often
decomposed,
retains moisture for too long, and
becomes a place where bacteria can
easily grow. So, replacing it is very
important.
Now, gently trim off all the roots that
are damaged, mushy, or have turned dark
brown.
These roots can no longer absorb water
or nutrients, so keeping them will only
weaken the orchid. When cutting, you
should use sterilized scissors or a
knife to prevent bacteria from entering
the wounds.
After removing the damaged roots, you'll
see a neater and healthier root system.
This is the foundation that helps the
plant recover and grow strong again.
Next, cut off all the flower spikes that
have faded and lost their petals. These
spikes can no longer support new blooms
and only continue to drain the plant's
nutrients. Once you remove them, all the
energy will be redirected to nourish the
roots and leaves, helping the plant
recover faster.
After that, rinse the entire plant under
a gentle stream of water. The water will
wash away dirt, remnants of the old
medium, and any bacteria clinging to the
roots. Be very gentle to avoid damaging
the new roots or the fragile base of the
plant.
When the plant is completely cleaned,
you'll see the roots looking brighter
and healthier, ready to absorb nutrients
for the next stage of recovery.
After rinsing, place the plant in a well
ventilated area and let the roots dry
naturally.
Next, prepare about 500 ml of clean
water in a container to start making the
recovery fertilizer for the wilted
leaves.
Then add about 1/3 teaspoon of sugar
into the container to mix with the
water.
Next, pour the diluted sugar water
solution in and soak the leaves for
about 20 minutes.
This soaking helps the wilted leaves
recover quickly as the sugar provides
instant energy, stimulating metabolism
and nutrient absorption.
Um, next, take about 500 ml of clean
water in a container to prepare the root
recovery fertilizer mixture.
The next ingredient is yeast. The yeast
will stimulate the growth of beneficial
microorganisms in the solution while
also releasing natural nutrients that
help the roots absorb better.
Add one teaspoon of this yeast into the
prepared water. Then stir well so the
yeast dissolves completely and starts
working effectively.
After stirring well, cover the container
and wait for about 20 minutes. During
this time, the yeast will multiply and
create an environment rich in beneficial
microorganisms, helping the plant roots
easily absorb natural nutrients.
After soaking the wilted leaves for
about 20 minutes, gently take out the
orchid and prepare for the next step,
stimulating root recovery.
Then take the diluted sugar water used
to soak the leaves and mix it with the
yeast solution. When combined, the two
solutions create a mixture rich in
nutrients and beneficial microorganisms,
helping the plant roots absorb maximum
nourishment.
Then soak the orchid roots in this
mixture for about 20 minutes.
When the roots are soaked in the
nutrient-rich solution with beneficial
microorganisms, the recovery process is
maximally stimulated. The roots will
quickly regain strength, grow new roots,
and be ready to nourish the leaves,
helping the orchid recover strongly and
grow evenly.
Next, you need to treat the growing
medium before replanting the orchid.
This helps remove bacteria, mold, or any
remaining debris, creating a clean and
airy environment for the roots to grow.
I put pine bark into the pot and pour
water to soak the medium, preparing for
the step of making the soaking solution.
The water will help soften the medium,
remove dirt, and allow it to absorb
nutrients from the recovery solution
more easily.
The ingredient for treating the growing
medium is baking soda.
Take one heaping teaspoon of baking soda
and dissolve it in the water in the pot.
This solution will help disinfect
bacteria and mold and clean the pine
bark, creating a safe environment for
the roots to anchor and absorb
nutrients.
Once the growing medium has been
thoroughly treated with baking soda, it
will become clean and safe for
replanting the orchid. A clean medium
helps the plant roots.
After soaking the roots for about 20
minutes, gently take out the orchid to
let the water drain.
At the same time, take out the pine bark
medium and let it drain completely
before replanting. This helps prevent
the roots from staying too wet. avoids
root rot and creates the best conditions
for the plant to absorb nutrients.
The diluted sugar and yeast mixture used
to soak the roots can be reused to water
the roots and growing medium of other
orchids in your garden.
The beneficial microorganisms from the
yeast along with the energy from the
sugar will create favorable conditions
for the orchid roots to grow quickly,
produce new roots, and help the plant
absorb water and nutrients more
efficiently.
When watered onto the basin roots, the
sugar provides instant energy,
stimulating metabolism and helping the
weak leaves become fresher and greener.
The beneficial microorganisms from the
yeast will balance the ecosystem in the
growing medium, reduce harmful bacteria,
help the plant be less prone to pests,
and promote sustainable growth.
This mixture also helps increase the
nutrient absorption capacity from the
growing medium. The plant roots will
easily take in minerals and natural
nutrients thanks to the environment rich
in microorganisms and nutrients that the
solution creates.
Evenly watering the orchid with the
sugar and yeast mixture helps it bloom
quickly and grow evenly. Healthy plants
with strong roots and vibrant green
leaves form the foundation for new
flower buds to appear, bringing
brilliant beauty and sustaining
long-lasting vitality in your garden.
Once the roots and growing medium have
drained, we proceed to plant the orchid
into a new pot. The pot I chose has
drainage holes at the bottom, allowing
excess water to escape quickly,
preventing water logging and root rot.
At the bottom of the pot, I place a few
pieces of foam to improve drainage and
create air flow for the roots.
At the same time, these foam pieces can
also be used to hold stakes, securing
the orchid when planting, helping the
plant stand upright, and the roots
anchor firmly into the medium.
After placing the plant in the pot, use
plastic clips to secure the orchid to
the steak. This clipping helps the plant
stand upright, allows the roots to
anchor firmly into the medium, and
prevents movement during the recovery
process.
Then gently tuck the growing medium
around the roots and the plant stem. Be
careful not to break or damage the roots
while also keeping the plant stable in
the pot.
After planting, place the orchid pot in
a well ventilated area for about 2
weeks. During this time, you don't need
to apply fertilizer, just lightly mist
with water to keep the roots and medium
moist.
If the orchid grows new roots during
this period, they will naturally absorb
nutrients and minerals from the medium,
helping the plant recover naturally
while still growing healthily.
After 2 weeks, when the plant roots have
stabilized and grown well, we can then
proceed to fertilize the orchid.
First, I use a soft cotton pad soaked in
the diluted sugar and yeast mixture to
carefully wipe both the top and
underside of the leaves.
This helps the nutrients penetrate
directly into the leaves, providing
instant energy and stimulating
metabolism.
At the same time, wiping the leaves
clean also removes dirt, bacteria, and
small insects, making the leaves
healthier and aiding in faster recovery.
Then, water the diluted sugar and yeast
mixture directly onto the roots and
growing medium.
This solution will provide nutrients and
beneficial microorganisms,
stimulate root growth, and increase the
ability to absorb water and minerals
from the medium.
Doing this leaf wiping and watering with
the mixture every 2 weeks will help the
plant grow many new roots. A healthy
root system will increase the ability to
absorb water and nutrients, thereby
helping wilted leaves recover quickly
and become vibrant.
Then place the orchid pot in a location
with gentle sunlight. The soft light
will help the plant photosynthesize
effectively, keeping the leaves green
and the roots growing evenly.
And here are the results after the next
month. You can see that although the
leaves are still soft and not fully
recovered, many new roots have grown and
are very healthy. This shows that the
orchid is actively recovering from
within and a strong root system will be
the foundation for the leaves to turn
green again.
As these new roots continue to grow,
they will help the plant absorb water
and nutrients quickly and efficiently.
As a result, the wrinkled weak leaves
will recover, becoming stronger and
greener day by day. A healthy root
system is the heart of the orchid,
ensuring that the leaves, flowers, and
the entire plant grow balanced, healthy,
and vibrant.
Once the root system is strong and well
established, from now on I will care for
the orchid using lightly fermented rice
water.
This solution provides natural nutrients
rich in beneficial microorganisms,
helping the roots maintain healthy
growth and keeping the leaves vibrant
and green.
Regular care using lightly fermented
rice water. applied every 2 weeks
combined with thorough watering when the
growing medium is dry will support the
orchid's overall development.
This method helps the roots absorb
nutrients effectively, boosts the
vitality of the leaves, and promotes
rapid recovery of the plant. In
particular, the wrinkled leaves will
quickly become firm again, turning green
and healthy, creating a solid foundation
for the plant to bloom evenly in the
coming period.
And here are the results after the next
3 months. You can see that the leaves
have fully recovered, becoming strong,
vibrant, and much healthier. This shows
that the orchid has successfully revived
with a healthy root system, lush green
leaves, and is ready to support
beautiful blooms in the coming seasons.
And you can see that the root system has
grown very strong and is firmly anchored
in the medium. This shows that the
orchid has fully recovered from within,
ready to absorb water and nutrients to
the fullest.
Thanks to strong roots, green leaves,
and a stable plant, the orchid will grow
evenly, ready to produce buds and bloom
in the next season. A solid root system
ensures the plant absorbs enough water
and nutrients, helping the flowers bloom
beautifully and last long, while keeping
the leaves vibrant and green.
When the orchid is properly cared for,
from roots to leaves, you will see it
full of vitality, creating a strong
foundation for brilliant blooms in the
seasons to come.
Take care of your orchids with all the
love and patience you have for plants.
Gradually, your orchid collection will
recover, grow, and bloom beautifully
throughout the garden, bringing vibrant
beauty and full of life. Just like in my
orchid garden, each plant will shine in
its own way, creating a wonderful
natural space where you can enjoy the
joy, the joy, and tranquility of flowers
and foliage.
That's everything I wanted to share with
you in today's video. I hope you enjoy
the video and find these instructions
helpful for caring for your orchids.
If you find the video useful, please
support me by liking, sharing so more
people can know about it and subscribing
to the channel to follow the next orchid
care tips.