Welcome to the happiness garden where
every moment spent with the orchid pots
becomes a gentle and inspiring joy.
Today I want to share with you a video
titled Use this instead of orchid soil.
Orchids will bloom abundantly and grow
new roots. This is a simple secret but
brings surprising results helping your
orchids not only bloom more beautifully
but also grow many new vigorous roots.
If you are caring for an orchid that
still hasn't bloomed, don't worry. Um,
that can be fixed with just a few minor
adjustments in your care. Follow each
step carefully and follow the
instructions and you will see the plant
begin to grow new roots and gradually
bloom brilliantly again.
First, gently remove all the old growing
medium and cut off any damaged roots.
This is an important step to help the
orchid start fresh with a healthier root
system and prepare for its new growth
stage.
Uh you can see that the growing medium
has been left for too long and is
constantly wet causing the roots to rot
and nearly decay completely. This is the
reason the plant cannot absorb nutrients
and has difficulty blooming.
Therefore, when growing orchids, you
need to pay special attention not to
overwater and to repot at the right time
so the plant always has a well
ventilated environment and avoids root
rot like this.
[Music]
Let me know in the comments which
country you are watching from. It's
wonderful that we can chat with each
other from all around the world.
Uh, if you haven't subscribed yet,
please hit the subscribe button to
support me and not miss any orchid care
tips. It's wonderful to have you here
with me.
Then you just need to rinse the entire
root system under running water to
remove dirt and help the plant truly
reset before moving on to the next step.
[Music]
Use a small aloe leaf and cut it into
thin slices to prepare a natural source
of fertilizer. Aloe contains a lot of
nutrient-rich gel that helps orchids
recover quickly and stimulates strong
new root growth. Not only that, aloe
also has natural antiseptic properties
that help protect the orchid from root
rot and leaf rot, keeping the plant
clean and healthy.
After that, you just need to add about
one liter of water to dissolve the
nutrients from the aloe.
[Music]
Next, add one teaspoon of honey. Uh, an
ingredient that not only has natural
antiseptic properties, but also provides
nutrients that help the orchid recover
faster and grow stronger.
Stir the mixture well and let it sit for
about 1 hour, allowing the nutrients to
fully dissolve and create a slight
fermentation process that makes the
mixture easier for the orchid to absorb.
[Music]
After letting the mixture rest for about
1 hour, use a soft cloth soaked in this
natural fertilizer solution and gently
wipe both the upper and lower surfaces
of each leaf. This simple method helps
the leaves absorb nutrients faster and
recover better.
Uh this method also helps remove fungus
and harmful bacteria, keeping the leaves
clean and helping the orchid stay
healthier throughout the recovery
process.
After that, soak the entire orchid in
this aloe and honey mixture for about 20
to 30 minutes. This is an important step
that helps the plant absorb nutrients
more deeply, thereby stimulating faster
new root growth and supporting a
stronger recovery process.
[Music]
Next, I reuse a plastic bottle and turn
it into a no watering orchid pot. With
this planting method, you almost don't
need to water at all. Yet, the orchid
still retains the necessary moisture and
grows very healthily. This is a simple,
economical, and extremely effective
method for those who are busy.
[Music]
If you find the content helpful and
meaningful, don't forget to like, share
so many people can see it and subscribe
to support me. Thank you for always
being with me.
[Music]
After preparing the recycled pot, you
just need to place the orchid inside and
use pine bark as the growing medium to
keep the roots well ventilated. This
way, the plant gets enough air to grow
strongly and greatly reduces the risk of
root rot.
[Music]
Finally, cover the surface of the pot
with a thin layer of moss. This layer
helps gently retain moisture for the
roots while still ensuring ventilation,
creating an ideal environment for the
orchid to recover and grow.
Now you just need to water a little to
moisten the growing medium, helping the
orchid begin to adapt to its new home.
When you create drainage holes on the
side of the pot like this, the water
level will always stay at a safe
position and never reach the entire root
system. Thanks to this, the orchid roots
won't become water logged and will stay
moderately moist.
With stable moisture and continuous
ventilation, new roots will grow
quickly, and the orchid will soon
recover strongly.
Place the orchid pot in a spot with
gentle sunlight where the plant receives
enough soft light without being exposed
to harsh direct sun.
This helps the leaves photosynthesize
better and supports faster root growth
and recovery.
And here are the results after 1 month
of recovery. You can see the new roots
growing strong and full of vitality.
This shows that this simple care method
has helped the orchid revive and enter a
stronger growth phase.
When the roots have grown healthy like
this, you should start using organic
folure fertilizers such as rice water,
soy milk, honey, fish emulsion. As I
have shared before, apply them to the
orchid about once every two weeks to
provide enough nutrients for the plant
to continue growing strongly and
blooming regularly.
And here are the results after 5 months
of recovery with natural fertilizer. You
can see that the orchid I cared for
using this method has grown extremely
healthy and produced many vibrant
blooms, showing that the combination of
careful care and natural nutrients is
truly effective.
[Music]
With this method, orchid flowers can
last on the stems for up to 6 months
before falling, keeping the garden
vibrant and spreading lasting beauty
without requiring overly complicated
care.
What do you think about my method for
reviving weak orchids? Please leave a
comment with your feedback and let me
know.
If you encounter any difficulties while
growing orchids, don't hesitate to
comment. I'm always ready to support you
so you can grow healthy orchids that
bloom abundantly.
Thank you so much for watching. I truly
appreciate your time and support. Don't
forget to like, subscribe, and share if
you enjoyed this video. Wishing you a
wonderful day full of joy and blooming
orchids.
See you in the next video.
Welcome to the garden of happiness.
Orchids are a tropical plant with a very
strong vitality.
[Music]
When you see this orchid, don't rush to
throw it away.
[Music]
Today I will show you how to restore a
wilted orchid like this in the fastest
way.
[Music]
First, you need to cut off all damaged
roots.
[Music]
If you haven't subscribed to the channel
yet, please hit the subscribe button to
support me and not miss any orchid
growing tips. It's great to have you
along.
[Music]
Rinse with water.
dry the cut.
Drop the molten candle solution on the
freshly cut wound. It will help orchids
not lose water and also work against
fungal diseases.
[Music]
Um, please comment to me which country
you are watching the video from. It's
great that we can chat together from all
over the world.
[Music]
Use one teaspoon of cinnamon powder.
Add four cups of boiling water, about
one liter.
[Music]
Close the lid and wait for the water to
cool.
[Music]
Now the water has cooled.
Filter out the residue.
[Music]
Uh, soak orchids in cinnamon water for
30 minutes.
[Music]
Spray this mixture evenly on the top and
bottom of the orchid leaves. Um,
cinnamon has antiseptic properties, so
it helps to eliminate fungi and insects
that are harmful to orchids very well.
Cinnamon also contains many minerals,
vitamins, and amino acids that are very
beneficial for the revival of orchids.
Do this once a month to keep your orchid
protected and healthy.
[Music]
After soaking for 30 minutes, take out
the orchid cutings and plant them.
I plant in shredded pine bark to help
with drainage, but also provide the
right amount of moisture for the orchid
to thrive.
[Music]
Spread one turn of dry moss on top of
the pot.
[Music]
Leave in a cool place and do not water
for one week so that the fungus does not
grow harmful.
[Music]
One week later, start watering to keep
the orchid moist.
[Music]
Pour water into the dish at the bottom
of the pot to create the right humidity
for the orchid to to revive quickly.
Recycling plastic bottles into miniature
green houses makes it easier for orchids
to revive.
[Music]
One month later.
Since the tree has grown roots, I use
organic fertilizer made from fish waste
to fertilize the orchid.
The baby orchid is still very small, so
I only apply it on the outside edge of
the pot to avoid causing the baby orchid
to be shocked with feces.
[Music]
Watering and moisturizing once a week.
2 months later,
you can see that the orchid has revived
and is growing very vigorously with
healthy roots and strong leaves.
This shows that natural fertilizer is
truly effective, helping the plant
recover after blooming and continue to
grow sustainably.
Uh, what do you think about the way I
revive this little orchid? Feel free to
leave a comment and share your thoughts.
I'd love to hear your feedback and
experiences.
If you encounter any difficulties during
the orchid growing process, don't
hesitate to leave a comment for me. I'm
always ready to support you so that you
can grow healthy orchids that bloom
abundantly.
I hope you will enjoy this video. If you
find it useful, don't forget to hit like
and subscribe to the channel so you
won't miss the upcoming shares on how to
care for orchids naturally and simply.