welcome to my
channel when growing orchids everyone
wishes for healthy plants and vibrant
blooms to help you take care of
your orchids at home in the best
way today I will share a natural fertilizer
recipe using familiar ingredients from your
kitchen this is a simple yet highly effective
method that helps orchids grow strong
and Bloom beautifully let's get started
do you have
rice I took 500 G of rice and washed it
clean uh rice contains many natural vitamins
and minerals such as phosphorus pottassium
and protein providing abundant nutrients
to help orchids grow strong and healthy
therefore I regularly use rice as fertilizer
for all types of orchids as well as other
plants add 1 liter of
water please comment to me which
country you are watching the video
from it's great it's great that we
can chat together from all over the
world stir well so that the
nutrients dissolve into the
water in addition to the English dub we've now
created dubs in French German Italian Spanish
Portuguese Japanese H Indonesian to help you
hear and understand the content more easily
then filter this water
next I need one
tomato and cut into thin slices
Tomatoes contain many micronutrients and
nutrients such as potassium phosphorus
and vitamins which help promote plant growth
put tomatoes in the
jar then pour in the rice
water to soak with the tomatoes
cover tightly and leave in
a cool place for one day to
ferment one day later
filter out residue
then take 200 M of this liquid fertilizer solution
and mix with 2 lers of
water method
one water the Orchid with this
liquid fertilizer at the base
rice water contains amino acids and
beneficial microorganisms which help
strengthen the soil microbiome
thereby stimulating root growth
fertilizer from fermented Tomatoes also improves
soil irration and moisture retention
helping plants absorb water and nutrients
beneficial bacteria in the fermentation process
help orchids increase their resistance to
diseases abundant nutrients and a Fresh Living
environment help orchids blue more bigger and more
beautifully after watering soaking in
this water for about 20 20 minutes is
best method
two use soft cotton to absorb this water and
thoroughly wipe the top and bottom of the leaves
wiping leaves helps remove
dirt and impurities helps
plants photosynthesize better and
increases their ability to absorb
light beneficial bacteria in
the solution help strengthen
plant resistance reducing the risk of pests and
diseases this solution creates light
moisture on the leaf surface helping
plants maintain moisture and prevent wilting
in addition when wiping the leaves the organic
substances in the solution will
be absorbed through the leaves
stimulates the growth of leaves
roots and flowers helping plants grow
healthier method
three if you have many Orchid
pots put this water in a spray
bottle then spray all over the
Orchid this method is like
fertilizing plants through the leaves
spray both the top and bottom of the
leaves and spray on Orchid roots
however you should not spray it on
flowers because when flowers get
wet the petals will quickly fall off
after soaking for about 20 minutes
take the Orchid pot out and place
it in a place with lots of scattered
light so the Orchid can photosynthesize
well do all three methods above one
to two times a month for your orchids
remaining liquid fertilizer solution you freeze
and store for next use this
method can be frozen for 3
months results after 3
weeks new Roots grow many and healthy
uh new Roots help the plant
absorb water and nutrients
from the environment ensuring survival and
growth new Roots help improve
metabolism promoting flower formation
the growth of new Roots is often accompanied
by the growth of other parts such as leaves and
flowers take care of your Orchids with
all the love you have for plants and you
will be rewarded with beautiful
orchids that you personally care
for care and love will help the plant grow
strongly bringing you Joy and comfort when
looking at the bright blooming and
fragrant flowers in your living space
hope you will like the video please comment for
me um if you haven't subscribed to the
channel yet please subscribe to support
me uh thank you for watching the
video I pray God always bless
you I pray God always bless
you goodbye and see you again in the next videos