Welcome to my
channel. If you have a wilted orchid
like this, don't rush to throw it
[Music]
away. Um, now I share how to recover
quickly with natural fertilizers.
[Music]
Please remove inorganic fertilizers and
damaged roots.
[Music]
Because the roots do not rot, I keep the
old planting material to help the orchid
recover
[Music]
quickly and remove all yellow and rotten
leaves.
[Music]
Which country are you watching videos
from? Please comment for
[Music]
me. Uh it's great that we can chat
together from all over the world.
[Music]
If you haven't subscribed yet, please
subscribe to support me. And to not miss
any orchid growing
[Music]
tips. Now you need to soak the entire
orchid in water at room temperature for
hour. This helps to quickly restore
wilted roots and
leaves. Awaken the ability of fresh
roots and leaves to absorb water.
[Music]
Place in a cool place for 1
hour. Now you take 1/3 teaspoon of
sugar.
[Music]
mix with 500 mm of water at room
temperature.
[Music]
Then take 500 ml of warm water.
Add one teaspoon of dry yeast. Yeast
used to make bread.
[Music]
Wait 1 hour for the yeast to develop
before using it as
fertilizer. After soaking for 1 hour,
take the orchid out.
[Music]
Then soak the leaves in sugar water for
30 That's
[Music]
After soaking for 30 minutes, take the
orchid
[Music]
out. Nutrients and sugar penetrate the
leaves, helping wilted leaves recover
quickly.
[Music]
Now mix the sugar water with the dry
yeast
[Music]
solution. Uh this will create a natural
fertilizer that will stimulate strong
rooting and plant recovery.
[Music]
Soak the orchid root in this water for
30 minutes will help stimulate rooting
extremely quickly.
[Music]
The remaining liquid fertilizer is used
to water orchid pots.
[Music]
Water each orchid pot with 10
tablespoons. This fertilizer helps
stimulate root growth. A strong root
system will help the orchid absorb
nutrients
[Music]
best. Doing this one to two times a
month will be very good for the orchid.
[Music]
Water the orch. roots with this
microbial fertilizer solution.
Beneficial microorganisms will grow in
the orchid pot. Helps protect orchid
roots from rot caused by fungi and
[Music]
bacteria. This type of fertilizer also
helps balance the pH level in orchid
pots. help stimulate orchid roots to
grow and not be damaged by
[Music]
acid. After soaking for 30 minutes, take
the orchid out.
[Music]
The roots have become juicier and
greener. I use pine bark to grow
orchids.
[Music]
Cover the surface of the orchid pot with
a little moss. Helps retain moisture
better.
[Music]
Then apply this microbial fertilizer to
the orchids every 2
weeks. Uh we'll create beneficial
organisms in the growing environment and
stimulate orchid roots.
Uh on weekdays you just need to spray
mist to keep it moist and water when the
substrate is
[Music]
dry. Then place the orchid pot in a cool
place with enough light for the orchid
to recover.
[Music]
Results after one
month. After only one month, orchid
roots have grown a lot and are healthy.
[Music]
Um, these new roots will help the orchid
absorb nutrients and water
[Music]
best. And gradually the leaves will
become fresh again.
[Music]
Take 1/5 teaspoon of sugar.
[Applause]
[Music]
and take 1/5 teaspoon of dry
yeast. Mix with 300 mm warm water.
[Music]
and wait until the water cools to room
temperature. Then use this microbial
fertilizer to water every 2 weeks.
[Music]
This type of fertilizer is especially
good for weak, stunted orchids with
underdeveloped roots because it does not
shock weak orchids like chemical
[Music]
fertilizers. Um, placing it in a place
with light sunlight will be best for
orchids.
After the next one month,
um, the orchid has completely recovered.
[Music]
The leaves are normal green and thick.
The roots are very fat and have many new
roots.
[Music]
Hope the video will help you a
lot. If you find it interesting, please
like, share, and subscribe to my support
channel. Thank you for watching.
Good luck and see you in the next
videos. Hello
friends. In my hand is a withered
Dendrobium orchid. And in this video I
will share how you can propagate any
Dendrobium
orchid. We cut off the spots that have
bloomed.
[Music]
Only keep these three parts for
propagation because they still have
dormant buds at the
nodes. Drip melted wax onto the cut to
protect it from absorbing water,
preventing the cut from rotting.
Which country are you watching this
video from? Please leave a comment for
me. It's amazing that we can chat with
each other from all around the world.
[Music]
Peel off the protective film of the
sleeping sprout.
[Music]
Use one sprig of chopped fresh ginger.
If you haven't subscribe to the channel
yet, click the subscribe button to
support
[Music]
me. 500 ml of boiled
water. Wait one day.
[Music]
Soak orchids in ginger water for 30
minutes. Soak moss in ginger water for
30 minutes.
[Music]
I use recycled plastic boxes to make
miniature green houses to help propagate
orchids faster.
[Music]
There's a vent here.
Put the orchid in a miniature greenhouse
and spray it with moisture once a
[Music]
week. Uh place in a bright place and
avoid direct
sunlight. 21 days after
[Music]
Continue misting to keep moisture and
keep in a light place. Avoid direct
sunlight.
[Music]
after 10 next day.
Continue misting to keep moisture and
keep in a light place. Avoid direct
sunlight. After two next weeks,
[Music]
I hope this video will be very helpful
for you in taking care of orchids at
home.
[Music]
Plant in pots to let the orchid adapt
and grow in the outside environment.
[Music]
If you find it interesting, please
subscribe to the channel, like, share to
let more people
[Music]
know. My videos have subtitles in
different languages. Please select the
appropriate language to understand the
video content
[Music]
clearly. Remember to plant the root
higher than the pot so that the orchid
does not have root
rot. That's all I want to share with you
in this
video. Now, goodbye and see you in the
next videos.
[Music]
Hello
friends. Nice to meet you on my channel.
You see here a withered orchid. Maybe
it's because you didn't water it or due
to direct sunlight shining on the
orchid.
[Music]
Um, if you want orchids to be nourished
and grow quickly, please watch this
video
[Music]
carefully. Now I will share this amazing
trick with you.
You need one aloe vera
leaf. Which country are you watching the
video from? Please comment
below. It's wonderful that we can chat
together from all around the
world. This aloe vera gel is great for
reviving orchids.
Now apply aloe vera gel on the top and
bottom of the
[Music]
leaf. Aloe vera gel has a very good
moisturizing effect.
[Music]
In addition, aloe vera also contains
vitamins's A, B, and C and minerals such
as nitrogen, phosphorus, and potassium.
[Music]
Uh do this every 5 days and leave the
orchid pot in a cool place for 3
[Music]
weeks. Next, take one liter of warm
water and put it in the bottle.
[Music]
Then take one spoon of rice and soak it
in this water for about 30 minutes. Let
the nutrients in the rice completely
dissolve into the water.
[Music]
Chop the remaining aloe vera leaves into
small pieces.
[Music]
Then puree with 300 mm of water.
Filter out residue. Then add 2 L of
water at room temperature.
[Music]
after soaking for 30 minutes. Filter
this rice water.
[Music]
mix rice water with aloe vera juice.
So, I ended up with about 3 L of this
wonderful liquid manure solution.
[Music]
Cover the pot with moss to retain
moisture better.
[Music]
Now you use the solution to water the
orchid every 5 days.
[Music]
Soak the orchid pot in this water for 2
hours.
After soaking for 2 hours, remember to
lift the orchid pot and place it in a
cool place to let the orchid
[Music]
recover. Two weeks later,
Fertilize after 2 weeks for fresher
orchid
[Music]
leaves. New roots develop very
well. Many new roots are growing.
[Music]
new roots will help transport water and
nutrients from the roots to the
stem. If the leaves are provided with
enough water and nutrients from the
roots, the leaves will gradually become
lush again.
[Music]
One month
later, you see the leaves are very
fresh.
[Music]
And the orchid grows a new leaf.
after the next two
[Music]
months, the orchid has grown two
branches, two buds.
[Music]
But the leaves at the base have turned
yellow. So I will cut off these yellow
leaves.
[Music]
uh instinctively when an orchid buds, if
the plant lacks nutrients, the the base
leaves will turn yellow and fall off to
provide nutrients for the buds to
[Music]
develop. Now I need to supplement the
orchid's nutrition by taking three
spoons of rice.
[Music]
Uh then soak in 2 L of water at room
temperature and wait 30 minutes for the
nutrients to completely dissolve in
water before using.
[Music]
30 minutes
later, add 3 tablesp of milk.
[Music]
Rice water and milk are excellent
sources of nutrients for orchids to
[Music]
grow. Now you water the orchid with this
solution once a week to help the orchid
recover
[Music]
quickly.
After the next one
[Music]
month, after three to four times of
applying liquid fertilizer from milk and
rice water. The orchid had many
[Music]
roots. Hope the video will help you a
lot. If you like the video, remember to
hit like, share, and subscribe to
support
[Music]
me. Uh, thank you for watching the
video. Wish you luck and see you in the
next videos.
[Music]
There you
go. There you go.
[Music]
Welcome to part four of this
video. I am an orchid care
specialist. Do you have vitamin
[Music]
B1? Subscribe to the channel and watch
till the end to see the magic.
[Music]
Five tablets of vitamin
B1. Mix in four cups of room temperature
water, about one liter.
[Music]
keep in a cool place away from direct
sunlight for 1
[Music]
hour. Then I took five eggshells
Eggshells contain many nutrients needed
by plants, including calcium, potassium,
and trace elements such as iron,
magnesium, manganese, copper, and
[Music]
zinc. Therefore, eggshells will help
provide necessary nutrients for orchids.
Dry on low heat for 5
minutes. This helps to eliminate fungal
diseases before using as fertilizer.
[Music]
When using eggshells as fertilizer, it
also helps to increase the pH of the
soil, helping orchids grow better.
[Music]
In addition, I also use 100 g of organic
fertilizer from livestock waste pressed
into dry
[Music]
pellets. Then mix the two types
together.
[Music]
With the orchids that have bloomed all
the last
[Music]
flowers, I apply about 1 oz, about 30 g
per
[Music]
Hot orchid after full bloom is very
exhausted. So I need to apply this
fertilizer to quickly
[Music]
recover. Pay attention to fertilizing
far from the root.
[Music]
with orchids in full
bloom. This fertilizer also helps
flowers bloom for a long
time. If you apply this fertilizer every
2 months, it is guaranteed that the
orchid will bloom for 6 months without
wilting.
[Music]
With orchids with buds, I also apply
this fertilizer to help flower buds grow
faster.
[Music]
1 hour
after. Decant the clear water above.
[Music]
Use this absorbent
cotton. Clean the top and bottom of the
leaves. Helps eliminate fungal diseases
and prevent parasitic insects on leaves.
At the same time, it supports the supply
of nutrients through orchid
leaves. Orchids are always green and
growing. Sprinkle the remaining water
into the orchid growing medium.
[Music]
Vitamin B1 helps strengthen the root
system and promote plant health while
improving the soil's ability to absorb
[Music]
nutrients. Vitamin B1 has the effect of
protecting plants from external agents
such as drought, sunburn, and cold, and
enhances resistance to plant diseases.
[Music]
You should fertilize B1 for orchids once
a month in the cool
[Music]
afternoon. Results after 1
week. You can see that after 15 days,
the flowers are still very fresh and
more fragrant than usual.
and flowers can bloom again and again
all year round in the
[Music]
garden. This helps me to always enjoy
the blooming flowers and the gentle
fragrance from the
garden. And you can see that after just
a week of using, the orchid has grown a
lot of new roots.
[Music]
So we can use these organic fertilizers
to take care of orchids very well.
[Music]
However, keep in mind that an overdose
can also harm plants. Therefore, it is
advisable to adhere to the dosage that I
have
instructed. Hopefully, the video will be
of great help to you in effectively
taking care of orchids at home.
If you find the content interesting and
meaningful, don't forget to like and
share so that more people know and
subscribe to support the channel. Thank
you for always accompanying
me. Thank you for watching the video. I
always pray for God's blessings to all
of
you. Welcome to part five of this video.
After the orchid has bloomed, what
should we do to help it grow and bloom
continuously? In this video, I'll show
you step-by-step instructions to ensure
your orchids stay healthy and bloom
regularly. Let's get
started. To make fertilizer for this
orchid, I need about 10 eggshells.
Uh eggshells are a natural source of
calcium which helps improve soil
structure, boost root development and
prevent diseases in orchids.
Using eggshells as fertilizer helps
orchids recover quickly after blooming,
stimulating continuous and healthy
flowering. Which country are you
watching videos from? Please comment for
me. Uh it's great that we can chat
together from all over the world.
You need to dry the eggshells and then
grind them into
powder. Then put the eggshell powder
into the jar.
Next, bananas are a very good choice as
fertilizer for
orchids. Take one banana peel and cut it
into small pieces.
[Applause]
Banana peels are rich in potassium and
minerals which help stimulate flowering
and promote quick recovery for orchids
after
blooming. Using banana peels as
fertilizer ensures consistent and
healthy blooming.
Add one liter of boiling
water. Cover and leave overnight to let
the nutrients mix into the water.
Next, I use oatmeal to make natural
fertilizer. Take three teaspoons of
oatmeal.
Add one liter of water at room
temperature. Cover and leave overnight
to let the nutrients mix into the water.
This is an orchid I bought at an
industrial orchid garden and has
finished blooming.
Uh to care for the plant to continue
flowering, I first need to cut off the
damaged leaves.
Then cut off the old flower
stems. If you haven't subscribed to the
channel, please subscribe and support
me. It's amazing to have you along for
the journey and supporting
me. Then use coffee powder to apply to
the cut to help the wound heal quickly.
Leave it overnight for the cut to heal
completely.
After one
night, stir well so that the nutrients
dissolve into the water.
Filter out eggshells and banana peels.
[Music]
Step
one, use soft cotton to wipe the leaves
to help keep them cleaner.
Wiping leaves helps remove dust, debris,
and bacteria from leaf surfaces, helping
orchid leaves breathe better and absorb
light more effectively.
Wiping leaves helps enhance
photosynthesis because clean leaves
absorb light better and can metabolize
energy more efficiently.
Wiping leaves with this water helps
reduce the risk of mold bacterial
diseases because clean leaf surfaces
limit the environment for harmful
pathogens to grow.
Step
two, pour this water into a spray bottle
and spray your orchid.
Spraying water infused with banana peels
and eggshells provides nutrients for
orchids, boosting their resistance,
promoting quick recovery after blooming,
and ensuring continuous
flowering. Thoroughly spray both the top
and bottom of the leaves.
When sprayed on leaves, liquid
fertilizer helps orchids absorb
nutrients more easily and enhance root
development.
[Music]
When sprayed on leaves, liquid
fertilizer helps orchids absorb
nutrients more easily and enhance root
development.
[Music]
will create a synthetic liquid
fertilizer solution that is very good
for orchids to recover after flowering.
Step
three, water this liquid fertilizer for
orchid pots.
Watering with a liquid fertilizer made
from banana peels, eggshells, and
oatmeal boosts nutrients, enhances
resistance, promotes quick recovery, and
ensures continuous blooming for orchids.
Uh, soak the orchid pot for 20 minutes
so the orchid can absorb the most
nutrients. After soaking for about 20
minutes, take it out. Take it out and
place the orchid pot in a place with
plenty of light.
Step
four, water droplets on leaves can
create a favorable environment for mold
and bacteria to
grow. Wiping off water helps reduce the
risk of infection.
Wiping off the water helps the stamata
stay open and function
better. And do the above four steps
every 10 to 15 days.
Remember, no matter how good the
fertilizer is, if the orchid lacks light
growth and cannot photosynthesize, it
will still be stunted and grow slowly.
Therefore, place the orchid in a
location with sufficient light for
healthy
growth. Results after 50 days.
You can see the roots and leaves of the
orchid growing very
quickly. The leaves are also stronger
and
glossier and also grew two new flower
buds.
Oh, the roots in the orchid pot grow so
well. New roots are an important factor
in helping orchids grow healthily and
sustainably throughout their life cycle.
Um, now I plant it in a larger pot so
the orchid grows
healthier. As a growing medium, I use
crushed pine bark to help airrate the
roots but still retain the necessary
moisture.
After planting, take care of it like
other normal orchids.
Take care of your orchids with all the
love and dedication you have for nature
because every leaf and every flower bud
is a testament to the effort and heart
you put into
it. Thank you for watching and
supporting my channel.