Welcome to the happiness garden, where
every leaf and every flower carries a
little story and the breath of nature.
If you want to care for orchids at home
so they stay healthy, produce plenty of
flowers, and those flowers can stay on
the stem for a long time before fading,
watch this video until the end to
discover all the secrets.
To start making the fertilizer, you just
need to take three tablespoons of rice.
A simple ingredient, but one that
contains many valuable nutrients for
orchids.
Add one liter of water and wait about 10
minutes for the nutrients from the rice
to dissolve into the water, uh, creating
a nutrient-rich solution for the
orchids.
[Music]
When eating bell peppers, I usually keep
a small piece to use as fertilizer,
adding extra natural nutrients for the
orchids.
[Music]
Bell peppers contain many vitamins and
minerals such as vitamin C, vitamin A,
and potassium. These nutrients support
the strong growth of orchids, providing
essential micronutrients to keep the
plants healthy and vibrant.
[Music]
Add 300 ml of water to the mixture and
blend it finely to create a natural
nutrient-rich fertilizer solution for
the orchids.
[Music]
In addition to the English dubbed
version, we also provide dubbed versions
in French, German, Italian, Spanish,
Portuguese, Japanese, Hindi, Dutch,
Polish, Korean, and Indonesian, making
it easy for you to listen and understand
the content in your preferred language.
Um to listen to the language, please
open the video and click on settings,
the gear icon to select the appropriate
audio language.
[Music]
After blending finally, strain the clear
solution, removing the residue so that
the fertilizer is smooth and easier for
the orchids to absorb.
[Music]
Please comment and let me know which
country you are watching the video from.
It's wonderful that we can connect and
chat together from all around the world.
[Music]
Dilute the solution by adding one liter
of room temperature water, helping the
fertilizer penetrate deeply and you know
nourish the orchids more effectively.
After soaking for 10 minutes, I strain
and take the clear liquid to use as
fertilizer for the orchids.
Rice water is rich in carbohydrates,
protein, vitamin B, and essential
minerals such as iron, phosphorus, and
potassium.
These nutrients not only help orchids
grow healthily, but also stimulate
stronger root growth.
Then you mix the strained rice water
with the bell pepper solution to create
a natural fertilizer mixture rich in
nutrients that help orchids develop
comprehensively.
[Music]
Method one, use a soft cloth to soak up
the fertilizer mixture. Then gently wipe
both the top and bottom surfaces of the
leaves to allow the nutrients to
penetrate deeply and keep the orchid
leaves healthy.
Uh this mixture helps eliminate fungi
and harmful insects on the leaves. As a
result, the leaf surface stays clean.
The stamata are not clogged or stained,
allowing the orchids to photosynthesize
more effectively and grow healthily.
[Music]
If you haven't subscribed to the channel
yet, please click the subscribe button
to support me and not miss any orchid
growing tips. It's wonderful to have you
along on this journey.
[Music]
You need to thoroughly clean the
underside of the leaves because this is
where bacteria, fungi, and insects often
reside, causing harm to the orchids if
not carefully cared for.
[Music]
Doing this one to two times a month will
help protect the orchid leaves, keeping
them always green and healthy.
Harmful insects such as red
spidermitites, white flies, aphids, and
thris will not be able to survive on the
plant when you maintain proper cleaning
and care.
[Music]
Beneficial microorganisms in rice water
also help protect orchid leaves from
fungal diseases, contributing to
maintaining the overall health of the
plant.
[Music]
Orchid leaves will always be strong,
thick, and full of vitality when
properly cared for.
[Music]
If you encounter any difficulties during
the orchid growing process, don't
hesitate to leave a comment for me. I am
always ready to support you so you can
grow healthy orchids that bloom
abundantly.
[Music]
Method two, you can use this mixture to
water directly onto the orchid roots,
helping provide essential nutrients and
stimulate stronger root growth.
[Music]
Thanks to containing nutrients such as
phosphorus and vitamin B, rice water
helps orchids develop healthier roots,
allowing the plants to more easily
absorb nutrients from the substrate and
soil, promoting comprehensive growth.
Potassium in bell peppers plays an
important role in stimulating the
flowering process, helping orchid
flowers develop more brilliantly and
last longer.
Antioxidants in bell peppers, especially
vitamin C, also help protect orchids
from negative environmental impacts and
effectively prevent diseases.
[Music]
Regular use of rice water helps improve
the development of beneficial
microorganisms in the soil, creating an
ideal living environment for orchids. At
the same time, it also helps maintain
moisture in the substrate, preventing
the plants from drying out.
Uh, applying this method once every 2
weeks will bring the best results in
nourishing and protecting your orchids.
[Music]
Method three, pour the fertilizer
mixture into a spray bottle to easily
spray evenly onto the leaves and other
parts of the orchid, helping the
nutrients absorb quickly and spread
effectively.
[Music]
Spray evenly on both the top and
underside of the leaves. This method is
similar to using folure fertilizer,
helping orchids absorb nutrients quickly
and comprehensively.
[Music]
That one.
The nutrients in rice water not only
stimulate the plant to produce more
flowers, but also help the flowers last
longer, keeping the plant fresh and more
vibrant everyday.
[Music]
Beneficial organic compounds in bell
peppers help strengthen the orchid's
resistance, protecting the plant from
pests and harsh environmental
conditions.
[Music]
And here is the result. A healthy
orchid, lush green leaves, brilliantly
blooming flowers that last long, clearly
showing the care and love you have for
your garden.
Um, this mixture has helped the plant
grow healthily and stimulated root
development. A healthy root system
allows the orchid to easily absorb the
maximum essential nutrients for growth
and flowering.
You can easily notice that the roots of
these orchids grow very strong and
sturdy, playing an important role in the
overall development of the plant.
[Music]
Okay.
Potassium found in rice water and bell
peppers helps orchid flowers bloom
brilliantly and stay on the stem for a
long time before fading. In fact, the
petals can remain on the stem for up to
6 months, bringing lasting beauty to the
plant.
I hope this video will help you take
better care of orchids at home. If you
find it useful, don't forget to like and
subscribe to the channel so you won't
miss the upcoming natural and simple
orchid care tips.
[Music]
If you encounter any difficulties during
the orchid growing process, don't
hesitate to leave a comment for me. I am
always ready to support you so you can
grow healthy, healthy orchids that bloom
abundantly.
[Music]
Thank you for watching. Wishing you
always happiness, good health and
success in caring for your garden.