Hello
friends. When the new orchid withers all
its flowers, this is the best time to
cut the flowers to help them sprout
faster. Which country are you watching
this video from? Please comment below.
It's so great that we can chat with each
other from all around the
[Music]
world. Uh, peel off the protective film
so that the buds will germinate faster.
[Music]
Cut back the branch with a sharp knife
so as not to crush the cut.
[Music]
Pour melted candle solution into the cut
to help the cut heal. quickly and not
[Music]
rot. Sprinkle cinnamon powder on the
freshly cut wound at the base to help
protect the orchid from rot.
Use one large garlic clove or two small
garlic
[Music]
cloves. How small
Put the garlic in the jar.
[Music]
Pour in 500 milllers of water at room
temperature. Wait 30 minutes for the
nutrients from the garlic to dissolve
into the water.
[Music]
Use foam to arrange
flowers. Heat. Heat.
[Music]
Uh after soaking for 30 minutes, filter
out the residue.
[Music]
Soak orchid branches in garlic water for
minutes. 30 minutes
later. Take
out. Plug in the sucker.
[Music]
Pour in filtered water just enough to
moisten. Close the lid and wait for the
orchid branch to sprout.
After the next three
[Music]
weeks, sprouts have woken up.
after one. Next
[Music]
month, the orchid sprouts have grown and
the roots have
[Music]
grown.
After the next two months,
[Music]
The small orchid has grown
healthy. Now, let's plant the orchid in
pots so that it can adapt to the outside
environment.
[Music]
In my hand is a withered orchid
branch. And in this video I will share
so you can propagate from any orchid
branch.
We cut off the spots that have
[Music]
bloomed. Just keep these three segments
and the orchid can
[Music]
sprout. Applying candle solution to the
cut will help protect the orchid from
rotting.
[Music]
Peel off the protective film of the
sleeping sprouts.
[Music]
Use one chopped fresh ginger branch.
boil 500 ml of water and wait 1 day.
[Music]
After one day, take it out and filter to
remove
[Music]
residue. Soak orchids in ginger water
for 30 minutes.
Soak the moss in ginger water for 30
minutes.
[Music]
I use recycled plastic boxes to make
miniature green houses to help propagate
orchids
[Music]
faster. There's a vent here.
Place the orchid in a miniature
greenhouse and spray it with moisture
once a
[Music]
week. Place in a bright place away from
direct sunlight.
[Music]
21 days
later.
[Music]
Continue misting to keep it moist and
keep it in a cool well-lit place away
from direct
[Music]
sunlight. After next 10
days, Continue misting to moisturize and
leave in a well-lit place, avoiding
getting direct
[Music]
sunlight after next 2 weeks.
Plant in a pot so the orchid can adapt
and grow in the outside environment.
[Music]
If you find it interesting, please
subscribe to the channel, like and share
so more people know.
[Music]
Remember to plant the base higher than
the pot to prevent the orchid from
rotting.
[Music]
When the orchid has just lost all its
flowers, it is the best time to
propagate from the flower stem.
Buttons that have bloomed cannot be
propagated. So I cut off the nodes that
have finished blooming.
[Music]
Uh, repair the cut to avoid crushing the
flower stem.
[Music]
Sprinkle cinnamon powder on the cut to
help it heal quickly and prevent rot.
Leave for one day for the cut to dry
completely.
[Music]
One day
later, peel off the protective film on
the flower
[Music]
button. This helps baby orchids easily
germinate.
[Music]
Now I use tomatoes to revive young
orchids from flower
[Music]
stems. Tomatoes contain many important
nutrients such as nitrogen N, phosphorus
P, and potassium K, which are essential
factors to promote the growth of
orchids.
[Music]
Then you tie the tomato core to this
position to awaken the baby orchid
sprouts to revive.
[Music]
This helps baby orchids quickly revive
from flower stocks.
[Music]
Leave for about 30 minutes for the
nutrients to penetrate into the flower
stem.
[Music]
after 30 minutes. Remove
it. Come
[Music]
on, baby.
Then insert the flower stem into the
[Music]
sponge. Place in a transparent jar.
and pour a little water to always have
the right humidity for the baby orchids
to
[Music]
revive. Cover with transparent plastic
and keep in a cool place.
[Music]
3 weeks
later. The flower branches have begun to
revive the baby
[Music]
orchids.
Continue to put it in the vase and place
it in a cool place for the baby orchids
to
[Music]
grow.
After the next one
[Music]
month, baby orchids have formed from
flower stems.
[Music]
The baby orchids also take root at the
same
[Music]
time. Both the small orchid and its
roots are
healthy.
[Music]
Continue to put it in the vase and place
it in a cool place for the baby orchids
to grow.
[Music]
after the next two
months. Uh this simple method helps baby
orchids grow very healthily.
[Music]
Now plant them in pots so they can grow
outside. Uh if you find it interesting,
please like, share and subscribe to the
channel to support
[Music]
me. I have created subtitles in many
different languages so you can choose
the appropriate language.
[Music]
Now plant in a pot so the orchid can
grow in an outdoor environment.
[Music]
If you find it interesting, please
subscribe to my channel to support me.
Don't forget to hit the like button and
share this video so others can discover
it, too. Every bit of support from you
motivates me to create even better
[Music]
videos. Thank you for watching the
video. Good luck and and see you in the
next videos.
[Music]
Hello everyone. Today I'm sharing a way
to propagate orchids using a simple and
easy method that anyone can
do. Please cut across here to take the
flower spike for propagation using the
cutting method.
[Music]
When the petals have just faded, it's
the best time to take cutings for orchid
[Music]
propagation. The parts of the flower
that have already fully bloomed can no
longer be used for propagation.
[Music]
and choose the raised or protruding
parts of the flower
[Music]
spike. After that, peel off this outer
layer.
[Music]
a new plant will begin to grow right at
this spot.
[Music]
cut again to avoid damaging the cut
surface.
[Music]
If you haven't subscribed to the channel
yet, please hit the subscribe button to
support me and not miss any orchid
growing tips. It's wonderful to have you
along. Uh make a diagonal cut here as it
will help with easier water absorption.
Next, you need to prepare an aloe vera
leaf. Choose a fresh, thick leaf that is
not damaged.
Aloe vera has antibacterial properties
and helps the orchid grow
stronger. Once you have the aloe vera
leaf, cut it into thin
slices. Let me know in the comments
which country you're watching this video
from. It's amazing that we can connect
and chat from all over the world.
[Laughter]
After cutting the aloe vera into thin
slices, place them in a cup and add
about 500 ml of water.
Um, the water will help dissolve the
nutrients from the aloe vera, creating a
supplement that aids in the healthy
growth of the
orchid. To enhance the effectiveness,
you can add a little honey to the aloe
vera water
solution. Honey helps the orchid fight
bacteria and provides extra nutrients.
Just add about 1 teaspoon of honey to
the cup and stir well to mix the
ingredients.
Leave the cup of water in a cool place
for a few hours so the nutrients from
the aloe vera and honey dissolve into
the
water. After the solution has been
soaked for a few hours, use a strainer
to filter out the residue.
You only need to keep the clear liquid
which contains the dissolved nutrients
from the aloe vera and honey to nourish
the orchid in the best way.
After filtering out the residue, soak
the orchid cutting you want to propagate
in this aloe vera and honey mixture.
uh soak it for about 20 minutes to allow
the orchid cutting to absorb the
nutrients and boost its ability to
develop strong roots. This is an
important step to ensure the cutting can
thrive during the propagation
process. You can use the remaining aloe
vera and honey mixture to water other
orchids in your garden.
[Music]
Uh this solution will provide additional
nutrients for the orchid promoting
healthy growth from the roots to the
leaves. When watering the orchids, just
apply about 10 tablespoons of the
solution to each pot.
This amount of water will be enough to
provide nutrients without causing the
plants to become water
logged. Make sure to water evenly around
the base of the plant to help it absorb
the nutrients in the best way.
In addition to the English voiceover, we
have now created voiceovers in French,
German, Italian, Spanish, Portuguese,
Japanese, Hindi, and Indonesian to help
you listen and understand the content
more
easily. For languages without a
voiceover, we have created subtitles so
you can read and understand the
content. With the aloe vera and honey
nutrient mixture, you can water the
orchid about one to two times a
month. Um, after watering, place the
orchid pot in a spot with gentle
[Music]
sunlight. Soft light will help the
orchid with photosynthesis and
metabolism, promoting strong growth and
blooming.
Avoid direct intense sunlight as it can
cause the orchid's leaves to
burn. This is the floral foam I will use
to arrange the orchid cutting.
Floral foam helps keep the orchid
cutting in place and retains moisture,
creating favorable conditions for root
development.
After preparing the floral foam, get a
clear glass cup ready for rooting the
orchid
cutting. The glass cup not only allows
you to easily observe the cutting's
growth, but also creates a good humid
environment for the
plant. After soaking the orchid cutting
in the aloe vera and honey solution for
about 20 minutes, gently remove it and
use a clean paper towel to dry it.
[Music]
After drying, drip a bit of candle wax
onto the upper cut of the orchid
cutting.
[Music]
This helps protect the cut from bacteria
and fungi while also preventing moisture
from evaporating too quickly through the
cut, helping the cutting retain internal
moisture. It's a small but very
effective tip to increase the survival
rate of orchid cutings.
[Music]
Then insert the orchid cutting into the
floral foam, making sure the base is
securely and uprightly positioned.
Next, place the floral foam into the
clear glass container. This method helps
retain moisture for the orchid cutting
while also allowing you to easily
observe root development later on.
[Music]
After placing the cutting into the
floral foam, add filtered water to the
glass container, ensuring the foam is
moist but not submerged in
water. This helps maintain the necessary
moisture for the cutting without causing
root
rot. Make sure the floral foam doesn't
dry out as orchids need moisture to
develop roots and shoots. Remember to
add water when you notice the foam
getting
dry. Then cover the glass jar to
maintain moisture for the
cutting. After that, place the orchid
cutting in a spot with gentle sunlight,
avoiding direct intense
sunlight. Just be patient, and the
orchid cutting will gradually develop
roots and grow into a new plant.
[Music]
Now after 3 weeks you can see that the
orchid cutting has sprouted and
developed
roots. This shows that the cutting
process has been successful and the
orchid is growing well.
Since the chute is still small and the
roots are weak, I will continue to root
the orchid uh cutting in the glass cup
for a while longer to allow the plant to
grow stronger.
After a while of rooting the cutting,
you should change the water in the glass
cup to ensure it stays clean and free
from impurities.
You can change the water weekly or when
you notice the water in the cup becoming
cloudy. Be sure not to leave the water
in the cup for too long as this could
affect root development.
[Music]
After 5 weeks, you'll notice that the
chute has sprouted leaves and the roots
have become stronger.
Yeah. Since the leaves are still weak
and the roots are young, I've decided to
continue rooting the orchid cutting in
the glass cup for a little longer so the
plant can grow stronger and develop more
steadily.
during this time. Make sure the plant
still receives gentle sunlight and that
the water remains clean.
[Music]
Once the leaves and roots have developed
stronger, I will transfer the plant to a
larger pot to continue caring for it.
[Music]
If you face any difficulties during the
orchid cutting process, don't don't
hesitate to leave a comment. I'm always
ready to support you so you can
successfully propagate healthy orchids.
After 8 weeks, the new chute is healthy
with vibrant green leaves and strong
roots. Your orchid has successfully
passed through the fragile early stage
and is now thriving.
At this point, you can transfer the
plant to a pot to continue caring for it
and allow it to fully develop.
[Music]
When transferring the orchid to a pot,
you can use pine bark chips as the
growing medium.
Pine bark helps with good drainage,
maintains the right level of humidity,
and creates an ideal environment for
orchid roots to
grow. Make sure the pot has good
drainage holes to prevent root
rot. Before placing the orchid into the
pot, spread a thin layer of moss on the
surface. This moss layer helps retain
moisture in the growing medium, creates
favorable conditions for root
development, and helps keep the orchid
stable during the early stage after
[Music]
planting. Then place the orchid on top
of the moss layer and gently pack moss
around the roots to secure the plant in
place.
Uh when the orchid is healthy and has a
strong root system, we can start
fertilizing it after repotting to
stimulate better
[Music]
growth. To make the fertilizer, I use
500 ml of water and 1 tbsp of rice. Then
let it soak for a few hours.
[Music]
This mixture will be an excellent
natural fertilizer for orchids,
especially those that have been cut from
stems and replanted in new pots.
[Music]
After soaking for a few hours, we filter
the rice water and use it to water the
orchid.
[Music]
Rice water contains many natural
nutrients that help stimulate root
growth and provide essential vitamins
for the plant.
After that, you can water the orchid
with rice water about one to two times a
[Music]
month. Regular watering will help
provide nutrients to the plant without
overwhelming it.
Be sure to observe the condition of the
plant to adjust the amount of water
accordingly. On regular days when the
substrate is dry, you just need to mist
or water the orchid lightly. This helps
maintain the necessary moisture for the
plant without causing water logging as
orchids do not like overly wet
soil.
[Music]
After 3 months, the orchid has grown
strong and sturdy from a cutting.
The roots have grown strong, the leaves
are lush and green, and the orchid is
ready for the next blooming
stage. This result proves the
effectiveness of proper care, cutting,
and natural fertilization.
[Music]
I continue to fertilize the orchid
regularly with natural rice fertilizer
twice a month, helping the plant grow
strong and maintain long-term health.
[Music]
Uh the result is that after 6 months
months. You can see the orchid has
matured, blooming vibrant flowers that
brighten up the
[Music]
space. You can see that patience is the
most important factor in the journey of
caring for
orchids. From the early days of cutting
a stem to taking care of each small
stage, every step requires time and
meticulous attention.
And now, after months of patient
waiting, we have a healthy orchid
blooming brilliantly and lighting up the
space. I hope this video will be helpful
to you in propagating orchids at home.
If you found the video useful, don't
forget to like and share it to help more
people. If you haven't subscribed to the
channel yet, don't forget to click the
subscribe button and turn on the
notification bell so you won't miss any
upcoming useful videos.
Thank you all for watching and I wish
you success with your
orchids. Hello everyone. Thank you for
visiting my
garden today. I'm very excited to
continue sharing with you how to
propagate orchids through cutings at
home using very simple ingredients that
you can easily find in your kitchen.
[Music]
If you find this helpful, don't forget
to subscribe to the channel to support
me and to make sure you don't miss any
tips on plant
care. As you can see, this orchid has
finished blooming and this is the
perfect time for us to start the process
of propagating orchids from
[Music]
cutings. I will cut across this old
flower stem to begin the process of
propagating the orchid through cutings.
We need to cut neatly to avoid crushing
the cut, creating the best conditions
for the orchid cutting to grow into a
strong, healthy, young
[Music]
plant. Next, we remove the protective
layer around the dormant bud to help
stimulate it to sprout faster, which
will encourage the young plant to grow
strong and quickly.
[Music]
Next, I take an onion as onions contain
a lot of nutrients and natural compounds
that are great for orchid
[Music]
propagation. Um, the components in
onions, especially antioxidants and
ends, help stimulate root formation and
enhance the growth potential of the
young plant.
[Music]
Onions also help prevent mold and
harmful bacteria, keeping the cutting
healthy throughout the development
process. I put the onion in here to
extract the onion juice.
[Music]
Please comment and let me know which
country you're watching the video from.
It's so amazing that we can chat
together from all around the
world. Do as I did. Then wait for about
10 minutes to allow the onion juice to
soak into the cutting.
[Music]
Uh after soaking the cutting in onion
juice for about 10 minutes, take it out
and let the cut dry naturally for a few
hours. This helps the cut to heal,
reducing the risk of infection and
creating optimal conditions for root
development later on.
Then apply a special plant glue to the
cut, which helps prevent water from
seeping into the wound. This will
protect the cut from bacteria and mold,
thus preventing rot and allowing the new
plant to grow
healthily. Then place the cutting in a
cool, wellventilated area to allow the
glue to dry completely.
This will help the glue dry evenly and
form a solid protective layer,
preventing bacterial infection and
supporting better growth of the
plant. While waiting for the glue to dry
completely, take one teaspoon of
cinnamon powder and soak it in one liter
of hot water to treat the growing medium
before inserting the cutting.
Cinnamon powder has antibacterial and
antifungal properties, helping to clean
the growing medium, prevent the growth
of harmful bacteria, and create a safe
environment for the cutting to
[Music]
develop. After the water cools, filter
out the residue to leave only the clear
liquid ready to be used for treating the
growing medium.
This ensures that the growing medium
will not be contaminated with
impurities, providing the best
conditions for the development of orchid
[Music]
roots. Then soak the dry moss in the
cinnamon water for about 20 minutes.
This will help the moss of absorb
nutrients from the cinnamon water while
also disinfecting it and creating a good
environment for the development of
orchid roots during the rooting process.
[Music]
Then remove the moss and let it drain.
The moss has now been treated and is
ready to be used as a growing medium for
rooting orchid cutings.
I have recycled a plastic bottle to
create a mini greenhouse which helps
speed up speed up the rooting process
and ensures better results for the
orchid cutings. Here I have created
ventilation holes in the plastic bottle
to ensure air flow helping to prevent
excessive moisture
buildup. Uh I also made drainage holes
at the bottom of the plastic bottle to
prevent water from accumulating which
could cause root rot in the cutings.
[Music]
After placing the moss inside, we will
insert the cutting and mist it regularly
to maintain moisture. This helps keep
the humidity stable for the cutting,
creating a favorable environment for
root development and allowing the young
orchid to sprout healthily.
Then place the mini greenhouse in a spot
with gentle sunlight and good
ventilation and continue to wait for the
orchid to
sprout. Soft light will help stimulate
the growth process without causing the
cutting to get sunburned or lose
moisture too quickly. Be patient. Those
lovely little sprouts will appear soon.
Now, let's take a look at the results
after 3 weeks of rooting the
[Music]
cutting. As you can see, the dormant bud
has now sprouted. This shows that the
cutting has adapted well to the
environment, absorbed enough nutrients,
and has begun developing into a healthy
young plant.
[Music]
I continue to mist regularly and place
the cutting in a spot with gentle
sunlight to maintain ideal conditions uh
helping the cutting develop steadily and
allowing the sprout to grow healthily.
[Music]
Now, let's check the results after 3
months of rooting the
[Music]
cutting. As you can see, the young
orchid has grown healthily with lush
green leaves that are strong and sturdy.
[Music]
The roots have also developed strongly,
proving that the rooting process was
successful and the orchid is growing
[Music]
well. Once the roots are strong and the
plant is sturdy, transferring the orchid
to a pot will help it grow better,
providing ample space for the plant to
continue
[Music]
thriving. Now I can transplant the young
orchid into a new pot so it can thrive
in an outdoor environment.
[Music]
I recycle plastic bottles into orchid
pots using the semihydroponic
[Music]
method. This method helps the orchid
receive sufficient moisture from the
water at the bottom of the pot while
keeping the roots well ventilated and
preventing water logging, creating ideal
conditions for the plant's growth.
[Music]
with this planting method. After
planting, I only need to water once and
change the water when it becomes dirty
in the pot.
The semihydroponic method helps maintain
moisture for the plant without the need
for frequent watering while also
promoting strong and healthy root
[Music]
development. The semihydroponic method
helps maintain moisture for the plant
without the need for frequent watering
while also promoting strong and healthy
root development.
[Music]
If you haven't subscribed to the channel
yet, please hit the subscribe button to
support me and not miss any orchid care
tips. It's wonderful to have you along
on this journey of caring for and
propagating
[Music]
orchids. Thank you for watching the
video. Goodbye and see you in the next
ones. Wishing you beautiful and healthy
[Music]
orchids. Welcome back to Happiness
Garden. Orchids are special plants that
require proper care to thrive and bloom
beautifully all year round.
Today, I'll guide you on how to make
natural fertilizer using simple, easy to
find ingredients that you probably
already have at
[Music]
home. This method is not only budget
friendly, but also incredibly safe for
your
plants. Let's dive in and get started.
[Music]
Today I used coffee grounds to make
natural
fertilizer. Take one cake of coffee
grounds about 20
[Music]
g. The next ingredient I used is
eggshells to make natural fertilizer.
Take clean, dry eggshells and crush them
into small
pieces. Coffee grounds provide nitrogen
for lush leaves, while eggshells add
calcium to strengthen roots.
The mild acidity of coffee grounds pairs
with the alkalinity of eggshells to
create a balanced pH suitable for
orchids.
[Music]
Put everything in a
jar. Add one liter of boiling
[Music]
water. If you haven't subscribed to the
channel yet, please click the subscribe
button to support me and not miss any
orchid growing tips.
In addition to the English voice over,
we have now created voiceovers in
French, German, Italian, Spanish, and
Portuguese to help you listen to and
understand the video content more
easily. How to select the audio language
on YouTube. One, open the video and
click on settings, the gear icon. Two,
select subtitles CC. Three, click on
audio and choose the language you want,
English, frutch, italiano, espanol, or
Portuguese.
Cover the jar and let it steep until the
water cools completely. Usually takes 1
to two
hours. Once cooled, strain out the
solids and keep the liquid.
Um, I don't watch videos, but if you
want to know where your viewers are
watching from, feel free to ask them to
share in the
comments. It's great that we can chat
together from all over the world.
[Music]
Add one liter of
water. Step one.
[Music]
Use a soft cotton pad to gently wipe the
upper and lower sides of the leaves with
this
solution. This method will remove dust,
helping the plant breathe better by
keeping the stamata open.
This fertilizer solution helps prevent
certain pests or fungi due to the mild
acidity from the coffee grounds and
minerals found in eggshells.
Uh, wiping the leave leaves helps supply
additional nutrients directly to the
plant, especially to weak areas or parts
that show signs of nutrient deficiency.
It's good to wipe the leaves with this
solution once every 1 to two weeks to
provide nutrients and help the plant
thrive. If you need to clean the leaves
or remove dust, you can wipe the leaves
once a week.
[Music]
Step
two. Next, we put this solution into a
spray bottle and spray it on each orchid
pot. Uh, shake the spray bottle before
use to ensure the solution is well
mixed.
Lightly spray the solution on both the
top and underside of the leaves,
avoiding the flowers to prevent
damage. You can also spray around the
roots if accessible.
spray the fertilizer solution once a
week or as needed.
Be sure not to overspray the plant to
avoid water logging.
[Music]
Step
three, water the orchid's growing
medium, focusing on the roots and around
the base of the
plant. Avoid watering directly onto the
leaves or flowers to prevent damage.
Uh, water the orchid with the fertilizer
solution once a week or as needed.
[Music]
If the solution feels too concentrated,
you can dilute it with water, especially
if the plant shows signs of being
sensitive.
Soak the orchid pot in the fertilizer
solution for about 20 minutes to allow
the roots to absorb enough water and
[Music]
nutrients. After soaking, remove the pot
from the solution and allow it to drain
before placing it back in its usual
[Music]
spot. Step four.
After watering or soaking the orchid pot
in the fertilizer solution, gently use
the cloth to absorb any excess water on
the surface of the leaves, both the top
and underside.
[Music]
Be sure to absorb thoroughly so there is
no water left on the leaves, which helps
the plant avoid water logging and allows
it to better absorb the nutrients.
[Music]
Then place the orchid pots in a spot
with gentle sunlight to help the orchids
photosynthesize well.
[Music]
However, avoid direct sunlight,
especially the harsh midday sun, as it
can cause leaf burn, heat shock, and
stress to the plants.
[Music]
Results after one
month. Uh as you can see the roots have
developed quickly and are very healthy.
[Music]
Healthy new roots promote faster growth,
providing a strong foundation for the
plant to bloom and develop.
[Music]
Healthy new roots promote faster growth,
providing a strong foundation for the
plant to bloom and develop, enhancing
its resilience against harsh
factors. You can see that the orchid has
produced many new flower spikes.
You see, on the same tree, four new
flower branches can grow at the same
time.
[Music]
And the leaves also become green, shiny
and very strong and
healthy.
Continue to care for your orchids with
all the love and dedication you have for
nature. When you invest your time and
effort, the beautiful blooms you receive
will be a wonderful reward, a testament
to the patience and care you've given to
each leaf and root.
[Music]
Keep nurturing them with love and you'll
experience the joy and satisfaction
every time you watch those orchids
bloom, bringing beauty and pride created
by your own hands.
Hope this video was helpful. Don't
forget to like, comment, share, and
subscribe for more
videos. Thanks for watching and
supporting the channel. Wishing you
success with your
orchids. See you next time.