Hello
friends today we will take care of
orchids with natural fertilizer from
[Music]
lemon more precisely lemon peel contains
a lot of vitamin C and essential oils
which are very beneficial for orchid
care supporting the plants Healthy
Growth from Roots to leaves and
[Music]
flowers choose one lemon
then just take the
[Music]
shell if you haven't subscribed to the
channel yet please click the Subscribe
button to support me and not miss any
Orchid growing tips it's great to have
company
[Music]
chopped in addition to the English dub
we've now created dubs in French German
Italian Spanish Portuguese Japanese
Hindi and Indonesian to help you hear
and understand the content videos are
easier uh to listen to the language open
the video and click the set settings
gear icon to select the appropriate
audio
language then puree with two cups of
water equivalent to about 500 M of
[Music]
water please comment to me which country
you are watching the video from it's
great that we can chat together from all
over the world
[Music]
filter out residue
take 100 ml of juice from lemon peel
about 1/3 a
[Music]
cup add water to get 1 liter of solution
first
[Music]
way clean the leaves with a solution of
the juice from the lemon peel
[Music]
this protects them from
pests wipe the underside of the leaves
carefully because this is where fungi
bacteria and insects often gather to
harm the Orchid
[Music]
second way
spray the solution on the entire
[Music]
Orchid this helps wash away dirt and
eliminate fungal diseases bacteria and
harmful
[Music]
insects spray this mixture on Orchids
every 2 weeks
[Music]
but do not spray on flowers and
buds because wet flowers will quickly
Fall
[Music]
Off Third Way
now we water this solution to take care
of the
roots lemon peel acidifies the Orchid
juice which contributes to better
absorption of nutrients and
[Music]
essential oils repel pests and protect
orchid leaves and roots from harmful
[Music]
bacteria or soak the Orchid pot in this
solution for 30 minutes if will be
[Music]
better do this every 2 weeks and the
Orchid will always be
[Music]
protected if you don't use all of it you
can freeze the juice from the lemon zest
for later use
[Music]
now let's see the results after caring
for orchids with natural
fertilizer after three times of use the
roots grow very well
[Music]
branched Roots developed to help the
Orchid absorb more
[Music]
nutrients leaves are clean always green
and free from pests
[Music]
help orchids photosynthesize
better flower buds grow and do not
fall flowers bloom brightly and stay
fresh
[Music]
fresh flowers stay on the branch for up
to 6 months before
[Music]
falling hope this sharing will help you
a lot
[Music]
subscribe to my channel to support me
and don't miss any tips on my
[Music]
channel next we will explore a simple
method for creating a beautiful flower
season and impressing with a fertilizer
easily found around the house
[Music]
surely you are wondering how to help
your flower plants grow strong and
vibrant right
[Music]
this simple method helps your orchids
Stay Green and have lots of buds the
buds always grow plump
[Music]
flowers bloom well and last a long
time new roots are always growing
helps orchids absorb nutrients
[Music]
best now let's make fertilizer
together this is garlic powder that
every home has right
take 1 teaspoon of garlic powder and add
1 liter of boiled
[Music]
water then wait for it to cool before
using
[Music]
then filter out the residue
after filtering use a towel to wipe the
top and bottom of the leaves with this
[Music]
water garlic has antibacterial
properties so it helps eliminate fungi
and insects on leaves very
[Music]
well in addition garlic also has many
natural minerals necessary for orchid
[Music]
growth apply once a month for better
protection and
[Music]
growth if you do this regularly your
orchids will always be green and
disease-free
[Music]
next you can also spray this water on
the entire orchid
[Music]
uh this also helps provide nutrients
through the leaves to the
[Music]
Orchid um you should thoroughly spray
both the underside of the leaves and the
leaf
[Music]
interstices because that is where
insects and fungi often reside causing
harm to orchids
[Music]
finally you use this water to care for
the roots
water each Orchid pot with about 10
tblspoon of garlic soaking
[Music]
water this and the way you spray you
apply it every 2 to 3
[Music]
weeks garlic contains natural compounds
that have antibacterial and antifungal
properties helps protect orchids from
pests and other harmful
[Music]
agents garlic powder also helps
strengthen the plant's natural immune
system and reduces the risk of infection
[Music]
nutrients found in garlic such as
potassium and phosphorus nitrogen
provides essential nutrients for orchid
[Music]
growth uh after 1 month of of fertiliz
in with garlic powder the plant has
grown many new
[Music]
Roots uh this will help the Orchid more
easily absorb more
[Music]
nutrients when new Roots grow a lot it
is necessary to combine the use of other
types of organic fertilizers such as
fish protein and soy protein follow my
instructions to help orchids absorb a
variety of
[Music]
nutrients if you encounter any
difficulties during the Orchid growing
process don't hesitate to comment I am
always ready to support you so you can
grow healthy orchids and Bloom lots of
[Music]
flowers using garlic powder as
fertilizer helps orchids grow strongly
[Music]
orchids grow many flower stems at the
same time in the same Orchid
[Music]
pot orchids become more vibrant and have
a characteristic fragrance
[Music]
now I share how to care for phenopsis
orchids that bloom continuously from
season to season
[Music]
in the summer orchids often rot like
this this is a disease caused by
[Music]
bacteria it spreads very quickly but
don't worry
[Music]
take one liter of water at at room
temperature this is an anti-rot medicine
for
cabbage its composition includes stomy
[Music]
40% it will remove bacteria very quickly
you only put in one4 of the tablet
[Music]
put it in a spray bottle and spray it
all over the
[Music]
Orchid uh I intentionally did not remove
the rotten leaves to show you how step
toyle works
[Music]
any rotten areas need to be sprayed
more spray even disease-free leaves
[Music]
after spraying leave the Orchid pot in a
cool place and do not water for one
[Music]
[Applause]
week see results after 1
[Music]
week all leaves affected by bacterial
rot are dry
[Music]
do you see the effectiveness of stomy
against bacteria that cause Orchid Leaf
[Music]
rot uh the rotten orchid has recovered
and grown new
[Music]
leaves after recovering from the disease
Recovery Care is needed to help the
Orchid grow and Bloom quickly
this is a
[Music]
multivitamin dissolve one tablet in one
liter of
[Music]
water uh wait for the vitamins to
dissolve and then add 2 L of water to
get 3 l of great
[Music]
fertilizer use cotton soaked in this
water to wipe the leaves
[Music]
help supplement nutrition and clear
stamata helps orchids photosynthesize
[Music]
better strong orchid leaves increase
resistance to fungi and insects
[Music]
or you can also spray this liquid
fertilizer on the entire orchid
um this method works as well as mopping
[Music]
leaves spraying evenly at the base is
very good for orchids
but don't spray it on the flowers
because if the flowers are wet they will
quickly
fade now you take care of the
roots you water this liquid fertilizer
on the Orchid roots
[Music]
this helps orchids absorb the most
nutrients because the roots are the main
nutrient absorbers of the
[Music]
Orchid for infected plants do this every
2 weeks
[Music]
with normal orchids you do this once
every 1 to 2
[Music]
months um helps orchids grow very
quickly and increase resistance
[Music]
uh it is best to soak the Orchid pot in
this water for 30 minutes and then take
it
[Music]
out after only 2 weeks of care the
orchid has grown grown many new
[Music]
Roots many flower buds grow on the same
tree
[Music]
thank you for watching the video good
luck and see you in the next videos