Hello
friends. When the new orchid withers all
its flowers, this is the best time to
cut the flowers to help them sprout
faster. Which country are you watching
this video from? Please comment below.
It's so great that we can chat with each
other from all around the
[Music]
world. Uh, peel off the protective film
so that the buds will germinate faster.
[Music]
Cut back the branch with a sharp knife
so as not to crush the cut.
[Music]
Pour melted candle solution into the cut
to help the cut heal. quickly and not
[Music]
rot. Sprinkle cinnamon powder on the
freshly cut wound at the base to help
protect the orchid from rot.
Use one large garlic clove or two small
garlic
[Music]
cloves. Hash small
Put the garlic in the jar.
[Music]
Pour in 500 milliliters of water at room
temperature. Wait 30 minutes for the
nutrients from the garlic to dissolve
into the water.
[Music]
Use foam to arrange
flowers. Heat.
[Music]
Heat. Heat. Heat.
After soaking for 30 minutes, filter out
the residue.
[Music]
Soak orchid branches in garlic water for
minutes. 30 minutes
later. Take
out. Plug in the sucker.
[Music]
Pour in filtered water just enough to
moisten. Close the lid and wait for the
orchid branch to
sprout.
After the next three
[Music]
weeks, sprouts have woken up.
after one. Next
[Music]
month, the orchid sprouts have grown and
the roots have
[Music]
grown.
After the next two months,
[Music]
The small orchid has grown
healthy. Now, let's plant the orchid in
pots so that it can adapt to the outside
environment.
[Music]
Welcome to my channel.
Today I will share an easy and quick way
to propagate orchids from flower spikes,
helping you propagate orchids at home
effortlessly. Let's get
started. This orchid has just finished
blooming. Now I will cut this flower
spike to start propagating the orchid.
[Music]
The best time to propagate orchids is
when the petals start to
[Music]
fade. The nodes that have already
bloomed cannot be used for propagation.
So, I will cut this part
[Music]
off. Uh, we can use the nodes that
haven't bloomed yet for orchid
propagation.
[Music]
I am removing the protective layer of
the dormant bud uh to help it sprout
faster.
[Music]
Please comment and let me know which
country you are watching from. It's
amazing that we can connect from all
around the world.
[Music]
In addition to the English dub, we've
now created dubs in French, German,
Italian, Spanish, Portuguese, Japanese,
Hindi, and Indonesian to make it easier
for you to hear and understand the
content. Enjoy the videos.
[Music]
I cut it again so that the orchid stem
is not crushed.
[Music]
This diagonal cut increases surface
area, allowing for better water
absorption when propagating from
cutings.
[Music]
Baby.
Then I apply cinnamon powder to the cut
to help it heal quickly and prevent
rotting.
[Music]
I continue applying cinnamon powder here
to help the cut heal quickly.
[Music]
Then I add 1 teaspoon of cinnamon powder
into a jar and mix it with 2 cups of hot
water about 0.5 L.
[Music]
Cinnamon powder contains natural
minerals such as nitrogen, phosphorus,
potassium, and calcium. It also has
anti-antibacterial and antiseptic
properties, making it excellent for
caring for and propagating orchids by
cutting.
After mixing, we let it sit for 2 hours
to allow the nutrients to dissolve into
the water and also to let the water cool
down before
applying. Then take an aloe vera leaf
which contains salicylic acid and and
enzymes that stimulate root formation,
help helping the cutings develop new
roots quickly.
[Music]
Insert the orchid cutting into the aloe
vera leaf and wait for 1
[Music]
hour. Thanks to its antibacterial
properties, aloe vera helps protect the
cutting from infections and harmful
bacteria or fungi.
Aloe vera contains essential minerals
and vitamins including calcium,
magnesium, zinc, and vitamins A, C, and
E, which support the healthy growth of
young
plants. The compounds in aloe vera help
the cutting resist adverse environmental
conditions, increasing its survival and
growth potential.
Then wait for 1 hour to allow the
nutrients to absorb into the
[Music]
cutting. After 1 hour, remove the orchid
cutting from the aloe vera gel.
[Music]
Then slice the aloe vera leaf into
pieces and put them into the jar.
[Music]
Add four cups of hot water, about one
liter.
[Applause]
Cover the jar and wait for the water to
cool before using.
[Music]
After the water cools, mix the cinnamon
water and aloe vera water together to
create a nutrient-rich solution.
[Music]
The mixture of cinnamon water and aloe
vera water is a highly effective natural
method for propagating orchids from
[Music]
[Applause]
cutings. Aloe vera contains oxin and
salicylic acid which help stimulate root
growth.
[Music]
[Applause]
Aloe vera provides essential vitamins A,
C, E, and minerals calcium, magnesium,
zinc that help the cutting stay
[Music]
healthy. Cinnamon contains
cinnamaldahhide, which helps promote
cell division, making roots grow faster
and stronger.
[Music]
Cinnamon is especially effective in
preventing mold and root rot. Uh
providing a clean environment for the
cutting to grow.
[Music]
Okay. Thanks to the bioactive compounds
in cinnamon and aloe vera, the plant
will have better resistance to
environmental stress and harmful
insects.
[Music]
Soak the orchid cutting in this mixture
for 20 minutes.
[Music]
Use the remaining mixture to care for
other
[Music]
orchids. Wiping orchid leaves with the
cinnamon and aloe vera mixture provides
many benefits. Not only keeping the
leaves shiny, but also enhancing the
overall health of the orchid.
[Music]
Dust on the leaves can reduce the
plant's ability to absorb light. Wiping
the leaves with this mixture helps keep
them clean, shiny, and improves
photosynthesis efficiency.
[Music]
Aloe vera gel provides natural moisture,
preventing the leaves from drying out or
losing water too quickly. Um, especially
useful in dry
[Music]
weather. The scent of cinnamon can help
repel certain pests, especially
spidermitites, meie bugs, and other
harmful insects.
Apply this method one to two times per
month to keep orchid leaves healthy and
shiny
[Music]
green. Then water each orchid pot with
this mixture.
Aloe vera contains oxin and salicylic
acid which promote fast and healthy root
growth. Cinnamon stimulates cell
division, helping orchid roots grow
longer and anchor firmly to the
substrate.
[Music]
To propagate orchids from flower spikes,
I use dried moss to maintain optimal
moisture
levels. Before propagation, I soak the
dried moss in the cinnamon and aloe vera
mixture to sterilize the growing medium.
[Music]
This is an important step to ensure the
orchid cutting has a clean, safe, and
nutrient-rich environment for quick root
development. We need to soak it for
about 20
[Music]
minutes. Then we take out the moss to
propagate the orchid cutting.
[Music]
Insert the orchid cutting into the pot,
ensuring the node is close to the
surface of the moist moss to prevent
rot.
[Music]
Then cover the cover the top of the
orchid propagation pot with a
transparent plastic lid with a
ventilation
[Music]
hole. Spray water to maintain moisture
in the orchid propagation pot once a
week.
[Music]
Place the orchid propagation pot in a
spot with gentle sunlight and a
temperature between 23 to 28° 73 to 82°
F, which is the ideal condition for the
orchid cutting to
[Music]
sprout. Now, let's take a look at the
results after 45 days of
[Music]
propagation. Amazing. You can see that
the orchid seedlings have sprouted and
developed healthy looking roots.
[Music]
However, the orchid is still small, so
I've decided to continue nurturing it in
the pot until it grows bigger before
transplanting. Continue misting once a
week and keep the nursery pot in a spot
with gentle sunlight.
[Music]
Now let's check the results after
another 45 days of propagation.
[Music]
You can see that after 90 days of
propagation from the cutting, the orchid
has grown strong with firm leaves and
healthy roots.
[Music]
With this simple method, you can
propagate orchids at home by reusing
flower spikes after the blooms have
faded.
[Music]
If you find this content helpful and
meaningful, don't forget to like, share
so more people can learn and subscribe
to support me. Thank you for always
being with me.
[Music]
Now I am planting them in pots so they
can grow in an outdoor
[Music]
environment. I am using crushed pine
bark because it retains the necessary
moisture to keep the orchid from drying
out. At the same time, it provides good
drainage, preventing root rot or plant
decay.
[Music]
And after planting in the pot, we spread
a thin layer of moss on top to maintain
proper humidity, helping the, you know,
helping the orchid adapt smoothly to its
new environment without stress.
[Music]
Um after planting we should water
regularly to maintain moisture whenever
the growing medium feels dry. Avoid
fertilizing until the new roots have
firmly attached to the
[Music]
substrate. If you stay patient and
dedicated in nurturing them, one day
you'll have a vibrant garden where
orchids bloom beautifully, just like
[Music]
mine. Thank you for watching the video.
Wishing you good luck and endless joy in
life.