Welcome back to Happiness Garden.
Orchids are special plants that require
proper care to thrive and bloom
beautifully all year round.
Today, I'll guide you on how to make
natural fertilizer using simple, easy to
find ingredients that you probably
already have at home.
[Music]
This method is not only budget friendly,
but also incredibly safe for your
plants.
[Music]
Let's dive in and get started.
Today I used coffee grounds to make
natural fertilizer.
[Music]
Take one cake of coffee grounds about 20
g.
The next ingredient I used is eggshells
to make natural fertilizer.
[Music]
Take clean, dry eggshells and crush them
into small pieces.
[Music]
Coffee grounds provide nitrogen for lush
leaves while eggshells add calcium to
strengthen roots.
[Music]
The mild acidity of coffee grounds pairs
with the alkalinity of eggshells to
create a balanced pH suitable for
orchids.
[Music]
Put everything in a jar.
Add one liter of boiling water.
[Music]
If you haven't subscribed to the channel
yet, please click the subscribe button
to support me and not miss any orchid
growing tips.
In addition to the English voice over,
we have now created voiceovers in
French, German, Italian, Spanish, and
Portuguese to help you listen to and
understand the video content more
easily.
How to select the audio language on
YouTube. One, open the video and click
on settings, the gear icon. Two, select
subtitles, CC. Three, click on audio and
choose the language you want, English,
Franc, Deutsch, italiano, espanol, or
Portuguese.
Cover the jar and let it steep until the
water cools completely. Usually takes 1
to 2 hours.
[Music]
Once cooled, strain out the solids and
keep the liquid.
[Music]
Um, I don't watch videos, but if you
want to know where your viewers are
watching from, feel free to ask them to
share in the comments.
It's great that we can chat together
from all over the world.
[Music]
Add one liter of water.
Step one,
[Music]
use a soft cotton pad to gently wipe the
upper and lower sides of the leaves with
this solution.
This method will remove dust, helping
the plant breathe better by keeping the
stamata open.
[Music]
This fertilizer solution helps prevent
certain pests or fungi due to the mild
acidity from the coffee grounds and
minerals found in eggshells.
[Music]
Uh, wiping the leave leaves helps supply
additional nutrients directly to the
plant, especially to weak areas or parts
that show signs of nutrient deficiency.
[Music]
It's good to wipe the leaves with this
solution once every 1 to two weeks to
provide nutrients and help the plant
thrive.
[Music]
If you need to clean the leaves or
remove dust, you can wipe the leaves
once a week.
[Music]
Step two.
Next, we put this solution into a spray
bottle and spray it on each orchid pot.
[Music]
Uh shake the spray bottle before use to
ensure the solution is well mixed.
[Music]
Lightly spray the solution on both the
top and underside of the leaves,
avoiding the flowers to prevent damage.
[Music]
You can also spray around the roots if
accessible.
[Music]
Spray the fertilizer solution once a
week or as needed.
[Music]
Be sure not to overspray the plant to
avoid water logging.
[Music]
Step three,
water the orchid's growing medium,
focusing on the roots and around the
base of the plant.
[Music]
Avoid watering directly onto the leaves
or flowers to prevent damage.
[Music]
Uh, water the orchid with the fertilizer
solution once a week or as needed.
[Music]
If the solution feels too concentrated,
you can dilute it with water, especially
if the plant shows signs of being
sensitive.
[Music]
Soak the orchid pot in the fertilizer
solution for about 20 minutes to allow
the roots to absorb enough water and
nutrients.
[Music]
After soaking, remove the pot from the
solution and allow it to drain before
placing it back in its usual spot.
Step four.
After watering or soaking the orchid pot
in the fertilizer solution, gently use
the cloth to absorb any excess water on
the surface of the leaves, both the top
and underside.
[Music]
Be sure to absorb thoroughly so there is
no water left on the leaves, which helps
the plant avoid water logging and allows
it to better absorb the nutrients.
[Music]
then place the orchid pots in a spot
with gentle sunlight to help the orchids
photosynthesize well.
However, avoid direct sunlight,
especially the harsh midday sun, as it
can cause leaf burn, heat shock, and
stress to the plants.
[Music]
results after 1 month.
Uh, as you can see, the roots have
developed quickly and are very healthy.
[Music]
Healthy new roots promote faster growth,
providing a strong foundation for the
plant to bloom and develop.
Healthy new roots promote faster growth,
providing a strong foundation for the
plant to bloom and develop, enhancing
its resilience against harsh factors.
[Music]
You can see that the orchid has produced
many new flower spikes.
You see, on the same tree, four new
flower branches can grow at the same
time.
[Music]
And the leaves also become green, shiny
and very strong and healthy.
[Music]
Continue to care for your orchids with
all the love and dedication you have for
nature.
When you invest your time and effort,
the beautiful blooms you receive will be
a wonderful reward, a testament to the
patience and care you've given to each
leaf and root.
Keep nurturing them with love, and
you'll experience the joy and
satisfaction every time you watch those
orchids bloom, bringing beauty and pride
created by your own hands.
[Music]
Hope this video was helpful. Don't
forget to like, comment, share, and
subscribe for more videos.
[Music]
Thanks for watching and supporting the
channel. Wishing you success with your
orchids.
See you next time.
[Music]
Welcome to the happiness garden. Today
I'm very happy to share with you a
simple yet incredibly effective way to
help orchids quickly grow roots and
bloom more brilliantly than ever.
You will be surprised by the results
after just a short time of proper care.
If you haven't subscribed to the channel
yet, please hit the subscribe button to
support me and not miss any orchid
growing tips. It's wonderful to have you
with me.
Let's get started.
This is one of the orchid pots that once
had rotting leaves, was wilted, and weak
after blooming. I bought it at a very
low price from a local flower shop
during a clearance sale.
Although it looked exhausted, I believed
that with just a bit of patience and
love, the plant could still be revived
and come back more radiant than before.
[Music]
Since this orchid has been planted for
quite a long time, the first step we
need to take is to remove all the old
growing medium.
[Music]
This helps eliminate any remaining
pathogens and creates the best
conditions for new roots to grow
healthily in a clean environment.
[Applause]
[Music]
As you can see, the entire root system
of this orchid has been completely
damaged. This is the reason why the
plant couldn't absorb water and
nutrients, leading to wilting and
weakening after blooming.
[Music]
We need to gently trim off all the old
roots, damaged roots, and any dry stems
that are no longer alive.
[Music]
Uh this cleaning process will help the
plant focus on nourishing the healthy
parts and stimulate faster root growth.
[Music]
Don't forget to remove the old leaves
that have turned black as they are
potential spots for harmful fungal
infections.
[Music]
Timely removal will help protect the
remaining parts of the orchid, keeping
them safe and healthier during the
recovery process.
[Music]
After trimming and removing the damaged
parts, let's rinse the entire orchid
thoroughly with water.
[Music]
Uh, this simple step helps remove any
remaining dirt and bacteria, creating a
clean condition before moving on to the
next treatment step.
[Music]
Uh to start making natural fertilizer,
simply take 100 ml of clean water and
pour it into a cup.
Next, add 1 teasp of garlic powder into
the cup.
Garlic has natural antibacterial
properties, helping to prevent fungal
diseases while also safely and
effectively stimulating orchid root
growth.
[Music]
After preparing the mixture, soak the
old stem of the orchid in this solution
for about 20 to 30 minutes. This gently
disinfects the plant while also
providing nutrients to stimulate the
formation of new roots.
[Music]
While waiting for the soaking process, I
take advantage of the time to recycle
old foam pieces into growing tools for
the orchid that needs recovery.
This is a simple and cost-effective
method that not only helps stabilize the
plant, but also creates ideal air flow
for new root development.
[Music]
Leave me a comment letting me know which
country you're watching from. It's
wonderful that we can connect and chat
from all around the world.
In addition to the English voiceover,
we've now created versions in French,
German, Italian, Spanish, Portuguese,
Japanese, Hindi, Dutch, Polish, Korean,
and Indonesian to help you listen and
understand the content more easily.
To listen in your language, open the
video and click on settings, the gear
icon, to select your preferred audio
language.
[Music]
After soaking for about 20 minutes, take
the orchid out and use a clean cloth to
dry off any remaining water on the stem.
[Music]
This gentle drying step helps prevent
prolonged moisture, one of the main
causes of stem rot and fungal
infections.
[Music]
Gently insert the base of the orchid
into the piece of foam just like I'm
doing here.
The foam will help keep the plant firmly
in place, creating an ideal environment
for young roots to grow strong from the
very beginning.
After securing the plant in the foam,
place the entire setup into a clear
glass cup.
Next, pour clean water into the glass
cup, just enough to keep the foam and
the old stem of the plant moist,
avoiding submerging the young stem
above.
This helps new roots grow quickly,
healthily, and stronger day by day.
[Music]
Each week you just need to change the
water once to keep the environment clean
and prevent harmful bacteria from
affecting the plant.
[Music]
Uh this method allows us to easily
observe the daily growth of new roots
while also creating a clean and elegant
feel for your little orchid care corner.
Place the orchid cup in a spot with
gentle sunlight, avoiding harsh direct
light that can burn the leaves. Soft
light will help the plant grow well and
stimulate faster root development.
[Music]
And here is the result after 3 weeks.
Uh you can see that the new roots have
grown abundantly, white, healthy, and
full of vitality. Um a wonderful start
to the orchid's recovery journey.
[Music]
I hope you'll enjoy this video. If you
find it helpful, don't forget to like
and subscribe to the channel so you
won't miss the next tips on how to care
for orchids naturally and simply.
[Music]
What do you think about the way I
revived this weak orchid? Don't hesitate
to leave a comment and share your
thoughts. I'd love to hear your feedback
and experiences.
[Music]
If you face any difficulties during the
orchid growing process, don't hesitate
to leave a comment. I'm always ready to
support you so you can grow healthy
orchids that bloom beautifully.
[Music]
Now I will plant the orchid in a new pot
so it can grow in an outdoor
environment.
[Music]
At the bottom of the pot, I place a few
small pieces of foam to improve air flow
and help with better drainage.
On top of the foam layer, I spread a
layer of hydroponic planting pellets.
This layer helps retain moisture,
provides air flow, and creates a clean
environment where orchid roots can grow
easily without becoming suffocated.
[Music]
On top, I cover with a layer of moss to
naturally retain moisture for the plant.
This moss layer helps maintain stable
humidity while creating a soft and root
friendly environment for new roots to
grow.
[Music]
Then, gently place the orchid into the
pot and remember to secure the stem with
a support stick. This stabilization
helps the plant stay upright and
prevents movement during the rooting and
recovery process.
[Music]
Only water to maintain moisture when you
see the growing medium starting to dry
out. Moderate humidity will help new
roots develop steadily and stay healthy
over time.
Keep in mind orchids need water to grow,
but they also tolerate drought quite
well. Overwatering can easily lead to
root rot. So, always maintain just the
right amount of moisture, not too wet
and not too dry.
Only when the roots have started to
firmly attach to the growing medium
should you begin fertilizing the orchid.
At this stage, the plant is stable and
ready to absorb nutrients for stronger
growth.
Place the orchid pot in a spot with
gentle cool sunlight. A soft morning
light will support good photosynthesis
and naturally encourage root growth and
sprouting.
[Music]
Each time you patiently revive a plant
over time, you'll gradually create a
beautiful garden like mine where orchid
blooms flourish in all four seasons,
bringing joy and peace every day.
[Music]
It helps brighten up your living space,
making it more vibrant and full of life.
Each blooming flower is not only the
result of care, but also a spiritual
gift that nurtures daily joy.
Thank you for joining me on the journey
of caring for and reviving orchid pots
that once seemed lifeless.
I hope you carry with you plenty of
inspiration and confidence to start
nurturing your own little garden.
See you in the next video where we'll
continue to share simple yet meaningful
things from nature. Wishing you a
peaceful day filled with blooming
flowers.