[Music]
Welcome to my garden. Today I continue
to share how to make natural fertilizer
for orchids using readily available and
inexpensive ingredients that are highly
effective.
To make today's natural fertilizer, I
need one aloe vera leaf. Then I cut the
aloe vera leaf into thin slices to
easily extract the nutrients from
inside. Uh please comment and let me
know which country you're watching the
video from. It's amazing that we can
chat together from all around the
world. Next, I place the sliced aloe
vera into one liter of clean water to
soak. Soaking the aloe vera in water
allows natural nutrients like vitamins
and enzymes to be released, creating a
nourishing solution that is very
beneficial for
orchids. Then I cover the container and
let the mixture sit for a few hours so
the aloe vera can naturally release its
nutrients. Next, I place the sliced aloe
vera into one liter of clean water to
soak. Soaking the aloe vera in water
allows natural nutrients like vitamins
and enzymes to be released, creating a
nourishing solution that is very
beneficial for orchids.
Next, I prepare.5 L of clean water to
dissolve the vitamin
B1. Dissolving the vitamin B1 separately
helps it dissolve better before mixing
with the aloe vera water, ensuring that
the orchid can absorb the maximum
nutrients.
[Music]
Uh, if you haven't subscribed yet, make
sure to hit the subscribe button to
support me and not miss any orchid care
tips. It's wonderful to have you as a
companion. Then I strain the mixture
through a sie to remove the residue of
the vitamin B1, keeping only the
nutrient-rich liquid.
This ensures that the nourishing
solution doesn't have any residue,
residue, or blockages when watering the
orchids, allowing the plants to easily
absorb the
nutrients. Step one, I use a soft cloth
to soak up the B1 solution and gently
wipe both the top and bottom of the
orchid leaves.
This helps the plant absorb nutrients
directly through the leaves while also
cleaning off dirt and bacteria,
supporting the orchid's healthy growth.
[Music]
Wiping the leaves helps the orchid
maintain good health throughout the
blooming period as vitamin B1 provides
the necessary nutrients for the leaves
and other parts of the plant.
When the orchid is blooming, the leaves
can easily accumulate dust or water
spots. Wiping the leaves clean helps
keep the plant fresh and ensures that
dirt doesn't block the photosynthesis
process.
[Music]
This method also helps reduce the risk
of orchids getting sick during the
blooming period, keeping the flowers
fresh for a longer
time. Clean orchid leaves will make it
easier to maintain good humidity,
helping the plant avoid dehydration
while focusing its energy on blooming.
Clean and shiny orchid leaves not only
help the plant stay healthier, but also
enhance the beauty of the flowers,
creating harmony for the entire
orchid. In fact, you only need to do
this one to two times a month to help
the plant maintain good health.
Step two, pour the B1 water into a spray
bottle. Then evenly spray it onto the
orchid
plant. When spraying B1 water onto the
plant, remember to spray both the top
and bottom of the leaves. This helps the
plant absorb nutrients more easily,
stimulates root growth, and supports the
plant's health throughout the blooming
process.
You can also spray it onto the roots and
base to boost the vitality of your
orchid. The best time to spray B1 water
is in the early morning or during the
cooler evening hours.
This helps the plant absorb nutrients
easily without being damaged by the
intense
sunlight. Don't spray too much. Just a
fine mist is enough to prevent the plant
from becoming water logged.
However, make sure not to spray B1 water
onto the
flowers because wet flowers are more
likely to lose their
petals. Only spray the leaves, base, and
roots to ensure the plant grows healthy
without affecting the flowers.
Um, you can pour the remaining B1 water
into a cup to use for the next step.
Then I proceed to filter out the aloe
vera residue. The filtered aloe vera
water will be mixed with the water that
already contains dissolved vitamin B1.
[Music]
Step three, water each orchid pot with
the aloe vera and B1 mixture.
I use this mixture to water directly at
the base of each orchid
pot. Each pot only needs to be watered
with just enough to keep the soil or
growing medium slightly moist.
This mixture will help the plant recover
quickly, grow strong roots, and be ready
for the next growth cycle.
[Music]
This mixture provides essential
nutrients, helping the orchid stay
healthy and keeping the flowers fresh
and beautiful throughout the blooming
process. Uh, vitamin B1 will help the
plant develop strong roots, which in
turn allows the orchid to absorb
nutrients better and grow steadily
throughout the blooming process.
Aloe vera water has natural
antibacterial properties, helping the
plant defend against disease-causing
agents like mold and
bacteria. This mixture supports the
orchid after the flowers fade, helping
to restore its health and prepare for
the new growth cycle.
[Music]
Watering with this nourishing solution
helps keep the leaves healthy and clean,
thereby improving the photosynthesis
process and providing enough energy for
the plant's
growth. Watering with this mixture helps
reduce stress on the plant, especially
in in changing environmental conditions
or when the plant faces difficulties in
blooming.
To keep the orchid healthy and growing
well, you only need to do this one to
two times a
month. If the orchid is blooming and you
feel it's necessary, you can do it once
more during the month, but remember, not
more than three
times. After watering the orchid with
the mixture, soak the pot in the
solution for about 20 minutes. This
helps the plant absorb nutrients
optimally, promoting strong root and
leaf
growth. Step four, use a dry cloth to
wipe off any leftover liquid fertilizer
droplets from the spaces between the
leaves.
This will help prevent the fertilizer
from staying on the plant for too long,
which could cause the tips to rot or
affect the plant's growth.
Um, after wiping, the plant will dry
quickly and be ready for a new growth
cycle. Remember to be gentle to avoid
damaging the
plant. Um, standing water is an ideal
environment for mold and disease-causing
bacteria. Drying the plant helps protect
it from common issues like leaf rot and
crown rot.
Clean and dry leaves absorb light more
efficiently, which supports a smooth
photosynthesis process and helps the
plant grow strong and healthy.
When you wipe off the water, you have a
chance to closely inspect the leaves and
promptly detect any any unusual signs
such as disease spots, pests, or damaged
leaves.
After soaking for about 20 minutes,
gently take the orchid pot out and place
it in a spot with gentle
sunlight. Placing the plant in gentle
sunlight helps the orchid
photosynthesize better, keeps the leaves
green and healthy, and supports root
development as well as flower
nourishment.
Avoid placing the plant under direct
harsh sunlight as strong light can cause
the leaves to wilt or shock the
plant. I hope today's video will be
truly helpful and bring great value to
you in the process of caring for your
beloved orchid pots.
Um, if you found the video helpful,
don't forget to hit like and subscribe
to support me. See you in the next
videos.