Hello everyone. Today I'm going to share
with you a simple way to make natural
fertilizer at home, which will help your
orchids grow healthy, lush, and bloom
beautifully throughout the
[Music]
garden. Thanks to this natural
fertilizer, the roots and leaves of the
plant will stay healthy, which in turn
helps the orchid produce not only more
flowers, but also longerlasting blooms
that retain their color and stay on the
stem for a long time before fading.
The method is very simple. Anyone can do
it using familiar ingredients found
right in the
kitchen. Let's get
started. You can easily notice that this
orchid is having a pro problem as many
of its leaves have turned yellow and
show signs of
rot. We need to remove the damaged
leaves from the orchid immediately as
this will help the plant recover and
grow better.
After removing the damaged leaves, we
need to carefully check the roots and
the orchid's growing medium to ensure
the plant is not infected and has a good
environment for for growth.
Cut off the damaged roots to help the
orchid regenerate and grow healthier.
[Music]
Um, this orchid pot I bought from an
industrial orchid garden is entirely
planted with moss which helps retain
moisture very well. However, if um if
the watering is not carefully
controlled, the plant is very prone to
root
rot. Therefore, I will remove about 2/3
of the old moss and replace it with new
growing medium, which is pine bark. uh
to help the roots stay more airrated and
prevent water
logging. You should not completely
remove the old growing medium because
the orchid still has flowers. Keeping it
will help to maintain moisture and grow
steadily.
Then remove the wilted flowers to help
the orchid focus its energy on
developing new buds and extend the
freshness of the remaining flowers on
the
stem. Next, we will prepare natural
fertilizer to help the orchid recover
quickly without affecting the beautiful
flowers remaining on the stem.
The first ingredient I need to make
natural fertilizer is
coffee. Take three teaspoons of coffee
and put them into the bottle.
[Music]
Next, pour one liter of boiling water
into the coffee
bottle.
Close the lid and let it sit overnight
so the nutrients from the coffee can
fully dissolve into the
[Music]
water. The next ingredient I will use to
make natural fertilizer is oat flour.
Take 3 teaspoon of oat flour and put
them into the bottle.
Then add one liter of room temperature
water to the bottle.
Um, close the lid and let it sit
overnight so the nutrients from the oat
flour can fully dissolve into the
[Music]
water. After one night, strain out the
coffee grounds and oat flour, keeping
only the liquid to use as fertilizer for
the
[Music]
orchid. After one night, strain out the
coffee grounds and oat flour, keeping
only the liquid to use as fertilizer for
the orchid.
[Music]
Step one, use a soft cotton ball to soak
up the coffee mixture and gently wipe
the top and bottom of the orchid
leaves. Wiping the leaves with the
coffee solution helps remove dust and
residue from the leaf surface,
especially the top side where most of
the photosynthesis takes
place. Clean leaves help the plant
absorb light more effectively, thereby
boosting energy production for the
orchid's growth.
[Music]
Coffee contains natural compounds that
can gently polish the leaves, making the
orchid leaves look healthier and more
vibrant. A glossy leaf surface not only
looks attractive, but also reflects that
the plant is in good health and
thriving.
This is sy mold on the orchid. Orchids
that lack sunlight and are in humid
environments are often affected by sy
mold. The coffee solution also helps
eliminate fungi, especially sy mold on
orchid leaves.
Diluted coffee solution can provide a
small amount of nutrients such as
potassium and antioxidants directly
supporting the nutrition of the
leaves. Um, absorption through the leaf
epidermis helps increase resistance and
improve the overall vitality of the
plant.
[Music]
The scent and natural compounds in
coffee can help reduce the presence of
small insects like aphids or fungusnats,
which are common pests that harm
orchids. Regularly wiping the leaves
helps keep the plant clean and less
prone to pest
attacks. Coffee has mild antibacterial
properties, helping to limit the growth
of harmful mold and bacteria on the
leaves. At the same time, it creates
conditions for beneficial microorganisms
to thrive, promoting healthy orchid
leaves and reducing the risk of rot or
leaf
spots. Wiping the orchid leaves with
coffee solution one to two times a month
helps keep the plant clean, provides
gentle nutrients, and reduces insects
without overloading the plant.
Step two, pour the coffee solution into
a spray bottle and spray it evenly over
the entire orchid plant.
Coffee has mild antibacterial
properties, helping to prevent the
growth of mold and harmful bacteria on
the leaves and
stem. When sprayed, the coffee solution
helps wash away dirt and mold, keeping
the orchid leaves clean and healthier.
[Music]
Diluted coffee solution helps provide a
small amount of nutrients such as
potassium and antioxidants, supporting
the orchid's healthy growth and boosting
its
resistance. The natural scent of coffee
helps repel some small insects,
protecting the orchid from pest
attacks. Um, you should spray the
diluted coffee solution on the orchid
about once a month. This helps the plant
absorb nutrients effectively without
overloading
[Music]
it. Then mix the oat solution with the
coffee solution to create a natural
fertilizer rich in nutrients, helping
the orchid recover quickly and grow
healthily.
[Music]
Before mixing, we need to strain out the
oat residue to ensure that the
fertilizer solution doesn't get clogged
when used and can easily be absorbed
evenly by the orchid.
[Music]
Then soak the orchid roots in this
mixture for 20 minutes to provide direct
nutrients to the roots, stimulating
growth and rapid recovery of the plant.
[Music]
Soaking the roots in this mixture helps
with antibacterial action, disinfecting
and stimulates the growth of new roots
for the orchid.
[Music]
Um, after soaking for 20 minutes, remove
the orchid and plant it in a new pot,
providing the orchid with a better
growing environment with well-airrated
growing medium and sufficient nutrients.
[Music]
I use broken pine bark as the growing
medium for orchids to enhance root
irerration, prevent water logging, and
create an ideal environment for orchid
growth. Please leave a comment letting
me know which country you're watching
this video from. It's amazing that we
can chat together from all around the
world. If you haven't subscribed to the
channel yet, click the subscribe button
to to support me and never miss any
orchid care tips. It's wonderful to have
you as a companion on this journey.
[Music]
Next, spread a little moss on top of the
pot to help retain moisture for the
plant while providing a gentle
protective layer for the orchid roots,
promoting healthy growth.
[Music]
After planting, water the orchid with
this mixture once a week to provide
regular nutrients, support the plant's
strong growth, and help maintain its
overall health.
[Music]
Um, after each watering, soak the orchid
pot in this mixture for about 20 minutes
to help the plant absorb the maximum
nutrients. Then, take the orchid pot out
and place it in a spot with gentle
sunlight or diffused light to allow
effective photosynthesis, boost
metabolism, and support healthy plant
growth.
[Music]
To protect the new roots as they grow,
we need to secure the orchid with a
support stick to stabilize its position,
prevent movement that could break tender
roots, and create favorable conditions
for the plant to anchor itself to the
growing
[Music]
medium. Remember, no matter how good the
fertilizer is, if the orchid lacks
sunlight, it will grow slowly, be prone
to rot, and will not be able to
bloom. Therefore, always place the
orchid pot in a spot with gentle
sunlight so the plant can
photosynthesize, absorb nutrients
efficiently, and grow healthily.
[Music]
Now, let's take a look at the results
after 3 weeks of recovery with natural
fertilizer. You will see new roots have
grown which shows that the orchid is
recovering and growing healthily.
These new roots help the orchid absorb
nutrients and water better, supporting
strong growth in the next blooming
cycle.
[Music]
The leaves have become plump and
greener, and the orchid looks healthy
and vibrant, which shows that the plant
has received enough nutrients and has
recovered well from the natural
fertilizer, improving its health and
promoting its growth.
[Music]
The leaves have become plump and
greener, and the orchid ID looks healthy
and vibrant, which shows that the plant
has received enough nutrients and has
recovered well from the natural
fertilizer, improving its health and
promoting its growth.
[Music]
Not only that, the orchid has also
started growing new buds, which proves
that the natural fertilizer recovery
process not only helps the plant become
healthier, but also stimulates
flowering, promising a vibrant bloom for
the next season.
[Music]
Take care of your orchid with all the
love for plants and you will see
wonderful
results. Um, each time you care for a
healthy orchid, you will gradually have
a beautiful and vibrant orchid garden
like a gift from nature to
you. What do you think of the way I
revived my weak orchid? Please leave a
comment with your thoughts and
suggestions. I hope you enjoyed this
video. If you find it helpful, don't
forget to like and subscribe so you
don't miss out on future tips on how to
care for orchids naturally and
simply. Thank you for watching the
video. I always pray for blessings for
all of you, wishing you a healthy orchid
garden full of beautiful blooms.