Welcome to the happiness garden where we
explore the wonderful beauty of orchids
together and learn how to care for them
with lots of love.
Today I will continue to share with you
a new method for uh making natural
fertilizer that is both simple and
effective, suitable for orchids and many
other types of plants using familiar
ingredients that almost every household
already has in the kitchen.
[Music]
This type of fertilizer will help your
orchid grow quickly, stay healthy, and
remain vibrant with beautiful clusters
of flowers that bloom evenly and last a
long time.
The flowers will stay fresh longer right
on the plant and may even bloom year
round, bringing lasting and vibrant
beauty to your garden.
[Music]
Let's get started.
To make today's natural fertilizer, I
will use eggshells. A simple, easy to
find ingredient that is very rich in
essential nutrients for plants, helping
to strengthen the health of orchids and
other plants in the garden.
[Applause]
Take about 10 eggshells and wash them
thoroughly with water to remove all dirt
and impurities, preparing for the next
step in making natural fertilizer.
[Music]
[Applause]
Um, please comment and let me know which
country you are watching the video from.
Um, it's wonderful that we can chat
together from all around the world.
[Music]
If you haven't subscribed to the channel
yet, please hit the subscribe button to
support me and not miss any orchid
growing tips. It's wonderful to have you
along for the journey.
[Music]
Then dry or with the eggshells on the
stove over low heat for about 5 minutes.
This step helps completely eliminate
fungi and bacteria, ensuring safety for
the plants when using the fertilizer.
[Music]
After roasting the eggshells on the
stove for five minutes, take them out
and let them cool naturally, preparing
for the next step in the fertilizer
making process.
Next, use a mortar and pestle to crush
the eggshells into small pieces, making
the fertilizer easier to dissolve and
allowing the plants to absorb the
nutrients in the eggshells better.
[Music]
After crushing, put the crushed
eggshells into a clean glass jar for
fermentation, helping the nutrients from
the eggshells blend and work best when
applied to the plants.
[Music]
Then pour about 100 mm of white vinegar
into the jar to help dissolve the
minerals in the crushed eggshells and
stimulate the decomposition process,
creating a natural fertilizer rich in
nutrients for the plants.
You close the jar lid and observe the
reaction process between the eggshells
and the vinegar.
When you see bubbling and foam appear,
that is a sign that the the minerals are
dissolving and breaking down, ready to
nourish your plants.
[Music]
Then let the mixture ferment overnight
at room temperature, allowing the
nutrients from the eggshells and vinegar
uh to fully blend before using it to
fertilize the plants.
[Music]
After fermenting overnight, prepare some
clean water to dilute the fertilizer
before use. This helps reduce the
acidity and ensures it's safe for the
plant roots when watering.
Prepare two cups, each containing one
liter of clean water.
[Music]
Then mix 2 ml of the fermented eggshell
and white vinegar solution into each
liter of water. This ratio provides just
the right amount of nutrients for the
plants without harming the roots or
soil.
[Music]
Then I proceed to treat the pine bark
before planting to eliminate fungi and
impurities while also making the bark
safer and more suitable as a growing
medium for orchids.
[Music]
Pour the diluted fertilizer mixture over
the pine bark and moss to soak them for
about 20 minutes before planting. This
helps with light sterilization, adds
initial nutrients, and softens the
materials, creating an ideal environment
for orchid roots to attach and grow
healthily.
Now I prepare a healthy small orchid to
repot into a new pot.
[Music]
You need to remove the old moss or
orchid growing foam before planting
because these mediums retain water very
well, but can easily cause root rot when
transferring to a larger pot, negatively
affecting the plant's growth.
[Music]
After removing the old growing medium,
we need to cut off any rotten and weak
roots.
This helps remove parts that can no
longer absorb nutrients while also
stimulating the plant to focus on
growing new, healthier roots, ensuring
good growth in the new pot.
[Music]
Then soak the orchid roots in the
diluted fertilizer mixture for about 20
minutes.
This helps with light sterilization,
stimulates the roots to absorb
nutrients, and promotes quick recovery
after pruning, creating the best
conditions for the plant to grow
vigorously.
Next, take a soft cloth, soak it evenly
with the diluted fertilizer mixture,
then gently and thoroughly wipe both the
top and underside of the orchid leaves.
This method helps remove dust and pests
while also directly supplying nutrients
to the leaves, helping the plants stay
healthy and more vibrant.
[Music]
After soaking the pine bark and moss in
the diluted fertilizer mixture for about
20 minutes, uh, take out the pine bark
and moss.
[Music]
and let them drain before using them as
a growing medium, helping to maintain
good irration and cleanliness for
healthy root development.
[Music]
Then we proceed to plant the orchid in a
new pot. Make sure to choose a pot with
drainage holes at the bottom to allow
excess moisture to escape, preventing
water logging and root rot and creating
ideal conditions for healthy plant
growth.
[Music]
After planting, place the orchid pot in
a spot with gentle sunlight, good
ventilation, and away from drafts.
Uh, and during the first week, avoid
watering to allow the plant time to
stabilize, prevent damage to young
roots, and help it adapt well to the new
environment.
Uh, you can pour the leftover fertilizer
into a spray bottle to use on other
orchid plants.
[Music]
You can use a spray bottle to mist the
orchids that are blooming. This is very
beneficial as it directly supplies
nutrients through the leaves, helping
the flowers stay fresh longer and
keeping the plants healthier throughout
the blooming season.
[Music]
The fertilizer will provide ample
calcium and essential minerals, helping
to strengthen the cellular structure of
the orchid flowers. This makes the
petals firmer, more vibrant, and extends
the blooming period, allowing you to
enjoy their brilliant beauty for longer.
Um, when sprayed directly onto the
leaves, the fertilizer quickly
supplements nutrients, enhances the
plant's photosynthesis capacity and
resistance, helping the orchid better
withstand changing weather conditions
and pests.
After spraying the fertilizer, remember
to gently wipe off any water droplets on
the surface and crevices of the leaves
with a soft cloth.
This helps prevent uh prolonged moisture
buildup, reduces the risk of fungal
infections, and keeps the orchid leaves
dry and healthy.
[Music]
After a week without watering to allow
the plant to stabilize, we begin
fertilizing the orchid.
[Music]
I use rice water to care for orchids.
Use a soft cloth soaked in the rice
water mixture to gently wipe the surface
of the orchid leaves clean.
This method helps remove dust, provides
nutrients, and keeps the leaves shiny
and healthy, contributing to enhancing
the plant's photosynthesis capacity.
[Music]
Then use the diluted rice water to water
directly onto the roots and growing
medium of the orchid.
Uh, it's best to alternate between
different types of natural fertilizers
for your orchids every 2 weeks.
[Music]
This method helps provide the plant with
a full range of diverse nutrients,
avoiding nutrient excess or deficiency
while maintaining balanced and
sustainable growth.
After that, remember to place the orchid
pot in a spot with gentle sunlight so
the orchid can photosynthesize
optimally.
[Music]
And here is the result after 3 months of
care.
Um, you can see the orchid leaves have
become noticeably larger, shinier, and
firmer.
[Music]
How do you find the way to restore your
weak orchid? Please write your feedback
and share your thoughts with me.
[Music]
Besides that, the plant has grown two
new flower spikes. A clear sign that
this natural fertilizing method has
helped the orchids stay healthy, grow
well, and get ready for a promising next
blooming season.
If you care for your orchid with all the
love and patience, just like we do,
using this natural fertilizer, your
garden will always reward you with
vibrant beauty and strong vitality. A
beautiful reminder of nature's power and
the deep connection between humans and
plants.
Orchids in full bloom bring you a deep
sense of tranquility, like a gentle
breeze soothing your soul.
They bring gentle, delicate joy and
brighten your living space with vibrant
natural beauty, making each day more
radiant and full of life.
[Music]
I hope you will like this video. If you
find it useful, don't forget to like and
subscribe to the channel so you won't
miss the next shares about how to care
for orchids naturally and simply.
[Music]
If you face any difficulties during the
orchid growing process, don't hesitate
to leave a comment for me. I'm always
ready to support you so you can grow
healthy orchids that bloom beautifully.
[Music]
Thank you for watching the video. I
always pray that God blesses you all
with health, happiness, and joy on your
journey of caring for plants and in
life.
[Music]
Welcome to my channel.
When the flowers bloom, nutrition will
focus on the bloom.
So, after the flowers bloom, the orchid
will weaken if you don't know how to
take care of it.
So, in this video, I continue to share
how to make organic fertilizer to help
orchids thrive.
[Music]
Let's get started.
This is the orchid after blooming.
[Music]
The orchid becomes weak and its leaves
wilt.
[Music]
First, remove yellow leaves and damaged
roots.
[Music]
This helps prevent the orchid from
rotting further.
[Music]
Okay.
Removing damaged roots will help prevent
rot from spreading to healthy roots.
[Music]
Then cut off the wilted flower stems.
Then take one aloe vera leaf.
[Music]
Aloe vera is rich in vitamins A, C, E,
and minerals such as calcium, potassium,
and magnesium, which help improve plant
health and enhance photosynthesis.
[Music]
Apply aloe vera gel to the cut so it
doesn't rot and heals quickly. Because
aloe vera gel has antibacterial and
antifungal properties, it helps protect
plants from diseases.
[Music]
Aloe vera gel helps provide moisture to
the plant, helping it recover quickly
when the leaves wither.
[Music]
Wipe the top and bottom of the leaf
evenly.
[Music]
Using aloe vera gel also helps plants
reduce stress caused by changes in the
environment or care conditions. Uh
especially good for orchids with wilted
leaves like this plant.
[Music]
which country are you watching videos
from? Please comment for me.
It's great that we can chat together
from all over the world.
[Music]
Don't forget to subscribe and hit like
if you found the video helpful. This
will help the channel grow and you won't
miss any orchid care tips.
[Music]
Applying this gel to the tree trunk will
help stimulate root growth in this
location.
[Music]
Doing this one to two times a month will
be very good for weak orchids.
Then leave it for one day without
watering to help the cut heal
completely.
[Music]
Cut the remaining aloe vera leaves into
thin slices.
[Music]
Then put it in a jar.
Add one liter of water at room
temperature.
[Music]
Add 3 teaspoons of rice.
Rice, especially rice water, has many
effects in restoring wilted and weak
orchids.
Then incubate and place in a cool place
for one day to help the nutrients
completely dissolve into the water.
[Music]
One day later,
stir well so that the nutrients dissolve
into the
[Music]
then filter this water.
Add one liter of water.
[Music]
Add some sterilized moss on top of the
orchid pot.
[Music]
This helps orchid pots retain moisture
better.
[Music]
Now water and soak the orchid pot in
this water.
[Music]
Enzymes and vitamins in aloe vera gel
stimulate root growth, helping the plant
absorb water and nutrients better.
[Music]
Aloe vera gel provides necessary
nutrients, helping plants sprout and
flower quickly.
[Music]
Do it twice a month.
Soak the orchid pot in this water for 20
minutes to help the orchid roots absorb
the best nutrients.
Um, and when soaked like this, the
insects in the orchid growing medium
will also die or run away.
[Music]
Next, pour this water into the spray
bottle.
[Music]
Then spray this water on the entire
orchid.
[Music]
This method is similar to folure
fertilization for orchids.
[Music]
Uh at the same time, it also helps wash
away dirt, mold, and insects on the leaf
surface. From there, orchid leaves will
photosynthesize light better.
[Music]
Do it twice a month.
After soaking for 20 minutes, take out
the orchid pot.
Place it in a place with lots of
scattered sunlight so the orchid can
photosynthesize and the plant can grow.
[Music]
results after 50 days.
After only 50 days, many new roots grew
from a weak orchid with withered leaves
and withered roots.
[Music]
Orchid leaves are glossier and greener.
When the roots develop, the orchid can
easily absorb water and nutrients.
will help orchids quickly recover
withered leaves.
[Music]
Harder and glossier leaves will help
with better photosynthesis and
metabolism.
[Music]
When healthy Orchids will continue to
grow and bloom in the next cycle.
Hopefully the video will help you a lot
in taking care of orchids at home.
[Music]
Uh if you find it interesting, please
like and share so more people know this
orchid growing tip.
And if you haven't subscribed yet,
please subscribe to my channel for
support.
[Music]
I always pray for blessings for everyone
on this earth.
Thank you for watching the video. I wish
you a wonderful day and look forward to
seeing you in the next video.