Did you know that more than 90% of new
orchid growers often make mistakes that
cause the roots to rot, the leaves to
yellow, and the flowers not to bloom?
[Music]
Today, I will point out the most common
mistakes and guide you on how to fix
them so that your orchid always stays
healthy, lush, and blooms beautifully.
Let's get started.
In fact, taking care of orchids is not
difficult, but just a few small mistakes
are enough to make the plant weak and
lose its vitality.
[Music]
Join me to learn how to avoid common
mistakes helping your orchid stay
healthy with lush green leaves and
vibrant blooms.
If you haven't subscribed to the channel
yet, please hit the subscribe button to
support me and not miss any orchid
growing tips. It's wonderful to have you
with me.
Leave a comment to let me know which
country you are watching from. It's
wonderful that we can chat with each
other from all around the world.
Mistake one, watering incorrectly.
[Music]
The first mistake is watering too much.
When the roots are submerged in water
for a long time, they will become water
logged and rot quickly, causing the
plant to weaken.
[Music]
Many people leave water standing in the
pot after watering without noticing.
This is the main cause of root rot.
Another mistake is watering at night. At
that time, high humidity and low
temperature make the roots more
susceptible to fungal diseases. Water in
the morning so the plant has the whole
day to stay dry and well ventilated.
[Music]
Some people also water on a fixed
schedule without paying attention to the
weather. If it rains a lot and the
medium is already moist but more water
is added, the plant will become water
logged.
Always check the growing medium before
watering to keep your plant safe.
[Music]
Before watering, take a close look. If
the medium is still wet and the roots
are still green, you don't need to water
yet. Wait until the medium is almost dry
and the roots turn a lighter color
before watering uh to keep the plant
healthy.
[Music]
water correctly. Healthy roots.
The solution is very simple. Only water
when the roots start turning silvery
gray. This is a sign that the plant is
thirsty and ready to absorb water.
Check the growing medium regularly. If
you see that it has dried out like this,
that's the right time to water the
plant.
These are roots that have turned
silvery, a sign that the plant needs to
be watered.
[Music]
Watering in the morning is best as it
gives the plant time to dry out during
the day. This helps prevent fungal
diseases and keeps the roots healthy.
Water slowly so that the water soaks
evenly throughout the entire growing
medium.
[Music]
Use room temperature water, avoiding
water that is too cold or too hot to
prevent root shock.
Avoid watering directly on the flowers
and leaves as this can make the flowers
fade faster and cause unsightly spots on
the leaves.
If you use a spray bottle, mist gently
around the base and roots, avoiding
spraying too strongly, which can damage
the young roots.
[Music]
You can see that after watering the
roots have changed from silver to green,
a sign that the plant has been given
enough water.
[Music]
This route clearly shows the difference
between the green part that has been
watered and the silver part that hasn't,
helping you easily know when to water.
[Music]
Mistake two, unsuitable pot and growing
medium.
If you grow in a pot without drainage,
caring for the plant will be much more
difficult and can easily cause the plant
to die from water logging.
Humidity in a closed pot is usually
high, creating conditions for fungi and
diseases to develop and attack the
plant.
Growing orchids in a closed pot without
drainage holes causes water to stagnate,
the roots to stay soaked for a long
time, and quickly leads to root rot.
[Music]
Humidity in a closed pot is usually
high, creating conditions for fungi and
diseases to develop and attack the
plant.
[Music]
When the growing medium holds water for
too long, the roots will not get enough
oxygen, causing the plant to suffocate
and gradually weaken.
[Music]
You can see that this growing medium is
holding too much water. Uh this will
cause the roots to suffocate and easily
rot.
The roots have developed black spots, a
sign that fungi are growing and
attacking the plant.
These black and brown spots on the
roots, if the pot and growing medium are
not changed in time, will quickly lead
to root rot and complete damage.
Prolonged root suffocation can cause the
orchid to die, even if you continue to
water and fertilize it properly.
[Music]
Proper pot and growing medium cools
green roots.
If you choose a closed pot, make sure it
has drainage holes at the bottom so that
water does not stagnate and the roots
stay healthy.
If you choose a pot with ventilation
holes around it, prioritize a clay pot
because it helps orchid roots breathe
better and keeps the growing medium well
airrated.
[Music]
For the growing medium, I usually choose
pine bark as the main medium combined
with a bit of moss of moss to retain
just enough moisture for healthy orchid
root growth.
[Music]
In addition to English dubbing, we have
now created versions in French, German,
Italian, Spanish, Portuguese, Japanese,
Hindi, Dutch, Polish, Korean, and
Indonesian to help you listen to and
understand the content easily.
To listen in a different language, open
the video and click on settings, the
gear icon to select the appropriate
audio language.
[Music]
When planting, place a layer of large
pine bark at the bottom of the pot to
ensure good drainage and keep the roots
dry.
Then add small pine bark around it to
stabilize the growing medium and help
the roots anchor more securely.
Additionally, small pine bark helps
retain moderate moisture while creating
a well ventilated space for the roots to
grow healthy.
After planting, you can spread a thin
layer of moss on top to retain moisture
and create an ideal environment for root
growth.
[Music]
Mistake three, placing in the wrong
location. When you place the orchid pot
under strong sunlight, the leaves can
get sunburned, turn yellow, and wilt,
causing the plant to lose vitality.
These are sunburned orchid leaves, a
sign that the plant has been exposed to
too much strong light.
[Music]
And here is an orchid pot placed under
strong sunlight, causing the plant to be
stressed and the leaves to wilt.
[Music]
And this causes many leaves at the base
of the plant to turn yellow.
[Music]
And you can see the roots also become
dried out due to the intense sunlight.
[Music]
But when the orchid is placed in low
light conditions, such as indoors or in
an office, the leaves become dull and
pale and the plant grows poorly.
Lack of light makes the orchid leaves
pale instead of deep green, causing the
plant to weaken and have difficulty
blooming.
Orchids grown in the shade for too long
will develop dull and soft leaves
lacking vitality.
Insufficient light reduces the
photosynthesis process causing the
orchid leaves to fade and the plant to
grow slowly.
Correct placement. Vibrant orchids.
Preferably place the orchid pot on a
window sill where there is gentle
sunlight and moderate air flow which is
ideal for healthy plant growth.
The best sunlight for orchids is morning
sun or late afternoon sun, helping the
plant grow healthily without burning the
leaves.
When the plant receives enough light,
the leaves become glossy and firm,
showing the orchid's strong vitality.
When the leaves are green and firm, it
helps the orchid grow healthy, absorb
nutrients well, and prepare to bloom
beautifully.
When you place the orchid pot in the
right location, the roots will also grow
strong and healthy, absorbing nutrients
efficiently.
The fourth mistake is overfertilizing.
[Music]
When you sprinkle too much chemical
fertilizer on each orchid pot, the roots
will burn, causing the plant to weaken,
the leaves to yellow, and making it
difficult to bloom.
[Music]
This orchid has been overfertilized with
inorganic fertilizer causing the roots
to burn and affecting the overall health
of the plant.
When the roots are burned, they can no
longer absorb water and nutrients and
gradually the leaves will turn yellow
and the plant will weaken.
The leaves near the base will turn
yellow first and then the yellow
gradually spreads to to the leaves at
the top of the plant.
[Music]
And if you use natural fertilizers,
remember to dilute them before watering
so the roots don't burn and the plant
grows healthy.
Moderate fertilizing equals healthy
roots.
Solution. When using chemical
fertilizers, it's best to dilute about/4
to half of the recommended dose and
apply to the plant about once every 2
weeks.
[Music]
If you use natural fertilizer, it's best
to follow the dosage I have demonstrated
in previous videos on the channel.
If this is your first time using
fertilizer, start with a very light dose
so the plant can gradually get used to
it and avoid shocking the roots.
Excellent results.
This is the result when you avoid the
mistakes above. Healthy orchid roots,
vibrant green, producing many new roots
that anchor firmly into the growing
medium and the pot.
[Music]
The leaves become glossy and firm,
showing the healthy vitality of the
orchid.
[Music]
When the leaves are healthy, the plant
absorbs nutrients better, grows
vigorously, and prepares to bloom
beautifully.
[Music]
When you avoid the mistakes above, the
flowers also become more vibrant, bloom
longer, and stay fresh.
Um, I hope you enjoy this video. If you
find the content helpful and meaningful,
don't forget to like, share so more
people can see it, and subscribe to
support me. Thank you for always being
with me.
[Music]
If you encounter any difficulties while
growing orchids, don't hesitate to leave
a comment. I am always ready to help you
grow healthy orchids that bloom
abundantly.
Thank you for watching. Goodbye and wish
you a day full of joy with beautiful
flowers.