welcome to my
[Music]
channel in my hand is a withered Orchid
and I will revive it with
[Music]
compost the roots are dry
cut off all damaged
Roots please comment to me which country
you are watching the video
from it's great that we can chat
together from all over the
[Music]
world uh removing damaged Roots helps
prevent healthy roots from rotting
[Music]
further if you haven't subscribed to the
channel yet please subscribe to support
me and not miss any orchid care
tips and stimulates new roots to
[Music]
grow cut off withered
branches in addition to the English Eng
voiceover we have now created voiceovers
in French German Italian Spanish and
Portuguese to help you listen to and
understand the video content more
[Music]
easily rinse with
water how to select the audio language
on YouTube One open the video and click
on settings the gear icon two select
subtitles CC three click on audio and
choose the language you want English
France Deutch Italiano espanol or
Portuguese soak in this water for 1
[Music]
hour take one aloe vera and cut it into
small
pieces aloe vera contains nutrients such
as vitamins minerals enzymes and amino
acids helps improve root and plant
growth thereby helping orchids better
absorb nutrients from the soil
[Music]
put aloe vera in the
jar add 500 M of room temperature
[Music]
water stir well and wait 1 hour
1 hour
[Music]
later thoroughly wash the back and front
of the
[Music]
leaves helps remove dirt mold and
insects on Leaf surfaces
[Music]
we'll help orchids recover faster
then put the wilted orchid leaves into
the
[Music]
jar then pour in aloe vera water and
soak for 30 minutes
[Music]
aloe vera gel contains many vitamins and
also has a good moisturizing effect
helping wilted orchids quickly recover
[Music]
next I need
oatmeal take 3 tbsp of
oatmeal then add 500 M of water
[Music]
then stir well and wait 30 minutes for
the nutrients to completely dissolve in
the
[Music]
water after soaking for 30 minutes
filter the oatmeal water
oats contain essential nutrients for
plants such as vitamins minerals such as
magnesium iron zinc carbohydrates and
proteins helps plants grow strongly and
improves overall root health
after soaking for 30 minutes take the
Orchid
[Music]
out mix aloe vera juice with oatmeal
water
[Music]
uh then soak the Orchid roots in this
water for 30
minutes will help restore roots and
stimulate faster rooting
[Music]
after soaking the roots for about 30
minutes take the Orchid out and plant it
in a new pot
[Music]
I grow orchids with moss which helps
retain moisture
better because Moss retains moisture
well you need to be careful not to water
it too
much only water when the growing medium
is dry
[Music]
if the growing medium is water logged
for a long time the roots will rot
[Music]
quickly filter this water
then water the Orchid every 10
[Music]
days the carbohydrate components in oats
stimulate root growth helps Orchid Roots
grow longer and healthier so the plant
can absorb water and nutrients from the
soil better
[Music]
aloe vera has the ability to stimulate
root growth especially for plants that
are wilted or show signs of
[Music]
weakness this helps the Orchid regrow
healthy roots and improve vitality
[Music]
it would be better uh if you soak the
roots in this water for about 30 minutes
and then take them
out uh on weekday you spray the leaves
with moisturizing water or when the
substrate is dry spray water to keep the
substrate moist
[Music]
then place the Orchid pot in a cool
place with enough light for the plant to
recover remember no amount of fertilizer
will help your orchids if they are not
receiving enough diffused light at least
12 hours a day
[Music]
okay results after 45
days leaves are
[Music]
fresher new Roots grow a lot
when the roots grow they will easily
absorb water and nutrients to nourish
the plant from there the wilted leaves
will quickly become fresh
[Music]
again aloe vera gel has the ability to
retain water helps keep soil and plant
roots moist for longer periods of time
this this is very important when orchids
Wilt due to lack of water
[Music]
please continue to take care of this
Orchid and wait to see the
[Music]
results after the next 3
months uh you can see that from a wilted
Orchid it has now fully recovered and is
very
[Music]
healthy uh the orchid has produced four
new flower spikes on the same plant
proving that it is thriving and very
healthy
[Music]
with this simple method you can easily
revive weak orchids at
[Music]
home I hope the video will be helpful
for you don't forget to support the
channel by liking subscribing and
sharing
[Music]
uh if you have any questions about
orchids comment and I'll share a video
with you
[Music]
thank you for watching wishing you a
joyful and energetic day see you in the
next video