Hello everyone. Welcome to the happiness
garden channel. Today I will share a
great tip for taking care of orchids
after the flowers have faded.
This method is especially effective in
helping wilted or weak orchids recover
and grow quickly.
[Music]
Um many people after buying orchids
often don't know how to take care of
them once the flowers have fully
bloomed.
Some let the plant wither while others
throw it away thinking it no longer has
any value.
But in fact, this is the time when the
plant needs to recover in preparation
for the next blooming cycle. If cared
for properly, it will continue to grow
and may even bloom more beautifully than
before.
The first thing you need to do is check
the roots. When the leaves are wilted,
it's often because the roots are damaged
and can no longer absorb water or
nutrients from the growing medium.
When the roots lose their function, the
plant will gradually weaken, the leaves
will wrinkle, and it will lose vitality.
Checking and properly treating the roots
will help the plant recover quickly.
[Music]
If you find that the roots are rotten,
soft, or dry and brittle, you need to
gently cut off those damaged parts.
Removing the damaged roots helps prevent
the spread of fungal diseases and
creates conditions for the plant to grow
stronger new roots.
[Laughter]
Leave a comment and let me know which
country you're watching from. Um, it's
amazing that we can connect and chat
with each other from all around the
world.
If you haven't subscribe to the channel
yet, please hit the subscribe button to
support me and not miss any orchid
growing tips. It's truly wonderful to
have you along on this journey.
[Music]
You can see that this orchid has many
damaged roots which is the reason why
the leaves are wilted and wrinkled.
[Music]
Next, cut off the faded flower spike.
After blooming, the flower spike no
longer provides nutrients to the plant
and may even drain additional energy to
maintain.
[Music]
After cutting off the damaged roots and
faded flower spike, you should rinse the
entire plant with water.
Use clean water that is not too cold and
be gentle to avoid damaging the
remaining roots.
[Music]
This helps remove dirt, bacteria, or
fungi that may still be clinging to the
roots and stem.
Uh after rinsing, you need to let the
orchid dry before proceeding to the next
steps.
[Music]
To revive a wilted orchid, I use a fresh
aloe vera leaf.
Aloe vera has natural antibacterial
properties and provides moisture and
nutrients that stimulate root growth. It
is a simple yet highly effective
ingredient for helping the plant recover
quickly.
[Music]
After cutting the aloe vera leaf into a
container, add 500 ml of water.
[Music]
Then blend it well to help the nutrients
in the aloe vera dissolve evenly into
the water, uh, creating a natural
solution to revive the orchid.
[Music]
After blending, I use a strainer to
remove the residue, keeping only the
clear aloe vera water.
Careful straining will keep the solution
from becoming too thick, allowing it to
absorb easily into the roots and
preventing clogging of the growing
medium when used on the plant.
[Music]
Then I soak the wilted leaves of the
plant in the aloe vera solution for
about 20 minutes.
[Music]
The solution will provide moisture,
soothe the dehydrated leaves, and help
the plant absorb nutrients more quickly,
thereby promoting the natural recovery
process.
[Music]
Next, prepare a clean cup and pour 500
ml of clean water into it.
[Music]
The next ingredient I use is a small
amount of molasses.
Although simple, molasses contains many
minerals and natural sugars that
stimulate beneficial microorganisms and
help the orchid recover faster when
combined with aloe vera.
[Music]
uh you only need to add about a/
teaspoon of molasses. This small amount
provides enough nutrients to support
root recovery without causing the
solution to ferment or or harm the
plant.
[Music]
After adding the molasses, stir the
solution well until everything is
completely dissolved.
[Music]
After soaking in the aloe vera solution
for about 20 minutes, gently take the
orchid out.
[Music]
Then mix the aloe vera water with the
water that has dissolved molasses.
[Music]
The next ingredient I use is vitamin B1.
It is an excellent supplement that helps
stimulate new root growth, reduces shock
after root trimming, and accelerates the
recovery process.
[Music]
I add three tablets of vitamin B1 to the
solution with each tablet containing 2.5
mg. This small amount is enough to
support new root growth and enhance
nutrient absorption without harming the
plant.
[Music]
After mixing, pour pour the solution
into a glass to soak the orchid roots
for about 20 minutes.
[Music]
The remaining mixture can be used to
water other orchid pots in the garden.
Um, the mixture of aloe vera, molasses,
and vitamin B1 can naturally stimulate
new root growth. When the roots are
properly nourished, the orchid will
quickly grow stronger.
[Music]
Um, you may notice that when cared for
with natural fertilizer, the orchid may
recover a bit more slowly at first, but
after a short time, the roots will grow
strong, the leaves will become glossy
green again, and the plant will start
accumulating energy in preparation for
the next bloom.
[Music]
Regularly watering with this mixture
also helps boost the orchid's
resistance. The plant will be better
able to withstand fungal diseases and
unfavorable environmental changes.
[Music]
You can see that not only the roots of
the mother plant grow vigorously, but
even the roots of the cakey orchid
babies growing on the spike also develop
abundantly.
[Music]
In addition to supporting the roots,
this solution also helps the leaves
become greener, thicker, and glossier.
This is a sign that the plant is
absorbing nutrients well and is full of
vitality.
[Music]
In particular, the vitamin B1 in the
mixture plays an important role in
reducing plant shock, especially after
root trimming or repotting.
You can see that many new roots are
growing, which shows that the plant is
recovering well and absorbing nutrients
effectively.
When the roots grow strongly, the plant
will have a solid foundation to nourish
its leaves, develop its stem, and
prepare for the next blooming phase.
[Music]
After soaking the roots in the solution
for about 20 minutes, gently take the
orchid out.
[Music]
Then use a soft cloth to absorb any
remaining water on the leaf surface and
in the crevices between the leaves.
This helps prevent moisture buildup that
could cause leaf rot or fungal diseases
and also keeps the plant dry before
repotting.
[Music]
When repotting, you should choose a pot
with drainage holes at the bottom.
[Music]
I choose crushed pine bark as the
growing medium to repot the orchid.
[Music]
After placing the orchid in the pot, I
gently add the crushed pine bark around
the base.
Handle with great care to avoid damaging
the new roots while ensuring the roots
are gently embraced by the growing
medium yet still have enough space for
proper air flow.
[Music]
Finally, I place a small amount of moss
on the surface of the pot.
Uh, this layer of moss helps retain
moisture around the base, creating a
cooler and more stable environment for
the plant in the first days after
repotting.
[Music]
After
repotting, you can use the remaining
natural fertilizer mixture that was used
for soaking the roots to water the newly
potted orchid.
This helps provide additional nutrients
to the growing medium, supporting the
roots to adapt quickly and grow strong
in the new environment.
For the cut on the spike, you can
lightly sprinkle a bit of cinnamon
powder on it.
Cinnamon powder has natural
antibacterial properties that help
prevent fungal infections and dry the
cut faster, thereby protecting the plant
during the recovery phase.
After that, you should place the orchid
pot in a cool, wellventilated area with
gentle sunlight.
Soft light allows the plant to
photosynthesize gently without losing
moisture too quickly, creating ideal
conditions for new roots to begin
developing.
And here's the result after 3 weeks of
care.
Um, you can see that the leaves are less
wilted compared to the beginning. This
is a positive sign showing that the
plant is gradually recovering, starting
to absorb water and nutrients to regain
its vitality.
New roots have also started to grow
around the orchid stem, especially in
areas close to the growing medium near
the rim of the pot.
Uh this is a very positive sign that the
plant is adapting well to its new
environment and growing steadily.
[Music]
Uh, what do you think about the way I
revived this small orchid? Don't
hesitate to leave a comment and share
your thoughts. Uh, I'd love to hear your
feedback and experiences.
[Music]
Um, I continue to apply natural
fertilizer to the orchid about once
every 10 days.
Regular supplementation helps the plant
maintain a steady supply of nutrients,
allowing the roots to grow strong, the
leaves to stay healthy and green, and
encouraging it to bloom again soon.
Remember,
[Music]
no matter how good the fertilizer is, if
the orchid doesn't receive enough light,
it still won't grow well. Light is an
important factor that helps the plant
photosynthesize and produce energy to
nourish the roots, leaves, and even the
blooming process. So, you should place
the orchid pot in a spot with gentle
sunlight.
[Music]
And here's the result after 3 months of
consistent care.
You can see that the once wilted leaves
have now recovered quite well, becoming
firmer and greener.
Uh especially the plant has also started
to grow new leaves. Uh a clear sign that
the orchid is returning to healthy
growth.
This wilted leaf has not fully recovered
yet, but that is completely normal.
When the root system is strong, the
plant will gradually absorb enough water
and nutrients, eventually restoring even
the previously affected leaves.
[Music]
Uh, continue to care the plant with
organic fertilizer about once every 10
days.
Regular fertilization will help the
plant maintain its vitality, nourish the
roots and leaves and fully prepare for
the upcoming blooming cycles.
Uh you can also alternate different
types of natural fertilizers so that the
orchid can absorb a wider variety of
nutrients.
Remember
[Music]
to place the orchid pot in a spot with
gentle cool and not too harsh sunlight.
Soft morning light will help the plant
photosynthesize well, promoting the
development of roots and leaves to fully
restore the wilted ones.
[Music]
And here's the result. After 5 months of
consistent care,
the orchid has truly revived. The roots
are growing vigorously and the leaves
are lush green.
[Music]
A slow but meaningful journey where you
give your time, patience, and love to
each small orchid pot. It is that gentle
care that will bring about miracles in
the most natural way.
Care for your orchid with all the love
you have for plants because it is that
very love and patience that will help
the orchid not just survive but shine
brightly in its own unique way.
Don't rush. A plant's life is just like
ours. It needs time to heal, to grow,
and to bloom at its own perfect moment.
And the orchid will reward you with
beautiful blooms as a quiet thank you
for the love and care you've given it.
Each flower that blossoms is the sweet
result of patience and affection. Thank
you for taking the time to watch the
video. Wishing you joy and peace always
beside the little orchid pots nurtured
with all your love. See you in the next