welcome back to happiness
Garden today I'll be introducing you to
a special natural fertilizer that not
only helps orchids grow sustainably but
also supports weak orchids in recovering
so they can become healthy again and
continue blooming
[Music]
beautifully stay tuned until the end of
the video to discover the recipe and how
to use this fertilizer
[Music]
if you have a wilted Orchid like this
don't throw it
away in this video I will share how to
revive it and help it grow strong
again if orchids are not properly cared
for after flowering they will be weak
and
stunted first I need to check the
roots when roots are damaged they can't
absorb water and nutrients for the plant
um causing the Orchid to become weak and
prone to disease
removing damaged Roots helps stop the
spread of bacteria and fungi while also
encouraging the growth of new healthier
Roots this helps the plant recover
quickly and grow strong again
[Music]
next cut off the old flower stem and the
plant will focus its energy on growing
new roots and leaves while also
improving its shape
[Music]
next wash wash the Orchid with water to
remove dirt and impurities helping the
plant stay healthier
washing the plant also helps prevent
diseases and pests from developing on
its surface
[Music]
next place the Orchid into the
pot then add water to soak the Orchid
helping it recover
[Music]
quickly soak the plant for about 1 hour
to allow the roots to absorb enough
water without causing water logging
helping it recover
[Music]
quickly next take 30 m of fresh milk to
make a natural fertilizer
[Music]
add 1 liter of
water if you haven't subscribed to the
channel yet it don't hesitate to hit the
Subscribe button now to get the latest
videos on orchid care and other amazing
gardening
tips after soaking in water for 1 hour
take the Orchid out and place the leaves
in a
glass after diluting the milk with water
water the leaves with the mixture and
soak it for 20 minutes to provide the
necessary nutrients for faster recovery
and growth of the orchid's leaves
this is yeast for making bread
add one teaspoon of this bread yeast
into the
[Music]
mixture bread yeast contains beneficial
microorganisms that stimulate root and
leaf
development uh when combined with
diluted fresh milk the yeast helps
provide nutrients while promoting the
breakdown of organic matter in the soil
improving the plant nutrient
absorption uh after soaking for 20
minutes take the Orchid out and place
the roots in into a glass
uh after soaking for 20 minutes take the
Orchid out and place the roots in into a
glass fresh milk provides calcium and
vitamins that stimulate root growth
bread yeast helps break down organic
matter improving nutrient
absorption together they help the plant
grow new strong roots
quickly after soaking for 20 minutes
take it out
then use a soft cotton pad to wipe off
the remaining mixture on the leaf joints
helping prevent mold and bacteria from
attacking the plant while keeping the
leaves clean and healthy
[Music]
then plant the Orchid in a new pot to
help it grow better
I plant with pine bark chips to provide
good air circulation drainage and create
an ideal environment for root growth
[Music]
add moss on top of the pot to retain
moisture longer create a good
environment for root growth and keep the
plant cool
[Music]
from now on every 2 weeks water the
Orchid with this mixture of milk and
yeast
[Music]
once water about 10 tbspoon for each
Orchid pot
[Music]
the mixture of fresh milk and yeast
provides essential nutrients like
calcium vitamins and beneficial
microorganisms when watered on the roots
this mixture helps stimulate new root
growth improve nutrient absorption and
enhance the overall health of the
[Music]
Orchid it also improves the soil
structure creating an ideal environment
for root
development on regular days when the
substrate or humidity in the garden is
dry simply water the orchids to maintain
moisture for the
plants then place the Orchid pot in a
spot with gentle sunlight avoiding
direct sunlight to prevent the leaves
from
burning the leftover mixture can be used
to water the other regular orchids in
the garden providing extra nutrients and
helping the plants grow healthy
[Music]
uh for these regular orchids you only
need to water each plant with about 10
tables of the mixture to provide enough
nutrients without
[Music]
overwatering you can also water this mix
on Orchids that are blooming to provide
extra nutrients helping the flowers stay
beautiful and last
[Music]
longer which country are you watching
videos from please comment for me
[Music]
uh it's great that we can chat together
from all over the
[Music]
world after one month of care the orchid
has clearly
recovered new Roots have developed
strongly helping the Orchid absorb
nutrients more effectively and enhancing
its overall health
[Music]
the wilted leaves have become fresher
than before showing recovery and
Improvement in the plant's health
um I continue to water the Orchid with
the the milk and yeast mixture once
every 2 weeks to maintain its health and
help it grow stronger
[Music]
the milk and yeast mixture helps restore
wilted orchids by providing essential
nutrients stimulating root and leaf
growth yeast improves nutrient
absorption while milk provides calcium
and vitamins helping the plant recover
quickly grow new roots and revive its
leaves then place the Orchid pot in a
place with light sunlight
after the next 2 months the Orchid grew
stronger Roots filled the pot and leaves
were green and healthy
uh the wilted leaves have completely
recovered becoming fresh and healthy
allowing the Orchid to grow steadily and
Bloom
[Music]
beautifully the Orchid grew larger
before recovering
uh continue caring for your orchid with
natural fertilizer and place it in a
spot with gentle sunlight
this will help your orchid grow healthy
and Bloom beautifully throughout the
year when you care for your Orchids with
love and patience you will be rewarded
with beautiful flowers that bring
relaxation and joy helping you Embrace
Life more each
day for