Welcome to the happiness garden. Today I
will share with you how to grow orchids
using the inverted planting method. This
is a technique that helps orchids grow
healthily and bloom regularly all year
round.
With this method, the roots will have
better air circulation, helping to
absorb nutrients effectively, thereby
making the plant more vigorous and the
flowers bloom more brilliantly. Let's
get started.
If you have a weak or weak orchid that
you've been caring for a long time, but
it still doesn't grow or bloom, then
follow this method of mine.
First, we need to check the orchid's
root system to see if there are any
problems.
Because the roots are the most important
part that determines the overall health
of the plant. If they are rotten, dry,
or no longer functioning well, the plant
will have a hard time growing.
Healthy roots are usually ivory white or
fresh green, while damaged roots are
brown, black, or mushy.
Then cut off all the damaged roots.
You can see that the roots of this
orchid are almost completely rotten,
causing the plant to lose its ability to
absorb water and nutrients from the
environment.
[Music]
Cutting off the damaged roots helps
prevent the spread of root rot disease,
thereby protecting the healthy remaining
roots of the plant.
After treating the roots, you should
also cut off the wilted leaves, damaged
leaves, or those showing signs of
disease.
Old, dry, or rotten leaves not only
spoil the appearance, but also consume a
lot of the plant's energy without
providing any benefits.
Removing damaged leaves helps the plant
concentrate nutrients on the healthy
parts while also reducing the risk of
disease spreading from the leaves to
other parts.
[Music]
When the plant is cleaned up like this,
the recovery and growth process will
happen faster.
[Music]
After cutting off the damaged roots and
leaves, the next step is to wash the
entire plant with clean water.
This helps remove dirt, impurities, and
any remaining bacteria or fungi on the
stem, roots, and leaves of the plant.
[Music]
Please comment and let me know which
country you are watching this video
from. It's wonderful that we can chat
together from all around the world.
[Music]
Next, take about 0.5 L of clean water
and pour it into a cup or small
container to prepare the nutrient
solution for the orchid.
[Music]
Then add about a/ teaspoon of pure honey
into the cup of water.
[Music]
And finally, add three vitamin B1
tablets into the cup of water.
[Music]
Stir the mixture in the cup until the
honey and vitamin B1 are completely
dissolved in the water. This way you
have a very good natural fertilizer
solution that helps promote the healthy
growth of the orchid.
[Music]
Then soak the entire orchid in the
natural fertilizer solution you just
prepared for about 20 minutes.
This soaking helps the nutrients from
the honey and vitamin B1 penetrate
deeply into the roots and stem,
stimulating the regeneration of new
roots and restoring the plant's health.
[Music]
Next, you will need to prepare baking
soda.
Take about half teaspoon of baking soda
and dilute it with one liter of clean
water.
[Music]
The growing medium I am using for the
orchids today is moss a very common and
suitable medium for orchids because of
its good moisture retention and
irerration.
However, before using it, we need to
sterilize the moss thoroughly to remove
all bacteria, mold, and pests that may
exist in the medium.
[Music]
Uh, soaking the moss in the diluted
baking solution for about 20 minutes
helps remove bacteria, mold, and pests
that may cling to the medium.
[Music]
After soaking the orchid in the solution
for 20 minutes, gently take the plant
out and use a soft cloth or clean tissue
to dry the water on the surface of the
leaves and in the leaf crevices.
[Music]
Uh this helps reduce water accumulation
that can cause rot or create favorable
conditions for fungal diseases to
develop especially in areas where water
doesn't drain easily such as leaf axles.
[Music]
Then take a small amount of cinnamon
powder and gently sprinkle it on the cut
area of the orchid stem.
[Music]
Cinnamon powder has natural
antibacterial and antifungal properties,
helping prevent infections and promoting
faster wound healing.
And now I will proceed to plant the
orchid upside down.
Um, this is an important step in the
recovery process and in stimulating the
plant to grow stronger. Please pay close
attention to each action I perform so
you can apply it correctly.
[Music]
I take a small copper wire stick to use
as a support to fix the orchid in place.
after planting.
[Music]
This fixing is very important because if
the plant shakes during care, the newly
grown roots can be easily damaged or
broken, affecting the recovery and
growth process.
[Music]
If you haven't subscribed to the channel
yet, please hit the subscribe button to
support me and not miss any orchid
growing tips. It's wonderful to have you
along for the journey.
[Music]
Then take the soaked moss and squeeze
out the excess water so the moss is not
too wet when used as the orchid growing
medium.
Squeezing thoroughly helps the moss
retain moderate moisture, create a
breathable environment, and prevent
water logging, which helps orchid roots
grow healthily.
[Music]
For this planting method, you need to
prepare a hook to hang the orchid pot
after planting.
[Music]
Besides English dubbing, we have now
created French, German, Italian,
Spanish, Portuguese, Japanese, Hindi,
and Indonesian versions to help you
listen to and understand the content
easily.
[Music]
Then we proceed to plant the orchid
using the prepared moist moss layer.
[Music]
Oh yeah.
After planting, you should hang the
orchid pot in a place with gentle
sunlight, avoiding harsh direct light so
the plant does not get stressed. Uh
during the first week after planting, do
not water the plant, but
After one week, prepare the honey and
vitamin B1 solution again as I
instructed at the beginning of the
video.
[Music]
Then use a spray bottle to evenly mist
the honey and vitamin B1 solution over
the entire orchid and growing medium.
Even spraying helps the nutrients
penetrate deeply not only into the roots
but also onto the leaves and stem
enhancing absorption and protecting the
plant from various fungal diseases.
[Music]
Uh, you only need to spray the honey and
vitamin B1 solution on the orchid about
two to three times per month.
[Music]
And now let's take a look at the results
after 1 month of caring for the orchid
using the upside down planting method I
demonstrated.
Uh after this period you will see the
orchid clearly recovering with roots
growing strong and healthy.
[Music]
Now let's check the orchid stem inside
the growing medium together.
[Music]
Wow, you can see many new roots growing
out.
[Music]
Uh with this simple care method, you can
easily See, many new roots have grown
vigorously around the base of the
orchid.
[Music]
The young white healthy roots are a
clear sign that the plant is recovering
well and absorbing nutrients
effectively.
[Music]
Stimulating root growth not only helps
the plant anchor firmly to the growing
medium, but also increases its ability
to absorb water and nutrients, making
the plant healthier and bloom more
regularly.
This is proof of the effectiveness of
the upside down planting method I just
shared.
After carefully checking the orchid
roots and seeing that the new roots have
grown strong, I proceed to replant the
orchid using the moist moss layer.
[Music]
After replanting, from now on, you
should continue caring for the orchid
using the liquid fertilizer mixture made
from honey and vitamin B1.
[Music]
Apply this liquid fertilizer to the
orchid two to three times per month.
That will be enough
to
[Music]
remember to hang the orchid pot in a
spot with gentle sunlight, such as near
a window or under a tree canopy, so the
plant can photosynthesize effectively.
[Music]
After 3 months of care, the orchid has
grown vigorously with strong roots, lush
green leaves, and especially it has
bloomed with many vibrant flowers.
[Music]
The fully bloomed, long-lasting, and
brightly colored flowers are clear proof
of the effectiveness of the upside down
planting method combined with with the
natural fertilizer made from honey and
and vitamin B1.
[Music]
This is the deserved reward for
persistence and proper care, helping the
orchid not only stay healthy but also
full of vitality and bloom brilliantly.
[Music]
I hope this video will bring you lots of
useful knowledge to help you care for
your orchids at home easily and
effectively.
And if you encounter any difficulties
while growing orchids, don't hesitate to
comment. I'm always ready to support you
so that you can grow healthy orchids
that bloom abundantly.
[Music]
Uh, if you find the content helpful and
meaningful, don't forget to like and
share so more people can know about it
and subscribe to support me. Thank you
for always being by my side.
Thank you all for watching and I wish
you success with your orchid garden.
Welcome to part two of the video. In
this part, I will guide you through
simple yet effective steps to propagate
Phelinopsis at home, helping you expand
your orchid collection without much
effort. After the orchid has just
dropped all its petals, this is the best
time to propagate from the flower spike.
At this point, the mother plant has
completed its flowering process and is
ready for a new growth phase, helping
the offshoots grow healthy and
effectively.
[Music]
Then take one clove of garlic and
squeeze out the juice. The garlic juice
will be used as a natural solution to
provide antibacterial protection,
safeguard the flower spike, and support
the orchid propagation process
effectively.
[Music]
If you haven't subscribed to the
channel, please hit the subscribe button
to support me and not miss any orchid
growing tips. It's wonderful to have you
along.
Please comment and let me know which
country you are watching the video from.
It's wonderful that we can chat together
from all around the world.
[Music]
Next, use a cotton swab to dip into the
garlic juice and apply it directly onto
the node that needs stimulation to grow
an orchid offshoot. The garlic juice
will help provide antibacterial
protection, safeguard the spike, and
naturally stimulate the formation of new
shoots.
Only the nodes that have not yet bloomed
can sprout and grow into orchid
offshoots. So you should apply the
garlic juice only to the young unopened
nodes. This ensures that the new shoots
will grow healthy and easily develop
into offshoots.
[Music]
Then use a transparent plastic wrap to
cover the part of the flower spike where
the node you want to stimulate into an
orchid offshoot is located. This helps
retain moisture, protect the young chute
from insects and bacteria, and create an
ideal environment for the offshoot to
develop.
Make a small hole for ventilation,
allowing the chute to receive enough
oxygen and preventing moisture that can
cause rot or fungus, uh creating the
best conditions for the orchid offshoot
to grow.
[Music]
And here is the result after 3 weeks of
care.
[Music]
You can see that the spot where the
garlic juice was applied has formed a
very healthy orchid offshoot. However,
at this stage, the offshoot has not yet
developed visible leaves or roots. This
is an early sign that the new chute is
beginning to grow and is ready for the
next stages of development.
[Music]
And here's the result after the next 2
months.
You can see that the orchid offshoot has
grown very healthily on the flower spike
with leaves starting to open clearly and
young roots forming.
This is an important step showing that
the new chute is ready to develop into
an independent plant in the future.
Note throughout the process of
stimulating the node to grow into an
orchid offshoot, place the orchid pot in
a shaded area with high humidity as this
helps the young chute form and develop
easily.
Conversely, if the orchid pot is placed
in a sunny area with low humidity, the
plant is more likely to produce flowers
instead of an offshoot.
[Music]
I have also applied this little tip to
another orchid and you can see the
result is that many healthy orchid
offshoots have formed on the flower
spike.
This simple yet effective method helps
propagate phelinopsis easily and
naturally at home.
Be persistent in applying these methods
and gradually you will have a thriving
and vibrant orchid garden just like
mine. Each offshoot will grow healthy,
bloom beautifully, and bring joy when
cared for at home.
I hope you enjoy this video. If you find
it useful, uh don't forget to hit
subscribe and share so that many others
can also learn these effective orchid
care and propagation tips.
[Music]