Uh, it's a pleasure to welcome you to my
little loving garden where flowers tell
stories through their fragrance and
colors and every leaf carries the breath
of
life. In today's video, I will continue
to share with you a simple yet effective
way to make natural fertilizer, helping
orchids stay healthy and continuously
show off their vibrant beauty throughout
all four seasons of the year.
If you also love orchids and want your
orchid pots to always be full of
beautiful blooms, be sure to subscribe
to the channel to join me on this
journey of caring for and discovering
the beauty of this special flower. Don't
forget to turn on notifications so you
don't miss any useful tips. It's
wonderful to have you with me.
Let's get
started. The first ingredient I will use
to create natural fertilizer is
eggshells. An easily available resource
that is full of nutrients for
orchids. Take two to three eggshells,
then wash them under running water to
remove any dirt and impurities.
Please let me know which country you're
watching the video
from. It's so amazing that we can chat
with each other from all over the world.
Next, place the eggshells upside down so
the water can drain out, allowing them
to dry and be ready for the next steps.
The next ingredient I will use to make
natural fertilizer is dried banana
peels, a component rich in potassium and
other wonderful nutrients for
orchids. Take two banana peels and wash
them under running water to remove any
dirt and impurities.
Or you can also use fresh banana peels
as they are also very good for
orchids. If you use fresh banana peels
to make natural fertilizer, remember to
wash the peels thoroughly before eating
to remove dirt and impurities.
After washing, let the banana peels dry
and be ready for the next
steps. The next ingredient I will use to
make natural fertilizer is beetroot. An
excellent source of nutrients for
orchids.
Uh, when eating beetroot, I often use
the peel to make fertilizer for orchids,
helping to provide additional nutrients
for the plant to grow
healthily. Uh, when eating beetroot, I
often use the peel to make fertilizer
for orchids, helping to provide
additional nutrients for the plant to
grow healthily.
After chopping the beetroot peels into
small pieces, I place them into a jar to
prepare for the next steps.
Next, I chop the banana peels into small
pieces and add them to the jar with the
beetroot
[Music]
peels. Next, I crush the eggshells and
add them to the jar along with the other
ingredients.
Uh, eggshells contain a lot of calcium,
a nutrient that is essential for helping
orchids grow strong and produce
beautiful
blooms. Then I add all the ingredients
into one liter of boiled water.
Close the lid and let it sit overnight,
allowing the nutrients from the
ingredients to dissolve into the water.
The next morning, you will have a
wonderful natural fertilizer for your
orchids.
[Music]
The next morning, stir well to ensure
the nutrients are completely dissolved
into the
[Music]
water. Then we strain the mixture to
collect the clear liquid which will be
used as fertilizer for the orchids.
[Music]
After straining, add another liter of
water to make a total of 2 L of liquid
[Music]
fertilizer. The final ingredient, add
about 1 teaspoon of neem oil to complete
the natural fertilizer solution.
Neem oil helps to repel insects, prevent
fungal diseases, and promote healthy
plant
growth. Remember to stir well to ensure
the neem oil is fully dissolved in the
solution.
[Music]
Step one, use a soft cloth to soak the
mixture and gently wipe the top and
bottom of the
[Music]
leaves. Wiping the leaves helps remove
dirt, creating conditions for the plant
to photosynthesize more easily,
promoting healthy leaves and boosting
flower productivity.
This mixture provides essential
nutrients such as calcium from
eggshells, potassium from banana peels,
and beetroot, helping orchids grow
healthy. Neem oil has antibacterial and
antifungal properties, helping the plant
prevent common diseases like fungi and
bacteria.
Neem oil is a natural substance that
helps repel harmful insects such as
aphids and spidermitites, protecting the
leaves from pest
attacks. Cleaning the leaves and
providing nutrients helps the plant
photosynthesize more effectively,
thereby promoting growth and longlasting
blooms.
The liquid fertilizer mixture also helps
maintain the necessary moisture on the
leaves, especially in dry environments,
supporting better plant
growth. You should wipe the leaves about
twice a month so that the orchid can
absorb nutrients well and stay healthy.
After wiping the leaves, pour the
remaining mixture into a spray bottle to
use
later. If you haven't subscribed to the
channel yet, please hit the subscribe
button to support me and not miss any
orchid growing tips. It's wonderful to
have you with me.
Step two, use a spray bottle to evenly
spray the mixture over the entire
orchid, including the stem, leaves, and
base of the
plant. The mixture provides nutrients
directly through the leaves and stem,
helping the plant absorb them faster and
promoting healthy growth from roots to
tip.
Neem oil in the mixture helps prevent
pests and fungi, protecting the plant
from harmful environmental
factors. Potassium and calcium from
natural ingredients help stimulate
flowering and extend the blooming
period, resulting in evenly distributed
flowers with vibrant colors that last
longer.
It is recommended to spray two to three
times a month to maintain the nurturing
and protective effects for the
orchid. Step three, water each orchid
pot with about 10 tablespoons of this
natural fertilizer
mixture. Watering with the fertilizer
mixture helps provide a steady supply of
nutrients to the plant from the roots to
the leaves, promoting stronger and
healthier growth.
Watering with the fertilizer mixture
helps provide a steady supply of
nutrients to the plant from the roots to
the leaves, promoting stronger and
healthier
growth. It is recommended to water one
to two times a month, depending on the
plant's needs and environmental
conditions. Step four, use a soft cloth
to wipe off any water droplets on the
leaves and between the leaf crevices to
avoid excess moisture, keeping the
leaves dry and healthy.
In addition to the English voiceover, we
have now created voiceovers in French,
German, Italian, Spanish, Portuguese,
Japanese, Hindi, and Indonesian to help
you listen to and understand the content
more
easily. To listen in a language, open
the video and click on settings, the
gear icon, to select the appropriate
audio language.
Then place the orchid in a spot with
gentle sunlight so it can
photosynthesize well, helping it grow
strong and produce beautiful
flowers. For orchids with leaf rot
caused by insects or fungi, we need to
treat them as follows.
We need to check and remove the rotting
leaves from the plant as soon as
possible to stop the spread of the
[Music]
disease. You can see that the rotting
orchid leaves have many small insects
appearing on them.
[Music]
If we don't treat it promptly, the rot
will spread to the stem and down to the
roots, causing the orchid to die very
quickly.
[Music]
After cutting off the rotting leaves,
you should dispose of them or keep them
far away from the garden to prevent the
spread of the
disease. Then use a soft cloth to dab
the fertilizer mixture made from
eggshells, banana peels, beetroot peels,
and neem oil to thoroughly wipe both the
top and bottom of the
leaves. Neem oil in the mixture has
antibacterial properties, helping to
kill the fungi and bacteria that cause
leaf rot, preventing the spread of the
disease on the orchid.
[Music]
The components from eggshells, banana
peels, and beetroot peels provide
essential nutrients, helping the orchid
recover quickly and return to good
[Music]
health. Then use turmeric powder to
sprinkle on the cut and rot spots to
help with antibacterial action and
promote fast healing of the wound.
After sprinkling the turmeric powder, do
not water for one week to allow the cut
and rot spots to dry and
heal. Once the wound and rot spots have
fully healed, you can then water and
fertilize the plant.
After the wound heals, I will use the
fertilizer made from eggshells, banana
peels, beetroot peels, and neem oil to
care for the orchid. And I will share
the results with
you. Once completed, remember to place
the orchid pot in a spot with gentle
sunlight so the plant can
photosynthesize well and grow healthily.
And here are the results after 3 weeks
of
care. Uh you can see that the orchid
leaves have become greener, shinier, and
sturdier. Um the leaves have also become
thicker, which shows that the orchid is
growing healthily and absorbing
nutrients well.
The orchid has also grown many new
roots, proving that the care process is
yielding good
results. These new roots will help the
orchid absorb nutrients more
effectively, supporting strong growth
and beautiful flowering.
And here is the orchid that was
previously affected by rot 10. You can
see that the rot spots have completely
healed and haven't spread any further.
After being cared for with natural
fertilizer, the orchid leaves have
become greener, shinier, and sturdier,
indicating that the plant has absorbed
nutrients well and is growing
[Music]
healthily. With this natural fertilizer
and proper care, the orchid has produced
many healthy flower stems with large and
plump buds. promising a vibrant blooming
[Music]
season. Many flower stems are growing on
the same branch, which shows that the
orchid is growing vigorously and ready
for a wonderful blooming
season. Take care of your orchid with
all the love you have for plants, and
you will be rewarded with healthy pots
of orchids full of vibrant flowers.
[Music]
Um, each orchid is a testament to
patience and love. And when you care for
care for them, they will bloom, bringing
joy and beauty to your
surroundings. Hope this video brings you
lots of useful information. If you find
it helpful, don't forget to like and
subscribe to the channel for more orchid
care
tips. Goodbye and see you in the next
videos. Wishing you always happiness and
great success in taking care of your
orchids.