Hello everyone. Welcome back to
Happiness Garden, the channel that
shares everything about taking care of
orchids and my gardening
[Music]
tips. If you're looking for a simple and
natural way to care for your orchids,
today I will share with you how to make
a super effective natural fertilizer
from used chamomile tea bags, rice, and
baking soda. This trick will not only
help your plant grow from the roots,
leaves, and flowers, but is also very
safe and easy to do at
[Music]
home. If you want to know how to combine
them and how effective they are, don't
miss today's video. Let's explore it
together. Now, don't forget to like and
subscribe so you don't miss my next
videos.
Before fertilizing, you should
thoroughly water the plant and and soak
the orchid pot in water for about 20
minutes. This helps the plant absorb
water better and reduces the risk of
fertilizer shock.
[Music]
Uh this method also helps remove mineral
salts from the fertilizer residues
remaining in the potting
[Music]
medium.
Residual mineral salts and decaying
organic matter are the main causes of
root rot in orchids. Therefore, you
should do this once a month for each
orchid
[Music]
pot.
Remember to soak for about 20 minutes to
allow the roots to absorb water and
clean the
[Music]
orchid. After soaking for 20 minutes,
remove the orchid pot and then proceed
to make the natural fertilizer for them.
to create a natural fertilizer for the
orchids. Today I will be utilizing used
chamomile tea bags. This is a simple,
economical and safe way to provide
natural nutrients and promote healthy
growth for your plants.
Add it to one liter of boiling
water. Next, I add 3 teaspoon of rice, a
natural fertilizer that is excellent for
orchids, providing essential nutrients
to promote healthy growth.
[Music]
And then I cover it with a lid and wait
for the water to cool down for optimal
use. And here is baking soda. I take one
teaspoon of baking
soda. Dissolve one teaspoon of baking
soda in one liter of water.
[Music]
Step one, use a soft cotton pad to soak
the baking soda mixture and gently wipe
the top and bottom surfaces of the
leaves.
Uh, this method helps remove residual
mineral salts, dust, and fungi or
bacteria from the leaves, thereby
promoting the healthy growth of your
orchids and preventing diseases caused
by bacteria or fungi. Regular cleaning
will also improve the plant's ability to
absorb sunlight and nutrients
effectively.
[Music]
As you can see, the cotton pad has
changed from white to brown, which
indicates that there's a lot of dust and
mineral salts accumulated on the
[Music]
leaves. Um, which country are you
watching this video from? Leave a
comment for me. It's so wonderful that
we can connect and chat with each other
from all over the world.
If you apply this method one to two
times a month for each orchid pot,
you'll protect them from harmful factors
and ensure they grow strong, vibrant,
and thrive beautifully through each
growth cycle.
Step two, pour the baking soda mixture
into a spray bottle.
Then spray it over the entire orchid,
especially the top side, underside, and
between the leaf
crevices. Spraying the baking soda
mixture over the entire orchid not only
helps remove dust, residual mineral
salts, and harmful agents such as fungi
and bacteria, but also creates a natural
protective layer on the leaves. This
enhances the plant's immune system and
promotes strong, healthy growth.
And doing this once a month will be very
beneficial for your orchids, helping
them stay healthy and effectively
prevent diseases.
[Music]
After the water has cooled, I strain the
chamomile tea and rice washing water to
create a natural fertilizer for the
orchids.
[Music]
Then mix the remaining baking soda
solution with this mixture.
[Music]
Step three, water this mixture into each
orchid pot with about 10
tablespoons. Watering this mixture into
each orchid pot provides essential
natural nutrients from chamomile tea,
rice washing water, and baking soda. It
also uh helps improve the plant's
overall health, stimulates root growth,
and prevents diseases caused by bacteria
and fungi. This is an effective way to
maintain vibrant and healthy growth for
your
orchids.
[Music]
Among them, chamomile tea. Rich in
antioxidants and natural compounds that
strengthen the plant's immunity. It
effectively kills bacteria and fungi,
preventing diseases.
[Music]
Rice washing water provides many natural
nutrients such as starch and vitamins,
supporting the growth of roots and
leaves. It adds beneficial
microorganisms to the potting mix,
improving the plant's ability to absorb
nutrients.
Baking soda has the ability to kill
harmful fungi and bacteria on the
leaves. It reduces the risk of diseases
and improves the pH of the potting
medium, allowing the plant to absorb
nutrients more effectively.
[Music]
Apply this mixture to each of your
orchid pots one to two times a month to
protect the plants and promote healthy
growth. Step four, use a soft cloth to
gently dab the remaining mixture on the
leaves, buds, and leaf crevices to
reduce the risk of rot caused by damp
conditions, keeping your orchids healthy
and thriving.
[Music]
You should perform this step after each
watering or after applying the
fertilizer mixture to the orchid leaves
to ensure the plant does not rot and
maintains optimal health.
If you haven't subscribed yet, click the
subscribe button now so you won't miss
the latest videos from Happiness Garden.
Next, place the orchid pot in a spot
with gentle sunlight to allow the plant
to photosynthesize effectively, boosting
its metabolic processes and promoting
healthy
[Music]
growth. Uh, let's take a look at the
amazing results after caring for orchids
using this natural fertilizer mixture.
New roots are growing abundantly and
strong, which helps the plant absorb
nutrients more effectively and thrive in
the upcoming season.
[Music]
This natural fertilizer mixture not only
promotes strong root growth, but also
encourages the orchid to produce
numerous new flower stems, resulting in
a stunning display of blossoms and
vibrant vitality for every pot.
[Music]
Happy happy.
The flowers nurtured with this natural
fertilizer mixture will remain vibrant
and graceful, transforming every orchid
pot into a mesme. Mesmerizing radiant
masterpiece. I hope this video provides
valuable insights and helps you take
better care of your orchids right at
home. Thank you for taking the time to
watch this video. Wishing you joy and
success in taking care of your orchids.
See you in the next
videos. Welcome to my
channel. Today I will restore an
exhausted orchid with wrinkled leaves in
a very simple way.
[Music]
Dash. Wake up any weak orchid pot under
any
[Music]
conditions. Helps any orchid pot grow
healthily, bloom brightly, and brighten
up your living
space. To restore orchids, I use
garlic. Please comment to me which
country you are watching the video from.
It's great that we can chat together
from all over the world.
[Music]
Take three cloves of garlic and slice
them. If you haven't subscribe to the
channel yet, please hit the subscribe
button to support me and not miss any
orchid growing tips.
It's great to have you
[Music]
along. Put in a jar and soak with 2 L of
water for 2 hours.
[Music]
An orchid has withered leaves and is
exhausted. Cut off all flower stems.
[Music]
Then cut off all damaged roots.
Rinse with water.
[Music]
Then leave it in a cool place and wait
for the water to dry.
[Music]
After 2
hours, filter out
[Music]
residue. Add water to make 3 L of
solution.
[Music]
Add three vitamin B1 tablets.
Soak for 20 to 30 minutes.
[Music]
Next, I recycled the plastic box to help
restore the
[Music]
orchid. Pour in some water.
place the orchid branch
[Music]
in. Regularly change the water when
dirty.
[Music]
and keep the orchid pot in a cool place
away from direct sunlight.
[Music]
Two months later,
The orchid has recovered. Its leaves are
green and strong.
[Music]
Roots grow very
healthily. Um this way of planting you
you will not have to water the orchids
as much as with normal planting.
[Music]
Uh, I continue to grow orchids in new
pots using the semihydroponic method.
[Music]
Um, this way of planting you you will
not have to water the orchids as much as
with normal
planting. Hope you enjoy this video. If
you find it useful, don't forget to like
and subscribe to the channel so you
don't miss out on future shares on how
to care for orchids naturally and
simply.
[Music]
Just persevere every day to take care of
orchids with all your love for nature.
Gradually, you will cultivate a garden
of colorful orchids bringing joy and
peace to your living
[Music]
space. Every morning when you wake up,
when the scent of keta orchids blends
with felonopsis orchids gently
spreading, you will feel serenity and
peace in your soul.
Every morning when you wake up, when the
scent of keta orchids blends with
felonopsis orchids gently spreading, you
will feel serenity and peace in your
soul.