Welcome to my channel. Have a nice day.
To help you have more options when
taking care of orchids at home using
natural methods. In this video, I
continue to share new methods that help
the leaves stay green and strong. The
roots grow firmly into the medium and
the pot produce many buds and bloom
continuously throughout the year with
large and beautiful flowers.
[Music]
Let's get started.
When the petals have faded, we should
cut off the flower spike to help the
plant focus on nourishing its leaves and
roots, preparing for the next blooming
period.
[Music]
Uh please comment and let me know which
country you are watching the video from.
It's wonderful that we can chat together
from all around the world.
[Music]
After that, remove the yellow and
damaged leaves so the plant stays clean,
well ventilated, and less prone to
fungal diseases.
[Music]
Next, cut off the damaged, rotten, or
dried roots so the orchid can grow
healthier and absorb nutrients more
effectively during hair.
Uh, if you haven't subscribed to the
channel yet, please hit the subscribe
button to support me and not miss any
orchid growing tips. It's wonderful.
It's wonderful to have you along for the
journey.
[Music]
Next, once a month, you should water and
soak the orchid pot in water for about
20 minutes before fertilizing.
[Music]
When you water or soak the orchid pot
before fertilizing, the dry roots will
be moistened and awakened, helping them
absorb nutrients from the fertilizer
more easily. If you fertilize while the
roots are still dry, the plant may
experience fertilizer shock, causing
root burn and weakening the orchid.
Pre-watering helps the fertilizer
dissolve evenly, penetrate deeply, and
nourish the plant more effectively.
[Music]
Watering before fertilizing also helps
wash away excess mineral salts and
fertilizer residues left in the growing
medium. This makes the root environment
more ventilated, balances the pH level,
and prevents the roots from being
poisoned by salts. Clean and healthy
roots are the foundation for sustainable
orchid growth.
[Music]
When the orchid pot is soaked in water
for about 20 minutes, the roots are
revived after a dry period, helping to
improve air circulation and stimulate
new root growth. This not only makes the
plant healthier, but also keeps the
leaves lush and green. And the flowers
bloom beautifully in the next season.
While waiting for the orchid pot to soak
in water, I will prepare natural
fertilizer for the plant. The first
ingredient I use is green tea, a
familiar ingredient that contains many
nutrients beneficial for orchids,
helping the plant stay lush, the roots
strong, and the flowers last longer.
With just 1 tbsp of green tea and 500 ml
of boiling water, you can make a natural
nutrient solution to nourish your
orchid.
[Music]
After mixing, cover and let the solution
steep until it completely cools down.
This helps the green tea retain its
maximum nutrients and natural aroma
while preventing the evaporation of
beneficial components for the orchid.
After soaking for about 20 minutes, take
the orchid pot out and let it drain
completely before fertilizing. Allowing
it to drain helps the roots absorb just
the right amount of nutrients,
preventing water logging or
overfertilization
and promoting healthier, more
sustainable growth.
[Music]
After the water has cooled, stir the
green tea solution well so that all the
nutrients are completely dissolved.
Then strain out the tea leaves so that
only the clear solution remains, helping
the natural fertilizer penetrate the
roots easily and preventing clogging or
residue buildup in the orchid's growing
medium.
[Music]
Next, add 500 ml of clean water to the
strained tea solution to dilute it
moderately. This helps the fertilizer
penetrate the roots, balances the
nutrient concentration, and is safe for
the orchid when applied.
Uh the last ingredient that we will use
is yogurt. Just one teaspoon of yogurt.
Yogurt contains many beneficial
microorganisms, helping to improve the
health of orchid roots, promote the
growth of leaves and flowers, and at the
same time increase the ability to absorb
nutrients from natural fertilizer.
Method one, use a soft cloth to soak up
this fertilizer mixture and carefully
wipe both the top and bottom surfaces of
the orchid leaves.
[Music]
Wiping the leaves with the tea and
yogurt mixture helps nutrients penetrate
directly into the leaves, providing
vitamins, minerals, and beneficial
microorganisms.
Healthy nourished leaves improve the
efficiency of photosynthesis, thereby
promoting the overall growth of the
orchid.
[Music]
The microorganisms in yogurt are not
only good for the leaves, but also
spread down to the roots through the
natural nutrient transport system,
helping the roots become healthy and
absorb fertilizer more effectively.
[Music]
This mixture when wiped on the leaves
removes dust, dirt, and bacteria on the
leaf surface, keeping the leaves clean,
ventilated, and reducing the risk of
pest attacks.
Healthy and clean leaves create
favorable conditions for the orchid to
produce vibrant flowers.
Regularly wiping leaves le yogurt the
tea and yogurt mixture helps enhance
nutrition and vitality for the plant,
making the flowers bloom longer.
[Music]
The beneficial microorganisms in yogurt
along with the polyphenols in green tea
help orchid leaves resist pathogens and
improve the plant's natural defense
ability. This is a gentle but effective
way to care for orchids, keeping them
healthy.
Method two, you can pour the mixture
into a spray bottle and spray it
directly onto the plant and the growing
medium. The growing medium. This method
helps nutrients distribute evenly,
easily penetrate the leaves and flowers,
and also saves time compared to wiping
each leaf individually.
[Music]
When spraying the natural fertilizer
mixture of green tea and yogurt, the
nutrients are evenly distributed on the
surface of the leaves and flowers,
helping the plant absorb nutrition
uniformly. This supports healthy, lush
leaf and flower growth and makes the
blooms last longer.
[Music]
The beneficial microorganisms in yogurt
combined with polyphenols from green tea
form a natural protective layer on the
leaves helping the orchid resist
pathogens and pests. Uh this is a gentle
care method that helps the plant remain
healthy and sustainable.
[Music]
Spraying the solution directly onto the
plant saves time compared to wiping each
leaf, especially for large orchid pots
or those with many leaves. At the same
time, this method helps nutrients
quickly penetrate the plant, nourishing
the orchid effectively from leaves down
to the roots.
Method three, pour this fertilizer
mixture directly onto the orchid's roots
and growing medium. This method allows
the roots to absorb nutrients directly,
nourishing the plant from the base up
and promotes healthy growth of leaves,
roots, and flowers.
Watering the fertilizer mixture of green
tea and yogurt directly onto the roots
helps nutrients quickly penetrate the
root system, providing energy for
healthy plant growth.
Strong roots support better water and
nutrient absorption, thereby promoting
the overall development of the orchid.
This mixture also helps improve the
quality of the growing medium by adding
beneficial microorganisms from yogurt
and compounds from green tea, keeping
the medium loose, well moisturized, and
ventilated, creating an ideal
environment for orchid roots.
The nutrients in the mixture not only
nourish the existing roots, but also
stimulate the growth of new roots,
helping the orchid expand its root
system, increase its ability to absorb
nutrients and water, and simultaneously
promote new shoots and the development
of young leaves.
After watering, you can soak the orchid
pot in the mixture for about 20 minutes.
This helps the roots absorb nutrients to
the maximum, supports more effective
uptake, and enhances the vitality of the
entire orchid.
[Music]
After soaking the orchid pot for 20
minutes, take the pot out and place it
in a spot with gentle sunlight to allow
the orchid to photosynthesize. Gentle
light helps the leaves absorb energy,
synthesize nutrients from the applied
fertilizer, and simultaneously promotes
flowering and healthy plant growth.
Remember, no matter how good the
fertilizer is, if the plant lacks light,
photosynthesis will be inefficient and
the orchid will have difficulty
blooming. Light is an essential factor
that helps the plant convert nutrients
into energy, nourishing healthy roots,
leaves, and flowers.
[Music]
When caring for orchids with natural
fertilizer, at first the plant may not
show immediate growth, but after the
roots and leaves have absorbed the
nutrients, you will see the leaves
become lush, firm, and healthy. A sign
that the orchid is absorbing nutrients
well and preparing for a vibrant
flowering stage.
[Music]
Both the new and old roots of the orchid
will grow strongly, anchoring firmly
into the growing medium and pot. Healthy
roots help the plant stay stable,
increase its ability to absorb water and
nutrients, and simultaneously provide a
solid foundation for lush leaf growth
and vibrant flowering.
[Music]
Additionally, strong root growth also
promotes the emergence of new shoots and
flower buds, helping the orchid remain
lush and bloom regularly in the
following seasons.
When the orchid is properly cared for,
the flower buds will be plump and full.
These healthy buds usually bloom evenly,
last long, and produce vibrant flowers,
indicating that the plant is growing
well from roots to leaves and we're
preparing for the next flowering season.
[Music]
Uh the petals that bloom will be bright,
soft, and vibrant, showing that the
orchid is being nourished healthily from
roots to leaves. Beautiful flowers not
only enhance aesthetic value but also
serve as evidence of proper care and
balanced natural nutrition.
I hope this video will be very helpful
for you in caring for orchids at home.
If you find the video meaningful, don't
forget to like, share so more people can
know, and subscribe to the channel to
support upcoming orchid care