[Music]
welcome to my channel
I am an orchid care
specialist do you have vitamin
[Music]
B1 subscribe to the channel and watch
till the end to see the
[Music]
magic five tablets of vitamin B1
mix in four cups of room temperature
water about 1
[Music]
liter keep in a cool place away from
direct sunlight for 1 hour
[Music]
then I took five
eggshells eggshells contain many
nutrients needed by plants including
calcium potassium and Trace elements
such as iron magnesium manganese copper
and zinc
[Music]
therefore eggshells will help provide
necessary nutrients for
orchids dry on low heat for 5
minutes this helps to eliminate fungal
diseases before using as fertilizer
[Music]
when using eggshells as fertilizer it
also helps to increase the pH of the
soil helping orchids grow better
[Music]
in addition I also use 100 G of organic
fertilizer from livestock waste pressed
into dry
[Music]
pellets then mix the two types together
with the orchids that have bloomed all
the last
[Music]
flowers I apply about 1 o about 30 G per
pot Orchid after full bloom is very EX
Ed so I need to apply this fertilizer to
quickly
[Music]
recover pay attention to fertilizing far
from the
[Music]
root with orchids in full
bloom this fertilizer also helps flowers
bloom for a long time
if you apply this fertilizer every 2
months it is guaranteed that the Orchid
will Bloom for 6 months without
[Music]
wilting with Orchids with buds I also
apply this fertilizer to help flower
buds grow faster
[Music]
1 hour
after decant the Clear Water above
[Music]
use this absorbent
cotton clean the top and bottom of the
leaves helps eliminate fungal diseases
and prevent parasitic insects on leaves
at the same time it supports the supply
of nutrients through orchid
leaves orchids are always green and
[Music]
growing sprinkle the remaining water
into the Orchid growing medium
[Music]
vitamin B1 helps strengthen the root
system and promote plant Health while
improving the soil's ability to absorb
[Music]
nutrients vitamin B1 has the effect of
protecting plants from external agents
such as drought Sunburn and cold and
enhances resistance to plant diseases
[Music]
you should fertilize B1 for orchids once
a month in the cool
[Music]
afternoon results after 1
week you can see that after 15 days the
flowers are still very fresh and more
fragrant than
usual and flowers can bloom again and
again all year round in the
[Music]
garden this helps me to always enjoy the
blooming flowers and the gentle
fragrance from the
garden and you can see that after just a
week of using the orchid has grown a lot
of new roots
[Music]
so we can use these organic fertilizers
to take care of orchids very
[Music]
well however keep in mind that an
overdose can also harm plants therefore
it is advisable to adhere to the dosage
that I have
instructed hopefully the video will be
of great help to you in effectively
taking care of orchids at
home if you find the content interesting
and meaningful don't forget to like and
share so that more people know and
subscribe to support the channel thank
you for always accompanying
me thank you for watching the video I
always pray for God's blessings to all
of you
hello
everyone after the orchid has bloomed
what should we do to help it grow and
Bloom
continuously in this video I'll show you
step-by-step instructions to ensure your
orchids stay healthy and Bloom
regularly let's get
started to make fertilizer for this
Orchid I need about 10 eggshells
uh eggshells are a natural source of
calcium which helps improve soil
structure boost root development and
prevent diseases in
orchids using eggshells as fertilizer
helps orchids recover quickly after
blooming stimulating continuous and
healthy
flowering which country are you watching
videos from please comment for
me uh it's great that we can chat
together from all over the
world you need to dry the eggshells and
then grind them into powder
then put the eggshell powder into the
jar next bananas are a very good choice
as fertilizer for orchids
take one banana peel and cut it into
small
pieces banana peels are rich in
potassium and minerals which help
stimulate flowering and promote quick
recovery for orchids after Bluing
using banana peels as fertilizer ensures
consistent and healthy
blooming add 1 liter of boiling water
cover and leave overnight to let the
nutrients mix into the
water next I use oatmeal to make natural
fertilizer
take three teaspoons of
oatmeal add 1 liter of water at room
temperature cover and leave overnight
till let the nutrients mix into the
water this is an orchid I bought at an
industrial orchid garden and has
finished blooming
uh to care for the plant to continue
flowering I first need to cut off the
damaged leaves
then cut off the old flower
stems if you haven't subscribed to the
Channel Please Subscribe and support me
it's amazing to have you along for the
journey and supporting
me then use coffee powder to apply it to
the cut to help the wound heal quickly
leave it overnight for the cut to heal
completely
after one
night stir well so that the nutrients
dissolve into the water
filter out eggshells and banana
[Music]
peels step one
use soft cotton to wipe the leaves to
help keep them
cleaner wiping leaves helps remove dust
debris and bacteria from Leaf surfaces
helping orchid leaves breathe better and
absorb light more effectively
wiping leaves helps enhance
photosynthesis because clean leaves
absorb light better and can metabolize
energy more efficiently
wiping leaves with this water helps
reduce the risk of mold bacterial
diseases because clean Leaf surfaces
limit the environment for harmful
pathogens to grow
step
two pour this water into a spray bottle
and spray your
orchid spraying water infus with banana
peels and eggshells provides nutrients
for orchids boosting their resistance
promoting quick recovery after blooming
and ensuring continuous
flowering thoroughly spray both the top
and bottom of the
leaves when sprayed on leaves liquid
fertilizer helps orchids absorb
nutrients more easily and enhance root
development
[Music]
when sprayed on leaves liquid fertilizer
helps orchids absorb nutrients more
easily and enhance root
[Music]
development will create a synthetic
liquid fertilizer solution that is very
good for orchids to recover after
flowering
step
three water this liquid fertilizer for
orchid
[Music]
pots watering with a liquid fertilizer
made from banana peels eggshells and
oatmeal boosts nutrients enhances
resistance promotes quick recovery and
ensures continuous blooming for
orchids uh soak the Orchid pot for 20
minutes so the Orchid can absorb the
most nutrients
after soaking for about 20 minutes take
it out take it out and place the Orchid
pot in a place with plenty of
light step
four water droplets on leaves can create
a favorable environment for mold and
bacteria to
grow wiping off water helps reduce the
risk of
infection wiping off the water helps the
stomata stay open and function
better and do the above four steps every
10 to 15
days remember no matter how good the
fertilizer is if the Orchid lacks light
growth and cannot photosynthesize it
will still be stunted and grow slowly
therefore place the Orchid in a location
with sufficient light for Healthy
Growth results after 50
days you can see the roots and leaves of
the Orchid growing very
quickly the leaves are also stronger and
glossier and also grew two new flower
buds
oh the roots in the Orchid pot grow so
well
new roots are an important factor in
helping orchids grow healthfully and
sustainably throughout their life cycle
sh
um now I plant it in a larger pot so the
Orchid grows
healthier as a growing medium I use
crushed pine bark to help aate the roots
but still retain the necessary moisture
after planting take care of it like
other normal orchids
take care of your Orchids with all the
love and dedication you have for nature
because every leaf and every flower bud
is a testament to the effort and heart
you put into
it thank you for watching and supporting
my channel