Welcome to the happiness garden. Um,
today I want to share with you how to
care for weak plants at home, helping
them gradually recover and become
healthy.
Uh, when properly cared for, each leaf
will become greener, each root stronger,
and finally, vibrant flowers will
appear, bringing joy and color to your
living space.
With this simple yet effective method,
you will see seemingly weak plants begin
to revive day by day. Each young root
stretches upward. Each leaf turns a
fresh green. And then the bright flowers
will gradually bloom. Join me on the
journey of caring for, restoring, and
enjoying the wonderful beauty that each
plant brings to your home.
You can see this is a weak anthetherium
plant, almost lifeless. Many leaves and
flowers have rotted, leaving only a few
fresh leaves that can sustain the
plant's life. However, with proper care,
we can still help the plant recover and
bloom again.
[Music]
And you can see on the surface of the
orchid pot there is a snail. They often
come to eat the roots and young leaves,
especially when it rains or the humidity
is high. If not dealt with promptly, the
plant can easily get fungal infections
from the bites, leading to rot and
weakening the plant's vitality.
[Music]
Uh to protect the enththerium plant, we
need to remove the snails immediately
and carefully check the surface of the
soil.
Then we gently remove the damaged leaves
so that the enththerium plant does not
waste energy on the parts that are
already dead.
[Music]
This helps the plant focus its energy on
the roots and the remaining healthy
leaves, creating conditions for a quick
recovery.
[Music]
You need to carefully check and cut off
any part of the stem that has rotted. If
not treated promptly, the rot can spread
and damage the entire anthetherium
plant. Removing the diseased parts from
the start will help the plant focus its
energy on the healthy parts and recover
faster.
[Music]
Uh, please leave a comment letting me
know which country you're watching from.
It's wonderful that we can connect and
chat together from all around the world.
Um, if you haven't subscribed to the
channel yet, please click the subscribe
button to support me and not miss any
home gardening tips. It's wonderful to
have you along on this journey.
Next, carefully check the roots and
growing medium of the antherum plant.
Upon inspection, you can see that the
anthetherum's roots are still healthy
and the growing medium remains well
ventilated. Therefore, at this stage, it
is not necessary to repot or change the
medium. Just focus on carefully caring
for the plant so it can recover. When
the roots are healthy and the soil is
well airrated, the plant will absorb
nutrients better and bloom again soon.
You can see that beneficial
microorganisms in the growing medium are
working very well. This shows that the
medium is still rich in nutrients and
biologically balanced, helping the
anthetherium's roots develop healthily.
When the root environment is stable, the
plant will recover more easily and be
ready for the beautiful flowers to come.
[Music]
Next, take a teaspoon of baking soda to
make a mixture which is used to treat
the old growing medium. This mixture
helps loosen the medium and adjusts the
pH to an ideal level, creating a perfect
environment for the anthetherium's roots
to absorb nutrients and recover quickly.
Add one liter of water to make the
solution.
[Music]
After mixing, pour the solution evenly
over the entire growing medium, the
wounds on the stem that you previously
cut.
This helps disinfect, prevent the spread
of fungal diseases, and support the
roots in absorbing nutrients more
effectively. With proper care, the
anthetherium will quickly recover and
prepare for vibrant blooms in the
future.
[Music]
Next, take a soft cloth, dip it in the
solution, and gently wipe both the top
and bottom surfaces of the leaves.
[Music]
Uh this helps remove dust, bacteria, and
fungi on the leaves while also allowing
the nutrients from the solution to
penetrate the plant more effectively.
When the leaves are well cared for and
clean, the anththerium will absorb
nutrients efficiently and recover
faster.
[Music]
When the leaves are carefully cared for,
the plant will be healthier and ready to
enter the recovery and flowering
process.
[Music]
Next, you can soak the entire antherum
pot in the solution for about 20
minutes. This allows the solution to
penetrate deeply into the growing medium
and roots, effectively disinfecting and
directly providing nutrients to the
plant.
[Music]
Uh after soaking for about 20 minutes,
remember to gently remove the antherum
pot from the solution. This helps avoid
over soaking and protects the roots from
excess water.
[Music]
If the leaves are still wet, you should
use a soft cloth to absorb all the water
on the leaf surfaces. This helps prevent
fungal growth and ensures the leaves
stay dry, creating better conditions for
the anththerum to absorb nutrients.
[Music]
Next, sprinkle a little cinnamon powder
on the cuts of the anthetherium plant.
Cinnamon helps disinfect, prevent
bacteria and fungi from entering the
wounds, and supports a faster recovery
process.
When the cuts are well protected, the
plant will retain its vitality and
prepare for strong growth of new roots
and leaves.
[Music]
Next, place the antherum pot in a cool,
wellventilated area for about 1 day and
do not water it. This allows the cuts to
dry naturally, reducing the risk of
fungal and bacterial infections.
Next, you can use aloe vera to make a
natural fertilizer for the enththerium
plant. Take the transparent gel part of
the aloe, removing the green outer skin,
as this gel is rich in nutrients and
very good for the plant's recovery.
Aloe gel provides many essential
vitamins and minerals, helping the weak
anthetherum, leaves, and roots recover
quickly. When applied properly, the
leaves become greener and softer while
the roots absorb nutrients effectively,
boosting the overall vitality of the
plant.
[Music]
Besides nutrients, aloe gel also
contains natural natural compounds that
stimulate the growth of new shoots and
roots. This helps the weak enththerium
recover faster with fresh new parts
emerging, signaling that vitality is
returning.
[Music]
After extracting the aloe gel, place it
in a clean container to prepare it for
making a fertilizer solution for the
anthetherium plant.
The final ingredient is rice. Rice
contains many amino acids and especially
vitamin B1 which is very good for weak
anththeriums.
You only need to take 3 tablespoons of
rice. This rice will be combined with
the alo gel to create a natural
nutrient-rich fertilizer solution for
the antherum. When mixed properly, the
solution will help the roots and new
leaves grow healthily while promoting
the plant's rapid recovery.
Then pour into one liter of water along
with the aloe gel and rice. Stir well,
cover, and let it sit for one day for
light fermentation.
The fermentation process will help
release the vitamins and nutrients in
the rice and aloe, creating a
nutrientrich fertilizer solution for the
anthetherium. When used, this solution
will help the roots, leaves, and new
shoots grow healthily, promoting a rapid
recovery.
[Music]
After one day of fermentation, once the
mixture has lightly fermented, strain
out the residue.
[Music]
This makes the fertilizer solution
smooth and easy to penetrate the roots
and growing medium while also preventing
the residue from causing blockages or
mold. When using the strain solution,
the antherum will absorb nutrients more
effectively, promoting healthy growth of
leaves, roots, and new shoots.
[Music]
After straining, pour this mixture
directly onto the roots and growing
medium of the anthetherium about once
every 2 weeks. Regular fertilization
provides continuous nutrients,
stimulating healthy growth of roots,
leaves, and new shoots. With consistent
care, the plant will recover quickly and
prepare for vibrant flowers in the
future.
[Music]
The fermentation process produces
beneficial bio compounds, helping weak
plants recover quickly. This mixture
also stimulates better growth of roots,
new leaves, and shoots, promoting
overall plant development, and preparing
it to bloom again.
Next, take a soft cloth, dip it in the
lightly fermented aloe and rice mixture,
and gently wipe both the the top and
bottom surfaces of the enththerium
leaves.
[Music]
This helps the leaves absorb nutrients
directly while also removing dust and
bacteria on the surface. When the leaves
are carefully cared for, the plant will
recover faster, the leaves will become
greener, and it will be ready to grow
new shoots.
Then, place the antherum pot in a spot
with gentle sunlight. Soft light helps
the plant photosynthesize effectively
while preventing the leaves from burning
or losing moisture.
And here is the result after 3 weeks of
recovery.
You can see that from the weak
anthetherium stem, three small
anthetherium plants have grown. This
shows that proper care and the natural
nutrient solution have helped the plant
revive strongly while stimulating the
growth of new shoots.
[Music]
I continue to care for the antherum by
regularly watering it with the
fertilizer mixture made from aloe. gel
and lightly fermented rice water.
[Music]
This provides continuous nutrients,
nourishing the roots, leaves, and new
shoots to grow healthily. With
consistent care, the plant will fully
recover. The leaves will be lush and
green, and it will be ready for vibrant
flowers in the future.
Next, place the anthetherium pot in a
spot with gentle sunlight. Soft light
helps the plant photosynthesize
effectively while preventing the leaves
from burning or losing moisture.
And here is the result after 4 weeks of
recovery. You can see that the three
small enthetheriums grown from the old
stem have grown larger and developed
more roots looking very healthy.
[Music]
Um these new roots help the enththerium
absorb nutrients and water more
effectively. They also provide a strong
foundation for the plant to grow lush
green leaves and healthy new shoots.
When the roots are strengthened, the
plant will recover quickly, preparing
for vibrant flowers in the future.
[Music]
I continue to care for the anththerium
by regularly watering it with the
fertilizer mixture made from aloe gel
and lightly fermented rice water. This
provides continuous nutrients,
nourishing the roots, leaves, and new
shoots to grow healthily.
[Music]
Uh by regularly applying the nutrient
solution, the plant will recover
strongly, the leaves will be vibrant
green, and the new shoots will grow
healthily, preparing for vibrant flowers
in the future.
[Music]
Simply water this fertilizer mixture
about once every two weeks and add water
if the growing medium becomes dry. This
combination helps the enththerium absorb
nutrients continuously while maintaining
proper moisture for the roots. With
proper care, the roots, leaves, and new
shoots will grow healthily, helping the
plant recover quickly.
Um, you can also put the mixture into a
spray bottle and mist it evenly over the
enththerium plant.
[Music]
This allows the nutrients to penetrate
directly into the leaves, supporting
photosynthesis and boosting the plant's
vitality.
Uh, when combining root watering and
leaf spraying, the plant will recover
faster, the leaves will be vibrant
green, new shoots will grow strong, and
it will be ready for vibrant flowers in
the future.
[Music]
And here is the result after 2 months of
recovery.
You can see that from a weak anthetherum
with nearly dead leaves. After 2 months
of proper care, the plant has grown into
a mature, healthy plant and is now ready
to bloom.
[Music]
This recovery process demonstrates the
plant's strong vitality when cared for.
The natural solution made from aloe gel
and and lightly fermented rice water
combined with proper light and watering.
[Music]
At this stage, we need to add more
growing medium to create a well
ventilated environment for the
anthetherium's roots to develop. The new
medium will help the roots absorb
nutrients and water more effectively
while preventing rot. When the roots
have good space to grow, the plant will
fully recover. The leaves will be
vibrant green, and it will be ready for
vibrant flowers.
[Music]
and here is the result after 3 months of
recovery.
You can see that the enthium has fully
recovered and grown. Now the plant has
produced beautiful vibrant new flowers,
demonstrating that careful care with the
nutrient mixture of aloe gel and lightly
fermented rice water combined with
proper light and well-arrated growing
medium has helped the plant revive
strongly.
Seeing the enththerium recover strongly
and bloom beautifully after 3 months of
care, you will realize that with love,
patience, and the right method, any weak
plant can be revived. Trust in your
ability. Care for your plants daily, and
you will be rewarded with beautiful
flowers that bring joy and color to your
home.
Start caring for your plants today. And
don't be discouraged if they are weak or
the leaves are wilted. With the right
method and patience, the plants will
recover strongly and bloom beautifully,
bringing joy and color to your living
space.
Today's video comes to an end. What do
you think about how I revived this small
anthetherum plant? Don't hesitate to
leave a comment and share your thoughts.
I'm really eager to hear your feedback
and experiences.
I hope you enjoy the video. If you find
the content helpful and meaningful,
don't forget to like, share so more
people can see it, and subscribe to
support me. Thank you for always being
with me.
Thank you for watching today's video.
Wishing you success in caring for your
anthetherum with lush green leaves and
vibrant blooms. Be patient and nurture
your plant everyday and you will see
wonderful results right in your own
home.