welcome to my
[Music]
channel to help you have many choices
when caring for orchids at home with
organic fertilizer in this video I
continue to share new
[Music]
methods um subscribe to the video so you
don't miss any tips on my
channel now let's get started
to make this type of organic fertilizer
you need black tea or tea
grounds I use 3 teaspoons of black tea
add 1 liter of boiled
[Music]
water incubate until the water cools
after the water cools filter to remove
sediment
[Music]
add water to make 5 L of black tea
solution
[Music]
next add 1 teaspoon of baking soda
first
[Music]
method water this fertilizer Solution on
the Orchid roots
[Music]
black tea contains many minerals and
organic substances that help provide
nutrition for
[Music]
orchids it contains nitrogen potassium
and phosphorus important nutritional
fact factors for orchid
[Music]
growth baking soda bicarbonate soda has
the ability to increase the pH level in
Orchid pots this is helpful in reducing
acidity if you use too much chemical
[Music]
fertilizer big soda has the ability to
kill insects and fungi that are harmful
to
[Music]
plants second method
spray this fertilizer on the entire
orchid
[Music]
this method is similar to using foler
fertilizer baking soda has the ability
to kill insects and fungi that are
harmful to plants
f
[Music]
third
method clean the leaf surface with this
fertilizer solution
[Music]
the leaf surface will always be clean
and the stamata will not be
[Music]
clogged orchids will photosynthesize
better
[Music]
um plant roots are protected and
supplemented with nutrients so they grow
very healthily
[Music]
we'll help orchids absorb the most
nutrients because they are provided with
enough nutrition the flowers bloom more
brilant
[Music]
brilliantly many flowers bloom on the
same
[Music]
Branch the flowers stay on the branches
for a long time before or
[Music]
fading thank you for watching the video
wishing you luck and success in life
goodbye and see you again in the next
videos welcome to Happy Garden Channel
wish everyone a good
day this is dendrobium Orchid an orchid
that is said to be beautiful and has a
gentle fragrance uh they have the
ability to bloom all year round and keep
the flowers on the branches for a long
time
if you're looking for an easy way to
breed this most beautiful orchid in the
world let me show you the simple yet
effective
[Music]
secret I cut this old Orchid to
propagate
which country are you watching videos
from please comment for
[Music]
me it's great that we can chat together
from all over the world
[Music]
apply toothpaste to the cut to help it
heal
[Music]
quickly then wait for the toothpaste to
dry recycle plastic bottles into tools
to stimulate rooting and sprouting
[Music]
if you haven't subscribed to the channel
yet please hit the Subscribe button to
support me and to not miss any orchid
care tips on my channel thank you so
much
[Music]
you can see the cut after the toothpaste
has
[Music]
dried take one aloe vera leaf
apply aloe vera gel all over this dry
orchid
[Music]
then wait for the aloe vera gel to dry
put the dry Orchid branches into this
plastic bottle
[Music]
place the bottle here and insert Moss
around it to help retain moisture
[Music]
water regularly to keep the environment
moist this helps the Orchid germinate
faster
[Music]
then put it in a cool place and wait for
the Orchid to
[Music]
revive 2 months later
with this method after only 2 months the
old withered Orchid branches were
[Music]
revived if you haven't Subs subscrib to
the channel yet please hit the Subscribe
button to support me and to not miss any
orchid care tips on my channel thank you
so
much now I cut them out to plant in pots
[Music]
hope the video will help you a lot
um if you find it interesting please
like share and subscribe to my support
[Music]
Channel wishing you success and
happiness in life
[Music]