Hello
everyone. Um, today I'm excited to share
a new method for making organic
fertilizer that will help you care for
your orchids at home.
If you're looking for helpful tips on
growing orchids, don't forget to
subscribe to the channel and support
me. Let's get
started. Now, let's learn together how
to care for orchid pots after the
flowers bloom and lose their petals.
Um, this is a very important period for
the plant to recover and prepare for the
next flowering
period. Throw away the old pot because
this orchid pot is only suitable for
growing in industrial orchid gardens.
If you haven't subscribed to the channel
yet, please subscribe to support me and
not miss any orchid care
tips. Removing old stems allows the
plant to to focus its energy on
producing new stems and flowers.
[Music]
Old and yellow leaves not only reduce
photosynthesis efficiency but also
consume the plant's
energy. Pruning helps the plant conserve
energy for healthier
[Music]
parts. Do you have pets? How do you like
it?
Damaged roots often harbor mold and
bacteria. Removing these roots helps
reduce the risk of disease spreading to
the entire plant.
My maid, how do you like
it? The roots of this orchid are still
very
healthy. After replanting these branch
roots, they will grow very quickly.
plant orchids in new pots to help them
grow
faster. So, I planted with shredded pine
bark, which helps retain moisture well
and is also easy to drain so the roots
don't get water logged.
Which country are you watching videos
from? Please comment and let me
know. It's great that we can chat
together from all over the world.
In addition to the English voice over,
we have now created voiceovers in
French, German, Italian, Spanish, and
Portuguese to help you listen to and
understand the video content more
easily.
In addition to the English voice over,
we have now created voiceovers in
French, German, Italian, Spanish, and
Portuguese to help you listen to and
understand the video content more
easily. Now, make fertilizer to care for
this orchid.
To make this compost, I use
bread. You can also take stale bread and
make it, which is great,
too. You can also take stale bread and
make it, which is great, too.
Put the bread in the jar.
Add 350 ml warm water.
Next, I took a
banana. Then cut into thin slices.
Put bananas in the bottle.
Seal the bottle and leave it in a cool
place to wait for 3 weeks to create GE
fertilizer, which is very good for
orchids.
This is the GE bottle I made with
bananas and bread 3 weeks
ago. Take this 50 mil GE.
mix with 2 L of water.
Step
one, water orchid roots with this GE
liquid fertilizer.
Bananas are rich in potassium, vitamins,
and minerals which enhance the plant's
health. Bread offers carbohydrates
serving as an energy source for the
plant.
The potassium in bananas helps promote
strong and persistent blooming,
increasing the orchid's flowering
[Music]
capacity. Soak the orchid pot in this
water for about 20 minutes so that the
roots absorb enough water and nutrients.
Step
[Music]
two, use soft cotton to absorb this GE
solution and gently wipe the top and
bottom of the leaves.
Cleaning the leaves helps remove dust,
debris, and residues, allowing the plant
to absorb light better, which enhances
the photosynthesis
process. The GE solution provides
essential nutrients, keeping the leaves
vibrant and healthy and boosting the
plant's resistance.
Maintaining clean leaves creates
favorable conditions for the development
of new leaves.
Clean and healthy leaves help the plant
focus its energy on growing and
flowering.
[Music]
Step
three, put this water in a spray bottle.
[Music]
Then spray the entire orchid from roots
to leaves.
Spraying GE helps the plant accumulate
energy in preparation for the next
bloom, resulting in more uniform and
beautiful flowers.
[Music]
The nutrients in the solution support
root growth, helping the plant absorb
water and nutrients more effectively.
After soaking for 20 minutes, take the
orchid pot out and place it in a place
with lots of scattered light for the
orchid to photosynthesize and
metabolize.
results after one
[Music]
month. Every one week or 10 days, I
apply GE solution to orchids and you see
the roots grow very
quickly. Uh many new roots grow from the
base of the orchid.
New roots improve the plant's ability to
absorb water efficiently, especially
during the recovery phase after
blooming, providing the necessary
moisture for the plant.
Um when the roots are healthy and
growing that the plant can produce new
shoots setting the stage for future
blooms.
New roots enhance the absorption of
nutrients from the growing medium,
ensuring the plant receives all the
essential elements for growth and
flowering.
[Music]
Take care of your orchids with all the
love you have for plants, and you'll get
to enjoy the beautiful flowers you've
nurtured yourself.
And that's the care tips for orchids I
wanted to share today.
If you found this video helpful, don't
forget to like and subscribe to the
channel so you won't miss any other
gardening tips.
If you found this video helpful, don't
forget to like and subscribe to the
channel so you won't miss any other
gardening
tips. I'm very happy that you are here.
If you have an orchid, I'm sure you
always want it to bloom for a long time,
right?
[Music]
Right. Orchids are known for their
ability to keep flowers on their
branches for 3 to 6
[Music]
months. For that to happen, you need to
nurture, water, and feed it well.
[Music]
Now I will show you what is the best
fertilizer for
[Music]
orchids. If you follow us till the end
of this video, you will learn how to
make orchids bloom like crazy.
[Music]
Now, let's get
started. Take a bowl and put 5 tsp of
rice in
[Music]
it. If you haven't subscribed to the
channel yet, please subscribe to support
me and not miss any orchid care tips.
[Music]
Pour in 500 ml of water at room
temperature. Mix the rice well and wash
the rice before cooking.
[Music]
Then filter the water to wash the
rice. Please comment to me which country
you are watching the video from. It's
great that we can chat together from all
over the
[Music]
world. Use a cotton ball soaked in water
to wash this rice.
Then wipe on the top and bottom of the
[Music]
leaves will help clean the surface of
the leaves, remove disease fungi and
insects on orchids. At the same time, it
provides the necessary nutrients for the
orchid's growth.
[Music]
Repeat after 2 weeks will help the
orchid stay green.
[Music]
or you can also pour the rice water into
a spray bottle.
[Music]
Then spray evenly on the top and bottom
of the
[Music]
leaves. This method also has the same
effect as the previous method using
cotton balls.
[Music]
Do not spray rice water on
flowers. Now take a deep bowl in which
you will place the orchid ready for
watering and soaking.
[Music]
Rice water is a great natural fertilizer
for orchids as it encourages the
flowering of this beautiful
[Music]
plant. You can soak the orchid in this
rice water for about 1 hour so that the
orchid roots can absorb the most
nutrients.
[Music]
Then remove and repeat this treatment
every 14 days.
[Music]
You can also freeze rice water to water
your orchids.
[Music]
When needed, you just need to take a few
cubes.
[Music]
Wait for them to defrost and reach room
temperature. You can feed your orchids
[Music]
again. Never place frozen blocks
directly on the base of the orchid
because orchids don't like the cold.
[Music]
After only 2 to 3 weeks of use, the
leaves will be green.
[Music]
Um, you can see that after fertilizing
the new roots grow very strongly. This
will help the orchid best absorb
nutrients through its
[Music]
roots. If you find the content
interesting or meaningful, don't forget
to like, share so that more people know
and subscribe to your support channel.
Thank you for always accompanying me.
With enough nutrition, your orchid will
flower all year
[Music]
round. And that will be all we have
prepared for you for this video.