welcome to happiness Garden today we'll
share an amazing secret to help orchids
bloom all year
[Music]
round uh after your orchids have bloomed
proper care will help them recover and
continue blooming for a long
[Music]
time let's explore how to make homemade
fertilizer to keep your orchids healthy
and blooming continuously
[Music]
do you have any
bread bread contains carbon an important
ingredient that helps promote the growth
of beneficial bacteria in Orchid growing
media these bacteria decompose organic
matter creating good conditions for
orchid roots to grow
[Music]
um bread especially whole grain bread
can contain vitamins and minerals such
as B vitamins iron and potassium which
can provide additional nutrients for
[Music]
orchids next I need ripe bananas
please comment to me which country you
are watching the video from it's great
that we can chat together from all over
the
[Music]
world in addition to the English dub
we've now created dubs in French German
Italian Spanish Portuguese Japanese
Hindi and Indonesian to help you hear
and understand the content more
easily take two ripe banana peels and
cut them into small
pieces banana peels are rich in
potassium an essential mineral that
helps orchids grow strong and withstand
harsh environment Al factors potassium
also enhances the plants resistance to
diseases and promotes beautiful
long-lasting
blooms put in jar
um next you need five sundried or
sundried
eggshells crush the eggshells into
pieces and put them in a
jar eggshells contain a large amount of
calcium about 90% of the eggshell is
calcium
carbonate calcium is an important
mineral that helps orchids grow healthy
roots and maintain a strong cell
structure next I need beer to help
ferment the solution
quickly add 100 m 2029 of beer
[Music]
then add 1 L 4 cups of
water seal the jar and leave in a cool
place for 3 weeks to create a very good
fertilizer for
[Music]
orchids 3 weeks
later I have a synthetic fertilizer
solution that is very good good for
orchids
a good solution should have a light
Aroma of fermented
bananas if there's an unpleasant odor do
not use
it take about 50 ml spr 10 TS beam of
this synthetic fer ER
solution fermented solution from bread
banana peels eggshells and beer acts as
a balanced fertilizer for orchids by
providing a variety of nutrients
add one liter and four cups of
water then you apply this liquid
fertilizer to the
Orchid this is an orchid that has
finished blooming
caring for orchids after blooming is
important so that the plant recovers and
continues to bloom in the following
Seasons uh you need to cut off all the
wilted flowers
step
one soak a soft cotton in this solution
and gently wipe the top and bottom of
the leaves
thoroughly helps remove dirt and mineral
salts that exist on leaves
the fermented solution from these
ingredients provides essential minerals
like calcium potassium phosphorus and
magnesium helping orchid leaves stay
healthy shiny and support better
photosynthesis
this enables the plant to absorb energy
from sunlight more
[Music]
efficiently the minerals in the solution
especially calcium and magnesium help
boost the orchid's resistance making the
plant more resilient to fungal diseases
bacteria and other harmful factors
[Music]
step
two put this solution into a spray
bottle and spray the entire orchid
[Music]
this solution not only helps keep leaves
healthy but also supports the growth of
roots and flower
buds nutrients will be absorbed through
the leaves and stems helping the plant
grow healthier
[Music]
step
three uh the fermented solution is rich
in minerals like calcium potassium
phosph phorus and magnesium which
enhance root health and
growth the calcium helps strengthen root
cell walls promoting strong root
development and secure anchoring in the
soil or growing
[Music]
medium step
four after spraying wipe off the liquid
fertilizer on the leaves
if this solution is left on the leaves
for too long especially in high humidity
conditions it can cause problems such as
Leaf rot mold or Leaf burn due to two
concentrated nutrients
it is best to care for orchids with this
liquid fertilizer in the morning when
the Sun rises the Orchid will
photosynthesize well helping the plant
metabolize nutrients
better then place the Orchid pot in a
place with plenty of light but no direct
sunlight
[Music]
results after 2
months since the Orchid finished
blooming 2 months ago after 2 months of
care the plant has recovered well it has
developed many new healthy roots and
most notably has produced two new flower
spikes demonstrating strong growth and
[Music]
vitality leaves become Greener and
glossier than before
[Music]
the old flower spikes are now continuing
to grow and Sprout new buds promising to
bring beautiful blooms in the near
future for
[Music]
than
this is an orchid that has flowered I
also took care of it with this solution
and It produced many new flower buds
care for your orchid with all the love
you have for plants and you will be
rewarded with vibrant flowers blooming
beautifully in every season
I hope you enjoyed this video if you
found it helpful don't forget to like
share with your friends and subscribe to
the channel for more updates thank you
for watching and see you in the next
videos