Welcome to the happiness garden where we
explore together the gentle and magical
beauty of nature.
I am your companion on the journey of
caring for orchids using natural, safe
and loving methods.
Today I will guide you on how to make
completely free organic fertilizer that
is incredibly effective for the growth
of orchids.
Helps orchids produce many flower buds
and bloom year round in the garden.
Uh, this fertilizer will help roots
develop exceptionally, creating a solid
foundation for orchids to grow fast,
healthy, and bloom again soon.
So, let's start exploring how to make
this wonderful organic fertilizer right
now.
Let's get started.
Right here, I'm holding a red beet, the
main ingredient for the natural
fertilizer we will make together today.
[Music]
When you eat beetroot, don't be quick to
throw away the peel because it contains
many valuable nutrients such as
potassium, phosphorus, and organic
compounds, all of which are extremely
beneficial for the development of
orchids.
[Music]
Leave a comment and let me know which
country you're watching from. It's
wonderful that we can connect and chat
from all around the world.
[Music]
The next ingredient I need is a few
small cloves of garlic. As garlic has
natural antibacterial properties that
help protect orchids from fungal
diseases and stimulate healthier plant
growth.
[Music]
Put everything into 0.5 L of water. Then
blend the beet peel together with the
garlic to release the maximum beneficial
nutrients for the orchids.
[Music]
After blending, strain out the residue
to get the clear nutrient solution,
which helps orchids absorb easily and
grow better.
[Music]
Next, use a cotton ball to evenly apply
this nutrient mixture.
[Music]
If you haven't subscribed yet, please
hit the subscribe button to support me
and never miss any orchid care tips.
It's truly wonderful to have you along
on this journey.
Then gently place the cotton balls
soaked with this solution into the leaf
axles exactly where we want the orchids
to develop fresh vibrant flower spikes.
[Music]
Uh, you only need to do this once a
week.
Um, on regular days when the cotton
balls have dried, you just need to
lightly spray water to maintain
moisture, helping the orchids stay fresh
and healthy throughout the care period.
[Music]
Dilute the remaining beetroot water with
3 L of water to create a watering
solution that gently provides nutrients
supporting orchids to develop
comprehensively from roots to leaves.
In addition to the English voiceover, we
have now created versions in French,
German, Italian, Spanish, Portuguese,
Japanese, Hindi, and Indonesian to help
you listen and understand the content
more easily.
To listen in your language, open the
video and click on settings, the gear
icon, to select your preferred audio
language.
[Music]
Then use this diluted mixture to water
your orchid pots every 2 weeks, helping
the plants grow healthy and sustainably
over time.
[Music]
This mixture will provide all the
essential nutrients, nourishing the
orchids from within, helping the plants
grow stronger and healthier every day.
At the same time, this mixture also
enhances the overall health and
resilience of the plants against harsh
conditions, helping the orchids stay
green and durable.
[Music]
Moreover, this mixture also promotes
orchids to produce more flowers,
bringing vibrant, fresh clusters that
captivate the heart.
Furthermore, it improves the flower
quality, making each bloom more vibrant,
longasting, and fragrant, enhancing the
beauty and value of your orchids.
In addition, you can absolutely combine
the fertilizer made from beetroot peel
with other natural fertilizers to create
a balanced nutrition regimen, helping
orchids develop comprehensively and
healthier.
[Music]
Um, however, before using red beetroot
as fertilizer, remember to follow the
proper dosage and usage instructions I
have shared in order to protect the
orchids from unwanted effects and ensure
optimal care results.
[Music]
And here are the results after 45 days
of application.
[Music]
You can easily see that my orchid has
started to grow many new flower spikes,
signaling a bountiful blooming season
and full of vitality.
On the same orchid plant, there are up
to five new spikes, creating a beautiful
and promising scene for the bright
blooming days ahead.
What do you think about the way I care
for orchids using natural fertilizer?
Don't hesitate to leave a comment and
share your thoughts. I'd love to hear
your feedback and experiences.
[Music]
This mixture also helps orchid flowers
firmly attached to the stems,
maintaining their fresh color and
lasting beauty before fading, giving you
many days to enjoy the vibrant blooms.
[Music]
The flowers can also stay on the stems
for up to 6 months before wilting.
[Music]
This mixture not only nourishes the
plant, but also stimulates orchids to
grow many new healthy roots, creating a
solid foundation for lasting growth and
flowering.
I hope you enjoy this video. If you find
it helpful, don't forget to like and
subscribe to the channel so you won't
miss the next tips on how to care for
orchids naturally and simply.
Thank you so much for watching. I truly
appreciate your time and support.
Wishing you a wonderful day filled with
joy and blooming orchids.
[Music]
Welcome to my channel.
If not treated promptly, rot will spread
to other trees very quickly.
This root is rotten, so it should be
thrown away.
[Music]
This leaf is still fresh, so it can be
restored.
[Music]
Remove all rotten leaves.
Uh please comment to me which country
you are watching the video from. It's
great that we can chat together from all
over the world.
Then rinse with water. This helps the
tree recover faster.
[Music]
And this method will remove dirt and
insects still attached to these leaves.
[Music]
Helps orchids, even though they only
have one leaf, can revive vive faster
and easier.
[Music]
Cutting extra to avoid crushing the stem
will help prevent the orchid from
rotting further.
[Music]
If you haven't subscribed to the channel
yet, please subscribe to support me and
not miss any orchid care tips.
[Music]
I use coffee as a natural fertilizer to
help orchids recover quickly.
Take one teaspoon.
[Music]
Add two cups of boiling water.
If you encounter any difficulties during
the orchid growing process, don't
hesitate to comment. I am always ready
to support you so you can grow healthy
orchids and bloom lots of flowers.
[Music]
Um, wait until it cools before using it
as fertilizer.
[Music]
After cooling, filter to remove residue.
Coffee will be very good and help
orchids grow very quickly.
[Music]
In addition to the US English language,
I have added voiceovers in French,
German, Italian, Spanish, Portuguese,
Japanese, Hindi, and Indonesian to help
you hear and understand the video
content easier. Please click on the
settings on the video to select the
appropriate language.
[Music]
Use soft cotton pads. Wipe the leaves
again and add nutrients through the
leaves and eliminate insects and fungi.
Helps orchid leaves recover. Will not be
infected with insects and fungi.
[Music]
Put the leaves here and then add this
coffee water.
[Music]
Leave for about 30 minutes to help the
plant regenerate roots very quickly.
and use the remaining coffee water put
in spray bottle.
[Music]
Spraying directly on the orchid will
help the orchid grow quickly.
And remember to spray under the leaves
to prevent insect growth.
[Music]
Um you should apply this method every 2
weeks.
[Music]
or water orchid roots every 2 weeks.
This is a great way to provide nutrients
to orchids through the roots.
[Music]
You can see that orchids cared for by
this method have very healthy roots.
[Music]
A strong root system will help the
orchid absorb the most nutrients.
[Music]
When absorbing enough nutrients, the
plant will always be healthy and bloom
many flowers.
[Music]
The flower color is bright and stays on
the branch for a long time before
fading.
[Music]
The mineral and nitrogen content in
coffee helps leaves stay green and
strong.
[Music]
Potassium in coffee helps flower buds
not fall off before blooming.
[Music]
After 30 minutes, take the leaves out
and wipe dry.
[Music]
Use one clove of garlic. Garlic has very
good antibacterial and antiseptic
properties.
[Music]
Because garlic has good antibacterial
properties, it is very effective in
preventing orchid rot.
[Music]
Then leave it in a cool, dry place for
one day so that the cut will dry and the
orchid leaves will recover quickly.
Then take advantage of recycled plastic
boxes into orchid growing tools.
[Music]
Please cut like I do.
Take a cotton pad and place it here.
Cotton will help absorb water better.
[Music]
Put the leaf in.
Then pour in filtered water.
Then cut the orchid leaves into the box.
[Music]
Adjust the water level so that it does
not touch the base of the plant.
[Music]
And remember to add water when you feel
like you're running out of water.
[Music]
Cover and place in a cool, well-lit
place.
[Music]
With this method, you will not need to
spray mist to keep the leaves moist.
[Music]
And this is the result. After the next
month, the orchid has recovered and
grown healthy roots.
[Music]
The orchid has grown a new leaf.
With these methods, you need to be
patient because with orchids, there will
always be fast plants and slow plants.
So, when implementing these methods, we
need to be persistent.
[Music]
And the roots have grown very well.
I planted it in a new pot so the orchids
could grow in the outside environment.
[Music]
planting with pine bark will help the
roots always breathe so the orchid will
not rot.
I always share many ways for you to
easily choose what are the most suitable
and simplest ways.
[Music]
Add a little moss to the surface of the
orchid pot to help retain moisture
better.
[Music]
After planting, water and keep the
orchids moist.
[Music]
I have created many subtitles for you to
view and choose from which subtitle is
suitable.
[Music]
Hope it will always help you a lot.
Don't forget to like, share, and
subscribe to the channel and press the
bell to conveniently follow.
[Music]
Thank you for watching.
Goodbye and see you again. Wish you
always success.