welcome to my
channel when orchids have enough
nutrients and good soil environment the
plant will grow stronger and flower
[Music]
more to help create the best conditions
for flower development at the same time
make orchids bloom more beautiful both
roots and flowers grow Beyond
imagination in this video I share a new
fertilizer that few people know about
[Music]
let's explore with me
now when when you plant a lot of orchids
the Orchid rot is
[Music]
inevitable if it accidentally rots you
need to cut off the rotten part right
away
[Music]
then isolate the rotten Orchid pot from
other normal Orchid
[Music]
pots this helps prevent rot from
spreading to normal orchids
[Music]
after cutting off the rotten part you
need to dry the rot
[Music]
solution uh if you haven't subscribed to
the channel yet please hit the Subscribe
button to support me and not miss any
Orchid growing tips it's amazing to have
you as a
[Music]
companion please comment to me which
country you are watching the video from
it's great that we can chat together
from all over the
[Music]
world um waste from rotten orchids
should be isolated from the garden as
far as
[Music]
possible this is activated carbon it is
made from natural dry firewood
[Music]
I took a piece of activated carbon like
this and grounded into powder
[Music]
then sprinkle activated charcoal powder
on the newly cut wound helps Cuts heal
faster and eliminates fungal
diseases because activated carbon has a
very good sterilization function
[Music]
then you sprinkle more in between the
two leaves and on the
base then put the Orchid pot in a cool
place and do not water for one week the
Orchid will recover from the disease
next
[Music]
way mix one teaspoon of activated carbon
with 1 liter of water
[Music]
then use this water to water the base of
the
[Music]
Orchid perform periodically once every 2
weeks for normal orchids helps prevent
disease and improve pH in growing media
[Music]
in activated carbon there is also a high
content of calcium and natural minerals
that are very good for orchids helps
stimulate
[Music]
rooting soaking this water for 30
minutes is better
[Music]
the next way you filter this water to
get clear water
[Music]
then use this water to wash the
leaves Orchid will be protected from
fungi and insects
[Music]
the calcium content in activated carbon
helps to strengthen the
[Music]
leaves do it regularly once every 2
weeks and you will be healthy like this
[Music]
you can also use this water to spray the
entire Orchid it helps to eliminate
fungi and insects on leaves very well
and it also provides provides some
nutrients through the
[Music]
leaves now let's see the results
lots of new Roots growing this helps
orchids absorb nutrients best
[Music]
the potassium and phosphorus content in
activated carbon stimulates extremely
fast rooting
[Music]
the flowers are brighter and stronger
many flower buds growing on the same
tree
[Music]
surely you will be surprised with this
fertilizer if you find it interesting
please like and share it with many
people and don't forget to subscribe to
my
[Music]
channel thank you for watching the video
goodbye and see you again in the next
videos
[Music]