Welcome to the Happiness Garden channel,
where nature blooms from love and
patience, bringing joy and positive
energy everyday.
Today, I continue to share with you how
to care for your orchids at home using
homemade fertilizer. Simple but
effective.
Um, with this method, your orchid will
not only stay healthy, but can also
bloom continuously, bringing lasting
beauty to your little garden.
You will see new flower buds quietly
forming like a sweet gift the orchid
gives to its caretaker.
And after a short time, the leaves will
become glossy and sturdy.
[Music]
If you haven't subscribe to the channel
yet, please hit the subscribe button to
support me and never miss any orchid
growing tips. It's wonderful to have you
with me.
[Music]
Uh to make this natural fertilizer, we
will need bananas, a familiar ingredient
that is rich in potassium and essential
nutrients.
[Music]
Before using, you should wash the banana
thoroughly, especially the peel, as it
may still contain traces of
preservatives. This cleaning step helps
ensure your natural fertilizer is safer
for the plant and more environmentally
friendly.
[Music]
Bananas not only help stimulate root and
flower growth, but also naturally and
safely boost the orchid's resistance.
[Music]
Cut about 20 gram of banana. Just enough
to provide nutrients without overfeeding
the plant.
[Music]
Put the chopped banana into a clean
bottle. Then pour in about one liter of
water.
[Music]
Next, blend the banana and water mixture
until smooth.
[Applause]
[Music]
Next, prepare some vinegar. It helps
balance the pH of the solution and
supports mild fermentation, which
enhances the breakdown of nutrients in
the banana, making them easier for the
plant to absorb.
[Music]
Just one teaspoon of vinegar is enough.
You can use white vinegar, apple cider
vinegar, or banana vinegar, depending on
what you have at home.
[Music]
After stirring the mixture well, close
the lid tightly and let it sit overnight
in a cool, ventilated place. During this
time, the nutrients will continue to
dissolve and activate, creating a gentle
yet effective natural fertilizer
solution for your orchid.
[Music]
This is an orchid that has just begun to
wither its petals. A moment that seems
like the end, but in fact opens a new
cycle of revival if cared for properly.
[Music]
Gently remove the fading petals. This
simple action will help the plant save
energy and focus on nurturing its roots,
leaves, and the new flower buds that are
about to form.
[Music]
Removing yellow or damaged leaves is a
necessary step to keep the plant
healthy.
By removing the non-functional leaves,
you help the plant focus on nourishing
the fresh parts and stimulate stronger
growth.
[Music]
uh leave a comment and let me know which
country you're watching from. It's
wonderful that we can connect and chat
from all around the world.
[Music]
Next, you need to check the growing
medium. If it has decayed, retains too
much water, or is no longer well
airrated, it should be replaced
immediately. A clean and airy
environment will help the orchid roots
grow strong and prevent root rot.
The growing medium of this orchid is
still in good condition. It remains well
arrated and shows no signs of decay, so
there's no need to replace it yet.
Keeping the medium when it's still
usable helps prevent plant shock and
allows the orchid to continue growing
steadily.
Before fertilizing, water the orchid to
moisten the growing medium. This helps
the roots absorb nutrients more safely
and effectively while also reducing the
risk of root burn caused by concentrated
fertilizer.
[Music]
Um, in addition to the English voice
over, we have now created versions in
French, German, Italian, Spanish,
Portuguese, Japanese, Hindi, Dutch,
Polish, Korean, and Indonesian to help
you listen and understand the content
more easily.
To listen, listen in your language. Open
the video and click on settings, the
gear icon, to select your preferred
audio language.
Soak the roots in water for about 20
minutes to allow them to absorb enough
moisture before fertilizing. This helps
the plant take in nutrients more
effectively and maintain the necessary
moisture for growth.
[Music]
After soaking for about 20 minutes,
gently take the orchid out and let it
drain. Only when the root surface is dry
should we proceed with fertilizing.
During soaking, the water helps wash
away accumulated mineral salts in the
growing medium. If left too long, these
salts can harm the roots. This allows
the roots to absorb the new fertilizer
better and prevents burning from excess
minerals.
[Music]
After letting it sit overnight, stir the
mixture well again so the nutrients are
evenly distributed in the water.
[Music]
Then strain out the residue to obtain a
clear solution. This makes it easier to
water the orchid and prevents clogging
the growing medium.
[Music]
Next, dilute the filtered solution with
one liter of clean water to make a total
of 2 L of fertilizer solution. Diluting
it lowers the concentration, ensuring
the solution is gentle enough for the
orchid roots to absorb safely and
effectively.
[Music]
Method one, use a soft cloth soaked in
the fertilizer solution and gently wipe
both the top and bottom surfaces of the
leaves.
This not only provides nutrients
directly through the leaves, but also
helps remove dust, allowing the plant to
breathe better and making the leaves
naturally glossy and healthy.
When wiping the leaves with the banana
mixture, nutrients like potassium and
vitamins are absorbed through the leaf
surface, helping the plant absorb
quickly, recover well, and grow
vigorously from within.
[Music]
Uh over time, leaves often accumulate
dust and bacteria which reduces their
ability to exchange gases. Cleaning the
leaves helps keep the stamata clear,
enhances the plant's respiration, and
prevents the growth of harmful fungi.
While wiping the leaves, you can easily
observe every small detail on their
surface. This helps you detect signs of
pests, leaf spots, or abnormalities in
time, allowing for early treatment and
more effective protection of your
orchid.
Regularly wiping the leaves with a
natural solution also helps them become
glossier and healthier. This is not only
a sign of a well-rowing plant, but also
adds to the orchid's vibrant, lively,
and radiant appearance.
You only need to wipe the leaves with
this solution about one to two times a
month.
Method two, you can pour the solution
into a spray bottle for more convenient
use.
With this method, simply spray a light
mist onto both the underside and top
side of the leaves. This helps the
fertilizer absorb quickly while keeping
the leaf surfaces cool and fresh.
When spraying the solution onto the
leaves, the nutrients from the banana
quickly penetrate through the epidermis,
allowing the plant to absorb them
directly without waiting for root
uptake.
This is an effective way to supplement
micronutrients, especially during
recovery or before blooming.
The fine mist from the spray bottle
helps maintain stable moisture levels on
the leaves, especially on hot days or
when the air humidity is low. This
prevents the leaves from drying out,
reduces stress, and keeps the plant
looking naturally fresh.
Method three, you can use the diluted
solution to water directly at the base
of the plant, allowing the roots to
absorb nutrients naturally and
effectively. This is a way to care from
the inside out, nourishing the entire
plant from roots to tip, helping the
roots grow strong. The leaves stay lush
green and the flowers bloom longer.
The banana and vinegar solution has a
mild acidity that creates an unfavorable
environment for fungi and certain pests.
Regular watering with it not only
nourishes the plant, but also helps
protect the orchid from harmful agents.
After watering, you can let the orchid
pot soak in the solution for about 20
minutes to allow the roots to fully
absorb the nutrients, soften the growing
medium, and support the plant's overall
recovery.
Um, you can use the remaining solution
to spray on other orchids that are
growing normally in your garden. This is
a great way to gently uh provide
nutrients, helping the plants maintain
vitality and grow steadily.
For orchids that have finished blooming,
this type of fertilizer will help the
plant recover quickly, nourish the roots
to to grow vigorously, stimulate healthy
leaf growth, and prepare energy for the
next blooming cycle.
For blooming orchids, the natural banana
fertilizer provides gentle nutrition,
helping the flowers last longer, the
colors stay vibrant, and the leaves
remain healthy, creating a solid
foundation for the plant to maintain its
beauty throughout the blooming season.
[Music]
Uh, after soaking for about 20 minutes,
gently take the orchid pot out of the
solution.
[Music]
Use a soft cloth to absorb any remaining
water droplets on the leaf surfaces and
between the leaf joints.
This step helps prevent water
accumulation that can cause leaf rot
while keeping the plant dry, clean, and
healthy.
In addition, wiping off the remaining
water helps improve the plant's
photosynthesis process.
When the leaf surface is clean and dry,
light can more easily reach the
epidermis, thereby promoting more
effective light absorption and energy
conversion.
[Music]
After finishing the care, place the
orchid pot in a cool, well ventilated
spot with gentle light in the early
morning or late afternoon. This helps
the plant photosynthesize well, avoid
leaf burn, and recover healthily.
[Music]
And here is the result after 45 days.
You can clearly see the wonderful
changes
from the old flower spike. After being
properly cared for over time, new flower
branches have started to grow. This is a
sign that the orchid has not only
recovered well, but is also ready to
continue its blooming cycle with
vitality.
[Music]
These new flower branches are clear
proof of the plant's strong vitality
after the recovery process.
From an old flower spike that once
seemed drained of energy, fresh new buds
are now emerging, promising a vibrant
blooming season ahead.
[Music]
Each new flower bud that appears is not
by chance. It is the result of
consistent care, love, and patience
every day. Small actions like wiping the
leaves, watering properly, or choosing
the right time to fertilize all
contribute to creating this miracle.
Even if your orchid is weak, has
finished blooming, or seems lifeless,
just start today with gentle and proper
care, and it can still recover and bloom
again.
[Music]
Each orchid pot in the garden is not
just a flower. It is a life journey with
moments of budding, fading, and rising
again with strength. And you, the
caretaker, are an essential part of that
journey.
[Music]
This is another orchid pot that I also
cared for using the same method. And as
you can see, the new flower spike has
grown very well, strong, long, and full
of vitality.
And this orchid pot is the same. After
being cared for with a simple yet
effective method, the plant has clearly
recovered and started to bloom
beautifully. The vibrant petals seem to
be a gentle response to the care and
attention you've given it.
One plant at a time, gently, patiently,
and full of love. Gradually, you will
see your entire garden come back to life
with each orchid taking turns to sprout
new shoots, roots, and blooms. This is
the beauty of persistent care and the
joy that comes from simple everyday
moments.
I hope you will enjoy this video. If you
find it helpful, don't forget to like
and subscribe to the channel so you
won't miss upcoming shares on how to
care for orchids naturally and simply.
[Music]
Thank you so much for accompanying me on
the journey of caring for these beloved
orchid pots. I wish you always be filled
with joy, good health, and many
wonderful moments with your little
garden. See you again in the next
videos.