Welcome to the happiness garden, where
the simplest things are cared for with
all the love.
Today, I will share with you how to grow
orchids using the semihydroponic method.
A modern yet easy way to help the plant
grow healthily and bloom regularly.
[Music]
This is an orchid that has finished
blooming, which I bought at a discount
from a local flower shop. I brought it
home to revive it using the
semihydroponic method, a growing
technique that helps the roots absorb
water and nutrients more efficiently,
thereby encouraging the plant to grow
back healthily.
Although the plant has wilted leaves and
no flowers, its inner potential is still
waiting to be awakened with gentle and
proper care.
First, you need to cut off the old
flower spike. Since the plant is showing
signs of leaf wilt, removing the spent
flower spike will help it save energy
and focus on nourishing the roots and
recovering its leaves more effectively.
[Music]
Next, you need to check the growing
medium.
If the medium still retains moisture,
but the leaves are wilted, it's very
likely that most of the orchid's roots
have been damaged.
As you can see, the growing medium is
too moist, and this makes the roots very
prone to rot. Uh, when roots are
submerged in an overly wet environment
for too long, they lack the oxygen
needed for respiration, leading to root
rot and weakening the plant.
Oh, there's a small worm crawling in the
growing medium. This shows that the
environment is so wet that even a worm
can live inside.
Although it's just a tiny creature, its
presence is a warning sign. The growing
medium is retaining too much moisture
and could harm the roots if not changed
in time.
We need to completely remove the old
growing medium.
[Music]
You can see that most of the roots have
rotted.
[Music]
Now we need to cut off all the damaged
hollow or rotten roots.
[Music]
Uh these roots no longer serve to
nourish the plant and could even become
a source of disease if kept.
[Music]
Leave a comment and let me know which
country you're watching from. It's
wonderful that we can connect and chat
from all around the world.
And if you haven't subscribed yet, hit
the subscribe button to support me and
never miss any orchid growing tips. It's
truly wonderful to have you along on
this journey.
[Music]
We only keep the healthy roots, those
that are white, green, or slightly ivory
in color and still feel firm and full of
life to the touch.
[Music]
After pruning, we need to rinse all the
remaining roots thoroughly under running
water. This helps remove dirt, old
medium debris, and any bacteria still
clinging to the roots.
Under the cool stream of water, the
roots are gently cleaned, ready for the
next step in the plant's recovery
process.
[Music]
The first ingredient I use to revive
this orchid is rice.
I put 3 teaspoon of rice into the
container. Rice is a great natural
source of nutrients that helps stimulate
root growth. When used properly, it can
be a simple yet effective solution to
support the orchid's recovery from
within.
The next ingredient I use is aloe vera
leaf.
Aloe vera has antibacterial properties,
soothes and stimulates cell
regeneration, making it excellent for
orchid root recovery.
I cut the aloe vera leaf into thin
slices.
These cool, fresh slices of aloe vera
will be a wonderful natural support for
the orchid after being damaged.
When combined with rice, aloe vera
creates a natural mixture that helps the
plant grow quickly and grow steadily
again.
[Music]
I put everything into about one liter of
room temperature water.
Water that is neither too cold nor too
hot helps preserve the nutrients from
the rice and aloe vera while creating an
ideal environment for the natural
ingredients to blend together.
I cover it and let it sit for 1 hour to
give the rice time to absorb the water.
[Music]
After that, I stir the mixture well to
help the nutrients from the rice and
aloe vera dissolve evenly in the water.
[Music]
Next, strain it through a sieve.
I press the rice and aloe vera pulp
firmly against the sieve to extract all
the nutrients into the mixture. Uh, this
is a simple yet effective way to make
the most of the nutrients in natural
ingredients, resulting in a concentrated
solution rich in energy to help the
orchid recover.
[Music]
After preparing the mixture, I soak the
orchid roots in it for about 20 minutes.
Uh this amount of time is enough for the
nutrients from the rice and aloe vera to
deeply penetrate the roots, helping to
soothe the damage and stimulate new root
growth.
While waiting for the roots to soak, you
can use a soft cloth dipped in the
solution to gently wipe the surface of
the leaves.
This not only helps clean off dust, but
also provides extra nutrients to the
leaves through the epidermis. The leaves
will become shinier, fresher, and will
contribute to the orchid's overall
recovery process.
In addition, wiping the leaves with this
natural solution also helps prevent the
growth of fungi and bacteria on the leaf
surface.
Thanks to the mild antibacterial
properties of aloe vera, the orchid
leaves will be better protected,
especially during the period when the
plant is weak and more vulnerable to
pathogens.
[Music]
After soaking for about 20 minutes, I
gently take the orchid out of the
solution and use a soft cloth to pat the
roots dry.
[Music]
I drip a small amount of melted wax onto
the cut ends of the stem.
Uh, this thin layer of wax helps seal
the wound, prevents the entry of
bacteria and fungi, and stops the stem
from drying out at the tip.
This is a simple yet very helpful way to
protect the plant during its recovery
process.
[Music]
After that, I plant the orchid in a
clear glass container. This type of
container not only makes it easy to
observe the root development, but also
adds a touch of elegance and softness to
the space.
Then I pour chlorine-free clean water
into the container to begin growing the
orchid using the semi-hydroponic method.
[Music]
Chlorine-free water is safe for the
young roots, preventing root cell damage
and helping the plant absorb nutrients
more effectively.
The water level should only lightly
touch the bottom of the roots to create
a moderately humid environment, helping
the plant grow healthily without the
risk of rot.
I place the orchid pot in a spot with
gentle sunlight, good air circulation,
and away from direct harsh sun. Soft
light helps the plant photosynthesize
well without burning the leaves.
In addition, you should soak the orchid
roots in the natural fertilizer mixture
made from rice and aloe vera about once
every 2 weeks.
Each time you fertilize, be sure to
change the water in the container to
keep the environment clean, limit
bacterial growth, and create ideal
conditions for the roots to grow strong
and stay healthy over time.
[Music]
And here is the result after 3 weeks of
recovery using natural fertilizer and
the semi-hydroponic uh growing method.
[Music]
Wow. You can see that many new roots
have started to grow.
This is a wonderful sign that the plant
is recovering well and absorbing
nutrients effectively.
[Music]
These healthy young roots are proof of
the strong vitality the orchid is
gradually regaining after being properly
cared for.
[Music]
Once the new roots begin to grow, the
wilted leaves will gradually recover.
Because once the roots are healthy
again, the plant can absorb water and
nutrients more effectively, bringing the
wilted leaves back to life.
[Music]
And here are the orchids I previously
revived using the semihydroponic method
combined with natural fertilizer.
Thanks to proper care, the orchids have
grown strong and have started to form
buds.
This method of care not only helps the
plant grow strong and produce buds, but
also allows the flowers to stay on the
stem for a long time.
[Music]
With healthy roots, the orchid absorbs
nutrients consistently, helping it
maintain vibrant and long-lasting blooms
for many weeks.
If you face any difficulties while
growing orchids, don't hesitate to leave
a comment. I'm always here to help you
grow healthy orchids that bloom
beautifully.
[Music]
When growing orchids using the
semi-hydroponic method, the roots
receive adequate moisture while staying
well airrated, helping to prevent the
common issue of root rot in overly wet
environments.
[Music]
When healthy, orchid roots grow long,
thick, and cling firmly to the sides of
the container, not only helping the
plant stay upright, but also indicating
that it is efficiently absorbing water
and nutrients.
I hope you enjoy this video. If you find
it helpful, don't forget to hit like and
subscribe so you won't miss the next
tips on how to care for orchids
naturally and simply.
[Music]
You can see that when the roots are
healthy, uh the leaves also become
greener and shinier.
The plump, round flower buds are a sign
that the plant is in its best stage of
growth.
What do you think about the way I revive
this little orchid? Don't hesitate to
leave a comment and share your thoughts.
I'd love to hear your feedback and
experiences.
Nourished by healthy roots and lush
green leaves, these energyfilled buds
are ready to bloom into vibrant orchid
flowers in the near future.
[Music]
Uh though the orchid is small, its large
and full petals show that it has
absorbed nutrients well and has been
properly cared for.
When an orchid is nourished from within
using natural methods, it channels all
its energy into producing the most
beautiful and vibrant blooms.
With just patience and a little love
each day, any orchid can be revived and
bloom beautifully. Even starting with a
withered orchid pot, you can turn it
into into a radiant gift from nature
simply through gentle care from the
heart. Thank you so much for taking the
time to watch the video. Goodbye and see
you in the next one.
Welcome to my channel.
Today I will restore an exhausted orchid
with wrinkled leaves in a very simple
way. Dash
[Music]
wake up any weak orchid pot under any
conditions.
[Music]
Helps any orchid pot grow healthily,
bloom brightly, and brighten up your
living space.
To restore orchids, I use garlic.
Please comment to me which country you
are watching the video from. It's great
that we can chat together from all over
the world.
Take three cloves of garlic and slice
them.
[Music]
If you haven't subscribe to the channel
yet, please hit the subscribe button to
support me and not miss any orchid
growing tips. It's great to have you
along.
Put in a jar and soak with 2 L of water
for 2 hours.
[Music]
An orchid has withered leaves and is
exhausted.
[Music]
Cut off all flower stems.
Then cut off all damaged roots.
[Music]
Rinse with water.
Then leave it in a cool place and wait
for the water to dry.
[Music]
After 2 hours,
filter out residue.
[Music]
Add water to make 3 L of solution.
Add three vitamin B1 tablets.
[Music]
Soak for 20 to 30 minutes.
Next, I recycled the plastic box to help
restore the orchid.
[Music]
Pour in some water.
Place the orchid branch in.
[Music]
Regularly change the water when dirty.
and keep the orchid pot in a cool place
away from direct sunlight.
[Music]
Two months later,
The orchid has recovered. Its leaves are
green and strong.
[Music]
Roots grow very healthily.
Um this way of planting you you will not
have to water the orchids as much as
with normal planting.
[Music]
Uh, I continue to grow orchids in new
pots using the semihydroponic method.
[Music]
Um, this way of planting you you will
not have to water the orchids as much as
with normal planting.
Hope you enjoy this video. If you find
it useful, don't forget to like and
subscribe to the channel so you don't
miss out on future shares on how to care
for orchids naturally and simply.
[Music]
Just persevere every day to take care of
orchids with all your love for nature.
Gradually, you will cultivate a garden
of colorful orchids, bringing joy and
peace to your living space.
[Music]
Every morning when you wake up, when the
scent of keta orchids blends with
felonopsis orchids gently spreading, you
will feel serenity and peace in your
soul.
Every morning when you wake up, when the
scent of keta orchids blends with
felonopsis orchids gently spreading, you
will feel serenity and peace in your
soul.