Hello everyone. Today I will continue
sharing how to care for
[Music]
orchids. After the orchid has finished
blooming, what should we do to help it
grow and bloom
[Music]
continuously? In this video, I will
guide you step by step to ensure your
orchids stay healthy and bloom
regularly. Let's get started.
[Music]
This is the orchid I bought at the
industrial orchid
garden. One month after I bought it, all
the flowers fell
[Music]
off. To care for it to continue
flowering, I first need to cut off the
old flower stems.
[Music]
Then I sprinkle coffee over the
cut. Coffee contains some compounds with
antibacterial and antifungal properties
helping to prevent infection at the cut.
[Music]
This is crucial because cuts on the
plant can provide an opportunity for
bacteria and fungi to
enter. Then cut off damaged roots.
[Music]
Uh, cutting off damaged roots helps the
orchid recover quickly, stops the spread
of disease, and saves energy for the
[Music]
plant. Then leave overnight for the cut
to dry completely.
[Music]
To make fertilizer to take care of this
orchid, I need potatoes.
[Music]
Take about 30 g of potatoes and cut them
into small pieces.
Potatoes contain nutrients like
potassium, phosphorus, and vitamin C,
which help promote the growth of
orchids.
Compounds in potatoes help improve the
development of the root system, allowing
orchids to absorb water and nutrients
more
[Music]
effectively. And then put the chopped
potatoes into the jar.
And to make this fertilizer, I need one
more aloe vera leaf.
[Music]
Aloe vera when used as fertilizer for
orchids provides vitamins, minerals, and
natural enzymes stimulating the growth
of roots and leaves.
Put in
[Music]
jar. Add one liter of water at room
temperature. Cover and leave
[Music]
overnight. After one night,
Stir well so that the nutrients dissolve
into the
water. Then filter out the residue.
Step
one, water your orchid with this liquid
fertilizer solution.
Aloe vera provides vitamins and natural
enzymes, while potatoes add minerals
like potassium and phosphorus, helping
the orchid grow
robustly. This combination helps
encourage the orchid to bloom regularly
and for a longer period, thanks to the
nutrients that support the blooming
process.
After watering, soak the orchid pot in
this water for about 20
[Music]
minutes. Step
two, you choose this water into a spray
bottle.
Aloe vera and potatoes provide vitamins,
minerals, and enzymes, helping the
orchid absorb nutrients quickly through
its leaves and
[Music]
stem. You spray the solution on the top
and bottom of the leaves.
When sprayed on the leaves, liquid
fertilizer helps orchids absorb
nutrients more easily and enhances the
development of the root system.
Step
[Music]
three, use soft cotton to wipe the
leaves to help keep them cleaner.
Um, wiping the leaves helps remove dust,
debris, and bacteria from the leaf
surface, allowing the orchid leaves to
breathe better and absorb light more
effectively.
Wiping the leaves helps enhance
photosynthesis because clean leaves
absorb light better and can convert
energy more
[Music]
efficiently. Wiping the leaves with
water helps reduce the risk of mold.
[Music]
um and bacterial diseases because a
clean leaf surface limits the
environment for harmful pathogens to
grow.
[Music]
Step
four, spray the entire orchid again with
this water to help wash away dirt and
mold.
[Music]
Step
five, water droplets on the leaves can
create a favorable environment for mold
and bacteria to
grow. Wiping off the water helps reduce
the risk of infection.
[Music]
Water droplets can block the stamata on
the leaves, reducing gas exchange and
affecting
[Music]
photosynthesis. Uh, wiping off the water
helps the stamata stay open and function
better.
[Music]
Keeping the leaves dry prevents the
orchid from staying wet for too long,
helping to avoid diseases related to
excessive moisture and enhancing its
resistance. After soaking for 20
minutes, take it out and place the
orchid pot in a place with plenty of
light. And do the above five steps every
10 to 15 days.
[Music]
results. After 3
weeks, you can see the orchid's roots
and leaves growing very quickly.
[Music]
Please.
Wow, the roots in the orchid pot are
growing so well.
New roots are a crucial factor in
helping orchids grow healthy and
sustainably throughout their life cycle.
[Music]
Now I plant it in a larger pot so the
orchid grows
healthier. As a growing medium, I use
crushed pine bark to help the roots stay
airy but still retain the necessary
moisture.
[Music]
Water the orchid to grow.
Take care of your orchids with all the
love and dedication you have for nature.
As every leaf and every flower bud is a
testament to the effort and heart you
put into it.
[Music]
Thank you for watching and supporting my
channel.