welcome to happiness Garden
channel in this video I share how to
grow it to grow
[Music]
fast when I just bought orchids we
remove all this
Moss uh because these Orchid pots are
grown in an industrial environment
controlled by temperature humidity and
it uh ideal for orchids
but when brought back the environment
has changed making these roots
susceptible to rot therefore you should
cut off damaged
Roots please comment to
me which country you are watching the
video from it's great that we can chat
together from all over the
world then wash the roots
[Music]
taking advantage of used plastic bottles
I recycled them into hydroponic Orchid
[Music]
pots this method of planting will not
require watering but will still help
orchids grow very healthily and produce
more beautiful and vibrant flowers
[Music]
recycling plastic bottles to make Orchid
pots is not only a great way to
repurpose used
materials uh but also helps protect the
environment this way we reduce plastic
waste while creating unique and
sustainable Orchid
[Music]
Pots if you haven't subscribed to the
channel yet please click the Subscribe
button to support me and not miss any
Orchid growing tips it's great to have
company I need to wash the plastic
bottle to make sure it's clean from
fungi and bacteria that are harmful to
the Orchid
[Music]
using the drill bit will'll cut out the
positions here
[Music]
this part will be used as an orchid
pot the rest is for water storage
[Music]
using a glass jar on the bottom will
help the roots not absorb too much water
[Music]
put the Orchid
in put terracotta seeds around the
pot grown in a semih hydroponic
environment often in contact with water
so we use breathable terracotta beads as
the best
[Music]
if it's breathable it's very rarely
rotten and after planting The Roots will
grow very
[Music]
fast so I've finished planting
you water the potted
plants we only water once next time you
don't need to water
[Music]
anymore with this simple planting method
you save a lot of time to take care
of with this planting method you will
let the water level cover part of the
bottom of the
[Music]
pot the water will absorb itself helping
to maintain the moisture in the growing
medium we will not need to water
[Music]
anymore when the water in the container
is empty remember to add more water to
keep the growing medium in a moist state
[Music]
and this is the Orchid I planted it
using this method you can see it grows
very
quickly the flowers are durable and have
many flower stems on the same
[Music]
branch and I also grow this Orchid using
the semi hydroponic method using pine
bark when it flowers it has vibrant
colors and stays fresh
[Music]
longer uh growing semih hydroponic
orchids the moisture is always
well-maintained the roots will grow very
quickly a strong root system will help
the plant perform metabolism and absorb
organic fertilizer and water very well
uh with this simple planting method we
will get orchids that grow
faster I hope this video provides useful
information to help you take great care
of your orchids at home if you found it
helpful don't forget to like share it so
more people can learn too and subscribe
to the channel to stay connected with me
thank you for watching wishing you a
wonderful day and see you in the next
videos
welcome to happiness Garden Channel um
happiness Garden Channel specializes in
Sharing tips for caring for orchids
using natural fertilizers promoting
sustainable growth abundant blooms and
Environmental Protection if you love
orchids as much as I do subscribe to my
channel to support me and never miss any
tips today I'm sharing how to make a
natural fertilizer from garlic that's
both simple and effective for your
orchids
[Music]
I just need a clove of
garlic garlic promotes harmonious growth
and Lush long- lasting flowering of
[Music]
orchids it repels most pests and kill
spores of fungi viruses and bacteria
[Music]
substances in garlic water strengthen
the immune system of
[Music]
orchids I pour crushed garlic with 1
liter of hot water
[Music]
and this is turmeric powder which rich
in vitamins and minerals pottassium
calcium magnesium sodium phosphorus iron
manganese copper selenium and zinc
increases plant resistance to fungi and
diseases while stimulating growth and
flowering
[Music]
uh incubate until the water cools so
that the nutrients from the garlic and
turmeric starch are completely dissolved
in the water
[Music]
after the water cools we filter it to
remove sediment
[Music]
fertilizer for orchids must be carefully
filtered so that organic fragments do
not rot in the
[Music]
substrate guys please write a comment
letting me know which country you're
watching my video from yeah of
fence it's great to know that we can
communicate worldwide
[Music]
on
uh to know if it's time to water orchids
I look at the color of the
[Music]
roots when the Orchid Roots have a light
silver color it's time to water the
Orchid
[Music]
if the roots are bright green you should
wait until the roots turn pale silver
before
[Music]
watering if you water when the roots are
still green The Roots will easily become
water logged and cause root rot
[Music]
My Maids are tired and
sleeping and the cat seems to be hunting
down the mice that are destroying my
orchids orchids grown in pots with
drainage
holes I water this one to two times a
[Music]
month so the roots in this water for
about 20 minutes to help the roots
absorb nutrients
[Music]
best um the finished infusion for
orchids helps strengthen the immune
system promotes the development of the
root system
this water is also very good when
sprayed on
Orchids spraying your Orchids with
garlic and turmeric water will protect
them from diseases pests and boost their
immune system
[Music]
spray the entire Orchid from leaves to
Roots but you should not water the
flowers because wet flowers will quickly
fall off
do it one to two times a
[Music]
month if you have a very humid climate
orchids are susceptible to Leaf base
rot to prevent orchids from rotting at
the base of the leaves you can use
cotton balls to protect them
[Music]
now spray the cotton with garlic and
turmeric
water and spray it on your orchids to
protect them from diseases pests and
boost the immune system
[Music]
leave the cotton there for 20 minutes
then remove it
[Music]
then you take the Clear Water above
if you don't have access to spraying
orchids you can wipe the leaves with a
cotton pad soaked in this
[Music]
water will help remove mineral salts
still attached to the leaf
[Music]
surface helps orchid leaves avoid
burning when exposed to
[Music]
sunlight uh this not only clears the
dust but also provides them with
nutrients and protects them from
diseases and
pests thoroughly wipe both the top and
bottom of the leaf
[Music]
do this one or two times a
month uh it is enough to keep the Orchid
in this water for 20 minutes
soaked in this water The Roots will
change from Silver to purple blue like
this
[Music]
then place the Orchid pot in a warm
place with lots of diffused light so the
Orchid will grow quickly
[Music]
after 20 minutes remove the cotton ball
and place the Orchid pot in a warm place
with lots of diffused
[Music]
light
result um the leaves are always green
and shiny like this
[Music]
the roots are green large and
[Applause]
healthy thanks to the clean Leaf surface
orchid leaves photosynthesize
better when orchids have enough light
for photosynthesis they will always be
healthier than
[Music]
usual thanks to this care the Orchid
produces many
[Music]
flowers vibrant flower colors
orchids bloom all year round flowering
very long and
[Music]
boldly hope you like this video
thank you for viewing good luck and
success in life
[Music]