Hello everyone. It's wonderful to see
you again in a new video on the
Happiness Garden channel where we share
our love for nature together.
Orchids are famous for their lasting
beauty. Their blooms can open and stay
on the stem for a long time and with
proper care, the plant will continue to
gift you with one blooming season after
another.
That's why so many people on this planet
grow orchids.
[Music]
However, many beginners still struggle
to get their Phelinopsis orchids to
bloom abundantly. If you're still trying
to figure it out, watch this video to
the end. A wonderful secret is waiting
for you to discover.
[Music]
If you haven't subscribed to the channel
yet, please hit the subscribe button to
support me and never miss any orchid
growing tips. It's truly wonderful to
have you with me.
Let's get started.
First of all, the placement of the
orchid pot plays a very important role.
A spot with gentle light and good air
circulation will help the plant absorb
nutrients better and grow healthily.
Orchids need light for photosynthesis,
but they can't tolerate harsh direct
sunlight.
The ideal spot is on a window sill with
a sheer curtain or under a light shade
structure made especially for orchids.
Next, I'll share with you a simple yet
highly effective way to make organic
fertilizer for orchids.
With just a few familiar ingredients,
you'll help your plant grow strong roots
and bloom more beautifully.
All you need is 3 tablespoons of cooked
rice, a familiar ingredient that's
packed with nutrients for your plant.
[Music]
Then grind the rice into a fine powder.
Next, put the rice powder into a clean
jar. are.
[Music]
Next, I need to prepare a fresh aloe
vera leaf, an ingredient that helps
boost the plant's resistance.
Then, slice the aloe vera leaf into thin
pieces.
[Music]
Put the aloe vera slices into the jar
with the rice powder you prepared
earlier.
[Music]
Next, pour one liter of boiling water
into the jar to dissolve the nutrients
from the rice and aloe vera.
[Music]
Wrap a cloth around the jar to retain
heat. Then let it sit until the water
cools completely.
[Music]
Once the water is cooled, strain out the
residue and keep the clear,
nutrient-rich liquid.
In addition to the English voiceover, we
have now created versions in French,
German, Italian, Portuguese, Japanese,
Hindi, Dutch, Polish, Korean, and
Indonesian to help you listen and
understand the content more easily. To
hear your preferred language, open the
video and click on settings, the gear
icon, to select the appropriate audio
language.
[Music]
Then add clean water to the filtered
liquid until you have about 3 L of
fertilizer solution.
Leave me a comment and let me know which
country you're watching from. It's
wonderful that we can connect and chat
uh from all around the world.
Method one, pour the solution into a
spray bottle and mist it directly onto
the orchid's leaves and roots.
Spray the solution evenly on both the
top and underside of the leaves as well
as the roots to help the plant absorb it
most effectively.
About 30 minutes after spraying, if
there's still water on the leaves,
gently blot the excess with a soft cloth
from the surface and between the leaves.
This helps prevent leaf rot and keeps
the plant healthy.
[Music]
Just apply this method once every two
weeks and you'll see your orchids stay
lush. and full of life like this.
[Music]
Method two, you use the solution to
water directly onto the roots and
growing medium, helping to deliver
nutrients from below.
Um, this method allows the roots to
naturally absorb nutrients, stimulating
the plant to grow vigorously from the
base to the top.
Rice water is rich in vitamins and
minerals that nourish healthy roots,
while aloe vera has antibacterial
properties and boosts the plant's
resistance.
Combining both helps orchids thrive
overall, encouraging fast root growth,
lush green leaves, and long-lasting
blooms.
[Music]
You can choose method one, method two,
or combine both for the best results.
Just apply it regularly twice a month,
and your orchid will stay healthy and
bloom beautifully.
And don't forget to place your orchid
pot in a spot with gentle sunlight so
the plant can photosynthesize and absorb
nutrients more effectively.
[Music]
Uh and here is the result after 1 month
of care. You can see the plant has grown
many new roots full of vitality.
[Music]
Uh, a healthy root system helps the
plant absorb water and nutrients more
efficiently, leading to vigorous growth
and long-lasting blooms.
That's why roots are often compared to
the heart of an orchid because if the
roots are healthy, the plant will
thrive, grow strong, and bloom
beautifully.
[Music]
A healthy root system not only keeps the
plant stable, but is also the key to
beautiful and long-lasting orchid
blooms.
Um, what do you think about the way I
take care of these little orchids?
Don't hesitate to leave a comment and
share your thoughts. I'd love to hear
your feedback and experiences.
[Music]
The orchids in my garden cared for with
natural fertilizer always bloom
vibrantly, full of life, and last a long
time.
[Music]
Natural fertilizers usually work more
slowly than synthetic ones, but once the
plant absorbs them, the growth will be
sustainable and strong from the roots
all the way to the blooms.
That's why the blooms can stay on the
stem for a very long time. Some flowers
even last up to 6 months before they
start to fade.
[Music]
If you face any difficulties while
growing orchids, don't hesitate to leave
a comment. I'm always here to help you
grow healthy orchids that bloom
abundantly.
I hope you enjoy this video. If you find
it helpful, don't forget to like and
subscribe to the channel so you won't
miss future tips on caring for orchids
naturally and simply.
Thank you for watching until the end of
the video. Wishing you joy, good health,
and lots of beautiful blooming orchids.
See you in the next video.
Welcome to my channel.
If you want your orchid to bloom
abundantly all year round, this is the
video I made just for you.
So, if you haven't subscribed to the
channel yet, make sure to do so to
support me and not miss any great tips
on Tips 365.
It would be wonderful to have you
accompany me.
[Music]
When the orchid has finished blooming or
the plant is stunted, slow to grow and
has not yet bloomed.
[Music]
Cut all dry branches, roots, and leaves.
This helps orchids focus their energy on
healthy growth.
Removing dead parts helps prevent
disease, improves air circulation, and
encourages the growth of new roots and
leaves, resulting in stronger and more
vibrant blooms.
[Music]
Then take three teaspoons.
Add four cups of boiled water. About one
liter of water.
Then brew until the water cools.
[Music]
After the water cools, filter to remove
sediment.
residue.
[Music]
Please comment to me which country you
are watching the video from. It's great
that we can chat together from all over
the world.
[Music]
In addition to the English dub, we've
now created dubs in French, German,
Italian, Spanish, Portuguese, Japanese,
Hindi, and Indonesian to help you hear
and understand the content more easily.
Then add one US gallon of water, about
3.8 L, to the mixture.
[Music]
First, use this water to thoroughly wipe
the top and bottom of the leaves.
[Music]
This clears dirt and removes fungus,
disease, and insects that damage the
leaves.
[Music]
Apply this method once a month.
Helps
[Music]
leaves stay green, strong, and resistant
to pests.
[Music]
Then you use this water to water the
orchid roots.
This helps roots grow healthily and
prevents root rot.
[Music]
Uh coffee contains many minerals
necessary for the growth of orchids.
[Music]
organic phosphorus and potassium found
in coffee help roots and flowers develop
outstandingly.
[Music]
Do this twice a month for your orchids
so they grow and bloom profusely.
[Music]
[Applause]
Or you can also use this water to spray
the entire orchid.
[Music]
Thoroughly spray the top and bottom of
the leaves to remove dirt and insects
from the leaf surface.
[Music]
Do this every two weeks.
Coffee water helps repel orchid pests
very effectively.
[Music]
after spraying and soaking in this water
for about 5 minutes. The insects will
run away from the orchid pot.
[Music]
Uh if you encounter any difficulties
during the orchid growing process, don't
hesitate to comment. I am always ready
to support you so you can grow healthy
orchids and bloom lots of flowers.
[Music]
Then take the orchid pot out and place
it in a cool place with enough light for
the orchid to grow.
Two months later,
[Music]
uh, orchids will begin to sprout and
bloom profusely.
[Music]
Blooming flowers have bright colors.
Shoe petals will stay fresh longer.
[Music]
The flowers bloom for up to 6 months
before fading.
Hopefully the video will help you a lot
in taking better care of orchids at
home.
[Music]
If you find it useful, don't forget to
subscribe to the channel so you don't
miss any orchid growing tips.
Uh, thank you for watching the video.
Good luck and see you in the next
videos.
[Music]