Hello
friends. Today I will guide you when to
water
orchids. When orchid roots are green
like this, the orchid has enough water.
The leaves will be green and sturdy.
[Music]
But if the roots turn white, the plant
is lacking
water. Check the potting medium. You
will find it very
dry. Leaves will wilt very quickly if we
don't water them in
time. In this case, we need to quickly
water the
orchid. How to water as following.
Place the orchid pot in a deep dish and
water the substrate completely.
[Music]
If the roots are still fresh, but the
leaves are wilted, we can soak the
orchid in water for 20 to 30
[Music]
minutes. Uh, with pots using moss
growing medium, the ability to retain
moisture is very good. So, we only need
to water enough
moisture and no need to
[Music]
soak. When you eat a banana, don't throw
away the
peel. Banana peel contains a lot of
vitamins and minerals. Vitamins's A, B,
C, E, and protein, phosphorus.
Especially rich in potassium. Potassium
resists drought very well. Helps the
orchid to transport water from the root
to the top so the orchid does not
wilt. At the same time, potassium helps
to stimulate flower growth and keep
flowers fresh for a long time.
[Music]
We cut the banana peel as small as
possible. Put the entire banana peel in
a jar. Pour 500 milllers of boiled
water, about two cups, and let it sit
for one day to let the nutrients
dissolve into the water.
[Music]
Take five vitamin B1 tablets and mix
with two cups of water 500
ml. B1 helps plants to better absorb
nutrients and growth regulator. It also
stimulates root growth very well.
[Music]
After one day of incubation, we mix
banana juice with vitamin B1 water to
get one liter of synthetic organic
fertilizer
[Music]
solution.
Divide into a spray
[Music]
bottle. Spray the top and bottom of the
leaves evenly.
[Music]
Orchid plants are provided with a part
of nutrients that are supplemented
through the leaves and at the same time
it also eliminates insects to help the
orchid stay green.
You can also use a cotton ball soaked in
this synthetic organic fertilizer
solution to wipe the
leaves. Do this one to two times a
month. The orchid will always be
protected and green.
[Music]
Next, water your orchid with this
mixture. Do one to two times a month and
combine with other organic fertilizers
that I have shared on the channel. It
will help orchids easily absorb
nutrients.
Vitamin B1 helps stimulate root growth.
Potassium in banana juice will stimulate
flower growth and help flowers stay
fresh for a long
time. It is truly the perfect formula
for the full development of roots,
leaves, and
flowers. It's very good, but you should
not overdo it. It will harm the orchid.
Uh, you should only fertilize according
to my instructions so that your orchid
garden always blooms without affecting
the growth of
orchids. Please comment below about your
[Music]
results. Please comment in the video so
that I can help you further if your land
has problems.
[Music]
In addition to the English dub, we've
now created dubs in French, German,
Italian, Spanish, Portuguese, Japanese,
Hindi, and Indonesian to help you hear
and understand the content. Videos are
[Music]
easier. If you find it interesting,
don't forget to like, share, and
subscribe to support me.
[Music]
Don't rush to leave this video and
continue watching part tootses to
support
me. Hello
[Music]
friends. Uh when you plant a lot of
orchids, you will not be able to avoid
rotten orchids.
You see, my orchid has been infected
with a
[Music]
fungus. If not treated promptly, the
orchid may die.
[Music]
Even though it's rotten, it's still
fresh when cut
[Music]
across. It is also a favorable condition
for the spread to respawn faster.
[Music]
We need to cut off the branches and
remove all the
rot. We need to cut off the branches and
[Music]
rot. Then rinse with water.
Take one cup of room temperature water
about 300
[Music]
ml. Mix one tablespoon of unsweetened
fresh milk into the water.
[Music]
Add one vitamin B1 tablet.
Add one vitamin B1
[Music]
tablet. Then wipe the top and bottom of
the
[Music]
leaves. This water mixture has a
disinfecting effect.
helps get rid of fungal
[Music]
diseases. Then use this mixture of
water, B1, and milk to soak the orchid
root for 20 minutes.
[Music]
The rest is used to spray other normal
orchids. Helps get rid of fungal
diseases and supplement necessary
nutrients for orchids.
[Music]
After soaking for 20 minutes, take out
the branches and dry the cut.
[Music]
You're there.
Use toothpaste. Applying it on a cut
will help it heal faster and protect
orchids from rot.
[Music]
While waiting for it to dry, I recycle
old plastic containers to make tools to
revive orchids.
[Music]
Uh, use industrial cotton to put it in
the pot.
[Music]
Then let the orchid
in. Next, every 3 days, spray
moisturizing mist with normal
[Music]
water. Then, put the orchid pot in a
cool place.
[Music]
The most suitable temperature for
reviving orchids is from 20 to 30°
C. 1 month
[Music]
later, the orchid has rooted very well.
Like
[Music]
and grow one more young
leaf. B1 stimulates rooting very
well. Milk contains natural calcium to
help orchids stay strong and increase
resistance.
[Music]
Now I grow orchids in pots with moss so
that it adapts to the outside
environment.
[Music]
If you find it interesting, please like,
share and subscribe to support my
channel. Wish you all success and
happiness in
life. See you in the next videos.
[Music]
Welcome to my channel.
I am an orchid care
specialist. Do you have vitamin
[Music]
B1? Subscribe to the channel and watch
till the end to see the magic.
[Music]
Five tablets of vitamin
B1. Mix in four cups of room temperature
water, about one liter.
[Music]
keep in a cool place away from direct
sunlight for 1 hour.
[Music]
Then I took five
eggshells. Eggshells contain many
nutrients needed by plants including
calcium, potassium, and trace elements
such as iron, magnesium, manganese,
copper, and zinc.
[Music]
Therefore, eggshells will help provide
necessary nutrients for
orchids. Dry on low heat for 5
minutes. This helps to eliminate fungal
diseases before using as fertilizer.
[Music]
When using eggshells as fertilizer, it
also helps to increase the pH of the
soil, helping orchids grow better.
[Music]
In addition, I also use 100 g of organic
fertilizer from livestock waste pressed
into dry pellets.
[Music]
Then mix the two types together.
With the orchids that have bloomed all
the last
[Music]
flowers, I apply about 1 oz, about 30 g
per
[Music]
pot. Orchid after full bloom is very
exhausted, so I need to apply this
fertilizer to quickly recover.
[Music]
Pay attention to fertilizing far from
the
[Music]
root with orchids in full
bloom. This fertilizer also helps
flowers bloom for a long
time. If you apply this fertilizer every
2 months, it is guaranteed that the
orchid will bloom for 6 months without
[Music]
wilting. With orchids with buds, I also
apply this fertilizer to help flower
buds grow faster.
[Music]
1 hour
after. Decant the clear water
[Music]
above. Use this absorbent
cotton. Clean the top and bottom of the
leaves.
helps eliminate fungal diseases and
prevent parasitic insects on
leaves. At the same time, it supports
the supply of nutrients through orchid
leaves. Orchids are always green and
growing.
[Music]
Sprinkle the remaining water into the
orchid growing
[Music]
medium. Vitamin B1 helps strengthen the
root system and promote plant health
while improving the soil's ability to
absorb nutrients.
Vitamin B1 has the effect of protecting
plants from external agents such as
drought, sunburn, and cold, and enhances
resistance to plant
[Music]
diseases. You should fertilize B1 for
orchids once a month in the cool
afternoon.
[Music]
results. After one
week, you can see that after 15 days,
the flowers are still very fresh and
more fragrant than
usual, and flowers can bloom again and
again all year round in the garden.
[Music]
This helps me to always enjoy the
blooming flowers and the gentle
fragrance from the
garden. And you can see that after just
a week of using, the orchid has grown a
lot of new roots.
[Music]
So we can use these organic fertilizers
to take care of orchids very
[Music]
well. However, keep in mind that an
overdose can also harm plants.
Therefore, it is advisable to adhere to
the dosage that I have
instructed. Hopefully, the video will be
of great help to you in effectively
taking care of orchids at
home. If you find the content
interesting and meaningful, don't forget
to like and share so that more people
know and subscribe to support the
channel. Thank you for always
accompanying me.
Thank you for watching the video. I
always pray for God's blessings to all
of you.