Welcome to the happiness garden. Today I
will continue to share with you a new
natural fertilizer method that is simple
but effective. I hope this recipe will
give you more options to take care of
your orchid pots so they stay healthy
and always bloom beautifully at home.
When you have a small orchid from a
nursery pot or are about to repot a
mature orchid, the first step is to
check the growing medium. If the medium
is too old, decomposed, or retains
moisture poorly, you should remove it
completely. But if the medium is still
good, we just need to treat it for
reuse. For this young orchid, the medium
is still in good condition. So, I will
treat and keep the old medium.
[Music]
Um to treat the old growing medium,
prepare about one liter of clean water
to mix a natural disinfectant solution.
[Music]
Next, add 1 teasp of baking soda into
the prepared 1 L of water. Baking soda
is a natural disinfectant that gently
sterilizes the growing medium while
remaining safe for the roots. Stir well
until the baking soda is completely
dissolved in the water.
[Music]
If you haven't subscribed to the channel
yet, please click the subscribe button
to support me and not miss any orchid
growing tips. It's wonderful to have you
along.
[Music]
After preparing the baking soda
solution, gently dip the orchid's leaves
into it. For a small orchid, dipping for
about 10 to 20 seconds is enough. For a
mature orchid, you can soak the leaves
for a few minutes to increase the
disinfecting and diseasereventing
effect.
[Music]
After treating the leaves, continue
soaking the orchid roots and growing
medium in the prepared baking soda
solution.
Soaking for about 20 minutes will help
eliminate remaining bacteria, mold, and
insects while creating a safe condition
for the plant to grow after repotting.
After treating the old growing medium
and orchid roots, we also need to treat
the new growing medium before placing
the plant in the pot. This step is very
important to eliminate potential fungal
diseases in the new medium and help the
orchid adapt better to the new growing
environment.
[Music]
The new growing medium needs to be
soaked in the baking soda solution for
about 20 minutes before use.
[Music]
After soaking the growing medium for 20
minutes, take it out and place it in a
well ventilated area to drain. The
surface of the medium should be dry, but
it should still retain internal moisture
to help prevent the orchid from going
into shock when planted in the new pot.
[Music]
While waiting for the growing medium to
drain, uh, gently take the orchid out to
prepare for repotting into the new pot.
When planting orchids, you should choose
a pot with drainage holes at the bottom.
This is very important to prevent water
logging, keeping the orchid roots well
airrated and healthy.
First, place a few pieces of foam at the
bottom of the pot to improve drainage
and prevent the growing medium from
becoming compacted. Then, add a thin
layer of the medium on top to prepare
for placing the orchid in.
[Music]
Next, gently place the orchid in the
center of the pot.
Then, fill the growing medium around the
roots, pressing just enough to keep the
plant stable while still allowing the
roots enough space to breathe and grow.
[Music]
After filling in the growing medium,
gently tap the sides of the pot to help
the medium settle into the gaps around
the roots. This helps the plant stay
firm and stable in the pot, creating
good conditions for even root
development.
[Music]
Finally, you can spread a bit of dried
moss on the surface of the growing
medium. This moss layer helps lightly
retain moisture on the pot's surface and
creates a stable environment for the
plant to recover after repotting.
[Music]
After repotting, place the orchid pot in
a cool, wellventilated area away from
sunlight for a few hours to let the
plants stabilize before applying natural
fertilizer.
[Music]
To make today's natural fertilizer, I
continue using rice, but in a completely
different way. I hope this method will
give you another new option for taking
care of orchids at home.
[Music]
Put the rice in a pan and toast it over
low heat. Stir evenly until the rice
turns golden and releases a light aroma.
This is an important step to activate
the the nutrients in the rice, making
them easier for the plant to absorb.
Toasted rice differs from regular rice
in that after toasting, the nutrients in
the rice are activated and more easily
dissolved when mixed with water. As a
result, the orchid can absorb nutrients
better, especially during the recovery
and root development stage.
After toasting, transfer the rice to a
plate and let it cool completely.
Letting it cool helps preserve the rice
better so you can use it multiple times
while maintaining its quality and
distinctive aroma.
Put one spoonful of toasted rice into a
clean bottle. Then pour in about 1 L of
boiling water. The high temperature will
help extract the nutrients from the
toasted rice, creating a natural
fertilizer solution rich in energy for
the orchid.
[Music]
After pouring in the boiling water,
close the lid and let it sit until the
solution cools completely. Keeping the
lid on helps retain the full nutrients
and natural aroma of the toasted rice
during the soaking process.
[Music]
Once the solution has cooled, stir it
well and then strain out the residue.
Straining helps make the solution
clearer and cleaner, preventing clogging
during watering and allowing the plant
to absorb nutrients more effectively.
[Music]
Um, in addition to the English
voiceover, we've now created versions in
French, German, Italian, Spanish,
Portuguese, Japanese, Hindi, Dutch,
Polish, Korean, and Indonesian to help
you listen and understand the content
more easily.
To listen in your preferred language,
open the video and click on settings,
the gear icon, to select the appropriate
audio language.
[Music]
Leave me a comment letting me know which
country you're watching from. It's
wonderful that we can connect and chat
with each other from all around the
world.
Then use this mixture to water the
orchid directly. The solution made from
toasted rice will gently provide energy
and help the roots absorb nutrients
naturally and safely.
You only need to use this mixture twice
a month. Regular use will help your
orchid grow strong with firm roots,
green leaves, and readiness for the next
blooming cycles.
You can also soak the orchid pot in this
mixture for about 20 minutes. This
method allows the roots to absorb
nutrients more deeply while also
soothing the plant after repotting or
during its recovery period.
The leftover solution can be poured into
a spray bottle for easy use on your
orchid.
[Music]
Then lightly spray it on the leaves and
roots of other orchids in the garden to
help them absorb nutrients better while
also maintaining moisture and boosting
their natural resistance.
Spraying the toasted rice mixture will
provide a gentle amount of nutrients to
the orchid. As a result, the leaves
become greener, the roots grow stronger,
and the plant recovers more easily after
periods of stress.
In addition, the thin mist from the
solution helps retain moisture on the
surface of the leaves. This is
especially useful during dry weather or
when growing orchids in low humidity
environments.
[Music]
You only need to spray this mixture tur
twice a month. Regular use provides just
the right amount of nutrients, avoiding
excess while maintaining steady vitality
and natural beauty.
[Music]
Uh after soaking the orchid pot for 20
minutes, gently take the plant out and
place it in a spot with soft sunlight.
The gentle light helps the plant dry
naturally while also supporting
photosynthesis and recovery after
feeding.
And here's the result after 2 weeks. You
can see that the once small and weak
orchid has now clearly recovered and is
growing day by day. With a little
patience and a little love, your orchid
will always respond with fresh, vibrant
life.
[Music]
The roots have also become slightly
stronger, whiter, and are beginning to
cling to the new growing medium. This is
a positive sign that the plant is
gradually adapting and thriving in its
new environment.
[Music]
I will continue fertilizing this young
orchid twice a month regularly and
gently. Such consistent care will help
the plant absorb nutrients better and
grow steadily from roots to leaves. With
just a bit of patience and love for the
plant, you'll soon see the difference.
[Music]
Applying this mixture helps stimulate
strong root growth and enhances nutrient
absorption. When the root system is
healthy, the orchid will quickly
stabilize in the new growing medium and
begin to form new leaf shoots. This is a
vital foundation for the plant to
continue growing and prepare for the
next blooming cycles.
[Music]
After soaking for about 20 minutes, take
the orchid pot out and place it in a
spot with gentle indirect sunlight. At
this stage, the plant is absorbing
nutrients, so it needs a calm
environment with enough light to recover
and develop new roots.
And here is the result after the next 3
months. You can see the orchid has
clearly matured.
[Music]
From a tiny seedling, it has now
developed a strong root system, lush
green leaves, and is full of vitality.
Every stage of care has contributed to
this impressive transformation.
[Music]
And the special thing is that you can
see the orchid has produced two new
flower spikes, strong and full of
energy. This is a sign that the plant
has not only recovered well, but is also
ready to enter a new blooming cycle. A
welldeserved result for the the patience
and consistent care over the past
months.
[Music]
I continue fertilizing the orchid with
toasted rice regularly every 2 weeks.
This cyclical way of adding natural
nutrients helps the plant stay healthy,
grow steadily, and get ready for the
next blooming season. A simple yet
effective method that you can easily
apply at home.
[Music]
Please leave me a comment letting me
know which country you are watching the
video from. It's wonderful that we can
chat together from all around the world.
[Music]
After moistening the growing medium,
soak the entire orchid pot in this
mixture for about 20 minutes.
[Music]
Then place the orchid pot in a spot with
gentle light and good air flow. Soft
sunlight at this stage is very important
as it helps stimulate bud formation and
prepares the plant to bloom. A well-lit
environment will allow the orchid to
thrive at its best.
[Music]
And here is the result after the next
one month. You can see the two flower
spikes have started to bloom
beautifully, vibrant and full of life.
>> Each flower is proof of the persistent
and proper care. A well-deserved reward
for the love you have given to the
orchid.
[Music]
Thanks to this fertilizer, the petals
become softer and have more vibrant
colors than usual.
The natural nutrients deeply penetrate,
helping the orchid flowers maintain
freshness for a long time, highlighting
the plant's natural beauty and strong
vitality.
Uh, what do you think about how I care
for this young orchid? Don't hesitate to
leave a comment and share your thoughts.
I'm really looking forward to hearing
your feedback and experiences.
[Music]
If you encounter any difficulties during
the orchid growing process, don't
hesitate to comment for me. I'm always
ready to support you so you can grow
healthy orchids that bloom abundantly.
[Music]
I hope you will enjoy this video. If you
find it helpful, don't forget to hit
like and subscribe to the channel so you
won't miss the upcoming shares on how to
care for orchids naturally and simply.
[Music]
Welcome to the happiness garden, where
every plant tells a story of care,
patience, and joy blossoming every day.
Each orchid is a masterpiece with
vibrant colors and long- lasting blooms.
These wonderful qualities make orchids
always capture the hearts of flower
lovers around the world.
Uh, in this video I will share with you
many easy tips for caring for orchids at
home so you can enjoy vibrant blooms all
year round.
Let's get started.
To make this magical fertilizer, first
prepare 3 L of clean water in a clean
container, ready for the next steps.
Please comment and let me know which
country you are watching the video from.
It's wonderful that we can connect and
chat together from all around the world.
[Music]
Next, you can use expired milk or
leftover milk from the fridge. A great
way to avoid waste and help your orchids
grow.
Just about 1 tsp of milk, equivalent to
around 15 ml, is enough for this recipe.
Next, simply stir the milk into the
water until the mixture is fully
blended.
Next, we will add a little lemon juice
to the mixture.
You can choose either a yellow lemon or
a green lime. Both provide excellent
results.
[Music]
You only need 1/3 tablespoon of lemon
juice for the mixture to be perfectly
balanced.
[Music]
Next, stir the mixture well so all the
ingredients are fully blended.
[Music]
If you haven't subscribed to the channel
yet, please hit the subscribe button to
support me and not miss any orchid
growing tips. It's wonderful to have you
along for the journey.
The first method is to use a soft cloth
to soak up the mixture and gently wipe
both the top and underside of the leaves
so the plant can absorb the nutrients
best.
[Music]
By wiping the leaves, the orchid will
stay clean, photosynthesize more easily,
and have better air circulation, helping
the plant grow healthier.
Thanks to their antibacterial and
disinfectant properties, milk and lemon
will help you effectively eliminate
fungi and harmful insects from your
orchids.
[Music]
Moreover, wiping the leaves with the
milk and lemon mixture also helps the
orchid leaves become naturally shiny,
looking fresher and healthier.
[Music]
Uh, in the long run, caring for the
leaves with the milk and lemon mixture
helps orchids grow stronger with
healthier roots, thicker and greener
leaves, while also increasing their
ability to bloom regularly and for
longer.
[Music]
Looking at the orchids after wiping
their leaves with the milk and lemon
mixture, you will see sturdy, glossy
leaves full of vitality. A clear proof
of the effectiveness of this method.
[Music]
The second method is to put the mixture
into a spray bottle and evenly spray it
onto the leaves, stems, and roots of the
orchid.
[Music]
Spray the mixture evenly on both the top
and underside of the leaves so the plant
can absorb the nutrients optimally.
This spraying method also helps clean
dust and remove insects on the leaves,
especially on the underside where pests
often hide.
Additionally, spraying the mixture on
the leaves helps the orchid leaves
become naturally shiny, improves
photosynthesis, and enhances the overall
health of the plant.
Uh, if you maintain regular leaf
spraying, the orchids will always stay
clean with fewer pests and fungi,
allowing them to grow healthily and
bloom more consistently.
[Music]
By caring for the leaves properly, the
orchids will be healthy from roots to
leaves, ready for vibrant blooms in the
coming seasons.
You should spray or wipe the leaves
regularly about twice a month to keep
the orchids healthy and growing well.
[Music]
The third method is to water the mixture
onto the roots and growing medium,
helping the plant uh absorb nutrients
from root to tip.
When watering the diluted milk and lemon
mixture onto the roots and growing
medium, the orchid not only receives
nutrients directly, but is also
protected from fungi and harmful
insects. Milk and lemon provide
antibacterial and disinfectant effects
right at the base while keeping the
roots healthy for overall plant growth.
Um, when watering, make sure the milk
and lemon mixture spreads evenly over
the roots and growing medium. This
method both provides nutrients and
protects the roots from pests, helping
the orchids grow healthy and bloom
better.
[Music]
With the method of watering the roots
using the diluted milk and lemon
mixture, you not only provide nutrients,
but also keep the roots and growing
medium clean, preventing fungi and
harmful insects. By doing this
regularly, your orchids will grow
comprehensively, healthy from root to
tip, and ready to bloom vibrantly all
year round.
And here are the results after applying
the natural fertilizer care method. New
roots are growing evenly. Old roots are
strong, showing that the orchid is
developing vigorously.
You can also see the shoots of the new
orchid seedlings beginning to grow,
proving the strong vitality of the
mother plant.
Um, the new roots of the orchid look
very healthy, growing evenly and
strongly, preparing for the plant's
overall development.
Roots are often called the heart of the
plant because they determine the health,
growth, and survival of the orchid.
[Music]
When the roots are healthy, the orchid
absorbs nutrients better. The leaves
stay green, the flowers bloom
beautifully, and the plant grows
stronger day by day.
[Music]
Because roots are as important as the
heart of the plant, watering or spraying
the milk and lemon mixture helps the
roots stay healthy, allowing the orchid
to grow well and bloom more
consistently.
[Music]
Thanks to using this natural fertilizer,
your orchid will grow more flower
spikes. On the same plant, you can see
up to four new flower spikes emerging.
[Music]
The evenly growing new flower spikes
show that the orchid is strong from root
to tip with enough energy to produce
many blooms at once, making the entire
plant full of vitality and color
[Music]
with evenly growing spikes and plump
buds. You will enjoy vibrant, fresh, and
long-lasting blooms. a wonderful reward
for your patience and dedicated care.
Uh, not only are there many flower
spikes, but each bloom also opens
vibrantly with bright colors and
long-lasting beauty, bringing joy to
anyone who sees them.
The newly opened flowers are all healthy
and vibrant, making the orchid look
lively and full of energy.
These fresh and vibrant flowers are not
only beautiful but also inspiring,
proving that patience and proper care
bring excellent results. Give love to
your plants and they will respond with
radiant beauty.
Each fresh and vibrant flower is a
reward for your efforts in in caring for
the plant, reminding us that love and
patience are always rewarded with
natural beauty.
We've reached the end of today's video.
I hope you enjoyed and found the tips on
caring for orchids helpful.
[Music]
If you found this video meaningful,
don't forget to like, share, and leave a
comment so we can care for orchids
better together.
Thank you for watching. Goodbye, and may
you always be happy and joyful with your
beautiful orchids.
[Music]