Hi everyone. To give you more options
for taking care of your orchids at home,
today I'll be sharing a new way to make
a natural fertilizer. It's simple and
[Music]
effective. Let's dive
in. Weak orchids have been thrown away
by people.
[Music]
This orchid has completely rotted so it
cannot be
[Music]
restored. This orchid, although its
leaves are wilted, is still fresh and
can be revived.
[Music]
Then cut off all the damaged roots.
Damaged, rotting, or moldy roots can be
a breeding ground for bacteria and
fungi, which can harm the entire plant.
Cutting them off helps prevent the
spread of disease.
[Music]
When you cut off the damaged roots, the
plant won't waste energy on
nonfunctioning roots, allowing it to
focus on growing strong new
[Music]
roots. Then cut off all the old flower
spikes.
When you cut off the old flower spikes,
the plant will focus its energy on
growing new flower spikes, helping it to
bloom continuously and more beautifully
in the following seasons.
[Music]
Then wash the plant with water to remove
dirt, bacteria, mold, and other
impurities from the leaves and stem,
reducing the risk of the plant getting
infected.
Washing the plant also helps improve air
circulation for the leaves and stem,
allowing the plant to exchange gases
more easily and perform photosynthesis
more effectively.
Then place the wilted orchid in a
container and soak it in water for about
1 hour. This helps the plant absorb
moisture into the roots and leaves,
especially when the plant is dry or
lacking water. This helps the plant
recover quickly and reduce wilting.
[Music]
Take one teaspoon of cinnamon
powder. Add one liter of boiling
water. Cinnamon powder has strong
antibacterial and antifungal properties,
helping to prevent the growth of
bacteria and mold, which are common
threats to orchids.
[Music]
Cinnamon powder also stimulates the
growth of new roots by improving
metabolism and enhancing the plant's
ability to absorb
nutrients. Cover the container and wait
for the water to
cool. Next, take 3 tesps of breadcrumbs.
[Music]
Add 50 ml of beer.
and mix it into one liter of warm
water. Stir well.
[Music]
Cover the container and wait for the
water to
[Music]
cool. After 1 hour, the water has
cooled.
Stir well to ensure the nutrients are
completely dissolved in the
water. Strain to collect the cinnamon
water.
Step one, use a soft cotton pad to
gently wipe the top and bottom of the
orchid leaves with cinnamon water.
Cinnamon water has strong antibacterial
and antifungal properties, helping to
remove bacteria, mold, or impurities
that could harm the
plant. Wiping the orchid leaves with
cinnamon water helps clean off potential
pathogens on the leaves, protecting the
plant from bacterial and fungal attacks.
Now place the roots of the orchid into
the cup like this.
[Music]
Mix the breadcrumb soaking solution with
the cinnamon water solution.
[Music]
Step two, soak the orchid roots in this
solution for 20 minutes.
[Music]
Uh this mixture can help improve the
absorption of water and nutrients by the
orchid roots while also stimulating the
growth of new roots. The orchid roots
will have a better chance to grow
stronger and more easily absorb
nutrients from the surrounding
environment.
[Music]
After soaking for 20 minutes, we proceed
to plant the orchid in a new pot with a
growing medium of sterilized and dried
spagnum moss.
[Music]
Spagnum moss has excellent moisture
retaining properties helping to maintain
the necessary humidity for the orchid
especially when the plant is wilted or
weak. Orchids need stable humidity to
recover and grow and the moss will
provide continuous moisture to the roots
without causing water logging.
[Music]
Uh from now on we will water this orchid
with the cinnamon water and breadcrumb
water mixture once a week.
[Music]
Then place the orchid pot in a spot with
gentle sunlight. light to allow the
plant to photosynthesize and carry out
its metabolic processes
effectively. We use the remaining liquid
fertilizer solution to water the other
[Music]
orchids. Both cinnamon water and
breadcrumbs contain natural components
that help stimulate blooming. Cinnamon
water contains antifungal and
antibacterial properties which keep the
plant healthy while breadcrumbs provide
essential nutrients to promote the
plant's growth, especially during the
flowering preparation stage.
Breadcrumbs contain starch and sugar,
which are rich energy sources for the
plant. These nutrients help stimulate
the growth of new roots, supporting the
orchid in quickly recovering and
developing a strong root system.
After watering with this liquid
fertilizer, soak the orchid 20 minutes.
Then remove the pot.
[Music]
results after 1
month. As you can see, the new roots
have developed very
strong and the orchid has developed a
new leaf at the top.
[Music]
When the new roots grow strong, they
will be able to absorb water and
essential nutrients from the growing
medium more effectively. This helps the
orchid develop healthily with enough
energy and nutrients to bloom and
produce new
[Music]
spikes.
Continue to apply this liquid fertilizer
to the orchid once a week.
Regular fertilizing provides the orchid
with a continuous supply of nutrients,
preventing any deficiencies. This
supports the plant's growth at all
stages, from roots to stems, leaves, and
flowers.
[Music]
results after the next 3 months.
As you can see, the old orchid leaf is
still wilted, but the new leaves have
developed healthy and strong.
[Music]
Here a new flower spike has
emerged. And over here, a large flower
spike has developed and grown long.
It's wonderful to see a weak orchid
recover, grow strong, and continue to
bloom. After a period of meticulous
care, from reviving the roots, regular
fertilizing to protecting the plant from
harmful factors, the orchid has overcome
difficulties and shows its vibrant life
through beautiful blooms. Watching the
healthy orchid thrive and flower is an
invaluable joy, the result of patience
and love for nature. Each flower that
blooms is a testament to the care and
perseverance making us feel proud and
happy.