welcome to my
channel if you have orchids after
[Music]
blooming if all the flowers have fallen
don't rush to throw them
away uh let me tell you how to help
these branches continue to bloom
strongly again
[Music]
these nodes can continue to bloom very
well
[Music]
when you eat bananas don't throw away
the peel
[Music]
thinly sliced banana peels contain many
vitamins and minerals that are very good
for the bud formation
process please comment to me which
country you are watching the video from
it's great that we can chat together
from all over the world
[Music]
[Applause]
soak banana peels in 1 liter of boiled
[Music]
water then take 3 tblsp of coffee
grounds
[Music]
then soak this coffee grounds in 1 liter
of boiled water
then wait for the water to
[Music]
cool after the water cools filter to
remove sediment
[Music]
dip a cotton ball in water extracted
from coffee grounds and wash the
[Music]
leaves helps eliminate pests and
diseases of orchids
[Music]
and leaves will photosynthesize
better um if you haven't subscribed to
the channel yet please subscribe to
support me and not miss any orchid care
tips
[Music]
mix these two types
together dip cotton balls in this water
and clip them to nodes that are likely
to continue blooming
[Music]
do it once a
week will help stimulate rapid Sprout
growth
[Music]
uh keep the cotton pad on the branch
like that for 20 minutes
and then remove
[Music]
it then water The Roots once a week
soak it for 10 minutes then lift it
[Music]
out and spray this water once a week to
help supplement nutrients through the
leaves
[Music]
after 20 minutes remove the cotton pad
and then place the plant in a place with
lots of light so it can bloom easily
1 month
[Music]
later many buds have grown
if you encounter any difficulties during
the Orchid growing process don't
hesitate to comment I am always ready to
support you so you can grow healthy
orchids and Bloom lots of flowers
[Music]
cons
Pon if there in
[Music]
then place the plant in a place with
lots of light so it can bloom
[Music]
easily after the next one month
from the dry branches many beautiful
flowers have sprouted and
[Music]
bloomed the leaves are strong and sturdy
very resistant to pests and diseases
[Music]
the flower color is also more vibrant
than
[Music]
usual hope the video will help you a lot
if you find it interesting please like
share and subscribe to the channel to
help my channel reach 1 million
subscribers soon
[Music]
my videos have subtitles in many
different languages so you can choose
the appropriate
[Music]
language thank you for watching the
video good luck and see you in the next
videos
[Music]
welcome to happiness
Garden today we will explore how to care
for weak orchids helping them recover
strongly from Roots to leaves and Bloom
[Music]
beautifully don't forget to like And
subscribe so you won't miss any great
tips you can see that this Orchid hasn't
grown for 6 months its leaves are
gradually wilting the roots are rotting
and the plant is on the brink of
dying have you ever encountered a
similar situation and didn't know what
to do to save your beloved
Orchid uh first I'll carefully remove
all the wilted and damaged leaves this
is important because unhealthy leaves
can drain the plant's energy hindering
its recovery and growth
next I'll cut off all the damaged Roots
this is essential because rotten Roots
can spread Decay to healthy parts of the
plant preventing it from from absorbing
nutrients properly
[Music]
uh finally I'll cut off any old flower
stems if present this helps the plant
Focus its energy on New Growth rather
than wasting resources on Fading flowers
[Music]
then I'll rinse the Orchid thoroughly
with water to remove any remaining dirt
or contaminants that could harm the
plant uh which country are you watching
this video from leave a comment and let
me know
it's it's amazing that we can connect
with each other from all around the
[Music]
world then I'll place the Orchid into an
empty jar
[Music]
now I'll add 1 liter of water into the
jar
next I'll add 1 teaspoon of baking soda
to the water and mix it
well baking soda helps prevent mold and
bacterial diseases on
[Music]
Orchids then I'll pour the baking soda
mixture into the jar and soak the Orchid
in it for 10 minutes to disinfect the
roots and eliminate harmful mold and
bacteria this helps the Orchid recover
quickly prevent the recurrence of
diseases and promote the plant's
[Music]
growth next I'll take three teaspoons of
rice to make natural fertilizer for the
Orchid
add it to 1 liter of
[Music]
water rice water contains vitamins and
minerals that stimulate root development
and improve the health of wilted
orchids after rinsing the rice you can
let the rice water ferment overnight to
create beneficial bacteria for the
Orchid
[Music]
after soaking the Orchid in the baking
soda solution for 10 minutes gently
remove the plant and Pat it dry with a
soft cloth this helps remove any
residual solution prevents mold and
bacteria growth and allows the Orchid to
recover quickly and healthily
[Music]
then let it sit to allow the cut to heal
completely
[Music]
this is moss for planting orchids I put
it into the
jar then pour the baking soda mixture
into the jar to soak the Moss
soaking the Moss before planting orchids
helps eliminate harmful bacteria and
mold while providing a clean and safe
environment for the orchid's roots to
thrive I soak it overnight before using
it to plant the
orchids um after one night I take the
Orchid and place the Ro into the cup
like
[Music]
this then strain out the residue and
keep the rice water to make a liquid
fertilizer which is very beneficial for
orchids
[Music]
then soak the Orchid roots in the rice
water for 20 minutes this helps
stimulate rapid root growth because the
rice water is rich in nutrients and
benefit IAL microorganisms that promote
root development
[Music]
while waiting I take a soft cotton pad
soak it in the rice water and gently
wipe the leaves to help revive wilted
leaves because the rice water nourishes
and moisturizes the leaves promoting
recovery and Healthy Growth
[Music]
if you haven't subscribed yet please
subscribe to support me
[Music]
after soaking for 20 minutes take the
Orchid out and plant it immediately into
the new pot
[Music]
take the Moss that has been soaked in
the baking soda solution ring out the
excess water and then use it to plant
the Orchid
[Music]
planting orchids with soaked Moss helps
the wilted Orchid quickly grow roots
because Moss has good moisture retention
providing an ideal environment for
strong root development additionally
Moss retains nutrients from the soaking
solution aiding the plant in recovery
and rapid growth
[Music]
after that water the Orchid with rice
water once every 10 days to help it
recover quickly
[Music]
on regular days if the Orchid is dry you
only need to mist it with water to
maintain
moisture after watering remember to
place the Orchid pot in a spot with with
gentle sunlight so the plant can
photosynthesize and improve its
metabolic
processes the results after 3
weeks as you can see the wilted leaves
have become Greener shinier and a bit
[Music]
sturdier the orchid has also grown a new
healthy leaf that looks very
[Music]
strong the orchid has developed numerous
new Roots which efficiently absorb water
and
nutrients um this helps speed up the
recovery process and helps the wilted
plant recover faster
uh if you find the video helpful don't
forget to like share and subscribe to
the channel to support
[Music]
me uh after that I continue taking care
of the Orchid with natural fertilizer
made from rice water once every 10 days
[Music]
if you encounter any difficulties in
caring for your orchids don't hesitate
to comment below the video and I'll be
ready to advise you
the result after the next
month you can see that the orchid has
grown two new very healthy leaves which
proves that the Orchid is growing very
well showing that the care method
applied is effective
you can see that the orchid has grown
two new very healthy leaves which proves
that the Orchid is growing very well
showing that the care method applied is
effective
you can see that the orchid has grown
two new very healthy leaves which proves
that the Orchid is growing very well
showing that the care method applied is
[Music]
effective the result after the next 3
months
you can see that the orchid has almost
fully recovered with the leaves becoming
healthy and
strong and the orchid has even grown a
new flower Spike that's very healthy
with this simple care routine the orchid
has quickly recovered and bloomed
beautifully just like any other healthy
[Music]
Orchid this natural fertilizer not only
supports the recovery process of your
beloved Orchid but also helps the
flowers bloom more vibrantly uh last
longer and stay in bloom for up to 6
months before
[Music]
wilting I hope this video will be
helpful to you in caring for orchids at
home if you find it useful please like
share and subscribe to the channel
[Music]
thank you all for watching I always pray
that blessings will come to
you wishing everyone good health goodbye
and see you next time