hello Orchid lovers welcome to the
happiness Garden
Channel today I will show you how to
make natural fertilizer that is both
simple and
[Music]
effective this fertilizer will help your
orchids grow sustainably and Bloom for a
longer time
[Music]
now let's get
started this orchid has finished
blooming if not properly cared for the
plant can become stunted and grow slowly
so postflowering care is very important
to help the plant recover and prepare
for the next blooming
[Music]
cycle first remove all d damaged rotting
or dried
[Music]
Roots this will allow the Orchid to
focus its energy on healthy parts for
growth this process also helps stimulate
the plant to grow new roots and prepares
it for the next growth cycle
[Music]
after removing damaged Roots we will
proceed to cut off all unhealthy
[Music]
leaves next cut off the old flower stems
so the plant can focus its energy on
growing new roots and leaves
[Music]
Old Flower stems usually no longer have
the ability to grow and can cause the
plant to waste energy if left
attached sprinkle a layer of cinnamon
powder onto the cut areas to disinfect
and prevent infection
next leave it overnight without watering
to allow the cuts to heal completely
[Music]
now take one spoonful of cinnamon powder
and add it to a jar to prepare a natural
[Music]
fertilizer mix the cinnamon powder with
1 lit of boiling water to create a
natural fertilizer solution
cover the lid and let it sit overnight
to ensure the nutrients from the
cinnamon powder are fully dissolved in
the
water the second ingredient I use is
breadcrumbs which are rich in nutrients
and great for the growth of orchids
[Music]
mix one liter of warm water with 2
teaspoons of breadcrumbs to create a
natural nutrient
solution let it sit overnight to ensure
the nutrients from the breadcrumbs are
fully dissolved in the water
[Music]
after one night strain out the residue
to obtain Clean and Clear cinnamon water
[Music]
uh what country are you watching this
video from leave a comment to let me
know it's so wonderful that we can
connect and chat with each other from
all over the world
[Music]
step one use a soft cotton pad soaked in
the cinnamon water and gently wipe the
top and bottom surfaces of the
leaves this method helps eliminate fungi
pests and harmful insects from the plant
this method also cleans the leaves
allowing them to photosynthesize more
effectively which improves the plant's
overall nutrient
exchange if you haven't subscribed yet
click the Subscribe button to support my
channel
step two pour this cinnamon water
solution into a spray bottle
then spray the solution over the entire
Orchid to remove dust mold and any pests
clinging to the
plant this method also stimulates the
plant's natural resistance helping it
grow stronger and better withstand
diseases step three use a soft cloth to
wipe off any excess water from the
leaves to prevent mold and bacterial
growth
wiping off water helps the leaves dry
quickly improving the plant's ability to
photosynthesize and
exchange reduces the risk of the Orchid
getting sick due to prolonged damp
conditions
[Music]
uh step four add a thin layer of moss on
the surface of the Orchid pot to to
retain moisture and create a better
growing environment for the
[Music]
plant this Moss layer also helps
maintain moisture balance and prevents
the plant from losing water too quickly
in dry conditions
[Music]
now I mix the cinnamon water solution
with the breadcrumbs water solution
together
[Music]
after mixing we will have a natural
nutrient solution that is excellent for
the growth of
[Music]
orchids step five from now on water this
mixture on your orchids once every 10
days
[Music]
this solution stimulates the growth of
new Roots allowing the plant to absorb
nutrients more
[Music]
effectively encourages the growth of new
CHS and flowers allowing the Orchid to
bloom for a longer period
[Music]
after watering you should soak the
Orchid pot in this mixture for about 20
minutes to get the best
[Music]
results you can use the leftover mixture
to water other regular orchids as well
it will be very beneficial for their
growth too
[Music]
um this solution is very beneficial but
you should only water the plant every 10
to 15 days to avoid overfeeding
[Music]
after watering soak the base of the
Orchid pot in this mixture for about 20
[Music]
minutes then take the Orchid pot out and
place it in a spot with gentle sunlight
to allow the plant to photosynthesize
well improving nutrient Exchange
[Applause]
[Music]
uh keep in mind uh this fertilizer is
very beneficial but without sufficient
sunlight the plant won't be able to
synthesize nutrients effectively
[Music]
uh the results after 10
days can you see the new leaves have
grown longer than before which shows
that the plant is growing very
[Music]
well new Roots have also grown quite a
lot which will help the Orchid recover
and grow vigorously in the coming time
[Music]
and you can see the leaves have become
stronger and Greener which is a sign
that the Orchid is growing healthily
I will continue to water this natural
fertilizer mixture on the plant every 10
days to ensure the Orchid grows
[Music]
sustainably on regular days if the
potting medium is dry or the environment
ISO too dry you should simply water or
Mist lightly to maintain humidity for
the
Orchid after that remember to place the
pot in a spot with gentle sunlight to
allow the Orchid to photosynthesize
effectively
[Music]
the results after the next 45
days you can see that the new leaves
have grown longer and are
healthy and two new flower stocks have
emerged promising another vibrant
blooming season
ahead uh the leaves have become stronger
and grown exceptional well after being
cared for with this natural fertilizer
mixture uh The Roots have grown out of
the Orchid pot which is a sign that the
Orchid is growing very vigorously
[Music]
um with other orchids when cared for
with this natural fertilizer mixture
they also develop many new flower stocks
and healthy new
Roots I hope this video provides you
with useful information if you find it
helpful and interesting don't forget to
support me by liking sharing and
subscribing to the
channel uh care for your Orchids with
love and dedication and you will be
rewarded with vibrant blooms and the
pure joy of connecting with nature
thank you for watching I wish you
success in taking care of your orchids
and see you in the next videos goodbye