welcome to the happiness Garden
Channel today in this video I will share
with you tips for caring for orchids
from the seedling stage until they bloom
quickly these are effective tips and
methods to help your orchid grow healthy
and Bloom at the right
time let's explore it
[Music]
now these are young Orchid plants you
can propagate them yourself from flower
stems from tissue culture bottles or you
can also purchase them from Flower Farms
on e-commerce
[Music]
platforms after bringing orchids home
you need to check and cut off any
damaged
Roots this helps eliminate parts of the
roots that can no longer absorb water
and nutrients prevent bacteria and fungi
from invading the plant and allow new
healthy roots to grow
[Music]
next remove the plant from its old pot
gently remove the old potting mix from
around the roots to avoid damaging the
plant
[Music]
which country are you watching this
video from leave a comment so we can
connect and and
share it's amazing that we can chat and
connect with each other from all around
the world
[Music]
if you haven't subscribed yet hit the
Subscribe button to support me and never
miss the exciting videos coming
up in addition to the English dub we've
now created dubs in French German
Italian Spanish Portuguese Japanese
Hindi and Indonesian to help you hear
and understand the content more easily
[Music]
this is turmeric
starch it is a natural ingredient that
is very beneficial for plant care
especially in preventing harmful
bacteria and
[Music]
fungi next is fresh milk
fresh milk provides essential nutrients
helping the plant grow healthy and
boosting its
resistance next is
eggshells eggshells are rich in calcium
and minerals which promote root growth
and improve the overall health of
orchids
take about five to six eggshells and
crush them into small pieces
[Music]
then add four cups of boiling water
about 1
liter this allows the nutrients from the
eggshells to dissolve into the
[Music]
water um then let it sit and wait until
the water cools down so the nutrients
can fully dissolve
[Music]
uh after the water has cooled stir it
well
again this ensures the nutrients are
evenly distributed in the water before
use filter out any
residue this removes any undissolved
particles ensuring the solution is clean
and safe to use on plants
[Music]
add four more cups of water about 1
liter this helps dilute the solution
ensuring the plant receives the right
amount of nutrients without being
overwhelmed step one pour this mixture
to soak the roots and Orchid potting
mix this helps deliver nutrients
directly to the roots and potting mix
promoting Healthy Growth for the
plant step two use a soft cotton pad to
soak the mixture and gently wipe the top
and bottom surfaces of the leaves
[Music]
this helps deliver nutrients directly to
the leaves and protects the plant from
external threats such as bacteria and
[Music]
fungi soak the roots in the mixture for
15 to 20 minutes to prevent root rot and
fungal infections as turmeric starch has
natural antibacterial
properties after soaking for about 20
minutes remove the roots and plant them
into a larger pot to allow the Orchid to
grow and
Thrive planting with pine bark helps
ensure good drainage maintain optimal
moisture and provide natural nutrients
for healthy Orchid
growth if you haven't subscribed to the
channel yet please please hit the
Subscribe button to support me and not
miss any Orchid growing tips it's great
to have you along
use a plastic coated Steel Rod to secure
the Orchid preventing it from toppling
over due to wind or wind or watering
[Music]
is
cover the top of the pot with a little
Moss to retain moisture prevent the
potting mix from spilling out and create
a natural environment for Healthy
[Music]
Growth pour this natural fertilizer
mixture into a spray
bottle uh this makes it easy to evenly
spray on the leaves and Roots providing
direct nutrition and promoting the
orchid's
[Music]
growth from now on water the roots or
spray this mixture on the Orchid pot
once every 10 days to provide nutrients
and encourage Healthy
[Music]
Growth on regular days simply spray
water to maintain moisture when the
potting mix appears dry
[Music]
then place the Orchid pot in a spot with
gentle sunlight to improve
photosynthesis and nutrient
[Music]
exchange results after 10 days
new Roots have grown and are very
healthy the growth of new Roots
indicates that the orchid has recovered
well and is absorbing sufficient
nutrients in preparation for its next
growth phase
[Music]
when the roots develop they will
effectively absorb water and nutrients
causing the leaves to become Greener and
healthier
here then continue to care for the
Orchid by regularly using this natural
fertilizer
I continue to water the roots or spray
this mixture on the Orchid every 10 days
to maintain its health and encourage
growth
[Music]
this fertilizer helps stimulate root
growth boost resistance keep leaves
green encourage blooming and balance
moisture with natural nutrients
[Music]
after watering place the Orchid pot in a
spot with gentle sunlight to allow the
plant to absorb energy and grow well
results after the next 2
months uh thanks to this natural
fertilizer the orchid has grown
vigorously with healthy vibrant green
roots and leaves ready for the next
growth stage
[Music]
that then continue to care for the
Orchid by regularly using this natural
fertilizer
[Music]
I continue to water the roots or spray
this mixture on the Orchid every 10 days
to maintain its health and encourage
growth
[Music]
after watering place the Orchid pot in a
spot with gentle sunlight to allow the
plant to absorb energy and grow well
results after the next one
month uh the orchid has developed
numerous flower buds signaling a vibrant
blooming season ahead
I hope this video provides you with
helpful tips for orchid
care don't forget to hit like share and
subscribe to the happiness Garden
channel for more exciting plant care
tips
[Music]
nurture your plants with all your love
and they will reward you with their
radiant Beauty and vibrant
energy thank you for watching see you
the next videos and may your days be
joyful and your plants thrive