Hello
everyone. In today's video, we will
explore ways to care for weak orchids,
helping them revive and continue to
bloom
beautifully. If you're having trouble
caring for your orchids, don't worry.
These simple tips will help you bring
your plants back to
life. Let's get started.
Uh, if you have a wilted orchid like
this, don't throw it
away. Now I share how to recover quickly
with natural fertilizers.
You see that the growing medium is very
dry. These are inorganic fertilizer
particles.
Check the roots for damage.
At the bottom of the orchid pot, there
are many inorganic fertilizer
particles. It seems orchids are not
suitable for inorganic fertilizers.
Many roots are damaged. So we need to
cut off all damaged
roots. When orchid roots are damaged,
bacteria, mold, or viruses can appear
and harm the plant.
Cutting off these damaged roots helps
prevent the spread of harmful pathogens
to other parts of the
plant. Leave only fresh roots like this.
Then cut off all damaged
leaves. Damaged orchid leaves can become
a breeding ground for bacteria, fungi,
or viruses. Removing these leaves helps
prevent the spread of diseases to other
parts of the plant.
When a plant has damaged leaves, it
expends energy to maintain these parts,
reducing the resources available for
other
growth. Removing damaged leaves helps
the plant conserve energy and focus on
developing new healthy leaves.
Then cut all the old flower branches.
After the flowers have faded, the old
flower stems no longer contribute to
nutrient
absorption. Removing the old stems
allows the plant to conserve energy and
focus on developing other parts such as
stronger roots and leaves.
Now you need to soak the entire orchid
in room temperature water for 1 hour.
This helps quickly restore wilted roots
and leaves, awakening the ability of
fresh roots and leaves to absorb water.
Take.5 L of
[Music]
water. Then add/ teaspoon brown sugar.
Sugar, mainly glucose, provides a quick
energy source for the plant, enhancing
photosynthesis and aiding in faster
recovery, especially when the plant is
wilting due to nutrient deficiency or
stress.
[Music]
after soaking in water for 1 hour. Take
the orchid
out and soak orchid leaves in water
mixed with brown sugar for 20 minutes.
At the same time, it also helps plants
recover and regenerate damaged parts
quickly.
Next, I need oatmeal.
Take one teaspoon of
oatmeal and add one spoon of wine
yeast. Add.5 L of warm water.
Oatmeal is a rich source of fiber and
essential nutrients like B vitamins,
amino acids, and minerals which help
orchids grow
strong. Wait 20
minutes. 20 minutes later.
Filter this water.
After soaking the orchid leaves for
about 20 minutes, take them
out. Then soak the entire orchid root in
yeast water and oatmeal for about 20
minutes. This will stimulate rapid root
growth.
[Music]
After soaking the roots for 20 minutes,
take the orchid
out. The roots absorb this nutrient and
turn
green. All standing water must be
removed from the leaves before planting.
[Music]
Then plant the orchid in a pot so the
plant can grow in the outside
environment.
[Music]
I plant moss to help retain moisture so
the orchid can recover
[Music]
quickly. Which country are you watching
videos from? Please comment for me. It's
great that we can chat together from all
over the world.
[Music]
Uh, if you haven't subscribed to the
channel yet, please hit subscri hit hit
the subscribe button to support me and
not miss any orchid growing tips. It's
great to have you
along. Then you mix these two waters
together.
Then you apply this liquid fertilizer to
your orchid pot and repeat after 10
days. This liquid fertilizer will
stimulate root growth very quickly.
Um, if you take advantage of this
remaining liquid fertilizer to fertilize
other orchids, it will be very good.
New roots will grow very quickly.
The new root system of this weak orchid
has grown very strongly thanks to this
liquid
fertilizer. Every time you take care of
orchids, soak the orchid pot in this
fertilizer solution for about 20 minutes
and then take it out.
Then place the orchid pot in a place
with lots of light and fertilize with
liquid fertilizer every 10
days. Results after 1
month. Orchids develop many new very
strong
[Music]
roots. This will help the orchid recover
faster.
When the roots absorb water, the wilted
leaves will gradually
recover. Then continue to apply this
liquid fertilizer every 10 days. Then
[Music]
results. After the next 3
months, the orchid has recovered and
grown very well
by and grows two new flower branches.
[Music]
Take care of your orchids with all the
love and care you have for plants, and
you will be
rewarded. When you invest time and
attention into every small detail, the
plant will sense it and respond with
vibrant, healthy blooms.
Orchids are not just beautiful plants,
but a testament to love, patience, and
meticulous care. Let them thrive in an
environment full of attention and love,
and you'll see your orchids not only
grow strong, but bloom beautifully.