Hello orchid
[Music]
lovers. Today we will explore the secret
to watering orchids so they always bloom
and thrive with magical roots.
[Music]
With just a little patience and care,
you will see that taking care of these
plants is not as hard as you think.
[Music]
First, we need to understand the
incorrect watering techniques for
orchids. Do not water orchids like these
directly from the tap.
[Music]
And you should not water directly on the
orchid crown like this.
[Music]
You should also not water directly on
the
[Music]
flowers. Um, these three watering
methods can easily cause the orchid to
have damaged leaves, rotten leaves, and
rotten flowers.
[Music]
Like these orchid plants that have stem
and leaf rot caused by water
accumulation, which leads to fungal
growth, causing the stem and leaves to
rot.
[Music]
Um, you need to observe the roots and
the growing medium to decide whether to
water or not.
[Music]
If the roots are still green and the
growing medium is still moist like this,
then there is no need to water.
[Music]
But when you see the roots turn white
and the growing medium is too dry like
this, you need to water the orchid
immediately.
[Music]
The first
method. Once a month, soak the orchid
pot in water for 20 to 30 minutes.
[Music]
This helps remove excess mineral salts
from the orchid growing
[Music]
medium. This method also helps the roots
absorb water more effectively.
[Music]
The second
method, you water directly at the base,
but avoid getting the orchid stem and
leaves wet.
The third
method, mist to maintain humidity on
both the upper and lower surfaces of the
leaves.
[Music]
With this method, after watering, you
need to dry the buds and the leaf
joints.
[Music]
I apply this method regularly and the
leaves are always green and clean.
[Music]
When the orchid is watered adequately
and receives enough nutrients, it will
develop many flower buds just like this
orchid of mine.
[Music]
Uh many flower branches grow at the same
time on the same orchid
[Music]
plant. The leaves are sturdy and free
from
[Music]
disease. The flowers bloom with vibrant
colors.
[Music]
The flower buds are very
plump. This helps the pedals open wider
and stay fresh longer.
[Music]
An orchid plant that absorbs enough
water will not
[Music]
wilt. With enough moisture, the roots
can easily absorb
[Music]
nutrients. If the orchid has enough
water and nutrients, the flowers can
stay on the spike for up to 6 months
before
[Music]
falling. Adequate watering helps the
roots develop stronger.
[Music]
Healthy roots will also absorb water and
nutrients
[Music]
better. It helps the orchid increase its
resistance to pests and diseases.
[Music]
I hope the video content will help you
take better care of orchids at
[Music]
home. Um, if you find it helpful, don't
forget to like, share, and subscribe to
the channel to support me.
[Music]
Wishing you success and happiness in
life. Goodbye and see you in the next
[Music]
videos. Welcome to my channel.
Um, when the last Phelinopsis orchids
are about to fall, this is the right
time to cut branches to propagate
Phelinopsis orchids from flower stems.
[Music]
These nodes still contain dormant buds,
so they can be used to propagate orchids
from flower spikes.
[Music]
And these nodes have already bloomed. So
cut them off as they can no longer be
used for propagation.
[Music]
After that, I use a potato to create a
substance that helps propagate orchids
quickly.
[Music]
Potatoes contain many substances
necessary for the growth of orchids.
[Music]
I will recycle potato peels into organic
fertilizer. Pour one liter of hot water
into the jar.
[Music]
Then brew until the water
cools. Need to peel off the protective
film of the sleeping
sprout. This will help the sprouts grow
faster.
[Music]
Apply potato gel to the sleeping
sprouts. This helps stimulate sprout
growth.
[Music]
Next, apply toothpaste on the
cut. Helps cuts heal faster.
[Music]
wrap with thinly sliced potatoes.
This helps moisturize and awaken dormant
sprouts.
[Music]
Uh, leave for 6 hours to let the
nutrients from the potatoes penetrate
inside.
[Music]
Take one teaspoon of cinnamon
powder. Add one liter of hot water.
[Music]
After the water cools, filter to remove
sediment.
[Music]
Soak terracotta beads and aquaponic
resin beads. seeds in cinnamon water
solution for 30
[Music]
[Applause]
minutes. Soak the moss in the cinnamon
solution for 30 minutes.
[Music]
Recycle used boxes into orchid sprouting
tools.
[Music]
conduct orchid nursery. Okay.
Spray moisturizer every 3 days.
[Music]
Place in a cool
place. When cool, filtered to remove
[Music]
residue. Um, watering this liquid
fertilizer for orchids one to two times
a month will be very
[Music]
good. 3 weeks later
The sleeping sprouts have
[Music]
awakened.
Continue spraying water and leave in a
cool place for the sprouts to grow.
[Music]
after next one
month the sprout has grown leaves.
[Music]
Continue spraying water and leave in a
cool place for the sprouts to grow.
[Music]
After the next 2
months, small orchids grow very quickly.
[Music]
With this simple way, you can propagate
orchids at home
[Music]
easily. Hope the video will help you a
lot.
[Music]
Now I will plant it in a pot so the
orchid can grow in the outside
environment.
[Music]
Uh, if you find the video meaningful,
please like, share, and subscribe to
support me so my channel can reach 10
million subscribers soon.
[Music]
Then nurture the orchid with water and
organic fertilizer as I shared on the
happiness garden channel and take care
of it with all the love you have for the
plant. In return, it will bring you
beauty and growth.
[Music]
Wishing you success and happiness in
life. Goodbye and see you in the next
video.