Welcome to my little orchid garden where
each petal is nurtured with love and
passion.
Today I will guide you on how to
propagate orchids at home using the stem
cutting method. Simple yet effective.
The ideal time for stem cutting is when
the orchid flowers begin to fade. When
the plant enters its resting phase and
is ready for new growth.
[Music]
This flower stem is the ideal time to
take a cutting, helping the plant grow
stronger.
[Music]
Keep the unopened buds like this for
stem cutting as they contain dormant
shoots that can sprout into new orchid
plants.
[Music]
As for the positions where the flowers
have bloomed, you should cut them off as
they no longer contain uh dormant buds
to develop into new orchid plants.
[Music]
I keep these two dormant buds for stem
cutting and later the new orchid plant
will grow from here.
[Music]
I cut across here to avoid crushing the
cut as crushed areas are prone to
infection and can affect the plant's
growth.
At the base of the cutting, I make a
diagonal cut to create a larger contact
surface, which helps the cutting absorb
water and nutrients more effectively.
[Music]
Then I sprinkle turmeric powder on the
cut. This helps with antibacterial
protection, uh, prevents rot and
promotes faster healing of the wound.
[Music]
After that, I leave the cutting for a
few hours without watering to let the
cut dry, reducing the risk of infection
when planting.
[Music]
After that, you use rice, a material
rich in B vitamins and essential
minerals to support the orchid stem
cutting process.
Take 3 tablesp of rice and dilute it
with.5 L of water to create a solution
for soaking the cutings.
[Music]
Cover the lid and let it sit for a few
hours to allow the nutrients from the
rice to fully dissolve.
[Music]
Cover the lid and let it sit for a few
hours to allow the nutrients from the
rice to fully dissolve.
[Music]
Dilute the turmeric powder with 0.5 L of
water to create a solution for soaking
the stem cutings.
[Music]
Cover the lid and let the solution sit
for a few hours to allow the nutrients
from the turmeric powder to fully
dissolve into the water.
After 3 hours of soaking, I proceed to
filter the turmeric water to use for the
stem cutings.
[Music]
Make sure to filter out the residue as
it can cause blockages and affect the
cutting's ability to absorb nutrients.
[Music]
Step one, use a soft cloth to soak up
the turmeric solution and gently wipe it
onto the stem cutting.
[Music]
This method helps protect the cut,
prevent infection, and stimulate the
rooting process of the stem cutting.
[Music]
Then use this mixture to wipe both the
top and bottom surfaces of the stem
cutting, helping to enhance nutrient
absorption and protect the plant from
pests and diseases.
[Music]
If you haven't subscribed to the channel
yet, please hit the subscribe button to
support me and never miss any orchid
growing tips. It's wonderful to have you
along.
[Music]
Let me know in the comments which
country you're watching the video from.
It's amazing that we can chat together
from all around the world.
[Music]
Then mix the rice water with the
turmeric water to create the perfect
nutrient solution, helping the rooting
and growth process of the stem cutting
improve.
When mixing, make sure to filter the
rice water thoroughly to remove any
residue, making the solution cleaner and
easier for the stem cutting to absorb.
[Music]
After mixing, soak the stem cutting in
this mixture for about 20 minutes to
allow the nutrients to be absorbed into
the cutting.
This mixture helps the stem cutting
absorb nutrients more effectively,
stimulating the rooting process and
promoting strong growth.
[Music]
Um, while waiting, I will prepare the
tools to help improve the effectiveness
of the stem cutting process.
Prepare a plastic box or a transparent
glass cup and a piece of floral foam.
Then follow the steps I guide you
through.
In addition to the English voiceover, we
have now created voiceovers in French,
German, Italian, Spanish, Portuguese,
Japanese, Hindi, and Indonesian to help
you listen to and understand the content
more easily.
For languages without voiceovers, we
have created subtitles uh so you can
read and understand the content.
[Music]
After soaking for 20 minutes, take the
stem cutting out to proceed with placing
it in the prepared container.
Then add bottled water or cooled boiled
water enough to submerge the floral
foam.
[Music]
Then add bottled water or cooled boiled
water enough to submerge the floral
foam.
[Music]
Then cover it with a transparent plastic
lid and place it in a spot with gentle
sunlight for the stem cutting to develop
well.
[Music]
Um, the remaining mixture I used to
water the roots of the orchids in the
garden to provide nutrients to the
plants.
Water each plant with about 10
tablespoons as this amount provides
enough nutrients without overwatering
the plant.
This mixture helps the orchid strengthen
its rooting ability, promoting strong
growth from the base.
The vitamins and minerals in this
mixture help the orchid resist pests and
harmful factors.
[Music]
Watering with this mixture helps the
orchid absorb nutrients better, leading
to the production of beautiful and
long-lasting flowers.
[Music]
You can water each orchid pot with this
mixture one to two times a month to
provide consistent nutrients for the
plants.
[Music]
Now, let's take a look at the results
after 1 month of stem cutting.
[Music]
As you can see, the stem cutting has
sprouted two new orchid plants from the
dormant buds, proving that the cutting
process was successful and the plant is
growing well.
The young orchid plant may be small, but
it has already started growing roots,
showing that the plant is developing
healthily and is getting ready to
mature.
[Music]
I will continue to keep the stem cutting
in the container to allow the orchid to
grow larger before planting it in the
outside environment.
Um, when the water becomes cloudy or has
a strange smell, you should change it
immediately to prevent bacteria from
developing and harming the cutings.
[Music]
Use filtered water or boiled water that
has cooled down when replacing it to
maintain a clean environment and promote
faster root growth for the cutings.
Then place the cutings in a spot with
gentle sunlight to help the plant absorb
light, stimulate root growth, and
prevent leaf burn.
[Music]
And here is the result after 2 months of
rooting the cutings.
[Music]
You can see that the roots have grown
strong and healthy, proving that the
correct care method has yielded
excellent results.
[Music]
When the orchid seedlings are healthy
and the roots have developed well, that
is the ideal time to separate them and
plant them into new pots.
[Music]
Uh this helps the orchids have more
space to grow, which in turn promotes
strong growth in the new environment.
Plant the orchid in a pot with good
drainage holes to ensure that water
doesn't accumulate, helping the roots
avoid rot and promoting healthier
growth.
I choose pine bark chips as the growing
medium because it has good drainage
capacity, helps maintain stable moisture
levels for the orchids without causing
water logging, and also provides
essential nutrients for root
development.
[Music]
I choose pine bark chips as the growing
medium because it has good drainage
capacity, helps maintain stable moisture
levels for the orchids without causing
water logging and also provides
essential nutrients for root
development.
[Music]
How do you find my orchid cutting
tutorial video? Please leave a comment
below the video to let me know your
thoughts.
[Music]
Spread a little moss on top of the pot
before placing the orchid seedling in to
help retain moisture better. create
ideal conditions for the plant's growth
and prevent water from evaporating too
quickly.
[Music]
Thank you for watching the video. I wish
you success with your orchids. Goodbye
and see you in the next videos.
[Music]
Hello friends.
When the new orchid withers all its
flowers, this is the best time to cut
the flowers to help them sprout faster.
Which country are you watching this
video from?
Please comment below. It's so great that
we can chat with each other from all
around the world.
[Music]
Uh, peel off the protective film so that
the buds will germinate faster.
[Music]
cut back the branch with a sharp knife
so as not to crush the cut.
[Music]
Pour melted candle solution into the cut
to help the cut heal quickly and not
rot.
[Music]
Sprinkle cinnamon powder on the freshly
cut wound at the base to help protect
the orchid from rot.
Use one large garlic clove or two small
garlic cloves.
[Music]
How small?
Put the garlic in the jar.
[Music]
Pour in 500 ml of water at room
temperature.
[Music]
Wait 30 minutes for the nutrients from
the garlic to dissolve into the water.
[Music]
Use foam to arrange flowers.
Yeah.
[Music]
You
After soaking for 30 minutes, filter out
the residue.
[Music]
Soak orchid branches in garlic water for
30 minutes.
[Music]
30 minutes later,
take out.
Plug in the sucker.
[Music]
Pour in filtered water just enough to
moisten.
[Music]
Close the lid and wait for the orchid
branch to sprout.
After the next 3 weeks,
[Music]
sprouts have woken up.
after one next
[Music]
The orchid sprouts have grown and the
roots have grown.
[Music]
After the next two months,
The small orchid has grown healthy.
[Music]
Now, let's plant the orchid in pots so
that it can adapt to the outside
environment.
[Music]