Welcome to my channel. Uh, in this video
I'm sharing how to revive a weakened
orchid so it can grow normally and bloom
beautifully. If you haven't subscribed
yet, make sure to hit that subscribe
button so you don't miss any orchid care
tips on my channel.
[Music]
Let's get started.
This is an orchid that has rotted. It
was discarded, but I brought it home to
revive it.
After the orchid blooms, the plant often
becomes a bit weak because it has used a
lot of energy to flower.
Um, if not properly cared for, the
orchid may struggle to recover and it
will be difficult for it to bloom again
next time.
[Music]
You need to remove all the damaged
leaves, roots, and old stems.
[Music]
Removing the infected parts helps
prevent the growth of bacteria and mold.
[Music]
Uh the plant doesn't have to nourish the
weak parts, allowing it to focus on the
healthy sections.
Removing the old parts helps the plant
grow new, stronger shoots and roots.
[Music]
Now I'm cutting through the orchid stem
to check if there's any rot inside.
[Music]
Luckily the inside of the orchid stem
hasn't rotted yet.
[Music]
Cut off all the damaged leaves to
prevent the rot from spreading to other
areas.
[Music]
Then wash it thoroughly with water.
For the orchid stem, we need to make a
clean cut to avoid crushing it, which
will reduce the risk of rot from the
cut.
These rotting leaves should be removed
and kept far from the garden to prevent
spreading the rot to other orchids.
[Music]
Do you have cinnamon powder?
Take one spoonful of cinnamon powder and
put it into a jar.
Then add it to one liter of boiling
water.
[Music]
Stir well to prevent the cinnamon powder
from clumping.
[Music]
Then let it steep and wait for the water
to cool down.
[Music]
Once the water cools down, stir well to
ensure the nutrients are fully dissolved
in the water.
[Music]
That's my helper. Do you have any pets?
Now, strain out the residue.
Cinnamon has natural antibacterial and
antifungal properties, helping to
eliminate bacteria and fungi that cause
rot, especially root and stem rot.
Step one, use a soft cotton ball to soak
up the water and gently wipe the top and
bottom of the leaves.
Wiping the leaves clean helps remove
fungi, bacteria, or mold that may
develop on the surface, reducing the
risk of the plant getting infected.
When the leaves are cleaned, light can
easily reach the surface, helping the
plant photosynthesize more effectively,
especially during the recovery process.
Then place it here
and soak the leaf stem in the cinnamon
water for 10 minutes.
Cinnamon water has antibacterial and
antifungal properties, helping to
prevent infection at the cut. Cinnamon
helps stimulate the growth of new roots,
supporting the orchid's quick recovery.
[Music]
Then water the orchid pot with the
cinnamon water.
It helps prevent diseases caused by
bacteria and fungi in the roots.
It helps the orchid roots grow strong
and healthy.
[Music]
It enhances the plant's ability to
resist harmful factors.
After watering, soak the orchid roots in
this water for about 10 minutes for the
best effect on the roots.
[Music]
Then remove the roots and dry off the
cinnamon water.
[Music]
and take the orchid pot out.
Next, take one aloe vera leaf.
Aloe vera contains oxin, a natural plant
hormone that helps stimulate root
development from the leaf stem.
It helps protect the leaf stem from
bacteria and fungi, preventing infection
and supporting the rooting process.
Then take aloe vera gel and apply it to
the leaf stem.
[Music]
Then apply the aloe vera gel to the cut
on the orchid stem and roots to
stimulate root growth and protect
against rot from the cut.
[Music]
Aloe vera gel contains natural hormones
that stimulate the growth of new roots
and shoots.
[Music]
I use moss to plant orchids as it helps
retain moisture well and stimulates fast
root growth.
[Music]
Soak the moss in cinnamon water for
about 5 minutes to eliminate bacteria
and fungi that may be present in the
moss.
[Music]
Then take the moss out and ring out any
excess water.
[Music]
Place the moss in here as I
place the orchid leaf in here.
[Music]
Then you should spray water to maintain
moisture once every 3 days.
Use plastic wrap to cover the mouth of
the bottle.
Create
ventilation holes at the top like this.
Then place it in a location with enough
light, but avoid direct sunlight on the
orchid.
Now I'm adding more moss to the surface
of this orchid pot to help retain
moisture better.
[Music]
This method also helps stimulate the
rapid growth of new roots.
Then spray water to maintain moisture
for the orchid pot whenever you notice
the growing medium is dry.
Then spray water to maintain moisture
for the orchid pot whenever you notice
the growing medium is dry.
The results after 50 days.
[Music]
Wow. As you can see, many new roots have
grown from the leaf stem
and and the new leaves have also grown
bigger than before the recovery.
[Music]
the new roots help the plant absorb
water and nutrients more effectively.
Healthy roots help the plant resist
diseases and adverse environmental
factors.
This in turn helps the plant grow
stronger and healthier.
[Music]
You can see that the base of the orchid
has also revived very well.
[Music]
The orchid stem has grown a new very
healthy chute.
Many new roots are growing under the
layer of moss.
[Music]
These new roots help the plant grow
strong, recover quickly, and prepare to
bloom.
[Music]
Now I'm planting the orchid leaf in a
new pot so it can grow better in the
outside.
[Music]
Um I'm planting it with pine bark chips
uh which maintain uh moderate moisture
and provide good drainage for the roots
to grow.
[Music]
with this simple method. You can quickly
and effectively revive a weakened orchid
on your own.
I hope you enjoyed the video. Don't
forget to support the channel and leave
a comment.
Now you just need to care for it like
any other regular orchid plant.
Uh take care of your orchids with all
the love for plants and you'll get to
enjoy beautiful vibrant blooms. Uh,
thank you for watching. I wish you
success in caring for your orchids and
many wonderful moments with your plants.