Welcome to the happiness garden, where
every orchid tells its own story. Here
we not only learn how to care for the
plants, but also feel the beauty and
wonder of nature through every leaf,
every new root, and every blooming
petal. Let's enjoy the peaceful moments
and the joy that the flowers bring each
day.
After 1 to two years of planting, each
orchid should have its medium changed
and be transferred to a suitable pot so
the roots can grow, receive enough
nutrients and water, helping the plant
stay healthy, grow new roots, and
prepare for the next flowers.
Old growing medium often attracts
insects like snails, which can harm the
plant's roots and also creates
conditions for mold to develop.
When the growing medium has
deteriorated, it can no longer maintain
proper irerration and drainage, making
it difficult for the roots to absorb
nutrients. Therefore, replacing it with
new medium not only protects the roots,
but also helps the orchid grow more
vigorously.
Before changing the growing medium,
perform a preliminary check and remove
all harmful insects. This helps protect
the young roots of the orchid and
prevent insect born diseases. Only when
the roots are safe should we proceed to
replant them into the new pot and
medium.
[Music]
Then I remove the old pot because it is
too tight and no longer provides enough
space for the roots to grow.
Transferring to a new pot of suitable
size allows the orchid roots to spread
comfortably, absorb nutrients better,
and creates conditions for the plant to
be healthy. preparing for the next
blooms.
[Music]
Next, I remove the damaged or rotting
roots so the plant can focus on
developing healthy roots. This helps
prevent disease attacks and ensures the
orchid absorbs nutrients effectively,
preparing for strong growth in the near
future.
[Music]
You can see that if it is not
transferred to a new pot, these young
roots will not have enough space to
grow.
[Music]
Then I prepare a larger pot with good
drainage holes for planting.
I place a few small pieces of foam at
the bottom of the pot to help improve
drainage and prevent the roots from
being water logged.
This method also creates extra air
space, helping the roots grow healthy
and allowing the orchid to absorb
nutrients from the new medium.
[Music]
Then I plant the orchid using sterilized
pine bark chips. A clean medium helps
prevent mold and pests while providing
an ideal airrated environment for the
roots to grow vigorously and absorb
nutrients effectively.
[Music]
The new clean medium along with a larger
pot provides the roots with optimal
space to grow, absorb nutrients
effectively, and keep the orchid
healthy. This is an important step to
prepare for vibrant blooms in the
future.
If you haven't subscribed to the
channel, please hit the subscribe button
to support me and not miss any orchid
growing tips. It's wonderful to have you
along for the journey.
[Music]
After planting, leave the orchid in a
cool, airy place for one day without
watering. This helps the new roots
stabilize, reduces the risk of root rot,
and prepares them to absorb nutrients
from the new medium.
Today, to make natural fertilizer, I
will share how to make fertilizer from
potatoes. This method is simple,
environmentally friendly, and provides
all the necessary nutrients for orchids
to grow healthy and bloom brilliantly.
We only need about 10 g of potatoes to
make natural fertilizer. This small
amount already provides enough essential
nutrients to help the orchid stay
healthy, grow new roots, and prepare for
beautiful blooms.
Place the potatoes in a clean container
and add 500 ml of water.
[Music]
Then blend the potatoes with the water
to create a natural fertilizer solution.
[Applause]
Add another 500 mil of water so that we
have about one liter of the potato
mixture.
[Music]
To enhance the effectiveness of the
fertilizer, I add a spoonful of
molasses.
Molasses provides extra sugar and
nutrients for the microorganisms in the
medium, helping the orchid roots grow
vigorously and allowing the plant to
absorb nutrients better.
After adding the molasses, stir the
mixture well so that all the ingredients
are fully blended. This helps the
natural fertilizer work at its maximum
effectiveness.
[Music]
Cover the container and leave it in a
cool, airy place for 1 day. This process
helps the natural fertilizer solution
stabilize, allows the nutrients to blend
better, and gets it ready to nourish the
orchid for healthy growth and beautiful
blooms.
[Music]
After one day, take about 100 ml of the
clear liquid from the top to dilute.
This is the settled solution, easy to
use and safe for the roots, helping the
orchid absorb nutrients more
effectively.
[Music]
Dilute 100 milllers of the solution with
one liter of clean water.
This dilution makes the fertilizer
gentle and safe for the roots while
still providing enough nutrients for the
orchid to grow healthy.
[Music]
For the remaining mixture, simply
seal the container tightly
and place it in the refrigerator to use
later. This mixture can be safely stored
for for about 2 weeks while while still
retaining its nutrients for the orchids.
Method one, dip a soft cloth into this
mixture. Then gently wipe both the top
and bottom surfaces of the leaves.
[Music]
Um, wiping the leaves with this mixture
helps remove long accumulated dust,
making the leaves cleaner and allowing
the plant to photosynthesize more
effectively.
When wiping the leaves, the nutrients in
the mixture will be absorbed directly
through through the leaf surface,
helping the plant take them in quickly
and receive timely nourishment.
This mixture also helps prevent the
growth of mold and reduces some small
insects that cling to the leaves and
cause damage.
After being wiped, the leaves will
become glossy, green, healthy, and full
of vitality, making the orchid even more
beautiful.
Regularly caring for the leaves in this
way also helps boost the plant's
resistance, supporting the orchid to
bloom more evenly and last longer.
Please leave a comment to let me know
which country you are watching the video
from.
It's wonderful that we can connect and
chat with each other from all around the
world.
Method two, pour the mixture into a
spray bottle and gently spray it over
the entire leaves, stems, roots, and
even the growing medium.
When spraying, make sure to cover both
the top and bottom surfaces of the
leaves, especially the underside.
This is where the plant absorbs
nutrients more effectively and where
insects often hide. So, thorough
spraying will help the orchid leaves
stay healthier and free from disease.
Spraying this mixture helps the leaves,
stems, and roots of the orchid absorb
nutrients quickly, allowing the plant to
grow more fully and become healthier.
A light mist also keeps the leaf surface
cool and clean, reduces dust buildup,
and lowers the risk of fungal diseases
developing.
[Applause]
When sprayed regularly, the orchid
leaves become glossy green. The roots
grow stronger and the plant blooms more
easily with beautiful longerlasting
flowers.
[Music]
Method three, water this mixture
directly onto the roots and the growing
medium. This this simple way allows the
orchid to absorb nutrients right from
the roots while keeping the medium moist
and nutrient-rich, creating the best
conditions for strong growth.
Watering with this mixture allows the
roots to directly absorb nutrients,
helping the orchid become healthier,
grow new roots quickly, and develop more
steadily.
When absorbed into the growing medium,
the mixture provides a nutrient-rich
environment, helping the medium not only
retain moisture well, but also nourish
the plant over the long term.
[Music]
Regular watering also stimulates the
harmonious growth of leaves, stems, and
roots, creating a solid foundation for
the orchid to soon produce beautiful
blooms.
After watering, you can soak the whole
orchid pot in the mixture for about 20
minutes so the roots can absorb the
maximum nutrients and refresh the
growing medium, helping the plant grow
strong and last longer.
Uh while waiting for the soak, use a
soft cloth to gently dab the water
accumulated on the leaves and in the
leaf crevices. This helps keep the
leaves dry and airy, reduces the risk of
leaf rot, and protects the orchid to
grow healthy.
[Music]
Dabbing the water off the leaves also
helps prevent mold and bacteria from
growing, keeping the orchid leaves
clean, healthy, and ready to absorb
nutrients.
[Music]
After soaking for about 20 minutes, take
the orchid pot out and place it in a
cool, airy spot with gentle sunlight.
This allows the plant to absorb
nutrients gradually, the roots to dry
naturally and helps the orchid grow
healthy, preparing for beautiful blooms.
And here are the results after 2 weeks.
You can see that many new roots have
developed. This shows that the care
method and the use of the natural
fertilizer mixture have helped the
orchid uh absorb nutrients well and grow
healthily.
These new roots will help the orchid
absorb more nutrients, nourish healthy
green leaves, and prepare for the next
flowers to bloom strong, vibrant, and
long-lasting.
Thanks to proper care, the leaves have
become glossy green and sturdy,
reflecting the orchid's good health and
strong growth.
Glossy green and sturdy leaves help the
orchid photosynthesize more effectively,
boost its resistance, and prepare it
well for even and beautiful flowering in
the future.
Uh, this is another orchid that has been
cared for using this method before. And
you can see that its roots have
developed very healthily.
[Music]
This proves that the method of using the
natural fertilizer mixture combined with
proper care helps the orchid develop
comprehensively
from roots, stems, and leaves to
flowers, creating a strong foundation
for healthy growth and beautiful blooms.
You can see the large and beautiful
petals with many blooms opening
brilliantly on a single stem, creating a
truly vivid and captivating scene.
[Music]
From the stems and leaves to the
branches and flowers, everything grows
healthy and balanced, creating a
harmonious and vibrant hole.
Other
orchid varieties such as Catalia in the
garden when cared for with a combination
of natural and inorganic fertilizers
also grow vigorously and bloom
brilliantly creating a colorful and
lively scene.
Thank you all for watching. Goodbye and
I wish you always have joyful moments
with your beautiful flowers.