Welcome to the happiness garden, where
every green leaf and every flower tells
its own story. This is not just a
garden, but also a space that brings
peace, joy, and inspiration to those who
love nature.
In this video, I will guide you on how
to revive weak orchids with yellowing or
wilting leaves using aloe vera. Because
inside the aloe vera leaf, there is a
natural gel rich in nutrients that helps
stimulate strong root growth and makes
the wrinkled leaves quickly become firm
and smooth again.
[Music]
You just need to take a small aloe vera
leaf, then cut it into pieces to prepare
a wonderful natural fertilizer for your
orchids.
Next, take two eggshells because
eggshells contain a lot of organic
calcium. When combined with aloe vera
leaves, they will create a natural
source of nutrients that helps orchids
grow healthier from roots to leaves.
[Music]
Eggshells need to be dried, then cleaned
to remove dirt and only then added
together with the aloe vera leaves,
preparing for the step of grinding the
mixture.
[Music]
Eggshells need to be dried, then cleaned
to remove dirt and only then added
together with the aloe vera leaves,
preparing for the step of grinding the
mixture.
[Music]
Please comment and let me know which
country you are watching this video
from. It's wonderful that we can chat
together from all around the world.
[Music]
After blending, strain out the residue,
keeping only the clear solution so that
the orchids can absorb it more easily.
[Music]
Add more water to make about 3 L of
solution. And this is the natural
fertilizer mixture from aloe vera and
eggshells.
[Music]
On my channel, there are currently
narrations available in 20 different
languages. Please go to the settings to
choose the language that suits you.
If you haven't subscribed yet, please
click the subscribe button to support me
and not miss any orchid care tips. It's
wonderful to have you along on this
journey.
[Music]
After mixing, use a soft cloth soaked in
the aloe vera and eggshell mixture.
Then, gently wipe both the upper and
lower sides of the leaves. This method
is especially effective for leaves that
are wrinkled from lack of water or
wilting.
[Music]
Aloe vera gel contains many essential
vitamins and minerals for the plant. At
the same time, it also has good moisture
retention, helping wilted leaves quickly
regain their vitality.
You can do this every 2 days. If
maintained regularly, the orchid leaves
will always stay green and healthy while
also reducing the attack of fungi and
insects.
[Music]
The second method is to use this aloe
vera and eggshell mixture to water
directly onto the roots and growing
medium helping the plant absorb
nutrients naturally and effectively.
For orchids with wrinkled leaves due to
wilting, you just need to water the
plant with the aloe vera solution about
once a week. This method will provide
sufficient vitamins and minerals through
the roots while also acting as a natural
fertilizer that helps the root system
recover quickly.
For orchids that are growing normally,
you only need to water them with aloe
vera about once every 2 weeks. That is
enough for the plant to absorb nutrients
without the risk of excess.
[Music]
The third method is to put the mixture
into a spray bottle and mist it onto
wilted orchids about every 2 to 3 days.
This method works like folure feeding,
helping the plant absorb nutrients
directly and recover faster.
[Music]
For healthy orchids, you only need to
spray this mixture about once every two
weeks. A simple method will help orchids
grow better and keep the flowers fresh
longer with stronger stems.
[Music]
Now let's take a look at the results
after 2 weeks.
You can see a little caterpillar on this
leaf, which shows that the new leaf has
become tender and soft, making it a
favorite spot for the caterpillar to
stay.
I gently guided the caterpillar to
another spot so it would not continue
damaging my orchid.
[Music]
You can see that my wilted orchid has
started to grow many new roots. These
new roots will help the plant absorb
more nutrients and water, allowing the
wilted leaves to quickly regain their
vitality.
[Music]
These new roots will help the orchid
absorb nutrients and water more
effectively, thereby restoring vitality
to the leaves and the entire plant.
[Music]
Therefore, roots are often referred to
as the heart of the orchid because they
play an important role in nourishing and
sustaining the vitality of the entire
plant.
[Music]
Therefore, to help orchids grow well, we
need to focus on caring for the roots
first, ensuring they are healthy to
nourish the entire plant.
[Music]
When the roots are healthy, they will
absorb nutrients efficiently, thereby
nourishing the plant and giving us
vibrant flowers.
And when the flowers bloom, they are not
only beautiful, but also fragrant,
bringing joy and relaxation to everyone
around.
I hope this video will be very useful
for you, helping you care for and revive
orchids at home effectively and easily.
If you find this video meaningful, don't
forget to hit like and share so that
more people can learn how to care for
orchids.
Welcome to my channel. I am very happy
to have you here with me sharing the
love for taking care of orchids.
If you want your orchids to grow well
and bloom year round with vibrant
colors, take care to promote strong root
development. That way the plant will
absorb more nutrients. In this video, I
will share simple, easy to do, but very
effective steps to achieve that. Please
watch the video carefully so you don't
miss any important tips.
[Music]
To make natural fertilizer for orchids
yourself, you only need one banana. You
can use either a green or a ripe one.
The banana will provide plenty of
nutrients to help the plant stay healthy
and bloom more easily.
Slice the banana into very thin pieces
uh so the nutrients dissolve more easily
during fermentation, allowing the
natural fertilizer to break down faster
and be absorbed better by the plant.
[Music]
Please comment and let me know which
country you are watching this video
from. It's wonderful that we can connect
and chat together from all around the
world.
Then put the sliced banana into a clean
glass jar to start the fertilizer
fermentation process.
Next, pour about 4 cups of water into
the jar, which is equivalent to one
liter.
To help the fermentation process happen
faster and prevent the banana from
spoiling, I add a little beer to the
mixture.
[Music]
Add about 6 tablespoons of beer,
equivalent to around 100 millm, to help
the mixture ferment effectively and
maintain a pleasant fragrance.
[Music]
And finally, add one tablespoon of honey
to provide extra nutrients and stimulate
a better fermentation process.
[Music]
Uh if you haven't subscribed to the
channel yet, please hit the subscribe
button to support me and not miss any
orchid growing tips. It's wonderful to
have you along on this journey.
[Music]
On the jar lid, make a small ventilation
hole so that the gas produced during
fermentation can escape, preventing the
jar from bursting.
Then place the jar in a cool, airy spot
for about 2 to 3 weeks for the mixture
to ferment completely and be ready to
use.
And here is the result after about 2
weeks of fermentation. The banana has
completely softened, ensuring the
nutrients are fully dissolved and ready
to be used as fertilizer for orchids.
[Music]
Simply take 3 tablespoons of this
fermented banana mixture and mix it with
four cups of water, equivalent to about
one liter, and you will have a natural
fertilizer solution for your orchids.
[Music]
Method one, fertilize the orchid roots
directly with the liquid solution made
from fermented bananas, helping the
roots stay strong and absorb nutrients
more effectively.
Simply water each orchid pot with about
10 tablespoons of this solution, which
is enough to ensure the plant receives
sufficient nutrients without any waste.
[Music]
The fermented banana solution also
provides plenty of natural vitamins and
minerals, helping the orchid's leaves
and flowers stay fresh and glossy while
keeping the flower colors vibrant for
longer. This is a natural, safe, yet
effective way to care for orchids.
[Music]
Um, liquid fertilizer made from
fermented bananas helps orchid roots
grow strong, firm, and healthy. When the
roots are healthy, the plant can absorb
more nutrients from the soil or growing
medium, thereby increasing vitality and
the ability to bloom consistently year
round.
[Music]
Using liquid fertilizer from fermented
bananas also helps improve the structure
of the soil or orchid growing medium,
making the environment around the roots
more loose and airy. This not only
supports root development but also
prevents root rot or fungal diseases.
[Music]
Additionally, the fermented banana
mixture stimulates the growth of
beneficial microorganisms in the soil,
creating a biological balance and
promoting the natural breakdown of
nutrients. As a result, the orchid
absorbs nutrients more effectively and
remains healthy for a long time.
Method two,
you can put the fermented banana mixture
into a spray bottle and spray it
directly onto the orchid's leaves and
flowers. This method helps the plant
absorb nutrients quickly through the
leaves while keeping the leaf surface
clean and glossy, contributing to
longerlasting blooms.
[Music]
Spraying liquid fertilizer made from
fermented bananas directly onto the
leaves helps the orchid absorb essential
nutrients quickly, improves
photosynthesis, and increases the
plant's vitality. When the leaves are
healthy, the plant grows more balanced,
and has a better ability to bloom
consistently.
[Music]
Uh when sprayed on the leaves, the
fermented banana mixture also stimulates
the growth of beneficial microorganisms
on the leaf surface, creating a natural
protective layer against pests and mold.
As a result, the orchid becomes
healthier and the risk of disease is
minimized.
[Music]
But you should not spray this solution
directly onto the flowers because when
the flowers get wet, they can easily
drop, reducing their lifespan. No.
[Music]
Next, if you want the orchid leaves to
stay glossy and firm, take half a lemon,
squeeze out the juice, and prepare to
mix it into the leaf care solution.
[Music]
Then dilute the lemon juice in about 3 L
of water to create a gentle solution
that is safe for the orchid leaves while
still helping them stay glossy and
healthy. Okay.
[Music]
Next, use a soft cloth soaked in the
diluted lemon juice solution and gently
wipe both the top and underside of the
orchid leaves, helping them stay clean,
glossy, and better absorb nutrients.
Lemon has antibacterial and antiseptic
properties, effectively eliminating
harmful fungi and insects. At the same
time, um, wiping the leaves with the
lemon solution adds vitamins, helping
the orchid leaves stay healthy, glossy,
and grow well.
Thanks to being cleaned and nourished,
the orchid leaves can perform
photosynthesis better, helping the plant
store more energy to develop roots, new
leaves, and prepare for the next
blooming cycles.
And so with just a few simple steps, you
have completed caring for the orchid
leaves using diluted lemon water. The
leaves are clean, glossy, protected,
protected, and supplied with essential
vitamins, creating a solid foundation
for the plant to grow strongly and bloom
beautifully in the future.
And here is the result. You can see that
the orchid leaves are well protected,
always fresh, glossy, and healthy.
Besides staying fresh, the leaves also
become firmer, helping the plant
withstand light sunlight and
environmental factors while providing a
solid foundation for the orchid to grow
well. and lounge grid.
[Music]
The newly developed roots are very
strong, thick, and firm, helping the
plant absorb more nutrients, thereby
promoting overall growth and preparing
for upcoming flower buds.
These healthy roots also help the plant
anchor firmly to the growing medium,
providing stability and reducing the
risk of falling or damage, creating a
solid foundation for the long-term
growth of the orchid.
[Music]
And so with strong roots, the orchid
will absorb nutrients optimally, grow
balanced from roots to leaves, and be
ready for the next vibrant blooms. This
is the essential foundation for the
orchid to stay healthy, and bloom
consistently.
[Music]
The potassium in bananas helps orchids
resist drought very effectively. Thanks
to potassium, water is transported
better from the roots to the stems,
leaves, and flowers, helping the blooms
last longer, maintain vibrant colors,
and reduce the risk of wilting or
premature fading.
Potassium also stimulates the orchid to
produce more flower buds, helping the
plant bloom consistently and increasing
the number of flowers on each spike.
[Music]
With this very simple care method, you
can confidently grow and care for
orchids at home, ensuring the plant
stays healthy, the leaves remain glossy,
and the flowers bloom vibrantly all year
round.
I hope you enjoy this video. If you find
it helpful, don't forget to subscribe to
the channel and share it so more people
can learn how to care for orchids
naturally.
Thank you for watching. Wishing you a
wonderful day. And may your orchids
always stay fresh, green, and bloom
beautifully.