Welcome to this cozy little space where
we care for our beloved orchid pots
together. Today I am very excited to
share with you a simple but effective
method to propagate orchids at home.
That is stem cutting.
With each step I will guide you through
you will feel a connection with the
plant. And it is patience along with
care that will bring brilliant results.
Let's explore stem cutting for orchids
together so that each young chute
becomes a beautiful flower in your
garden.
Today's ingredient to make a natural
fertilizer that stimulates orchid roots
is ginger. You only need a small piece
of ginger like this and then carefully
cut it into thin slices.
Ginger contains special natural
compounds that help stimulate the growth
of orchid keis while also promoting root
and leaf development naturally.
Let me know in the comments which
country you're watching from. It's
wonderful that we can connect and share
with each other from all around the
world.
And if you haven't subscribed yet, click
the subscribe button to support me and
not miss any orchid growing tips. It's
wonderful to have you along on this
journey.
After slicing the ginger, the next step
is to put the fresh ginger slices into a
clean jar.
Using a clean jar will help preserve the
ginger better and retain its natural
nutrients, ready to stimulate the growth
of orchid roots and leaves.
Next, pour about 300 ml of warm water
into the jar, just enough to cover the
ginger slices.
The next ingredient to make natural
fertilizer is molasses. And you only
need a small teaspoon.
Molasses contains many minerals and
natural sugars, helping provide energy
for orchid roots to grow strongly and
stimulating beneficial microorganisms in
the soil to become more active.
After stirring the molasses into the
ginger solution, cover the jar tightly
and place it in a cool, ventilated area
away from direct sunlight for about 3
weeks.
Once the natural fertilizer solution is
ready, the next step is to select
healthy flower spikes for propagation
using the stem cutting method.
Choose sturdy flower stems that are free
from pests or damage as these will be
the foundation for creating healthy new
plants.
In some orchid gardens, when the flowers
bloom, growers often remove the dormant
buds that haven't opened before selling.
This habit makes it difficult for buyers
to propagate orchids from flower spikes
using the stem cutting method because
the potential stems for creating new
plants have been removed.
The orchid I bought had most of its
dormant buds removed before blooming.
Therefore, all the flower spikes on the
plant will also need to be removed and
we won't be able to use them for
propagation through the stem cutting
method.
Next, I also bought this orchid from an
industrial orchid garden when it was
blooming. And just like before, they had
removed all the dormant buds that hadn't
opened. This means we also cannot
propagate from the flower spikes as the
potential buds to create new plants are
no longer there.
As for this orchid, I planted it from
the beginning in my own garden. So, the
dormant buds that haven't bloomed are
still intact. This is wonderful because
we can use these buds for propagation
through the stem cutting method,
creating healthy new plants ready to
grow.
The buds that have already bloomed like
this, we will carefully cut off.
And the buds that haven't bloomed,
meaning inside this protective sheath,
there are still dormant buds have the
potential to develop into healthy new
orchids.
Therefore, we will proceed with stem
cutting from these buds, maximizing the
growth potential that the mother plant
has prepared.
Next, use a sharp knife to trim the cut,
completely removing any bruised parts
because bruised areas are prone to
rotting. and can harm the dormant buds.
A clean cut will keep the flower spike
tidy and safe, increasing the chances of
strong root development when propagating
through stem cutting.
Oh my god.
After trimming the cut, the next step is
to gently peel off the protective sheath
around the dormant bud. This sheath
protects the bud during development. But
when performing stem cutting, removing
it allows nutrients from the ginger
molasses solution to penetrate directly
into the bud, stimulating faster root
and leaf growth.
Handle it carefully so the dormant bud
remains intact and ready to root,
preparing to become a healthy new
orchid.
This is the ginger extract after 21 days
of fermentation, fully prepared and
ready to use. You will notice a layer of
natural white mold on top, which is a
sign that the solution is working well.
The mild sour aroma and clear color of
the liquid are the standards to ensure
its effectiveness when fertilizing
orchid dormant buds.
Next, take about 50 ml of the finished
ginger extract solution to prepare for
the stem cutting process.
Next, pour one liter of water into the
ginger extract solution to dilute it.
This dilution helps the nutrients from
the ginger distribute evenly, just
enough to nourish the dormant buds,
promote strong root development, and
encourage healthy leaf growth without
overloading the buds.
After diluting, pour this water to soak
the cutings for about 20 minutes. The
soaking time is just enough to allow the
nutrients from the solution to penetrate
deeply into the dormant buds,
stimulating quick root growth and
healthy leaf development.
The remaining mixture can be poured into
a spray bottle to water the other
orchids in your garden.
This helps the orchids receive
additional nutrients from the ginger,
stimulates strong root and leaf growth,
and enhances the overall vitality of the
entire garden.
When spraying the ginger extract
mixture, the natural nutrients from the
ginger penetrate deeply into the roots,
helping them grow quickly and strong and
increasing their ability to absorb
nutrients from the surrounding
environment. This creates a solid
foundation for the plant's overall
development.
The leaves will become glossy green,
lush, and vibrant when provided with
sufficient nutrients. Regularly spraying
the solution keeps the leaves healthy,
showcasing the strong vitality of the
orchid.
The ginger extract mixture helps the
flowers on the stems maintain their
vibrant appearance for longer, reducing
rapid wilting. This way you can enjoy
the beauty of fresh flowers for an
extended time, adding a highlight to
your garden.
Uh after soaking the cutings in the
solution for about 20 minutes, gently
remove them and pat dry with a soft
cloth. This helps remove excess water on
the dormant buds, preventing
accumulation that could cause rotting
during stem cutting.
After drying the cutings, sprinkle a
little cinnamon powder on the cut.
Cinnamon has antibacterial properties,
helping the cut heal quickly and
preventing bacteria or fungi from
causing rot. Uh protecting the dormant
buds during the stem cutting process.
And don't forget to sprinkle cinnamon
powder on the cuts of newly trimmed
orchid flower spikes. This helps protect
the cuts, prevent bacteria and mold from
entering, and supports the plant in
recovering more quickly after the
flowers fade.
Then then let the cutings or orchid pots
rest for about 1 day without watering,
allowing the cuts to dry completely.
This helps prevent the cuts from rotting
and creates a natural protective layer
before proceeding with stem cutting or
further care.
Uh while waiting for the cuts to dry, I
take the opportunity to recycle used
plastic cups, turning them into tools
for rooting the cutings.
Small, clean, and manageable plastic
cups help create an ideal environment
for dormant buds to root, maintain
proper moisture, and allow easy
observation of the young plant's growth.
This recycling is both economical and
environmentally friendly while also
preparing you for the next step of stem
cutting.
For the rooting pot, I choose pots with
drainage holes at the bottom. Uh the
drainage holes help prevent water
logging, maintain moderate moisture in
the growing medium, and ensure the
cutting's roots develop healthily.
For the main growing medium, I choose
finely shredded pine bark that has been
thoroughly sterilized.
Shredded pine bark retains moisture
well, drains effectively, and provides a
well-arrated environment for orchid
roots to grow, while also limiting the
development of fungi and diseases.
To complete the rooting pot, I add a
little thoroughly sterilized dry moss on
top of the pot. This layer of moss helps
maintain stable moisture for the cutings
while creating a soft environment that
protects the dormant buds and young
roots as the plant begins to grow.
After one day, when the cuts on the
cutings have completely dried, we
proceed to plant the cutings into the
pots with the prepared growing medium.
Gently place the dormant bud into the
growing medium, making sure the bud
faces upward.
Correct orientation helps the roots grow
downward while the leaves and young
shoots grow upward, creating balance and
increasing the chances of success when
propagating through stem cutting.
Then regularly spray water to maintain
moisture, especially when the growing
medium starts to dry.
Maintaining moderate moisture helps the
cutting roots develop well, prevents the
dormant buds from wilting, and creates
an ideal environment for the young
plants to root quickly.
Then gently use pins to secure the
cutting so that the dormant buds make
good contact with the shredded pine bark
and the dry moss on the surface.
This helps the plant stay upright,
prevents shifting during root and leaf
development, and ensures the dormant
buds receive adequate moisture and
nutrients from the growing medium.
Next, use a plastic cup with holes
punched around it to cover the top of
the pot, creating a mini greenhouse.
The mini greenhouse helps maintain
stable humidity, protects the cutings
from drying out quickly, and creates an
ideal environment for the dormant buds
to develop.
And here are the results after 45 days
of rooting the cutings.
You can see that the small dormant buds
after rooting have now developed into
fairly healthy young orchids with deep
rooted roots and lush green leaves.
Um, the young orchid from this cutting
is still small, but its roots and leaves
are developing very healthily. This
proves that the stem cutting method
combined with the use of the ginger
extract solution and the prepared
growing medium has created ideal
conditions for the young plant to
develop fully.
The young orchid from this cutting,
though smaller than the previous one, is
quite sturdy. Although the leaves
haven't fully developed, the plant has
already grown its first root, showing
that the dormant bud is rooting and
ready to continue growing. This is a
positive sign indicating that the stem
cutting process is progressing well and
the young orchid will continue to mature
healthily.
Continue to spray water regularly when
the growing medium starts to dry,
maintaining the necessary moisture for
the roots and dormant buds. At the same
time, place the rooting pot in a cool
area away from direct sunlight to help
the young orchid develop steadily with
strong roots and vibrant green leaves.
And here are the results after 3 months
of stem cutting.
You can see that from a single cutting
with just dormant buds, they have now
developed into very healthy young
orchids with strong roots and lush green
leaves. This process proves that with
patience and proper care, even small
dormant buds can become vibrant young
orchids ready for the next blooming
seasons.
Um, when the orchid has developed strong
roots That is the ideal time to start
fertilizing the plant.
What do you think about the way I
propagate orchids using the stem cutting
method? Don't hesitate to leave a
comment and share your thoughts. I'm
really looking forward to hearing your
feedback and experiences.
I hope you enjoy this video. If you find
it helpful, don't forget to hit like and
subscribe to the channel so you won't
miss future tips on caring for orchids
naturally and easily. And don't rush to
leave. Watch until the end to discover
important tips that help your orchids
grow healthy and bloom beautifully all
year round.
Next, take 3 teaspoons of ginger extract
and mix with 500 ml of clean water to
water water the orchid. This solution
will provide sufficient nutrients,
stimulate strong root growth and lush
green leaves, and enhance the overall
vitality of the plant.
Then water the orchid one to two times a
month with this ginger extract liquid
fertilizer.
You can also alternate with other
natural fertilizers to diversify the
nutrient sources for the orchid.
Rotating different types of fertilizers
helps the plant absorb all the necessary
minerals, stimulating even and healthy
growth of roots, leaves, and flower
buds. This combination not only enhances
care efficiency, but also helps the
orchid adapt well to its environment,
maintaining long-lasting vitality.
Care for your orchid with all the love
and dedication you have for plants. When
you patiently observe, water, fertilize,
and attend to every small detail,
gradually you will see your garden
filled with healthy orchids blooming in
vibrant colors. Loving care not only
helps the plants grow well, but also
brings joy and happiness every day in
your garden.
When you infuse that love into every
small action, you not only nurture the
orchids, but also create an inspiring
space where each vibrant flower tells a
story of care and joyful creativity. Let
your orchid garden become an endless
source of inspiration where everyone can
admire its brilliant beauty and learn
how to care for and cherish plants
everyday.
Thank you for watching and accompanying
me on the journey of caring for orchids.
I wish you always happiness, full of
energy, and lots of joy while tending to
your garden. See you in the next videos
where we will explore more tips to help
orchids grow healthy and bloom
beautifully.