Welcome to the happiness garden. Um, in
today's video, I will guide you on how
to revive an orchid from being nearly
dead to blooming with stunning,
beautiful flowers.
You can see that this orchid is rotting,
its leaves are wilting, and the plant is
nearly dying.
If not treated in time, the condition
will continue to spread and the plant
may die.
[Music]
First, you need to remove all the
damaged leaves. This helps the plant
focus its energy on the healthy parts
and prevents the rot from spreading.
Please comment and let me know which
country you are watching this video
from. It's wonderful that we can chhat
together from all over the world.
Um, if you haven't subscribed to the
channel yet, please hit the subscribe
button to support me and not miss any
orchid growing tips. It's wonderful to
have you along for the journey.
Next, you need to carefully check the
roots of the plant.
You can see that many roots are hollow
and rotting.
Next, you cut off all the damaged roots.
This helps the plant prevent the rot
from spreading and focus on developing
the healthy roots.
[Music]
Then you cut off the damaged parts of
the stem. This helps the plant prevent
diseases from spreading and focus its
energy on the healthy parts.
[Music]
Next, you rinse the plant under running
water. This helps remove dirt and
bacteria, creating the best conditions
for the plant to recover.
Next, you take about 4 cups of water,
equivalent to 1.2 L, to prepare a
disinfecting solution for the plant and
the substrate before planting.
[Music]
Then take half a lemon and squeeze out
the juice to mix into the disinfecting
solution for the plant and substrate.
[Music]
Lemon contains organic acids, vitamin C,
and many minerals which help disinfect,
provide nutrients, and protect the plant
from bacteria.
[Music]
After mixing, pour this water and soak
the orchid for about 20 minutes. This
helps disinfect, remove bacteria, and
prepare the plant for replanting.
[Music]
Next, we will prepare natural fertilizer
to care for the orchid.
To make the fertilizer, I use rice. Rice
contains a lot of starch, protein, and
minerals, which help nourish the
orchid's roots and leaves, and also
support the plant's recovery after a
period of weakness.
Take three teaspoons of rice and mix
with four cups of water, equivalent to
about one liter.
[Music]
And here is the GE banana that I
fermented beforehand, which helps
provide natural nutrients for the
orchid.
[Music]
Take 50 mm equivalent to a little over 3
tablespoons to mix with the solution.
[Music]
Cover and let it sit for one day to
allow the mixture to ferment slightly.
[Music]
After soaking for 20 minutes, take the
plant out to drain before replanting.
Then you can use this disinfecting
solution to soak the pine bark. This
helps clean the substrate and remove
bacteria before using it to plant the
orchid.
Soak the pine bark for 20 minutes. Uh
this helps remove bacteria and
impurities.
[Music]
After soaking for 20 minutes, take out
the pine bark and let it drain before
planting the orchid.
After the pine bark and orchid have
drained, we proceed to plant the orchid
in a new pot. Using a new pot helps the
plant grow better, avoids leftover
bacteria, and provides space for healthy
root development.
[Music]
I usually place some foam at the bottom
of the pot, then plant the orchid on
top. This helps with good drainage,
prevents root rot, and creates an ideal
environment for the plant to grow.
[Music]
When inserting the pine bark, gently
arrange it evenly around the roots. This
helps stabilize the plant, ensures good
drainage, and creates an ideal
environment for root development.
After inserting the pine bark, gently
tap the sides of the pot to secure the
substrate. This helps the plant stand
firmly and allows the roots to have good
contact with the substrate, supporting
growth.
After planting, sprinkle a little moss
on the surface of the pot. This helps
retain moisture, creates a cool
environment, and supports the orchid's
healthy growth.
[Music]
Then place the orchid pot in a cool,
ventilated area. After 1 day, when the
roots have stabilized, you can start
applying natural fertilizer so the plant
can absorb nutrients most effectively.
[Music]
After soaking for one day, stir well to
dissolve the nutrients in the fermented
mixture. This helps the orchid absorb
the fertilizer better.
[Music]
Then strain out the sediment. This keeps
the solution clean and allows it to
penetrate the roots easily when
fertilizing.
[Music]
After straining out the sediment, pour
this mixture evenly over the roots and
substrate. This helps the orchid absorb
nutrients effectively and grow
healthily.
You water this mixture two to three
times a month. Regular care helps the
orchid absorb enough nutrients, recover
quickly, and grow healthily.
[Music]
Uh this mixture contains starch,
protein, vitamins and minerals from rice
and banana which help nourish the roots,
leaves and stem of the plant.
Or you can put the mixture into a spray
bottle and mist it evenly over the
roots, leaves, and substrate. This
method helps the nutrients penetrate
evenly, supporting the orchid's quick
recovery and healthy growth.
Keep spraying two to three times a
month. Regular care will help the orchid
quickly regain its vitality and soon
grow new roots and leaves.
[Music]
After watering, you can soak the entire
orchid pot in this mixture for about 20
minutes. This allows the roots to absorb
the maximum nutrients and recover
faster.
[Music]
After soaking for 20 minutes, take the
orchid pot out and place it in a spot
with gentle sunlight. This helps the
plant photosynthesize better, lets the
roots dry quickly, reduces fungus and
disease, and supports healthy recovery.
You can see that the dormant node on
this orchid's stem may develop into a
baby orchid. Right here,
I gently peel off the protective layer
on the dormant node to help stimulate
the sprouting process. This allows the
bud to have better contact with air and
nutrients, helping it grow faster and
stronger.
[Music]
Then place the orchid pot in a spot with
gentle sunlight so the orchid can
photosynthesize.
In addition to applying natural
fertilizer, you need to regularly check
the moisture of the substrate. When you
see it is dry, gently mist with water to
keep it moist. Then patiently wait for
the orchid to recover and grow again.
And here is the result after 2 months of
recovery care. You can see that from the
dormant node on the mother plant's stem,
a healthy, vibrant baby orchid has now
grown. A testament to patience and
proper care.
From the leaves to the roots, the baby
orchid is growing very healthily,
showing that it is absorbing enough
nutrients and has an ideal living
environment.
Uh the roots of the mother orchid are
also growing vigorously which helps the
plant absorb water and nutrients better
to nourish the baby orchid so it grows
quickly and healthily.
[Music]
I continue to fertilize this orchid with
natural fertilizer made from rice water
and GE banana two to three times a
month. This helps the plant receive
nutrients regularly, stay healthy, grow
quickly, and bloom again soon.
[Music]
What do you think about the way I
revived this little orchid? Don't
hesitate to leave a comment and share
your thoughts. I'd love to hear your
feedback and experiences.
[Music]
Don't leave the video just yet. Keep
watching to see how I take care of the
orchid until it blooms beautifully.
[Music]
Uh if you face any difficulties during
the orchid planting process, don't
hesitate to leave me a comment. I'm
always ready to support you so you can
grow healthy orchids that bloom
abundantly.
[Music]
Then place the orchid pot in a spot with
gentle sunlight. Soft light will help
the plant photosynthesize effectively,
absorb nutrients better, and recover
more quickly.
[Music]
And here is the result after 5 months of
patient care. You can see that from an
an orchid that was nearly dead, it has
now revived strongly and is blooming
beautifully. Truly something to be proud
of.
[Music]
Look closely. You will see that the
roots of the mother plant and the baby
plant as well as the leaves of both have
become lush and green. A clear sign that
the plant is recovering well.
[Music]
In addition to the English voiceover, we
have now created French, German,
Italian, Spanish, Portuguese, Japanese,
Hindi, Dutch, Polish, Korean, and
Indonesian versions to help you listen
to and understand the content more
easily.
To listen in your preferred language,
open the video and click on settings,
the gear icon to select the desired
audio language.
[Music]
The vibrant petals are in full bloom,
like a sweet reward for the patience and
love you have given the plant. This is
proof that as long as you care for it
properly and never give up, even an
orchid that was nearly dead can revive
and shine brighter than ever.
[Music]
Believe that you can do this, too. Start
caring for your weak orchids today, and
before long, you will be able to admire
the stunning blooms you nurtured with
your own hands.
[Music]
Share your care results in the comments.
I would love to see the blooms you have
revived and together spread joy to many
other orchid lovers.
[Music]
If you found this video helpful, don't
forget to hit the subscribe button and
turn on the notification bell. That way,
you won't miss any tips to keep your
orchids healthy and blooming
beautifully.
[Music]
Thank you for staying with me until the
end of the video. I wish you always find
joy and peace while taking care of your
beautiful orchids.
[Music]