Hello everyone. I'm so glad you came to
my channel.
When growing orchids, everyone wants the
flowers to bloom for a long time, right?
And each orchid pot will bloom a lot of
flowers all year round.
[Music]
Now, I will show you what is the best
fertilizer for orchids.
Uh, if you follow us till the end of
this video, you will learn how to make
orchids bloom all year round.
[Music]
Now, let's get started.
And when the flowers have all bloomed, I
cut off all the places that are no
longer able to flower.
[Music]
If you haven't subscribed to the channel
yet, please hit the subscribe button to
support me and not miss any orchid
growing tips.
It's great to have you along.
[Music]
Then, sprinkle white cement on the cut
to help the wound dry faster, limit
bacteria and fungi from entering,
thereby promoting the wound healing
process.
[Music]
Unflowered nodes like this will have the
potential to sprout buds or flower buds.
Here
[Music]
I peel off the protective film that will
make it easier to germinate.
[Music]
Then I took the tomatoes to make natural
fertilizer for the orchids.
[Music]
Take a slice of tomato like this.
Tomatoes contain a lot of vitamin A,
vitamin C, and are rich in potassium,
calcium, and phosphorus, which are very
good for orchids. Therefore, when caring
for orchids with tomatoes, orchids will
grow very quickly.
Please comment to me which country you
are watching the video from. It's great
that we can chat together from all over
the world.
[Music]
Puree tomatoes with 1 cup water.
Then filter the water.
[Music]
I added water to get 2.20462
lb of tomato juice, about one liter.
[Music]
Method one. Then gently wipe the leaves
with the tomato mixture, a natural way
to clean and nourish the plant.
Then using cotton soaked in tomato
mixture and wrapping it around the
dormant buds is a good way to stimulate
bud growth.
[Music]
You should do this every 7 days to
create the right humidity to stimulate
dormant buds to develop into flowers.
[Music]
I continue to wrap cotton soaked in
tomato mixture here will help this
flower branch continue to bloom new
flowers.
[Music]
This method maintains moisture for the
flower stem and the flower tip recovers
very quickly.
On normal days, you just need to use
regular water to keep the flower
branches moist.
Way two.
Way too.
[Music]
Tomatoes contain many vitamins and
minerals that can help make the leaves
healthier while removing dirt and
residue on the leaf surface.
[Music]
Uh, you can use a soft cotton or clean
cloth soaked in a diluted tomato mixture
to gently wipe, helping the plant absorb
light better and grow strongly.
Please apply this every 2 weeks to the
tree.
[Music]
the leaves after being taken care of
will be green and healthy like this.
[Music]
Way three.
You can also use this tomato juice to
spray on the top and bottom of the
leaves.
And spray evenly on the root.
Wave four.
Use this water to water the orchid once
every two weeks.
Orchids grow because nutrients are
transported from the roots to all parts
of the orchid, including the flower
stock furthest from the roots.
Before fertilizing, water the orchid
pots thoroughly. This will help the
plant absorb the fertilizer better.
[Music]
Now, let's see the results after taking
care of them with natural fertilizer
from tomatoes
[Music]
And with this simple way, the
regenerated flower branches will be very
big and fat.
[Music]
Uh this way I also get a seedling
orchid.
[Music]
This way also helps flower buds to be
big and healthy.
[Music]
So many flower buds are reborn in this
way.
[Music]
and uh gradually your garden will always
be filled with colorful orchids.
How do you like my method of caring for
orchids to bloom all year round? Feel
free to leave a comment and share your
thoughts. I would love to hear your
experiences and suggestions.
Thanks for watching. Have fun and have a
beautiful orchid garden.
Welcome to my channel.
When you buy an orchid or someone gives
it to you.
You need to do the following.
[Music]
First, you need to remove the packaging
from the orchid.
[Music]
Next, leave the orchid in a cool place
for a few hours to allow it to adjust to
the new climate.
[Music]
Uh if the growing medium is moss or
small wood chips, it is only suitable
for industrial orchid gardens.
[Music]
[Applause]
Because moss retains a lot of moisture,
many plant roots rot due to water
logging.
If you haven't subscribed to the channel
yet, please hit the subscribe button to
support me and not miss any orchid
growing tips. It's great to have you
along.
[Music]
Uh the humidity was too high, so the
leaves were also infected with black
mold.
In addition to the English dub, we've
now created dubs in French, German,
Italian, Spanish, Portuguese, Japanese,
Hindi, and Indonesian to help you hear
and understand the content more easily.
[Music]
Therefore, you need to remove all moss
or old growing medium.
Um because this type of substrate is
only suitable for industrial orchid
gardens that can control special
humidity.
[Music]
Please comment to me which country you
are watching the video from. It's it's
great that we can chat together from all
over the world.
[Music]
Then you cut off all damaged roots.
and cut off all wilted flowers.
[Music]
Then you take one aloe vera leaf.
and take a clove of garlic.
[Music]
Put all the aloe vera and garlic in a
jar and soak it with 2 L of water.
[Music]
Wait 30 minutes for the nutrients from
the garlic and aloe vera to dissolve
into the water.
[Music]
30 minutes later,
Soak the roots in this solution for 30
minutes.
[Music]
Garlic and aloe vera help stimulate root
growth and effectively fight harmful
insects and fungi.
[Music]
Um, spraying this solution on the entire
orchid will help repel insects,
eliminate fungal diseases, and keep the
leaves green.
[Music]
Then clean the black mold stains with
this solution.
[Music]
This helps prevent orchids from
recurring mold.
[Music]
Now I recycle used plastic containers to
make orchid pots.
[Music]
I put a layer of pummus on the bottom of
the orchid pot.
[Music]
This helps keep the bottom of the orchid
pot clear so the roots don't get water
logged.
[Music]
For the top, I use dried pine bark as a
growing medium
[Music]
and mix in some dry moss.
When planting, cushion the substrate
tightly so that the roots do not move.
[Music]
Insert the flower branch into the right
position to help prevent the orchid from
shaking.
[Music]
After planting, let it dry for 5 days
before watering.
[Music]
Take care of your orchids with all the
love you have for plants and they will
bloom all over the garden this way.
[Music]
Thank you for watching the video. Good
luck and see you in the next videos.