Welcome to the happiness garden. Today I
want to tell you the story of the
journey to revive an orchid that seemed
to have no chance of survival.
This orchid had only a single leaf left,
wilted and wrinkled as if all its life
had left it. But I believe that with a
little patience and love, even plants
that seem dead can be revived and bloom
again.
So let's begin the journey to revive
this orchid together.
This is an orchid that had been
discarded. Looking at it, the leaves
were wilted, wrinkled, and seemed
completely lifeless. But I believe that
with just a little patience and love,
even plants that seem dead can be
revived.
So, I decided to take the plant home to
revive it. If you also have a weak plant
or one that seems beyond saving, don't
give up. Believe that with just a little
patience and love, you can completely
revive your plant. Let's begin step by
step and witness the miracle happening
right before your eyes.
First, I removed all the damaged leaves,
helping to prevent disease from
spreading to the remaining leaf while
allowing the plant to focus on nurturing
its roots and the single remaining leaf.
Every care action, no matter how small,
contributes to reviving the plant. And
step by step, hope rises again in the
heart.
[Music]
Next, we need to check the roots.
You can see that many roots are hollow.
Probably only one to two fresh roots
remain. This is exactly why the orchid
cannot absorb enough water and
nutrients, leading to wilted, wrinkled,
and falling leaves.
[Music]
All the damaged roots need to be cut
off. This helps remove the rotted parts,
prevents disease from spreading to the
remaining healthy roots, and allows the
plant to focus on nurturing the
remaining strong roots.
Only keep the fresh roots. These roots
will serve as the foundation for the
plant to absorb water and nutrients,
nourishing the single leaf and new
shoots.
After keeping only the fresh roots, I
rinse them under running water. This
helps remove dirt, impurities, and any
remaining pathogens, ensuring the roots
are completely clean and ready to absorb
nutrients from the new substrate.
Um, if you haven't subscribed to the
channel yet, click the subscribe button
to support me and make sure you don't
miss any orchid care tips. It's
wonderful to have you along on this
journey.
Next, take about 10 g of ginger to
prepare fertilizer, which helps
stimulate new root growth. Ginger not
only provides nutrients but also boosts
the plant's resistance, creating a solid
foundation for the revival of the single
leaf and new shoots.
Uh, chop the ginger into small pieces to
prepare for making fertilizer. Chopping
it helps release nutrients faster,
allowing the plant's roots to to absorb
them more effectively.
[Music]
Please comment and let me know which
country you are watching the video from.
It's wonderful that we can connect and
chat together from all around the world.
[Music]
After chopping, put the ginger into a
clean jar to prepare for fermentation.
[Music]
Next, add one liter of water for
fermentation.
[Music]
And the final ingredient is rice. Rice
contains plenty of starch and essential
nutrients, helping nourish the roots and
stimulate strong growth of new shoots.
Take three tablespoons of rice and add
them to the ginger and water mixture for
fermentation.
When combined with proper fermentation
steps, this will be the perfect natural
fertilizer, helping the plant regain
vitality, nourish new roots, and prepare
for the vibrant flowers about to bloom.
Then cover the jar and let the mixture
ferment for about 1 hour. This
fermentation time allows the nutrients
from the ginger and rice to fully
dissolve into the water, creating a
nutrient-rich liquid fertilizer.
[Music]
After fermenting for about 1 hour, stir
well so that the nutrients from the
ginger and rice are fully dissolved in
the water. Stirring thoroughly makes the
liquid fertilizer uniform, ensuring that
every drop watered onto the roots is
nutrient-rich,
stimulating strong new root growth and
restoring the plant's vitality.
After stirring well, strain out the
residue. This makes the fertilizer
solution clear and smooth, allowing it
to penetrate the roots easily and
ensuring maximum nutrient absorption.
Uh after straining out the residue, pour
the filtered mixture to soak the wilted
orchid with wrinkled leaves for about 20
minutes. This soaking helps stimulate
new root growth, directly provides
nutrients to the remaining live roots,
and awakens the plant's latent vitality.
While waiting for the soak, I repurpose
a plastic cup to use as a seedling
container. This helps prepare a place
for new root shoots to grow, makes use
of available materials, and saves costs.
[Music]
After soaking for about 20 minutes, take
the orchid out and gently dry the leaves
with a soft cloth to prepare for
planting.
[Music]
Drying helps remove excess water,
prevents leaf rot, and provides the best
conditions for the roots to make contact
with the new substrate.
[Music]
Use a stake to secure the orchid before
placing it into the seedling container
container. Securing it helps the plant
stand upright, prevents it from tilting
or falling, and keeps the roots and
leaves in the proper position for
growth.
[Music]
Uh then place the orchid into the
seedling container and make sure the
plants That stands firmly.
[Music]
Then pour water in like when growing
orchids semihydroponically with the
water level just reaching the roots.
This keeps the roots adequately moist,
prevents water logging, and creates
optimal conditions for strong new root
growth and maximum nutrient absorption.
[Music]
After adding water to the pot, place the
orchid in a cool, airy spot. Moderate
temperature and gentle light help
prevent plant stress, allow new roots to
grow strong, and gradually restore the
single leaf to a healthy green. A well
ventilated location is a crucial factor
for the plant's safe revival.
After soaking, you can repurpose the
mixture by pouring it into a spray
bottle and misting it on other orchids
in the garden.
[Music]
This provides nutrients directly to the
roots and leaves, stimulates healthy
growth, and maximizes the use of the
natural fertilizer you just prepared.
It's a smart way to ensure all the
orchids in the garden gain vitality and
get ready for vibrant blooms.
When sprayed directly onto the roots and
leaves, the plant also receives starch
and minerals from the rice, helping the
leaf maintain its green color, and the
new shoots grow strong. Using this
mixture not only saves resources, but
also spreads vitality throughout the
garden, bringing vibrant flowers in the
near future.
You should spray this mixture every 2
weeks, alternating with regular
watering. This ensures the plant
receives continuous nutrients while
maintaining proper moisture for the
roots.
And here are the results after 3 weeks.
[Music]
Uh you can see many new roots growing
showing that the plant is recovering
strongly.
The single remaining leaf is still soft,
but new leaves have begun to grow,
bringing full vitality to the plant.
This is proof that with love, patience,
and proper care, even plants that seem
beyond saving can be revived, preparing
for the vibrant flowers about to bloom.
[Music]
Um, from now on I use the fermented
ginger and rice fertilizer mixture to
care for this orchid. Providing
nutrients regularly helps the new roots
grow strong, restores the single leaf to
a healthy green, and allows the new
shoots to continue growing robustly,
bringing full vitality to the plant.
[Music]
Soak the roots in the mixture for about
20 minutes once a
Soaking helps the roots directly absorb
nutrients from the ginger and rice,
stimulating rapid new root growth and
restoring the plant's vitality.
While waiting for the soak, use a soft
cloth to absorb the mixture and gently
wipe both the top and bottom surfaces of
the leaves.
This allows the nutrients from the
ginger and rice to be absorbed directly
by the leaves while also cleaning dust
and bacteria, strengthening the leaf's
health and supporting the plant's
recovery. Such meticulous care actions
help the orchid revive quickly.
[Music]
After soaking for 20 minutes, place the
orchid back into the seedling container
and continue soaking the roots with the
fertilizer mixture once a week. This
regular care helps the roots
continuously absorb nutrients from the
ginger and rice, stimulates strong new
root growth, restores the single leaf to
a healthy green, and allows the new
shoots to continue growing robustly.
[Music]
Each time you soak the roots in the
fertilizer, you should also change the
water in the seedling container. This
keeps the water clean, prevents bacteria
and fungi from growing, and ensures the
roots absorb nutrients effectively.
[Music]
Uh when combining regular fertilizer
soaking with proper water changes, the
orchid will recover strongly, the single
leaf will return to a healthy green and
the new shoots will grow robustly.
Then continue placing the orchid pot in
a cool, airy spot. A well ventilated
space helps the plant avoid stress,
allows roots to grow strong, and
restores the single leaf to a healthy
green. A cool location with gentle light
is a crucial factor for the plant's safe
recovery.
[Music]
And here are the results after 2 months.
Um, you can see that the roots have
grown very strong, showing that the
plant is recovering well.
These new roots will help the plant
absorb nutrients more effectively,
nourish the single leaf, and support the
healthy growth of new shoots after
planting in the substrate. When the
roots become strong, the plant will
fully recover with healthy leaves and
shoots, preparing for vibrant flowers
about to bloom, bringing full vitality
to the garden.
What do you think about my method for
reviving weak orchids? Please leave a
comment and share your feedback with me.
If you encounter any difficulties while
growing orchids, don't hesitate to leave
a comment. I'm always ready to help you
grow healthy orchids that bloom
beautifully.
[Music]
The single remaining leaf has also begun
to turn green again, and new leaf shoots
are emerging strong, bringing full
vitality to the plant. This is a clear
sign that the plant is on its journey of
revival and preparing for the vibrant
flowers about to bloom.
Now, I plant the orchid into a new pot
so it has space to grow in an outdoor
environment.
Planting in a spacious pot allows the
new roots to stretch out, absorb
sufficient nutrients and water, and
enables the leaves and new shoots to
grow strong. This is an important step
for the plant to fully recover and
prepare for the vibrant flowers about to
bloom.
After planting, care for the orchid like
any other plant in the garden.
Be patient and nurture the plant every
day, and you will witness the miracle of
its revival right before your eyes with
vibrant flowers as a well-deserved
reward for your efforts.
How did you feel about today's video?
Please comment and share your thoughts
and experiences. Your feedback is very
important, helping us share more useful
orchid care tips and inspire every
orchid to grow healthy and bloom
beautifully.
Thank you for watching. Goodbye and
wishing you success in caring for your
orchids with green leaves and beautiful
blooms. See you in the next videos.
[Music]