Welcome to my channel.
When you grow orchids, it is unavoidable
that the leaves may rot.
If your orchid's leaves are rotting like
this, don't worry because in this video,
I'm sharing a new method to help you
quickly treat leaf rot in time.
First, you need to cut off the rotting
part of the leaf from the orchid. This
helps prevent the rot from spreading to
the stem and other healthy leaves.
Then we check the roots and remove any
rotten ones from the orchid. This helps
prevent the rot from spreading
throughout the entire plant from the
roots to the stem and leaves.
[Music]
Please comment to me which country
you're watching the video from. It's
great that we can chat together from all
over the world.
[Music]
If you haven't subscribed to the channel
yet, please hit the subscribe button to
support me and not miss any orchid care
tips. It's wonderful to have you along.
[Music]
If you encounter any difficulties while
growing orchids, don't hesitate to
comment to me. I'm always ready to help
you so you can grow healthy orchids that
bloom beautifully.
[Music]
In addition to the English voiceover, we
have now created voiceovers in French,
German, Italian, Spanish, Portuguese,
Japanese, Hindi, and Indonesian to help
you listen and understand the content
more easily.
Please go to the settings in the video
to choose the audio version in the
language that suits you.
Uh, it's best to check the orchid once a
week to remove yellow or rotting leaves.
For orchids with rotting leaves caused
by bacteria, we need to isolate them
from the garden to treat the rot. This
helps prevent the rot from spreading to
other plants.
Now I am using turmeric powder because
it has excellent natural antibacterial
and anti-inflammatory properties which
are great for treating orchid leaf rot.
[Music]
Apply turmeric powder to the cut as it
helps the wound heal quickly.
This helps reduce the risk of infection
and aids the plant in recovering
quickly.
[Music]
Moreover, turmeric helps stimulate the
process of cell regeneration, allowing
the cut to heal quickly and the plant to
return to a healthy state.
Then place it in a well ventilated area
and avoid watering to help the cut heal
quickly.
Then add one teaspoon of turmeric powder
into a bottle and mix it with four cups
of hot water, about one liter.
Cover the bottle and wait for the water
to cool down.
This is oatmeal which can be used as a
very good natural fertilizer for
orchids.
Take 1 tbsp of oatmeal powder and mix it
with four cups of room temperature
water, about one liter.
Wait for about 2 hours to allow the
nutrients to fully dissolve into the
water.
[Music]
after the water cools down, strain the
residue to obtain the turmeric water.
You can use a sieve or a thin cloth to
filter, ensuring that only clean liquid
turmeric remains, which will easily
absorb into the plant's cut.
If you haven't subscribed to the channel
yet, please click the subscribe button
to support me and never miss any orchid
growing tips. It's wonderful to have you
as a companion.
[Music]
The first step is to soak a cotton ball
in the turmeric water mixture and gently
wipe both the top and bottom of the
orchid leaves.
Wiping the leaves with turmeric water
not only helps clean the leaves but also
provides nutrients that keep the leaves
healthy. Additionally, it has
anti-inflammatory and antibacterial
properties helping the leaves avoid
diseases.
You should wipe evenly and gently to
avoid damaging the leaves.
Turmeric contains curcumin which helps
reduce inflammation and prevent the
growth of harmful bacteria and fungi on
the leaves. This helps the plant fight
against diseases such as leaf rot and
mold.
Curcumin and turmeric also has
antioxidant properties, protecting the
leaves from the harmful effects of the
environment and strong sunlight, helping
the orchid leaves maintain their
freshness.
To care for orchids effectively, you can
wipe the leaves with turmeric water
about one to two times a month.
Step two, pour the turmeric water into a
spray bottle. Then spray it onto the
entire orchid plant.
Um, this helps the turmeric water cover
the leaves, roots, and stem evenly,
providing nutrients and protecting the
plant from harmful agents.
Regularly spraying turmeric water helps
the orchid maintain its health, reduce
inflammation, and prevent mold growth.
You should spray turmeric water on the
orchid about one to two times a month.
This is enough to provide the plant with
nutrients from turmeric while also
protecting the leaves from bacteria and
fungi without causing excess moisture to
linger too long.
Um, if the plant has health issues or is
infected, you can do it more frequently,
but for healthy plants, a frequency of
one two times a month is ideal.
Now, mixing turmeric water with oatmeal
water is a great way to create a
natural, nutrient-rich mixture for
orchids.
Oatmeal water is rich in vitamins and
minerals, providing essential nutrients
for the plant's healthy growth. While
turmeric water adds antibacterial and
anti-inflammatory properties,
[Music]
you need to strain the oatmeal residue
and use only the clear liquid for
application.
[Music]
And then use a watering can or a small
cup to pour the turmeric and oatmeal
water mixture onto the plant's roots.
[Music]
Um, you can water slowly and evenly,
ensuring the mixture soaks into the soil
or the plant's roots. Be sure to water
both the main roots and the secondary
roots evenly.
Um, you can water slowly and evenly,
ensuring the mixture soaks into the soil
or the plant's roots. Be sure to water
both the main roots and the secondary
roots evenly.
[Music]
Moss has excellent moisture retention,
so you only need to water with this
mixture once every 2 weeks.
With moss as the growing medium, you
don't need to water too frequently
because it retains water longer, helping
to maintain a stable moisture level for
the plant's roots.
[Music]
However, if your orchid's growing medium
is bark chips, it drains water faster.
So, you will need to water with this
mixture once a week to ensure the plant
receives enough nutrients.
Bark chips don't retain moisture as well
as moss, so more frequent watering is
needed to ensure the plant doesn't lack
water and nutrients.
[Music]
Step four. After watering the plant with
the turmeric and oatmeal mixture, you
should wipe off any remaining mixture on
the leaves and leaf axles.
Uh this is an important step to prevent
the mixture from remaining on on the
plant which could create prolonged
moisture and provide favorable
conditions for mold or bacterial growth.
Um, you can use a soft cloth or cotton
ball to gently wipe away any excess,
ensuring that areas like the top and
bottom of the leaves and the leaf axles
are dry and not left wet for too long.
This helps the orchid maintain its
health, prevents mold, and keeps the
leaves clean.
After wiping off the excess mixture, you
should place the orchid pot in a spot
with gentle sunlight as light is a
crucial factor that helps the orchid
perform photosynthesis and grow well.
However, you should avoid direct and
intense sunlight as it can cause leaf
burn or stress the plant.
[Music]
Now, let's take a look at the results
after 2 months of caring for the orchid.
The with it with the natural fertilizer
mixture made from turmeric powder and
oatmeal.
[Music]
You can see that my orchid pot has grown
three new flower spikes, all thick and
healthy. This shows that the natural
fertilizer made from turmeric powder and
oatmeal has truly had an amazing effect.
Not only has it produced many new flower
spikes, but it's also developed many new
roots.
This proves that the plant is very
healthy and receiving enough nutrients
from the natural fertilizer.
[Music]
New roots help the orchid absorb water
and nutrients more efficiently, which in
turn helps the plant grow better and
maintain its health.
The strong growth of the flower spikes
is a sign that the plant is receiving
all the necessary nutrients and the care
environment is perfect for its growth.
This orchid, although smaller, has grown
two flower spikes after 2 months of
careful care, which is a very positive
sign.
This proves that although the plant
doesn't grow as vigorously as the
others, with the right care and natural
fertilizer, it can still bloom and
recover its health.
Uh this is a clear example that patience
and careful care will help the plant
recover and produce beautiful blooms.
Here's another regular orchid. And when
cared for using this method, you can
clearly see the difference. The leaves
are vibrant, firm, and healthy.
The flower spikes are not only large but
also thick and full of vitality.
[Music]
This care method has helped the plant
grow vigorously and bloom brilliantly,
proving its exceptional effectiveness in
nurturing and caring for orchids.
With this simple method, you can easily
care for and revive orchids right at
home, helping them grow healthily and
bloom beautifully.
If you found the content helpful and
meaningful, don't forget to like, share
so more people can know and subscribe to
support me. Thank you for always being
with me.