welcome to my
Channel today I will show you how to
revive a rotten Orchid like
[Music]
this when the orchid has withered all
the leaves and only the stem and Roots
do not rush to throw it away
[Music]
where are you watching the video from
please leave a comment and let me
[Music]
know it's amazing that we can chat
together from all around the
world uh here the branches are still
fresh
my video features voiceovers in six
languages English French German Spanish
Portuguese and Italian additionally I
have subtitles in various other
languages around the world for you to
choose
from I will remove all wilted and rotten
leaves
[Music]
and I remove all the broken
Roots um if you haven't subscribed to
the channel yet please hit the Subscribe
button to support
[Music]
me I keep only the fresh roots that are
left
[Music]
over I cut off the flower stock so that
the Orchid can concentrate nutrients for
the new Sprout to grow
rinse with
[Music]
water apply melted candle solution to
the cut to prevent water from seeping
into the tree
[Music]
use three cloves of garlic and
mince soaked garlic in one L of water at
room
temperature incubate for 1
[Applause]
[Music]
day at the same time spread in a cool
place for one
[Music]
day one day after
filter out
[Music]
residue soak Orchid branches in garlic
water for 20 minutes
[Music]
the rest of the water I will spray on
other orchids to help protect the Orchid
from insects and fungi at the same time
garlic juice also stimulates the
development of roots and Flower sprouts
very well
[Music]
20 minutes after
after soaking for 30 minutes
plant using pine bark or dry pmus Stone
to plant will help absorb moisture in
the roots making the Orchid roots not
[Music]
rot put in a cool place for 1 week
without watering
[Music]
one week
later from now on water the Orchid to
keep it
moist then place it in a place with
light sunlight the best temperature is
20 to 25° C
[Music]
regularly spray moisture to spread life
and revive
faster 2 weeks after
[Music]
use 3 m of GE Ginger water mixed with 1
liter of water
[Music]
um GE ginger juice is considered an
organic fertilizer that helps to
stimulate plant growth very
[Music]
well water this G Ginger every 10 days
continue to place the plant in a place
with light
sunlight uh cover with a clear vented
plastic container and wait for the plant
to
revive 1 month
later the root system is very
welldeveloped
[Music]
when the roots are strong like this you
can fertilize the Orchid with organic
fertilizer like I shared on the channel
uh to help the Orchid grow healthier
hope this sharing content will help you
in resurrecting weak orchids to grow
again if you find it interesting
remember to like share and subscribe so
that my channel can soon reach 10
million
[Music]
subscribers um the video I have created
many subtitles you you can choose the
appropriate language to understand my
[Music]
sharing I'm very happy happy that you
are
here if you have an orchid I'm sure you
always want it to bloom for a long time
right
[Music]
right orchids are known for their
ability to keep flowers on their
branches for 3 to 6
[Music]
months for that to happen you need to
nurture water and feed it well
[Music]
now I will show you what is the best
fertilizer for
[Music]
orchids if you follow us till the end of
this video you will learn how to make
orchids bloom like crazy
[Music]
now let's get
started take a bowl and put 5 tbsp of
rice in
[Music]
it if you haven't subscribed to the
channel yet please subscribe to support
me and not miss any orchid care
[Music]
tips pour in 500 M of water at at room
temperature mix the rice well and wash
the rice before
[Music]
cooking then filter the water to wash
the
[Music]
rice please comment to me which country
you are watching the video from it's
great that we can chat together from all
over the
[Music]
world use a cotton ball soaked in water
to wash this
[Music]
rice then wipe on the top and bottom of
the leaves
[Music]
will help clean the surface of the
leaves remove disease fungi and insects
on Orchids at the same time it provides
the necessary nutrients for the orchid's
growth
[Music]
repeat after 2 weeks will help the
Orchid Stay
[Music]
Green or you can also pour the rice
water into a spray
[Music]
bottle then spray evenly on the top and
bottom of the
[Music]
leaves the this method also has the same
effect as the previous method using
cotton
[Music]
balls do not spray rice water on flowers
now take a deep Bowl in which you will
place the Orchid ready for watering and
[Music]
soaking rice water is a great natural
fertilizer for orchids as it encourages
the flowering of this beautiful
[Music]
plant you can soak the Orchid in this
rice water for about 1 hour so that the
or Roots can absorb the most
[Music]
nutrients then remove and repeat this
treatment every 14 days
[Music]
you can also freeze rice water to water
your
[Music]
orchids when need needed you just need
to take a few
[Music]
cubes wait for them to defrost and reach
room temperature you can feed your
orchids again
[Music]
never Place Frozen blocks directly on
the base of the Orchid because orchids
don't like the
[Music]
cold after only 2 to 3 weeks of use the
leaves will be green
[Music]
um you can see that after fertilizing
the new Roots grow very strongly this
will help the Orchid best absorb
nutrients through its roots
[Music]
if you find the content interesting or
meaningful don't forget to like share so
that more people know and subscribe to
your support Channel thank you for
always accompanying
[Music]
me with enough nutrition your orable
flower all year
[Music]
round and that will be all we have
prepared for you for this video