Hello everyone. Today I will share how
to take care of newly purchased orchids
using only rice, a simple but extremely
effective ingredient.
If you just bought orchids and are
worried about weak roots, yellow leaves,
or orchids not blooming, make sure to
watch this entire video. I will also
share little tips to help your orchids
grow strong from roots to leaves and
bloom beautifully in the future.
Um, as soon as you bring a new orchid
home, the first thing you need to do is
gently open the packaging so the plant
can breathe.
[Music]
Next, place the orchid pot in a well
ventilated area for one day, allowing
the plant to adapt and feel safe in its
new environment.
This helps the orchid quickly adapt to
the new environment and minimizes stress
as the plant has already endured a lot
of pressure during packaging and
transportation.
[Music]
After one day, gently take the orchid
pot out and remove the yellow or wilted
leaves so the plant can focus its energy
on nurturing the healthy parts.
[Music]
Next, carefully check the orchid's
growing medium and root system to ensure
the plant is developing healthily.
[Music]
During the inspection, I noticed that
this growing medium is quite old and
needs to be replaced for the orchid to
grow better.
[Music]
However, since the orchid has many buds
and flowers on its stems, if you want to
keep the flowers from wilting, you
should retain part of the old growing
medium. This helps the plant avoid shock
and keeps the petals looking fresh and
beautiful.
[Music]
If you haven't subscribed to the
channel, please hit the subscribe button
to support me and not miss any orchid
growing tips. Uh it's wonderful to have
you along for the journey.
Please comment and let me know which
country you are watching this video
from. It's wonderful that we can chat
together from all around the world.
Have you ever used any natural methods
to care for orchids? Comment below.
The ingredients and tools needed to care
for orchids. First, a cup to mix the
solution.
Next, we need to prepare rice, a simple
but extremely useful ingredient for
orchids.
Next, prepare methylionium chloride,
which helps disinfect and protect the
orchid from harmful bacteria.
A clean jar to ferment the rice,
allowing the fermentation process to
occur gently and safely for the orchid.
Next, prepare a bowl to mix the solution
and a small spoon to water the plant
easily and accurately.
Also prepare a sieve to filter out
residues, ensuring the orchid watering
solution is clean and safe for the
plant.
Next is clean water, an essential
ingredient for preparing the orchid care
solution.
Prepare an orchid pot with drainage
holes at the bottom to keep the roots
well ventilated and prevent water
logging.
Prepare the growing medium, which is
sterilized pine bark chips to help the
orchid roots anchor firmly and grow
healthily.
And finally, prepare a bit of moss to
retain moisture for the roots and keep
the orchid fresh, the orchidish, and
healthy.
Step one, disinfect the orchid. Protect
the roots and leaves from the very
beginning.
Next, take two cups of water, about 500
ml, to prepare the disinfectant
solution.
[Music]
Add about three drops of methylionium
chloride to create a safe disinfectant
solution for the orchid.
[Music]
Methylionium chloride has antibacterial
properties that help eliminate pathogens
and protect healthy orchid roots.
[Music]
Then pour this solution in and soak the
roots along with the growing medium for
about 20 minutes. This helps remove
bacteria and fungi clinging to the roots
and medium, creating a clean environment
for the plant to grow.
Next, use a soft cloth soaked in the
solution and gently wipe both the top
and bottom surfaces of the leaves. This
helps remove dust, fungi, and insects
from the leaves, keeping them clean and
improving photosynthesis.
[Music]
You can see that this orchid has black
mold, probably because it was grown in
an industrial orchid garden with
insufficient sunlight, making it prone
to fungal infection.
[Music]
Wiping the leaves with this mixture will
help remove black mold after just a few
applications.
In addition, you should place the orchid
pot in a location with sufficient light
to prevent black mold from continuing to
develop.
[Music]
Step two, soak fermented rice. Create a
natural fertilizer source for the
orchid.
[Music]
Take about three teaspoons of rice and
put them into a clean jar, preparing for
the fermentation step.
[Music]
Add about 4 cups of room temperature
water equivalent to one liter to start
the rice soaking process.
Cover the jar and place it in a cool,
well ventilated area for one day to
allow the rice to ferment lightly,
creating a natural source of nutrients
for the orchid.
Step three, repot the orchid with a new
pot and growing medium, helping the
plant anchor its roots and grow strong.
[Music]
After soaking for about 20 minutes,
gently take the orchid out and repot it
into the new pot you have prepared.
[Music]
After repotting, use a stake to support
the orchid stem, helping the plant stay
upright and preventing branch breakage
while the roots have not yet anchored
firmly into the growing medium.
[Music]
Next, spread a thin layer of moss over
the surface of the pot, helping retain
moisture for the roots and creating an
ideal environment for the orchid to
grow.
[Music]
Uh after repotting, place the orchid pot
in a well ventilated area for 1 day and
do not water it, allowing the plant to
adapt to the new environment without
stress.
[Music]
Step four, water the orchid with rice
water.
After fermenting for one day, stir the
mixture well and filter it to remove
residues, obtaining a clean fermented
fertilizer solution ready for watering
the orchid.
[Music]
Use the soaked rice water to pour
directly onto the medium around the
roots. Um, providing natural nutrients
and promoting healthy root growth for
the orchid.
Water about two to three times per
month, allowing the orchid to absorb
nutrients from the rice while still
growing naturally and healthily.
Fermented rice water is rich in
vitamins, minerals, and natural sugars,
helping orchid roots and leaves absorb
nutrients effectively and promoting
healthy plant growth.
The fermentation process produces
beneficial microorganisms, helping
improve the quality of the growing
medium, balance the living environment
for orchid roots, and limit harmful
bacteria and fungi.
You can also pour this mixture into a
spray bottle to mist directly onto the
leaves, helping nutrients cover evenly
and allowing the orchid to absorb them
faster.
When spraying, remember to mist both the
top and underside of the leaves so
nutrients penetrate deeply while also
removing dust and harmful microorganisms
on the leaves.
Regularly spray or water with fermented
rice water about two to three times per
month. This not only provides nutrients
but also helps the the orchid grow
naturally with lush green leaves and
healthy roots.
[Music]
However, you should not spray onto the
flower petals because when the petals
get wet, they wilt quickly and are
easily damaged.
Therefore, when watering or spraying the
solution, focus only on the roots and
leaves, avoiding wetting the flowers to
keep them fresh and beautiful for
longer.
After watering, you can leave the orchid
pot soaking in the liquid fertilizer
solution for about 10 to 20 minutes,
allowing the roots to absorb the maximum
nutrients.
Step five, additional care, light, and
environment.
After soaking for about 20 minutes, take
the orchid pot out and place it in a
location with gentle sunlight, avoiding
harsh sun so the plant can gradually
adapt and keep the flowers and leaves
healthy.
In addition, you should regularly
observe the growing medium. If it
appears dry, you can supplement with
clean water intermittently to maintain
ideal moisture for the orchid roots to
grow.
And don't forget to regularly check the
roots, leaves, and flowers as these are
key indicators reflecting the health of
the orchid.
And here are the results after 3 weeks.
After just 3 weeks of care, the orchid
leaves have become firm, glossy green,
and almost all the black mold on the
leaves has disappeared.
[Music]
In addition, you can also see many new
roots growing healthy and developing
well.
All these changes show that the orchid
is recovering and growing vigorously
thanks to healthy roots, green leaves,
and wellprotected flowers.
[Music]
The petals are still fresh and have not
fallen, indicating that the orchid is
being cared for properly and maintaining
good health.
The combination of lush green leaves,
healthy new roots, and long-lasting
flowers shows that this entire care
method is truly effective, helping the
orchid grow comprehensively from roots
to blooms.
I hope you enjoy the video. If you find
the content helpful and meaningful,
don't forget to like, share, so many
people can see it, and subscribe to
support me. Thank you for always being
with me.
Thank you for watching. Goodbye and
wishing you a day full of joy with
beautiful orchids.