hello everyone today I will share a
great way to revive wilted orchids
helping them grow strong and Bloom
[Music]
beautifully let's explore
together these are orchids that people
have thrown away
this Orchid is dead so it cannot be
[Music]
revived this plant is also dead so it
cannot be revived
[Music]
this Orchid is wilted but still alive so
I decided to bring it home to revive it
[Music]
you need to check the roots and cut off
all the damaged ones
[Music]
cutting them off helps stop the spread
of bacteria mold and other
diseases after cutting the Orchid will
focus its energy on the healthy Roots
helping the plant grow
[Music]
better then cut off the old orchid
flower spikes and withered Leaf stocks
to help the plant Focus its energy on
developing new parts including fresh
flower spikes and
leaves when the flowers have faded faded
or the leaf stalks become dry and wilted
cutting them off not only makes the
plant look tidier but also prevents the
spread of diseases this helps the orchid
bloom more vigorously and grow healthier
in the next season
then soaking the wilted orchid in water
for about 1 hour is a simple yet
effective method to help the plant
recover this provides moisture to the
roots making it easier for them to
absorb water and
nutrients soaking the Orchid also helps
remove any toxins or dirt that may be
present on the roots creating a better
environment for the plant to recover
quickly and grow
healthier take a/ teaspoon of sugar
add it to one liter of
water sugar helps revive wilted orchids
by providing an easy source of energy
for the
plant uh when the Orchid is wilted it
may lack energy due to the roots not
functioning effectively or being
damaged remember to stir well to ensure
the sugar completely dissolves in the
water
take one liter of
water and add 3 teaspoons of
breadcrumbs breadcrumbs can help the
Orchid quickly recover and develop Roots
due to the Nutritional components they
contain such as vitamin and vams and
minerals when soaked in water they
create a solution that provides
beneficial nutrients giving energy to
the plant in particular breadcrumbs can
stimulate the growth of beneficial
bacteria in the soil improving the root
environment and promoting the
development of new
Roots after soaking for 1 hour remove
the or
kid then immerse the wilted leaves in
the diluted sugar water for about 20
minutes
the sugar water provides energy to the
leaves helping them absorb nutrients and
moisture more effectively this process
also stimulates cell regeneration aiding
in the rapid recovery of the leaves
then remove it and wipe off any excess
water from the
Orchid what country are you watching the
video from please leave a comment for
me it's so fun that we can chat together
from all around the world
[Music]
now let's mix the diluted sugar solution
with the breadcrumb soaking
solution this solution provides energy
from sugar and nutrients from the bread
crumbs helping the plant recover
quickly the sugar provides carbohydrates
giving the plant extra energy while the
bread crumbs Supply vitamins and
minerals stimulating the growth of roots
and
[Music]
leaves then soak the Orchid roots in
this combined solution for about 20
minutes you need to be careful and soak
for a short time to avoid rotting the
roots or affecting them with too much
sugar residue
[Music]
the leftover mixed solution from soaking
the Orchid Roots can be used to
fertilize other orchids providing
additional nutrients and energy the
vitamins minerals and carbohydrates from
the sugar and breadcrumbs support the
growth of orchids very well
[Music]
this fertilizer stimulates flower growth
very effectively as you can see this
orchid has developed four new flower
spikes
[Music]
and as you can see this Orchid of mine
has very well-developed Roots after
using this Liquid Fertilizer
[Music]
after applying this liquid fertilizer
soak the roots for about 20 minutes to
allow the Orchid to absorb the water and
nutrients
effectively then take the Orchid pot out
and place it in a location with plenty
of light but avoid Direct
sunlight to protect the plant you should
place the Orchid in areas with indirect
light or shade especially during the
intense midday
Sun after soaking for 20 minutes remove
the wilted
Orchid you can see that the Orchid Roots
have become fresher and Greener after
soaking in this mixed solution for 20
minutes
now I'm planting the Orchid in a new pot
to make the recovery process
easier uh I use spagna Moss as the
growing medium for the Orchid to help
retain
moisture spagna Moss is an excellent
growing medium because it can hold water
for a long time and creates a stable
humid environment for the Orchid roots
to grow
[Music]
from now on you should W water the
Orchid with the mixed solution of sugar
and breadcrumbs once a week
sugar provides energy for the plant
helping to stimulate the growth of roots
and leaves and while breadcrumbs Supply
the vitamins and minerals necessary for
the plant's healthy development
[Music]
the result after 3
weeks as you can see many new Roots have
[Music]
developed when the wilted orchid leaves
are revived and new Roots start to grow
it is a sign that the plant is gradually
recovering the new Roots will help the
plant absorb water and nutrients better
while also providing energy for the
growth of leaves and
flowers at this point you can continue
to care for the plant by ensuring it
receives enough light moisture and
appropriate fertilization so the Orchid
can grow strong and Bloom beautifully
[Music]
I continue to fertilize this Orchid with
with the liquid fertilizer made from
sugar and breadcrumbs once a week
[Music]
the result after the next two
months uh as you can see the orchid has
recovered and grown very
healthily the leaves have recovered and
are no longer wilted
[Music]
the roots are plump and
healthy and the orchid has produced two
new flower spikes
[Music]
give all your love and care to your
orchids and you will be rewarded with
beautiful blooms like a healing remedy
that banishes all worries bringing joy
and peace to your soul
I hope you enjoyed this video don't
forget to like subscribe to the channel
and stay tuned for more helpful videos
goodbye and see you in the next video