hello
everyone to give you more options for
making natural fertilizers to care for
orchids at home helping your plants grow
healthy and Bloom beautifully today I'll
continue sharing a new fertilizer making
method that's super simple and
[Music]
effective let's explore
together uh this is the Orchid bought uh
which was grown in an industrial orchid
garden and it has now finished
[Music]
blooming if you don't know how to care
for it the Orchid after blooming may
become weak and difficulty in flowering
the following
crop first remove all damag
leaves because damaged orchid leaves can
Harbor pests mold and bacteria
negatively affecting the plant's health
and hindering its new
[Music]
growth if you haven't subscribed to the
channel yet please subscribe to support
me and not miss any orchid care tips
[Music]
and remove all the damaged
Roots because damaged Orchid Roots can
cause rot to spread to healthy Roots
making it difficult for the plant to
absorb water and nutrients which weakens
the plant and hinders its
[Music]
growth in addition to the English
voiceover we have now created voiceovers
in French German Italian Spanish and
Portuguese to help you listen to and
understand the video content more
[Music]
easily um here there are still dormant
flower buds that have not yet bloomed so
I'll keep it so it can continue to
develop and flower
uh at the spots where the flower Spikes
have finished blooming they won't bloom
again so they should be discarded
[Music]
I recut the cut to make sure it wasn't
crushed so it would heal
quickly then take cinnamon powder and
sprinkle it on the cut to help it heal
faster
[Music]
then leave it overnight without watering
to let the cut heal
completely um this flour is still fresh
so I put it in a vase
[Music]
uh watering will help the flowers stay
on the branches for a long time before
[Music]
fading today I used apples and lemons as
natural fertilizer
[Music]
uh take about 5 G of apple and 5 G of
lemon apples and lemons are beneficial
natural nutrient sources when used as
fertilizer for
orchids put them in a blender add 300 M
of water and
blend when combined apples and lemons
create a nutrient-rich solution that
supports the growth and health of
orchids Apple contains natural sugars
and vitamins that help stimulate
beneficial BAC ACA in the soil providing
energy for the
plant lemon rich in citric acid it helps
lower soil PH allowing the plant to
absorb nutrients more effectively while
also preventing harmful fungi and
bacteria then strain to extract the
apple and lemon juice
mix it with 2 L of water
step
one use a soft cotton pad and gently
wipe the top the top and bottom of the
leaves with this homemade
solution this method will help clean the
leaves removing dust and impurities at
the same time the solution provides
nutrients for the plant helping the
orchids stay healthy and grow
better however it's important to wipe
gently to avoid damaging the leaves
which country are you watching videos
from please comment for
me it's nice that we can chat together
from all over the
world how to select the audio language
on YouTube One open the video and click
on settings the gear IC
two select subtitles CC three click on
audio and choose the language you want
English France deut Italiano espanol or
[Music]
Portuguese then use a soft cloth to wrap
the dormant flower bud
uh this method helps awaken dormant
flower buds so they can develop into new
flower spikes
[Music]
step
two put this solution into a spray
bottle and spray it on the
[Music]
Orchid you spray skills above and below
the leaves
this provides additional nutrients to
the plant enhances Leaf growth
stimulates flowering and helps the
Orchid grow healthy resist pests and
improve its overall
resistance then spray this water here to
awaken the dormant flower Bud helping it
bloom faster
then you put the Orchid pot in a large
cup like
[Music]
me step three water the solution onto
the roots and the Orchid growing
[Music]
medium step three water the solution
onto the roots and the Orchid growing
medium
[Music]
uh soaking in this solution for about 20
minutes helps plant roots absorb water
and nutrients
[Music]
best after 20 minutes take the Orchid
pot out
[Music]
remove the wrapper from the sleeping
Bud do all three steps once a week with
this liquid fertilizer for your
orchids place it in a well lit area so
the Orchid can photosynthesize and
metabolize properly
results after 1
month the leaves will be greener and
healthier
[Music]
The Roots grow very quickly and many new
root tips grow
[Music]
and new Roots help the plant absorb
water and essential nutrients from the
soil or growing medium which is vital
for healthy plant development and
blooming
if the new roots are not strong and
healthy the plant will struggle to
supply nutrition and moisture to the
flowering
[Music]
tissues when new Roots develop well the
plant will absorb more nutrients helping
to flower better
you can see that the sleeping bud has
awakened and grown into a new flower
Spike
[Music]
now I will transplant the Orchid into a
larger pot so it can grow more
vigorously you need to remove some Moss
because Moss that grows on orchids for a
long time has the property of holding a
lot of water which can lead to water
logging and root rot
[Music]
and remove any damaged Roots before
replanting
we
planting with pine bark chips helps main
moisture well while also draining
quickly preventing the orchid's roots
from rotting
then you take care of the Orchid like
other normal
orchids I hope you enjoyed this video
video don't forget to like share and
subscribe to the channel so you don't
miss out on helpful videos about orchid
care uh take care of your Orchids with
all the love and attention you have for
nature and you will be rewarded with
stunning vibrant flowers that light up
your world dispelling all worries and
stress bringing you peace and endless
Joy
thank you for supporting the channel and
I wish you peaceful moments and joy with
your beautiful orchids