Welcome to my
channel. Phelinopsis orchids are known
for their ability to keep flowers on the
stem for a long time. The flowers are
beautiful, so they are loved by many
people around the world.
[Music]
If you haven't subscribed to the channel
yet, please hit the subscribe button to
support me and not miss any orchid
growing tips. It's wonderful to have you
[Music]
along. Let's get
started. To make a hanging orchid
garden, I recycle old plastic bottles
into planting pots. This method not only
helps reduce plastic waste and protect
the environment, but also creates
beautiful and unique orchid
[Music]
pots. If you also love orchids, try
doing it like me. Simple yet full of
[Music]
inspiration. Uh this is a great way for
busy people to still satisfy their
passion for growing orchids without
worrying about daily maintenance and
care.
[Music]
With this method, you won't need to
water yet. The flowers will continue to
bloom all four
[Music]
seasons. Please comment and let me know
which country you are watching the video
from. It's wonderful that we can chat
together from all over the world.
[Music]
wash with water and antibacterial soap.
[Applause]
[Music]
Making holes helps ventilate so that
Orchid roots grow better.
[Music]
Use high water absorbent cotton fabric
to make the wick.
[Music]
insert the water absorbing wick into the
orchid pot.
[Music]
Uh, this is the hook for hanging the
orchid
pot. I make holes to hang the orchid pot
hooks here.
[Music]
Uh these are plastic beads commonly used
for hydroponic vegetable growing. I use
them as the growing medium for orchids.
[Music]
This wick has the task of drawing water
from the lower layer up, keeping the
growing medium at an ideal moisture
level for the orchid to grow best.
[Music]
Now I plant the orchid seedlings into
the semi-hydroponic orchid pots.
[Music]
after planting you water.
With this method, you only need to water
once and then you can be assured no need
to water
[Music]
again. The wick draws water from below,
helping the orchid pot always maintain
stable
[Music]
moisture. When the water runs out, you
just need to add water or replace it
after each time you spray natural
fertilizer on the
orchids. Then you hang the orchid pot in
a place with gentle sunlight.
[Music]
The most suitable temperature for
orchids is from 20 to 30°.
[Music]
You should spray natural fertilizer on
the orchids about two to three times a
month as I've shared on the channel.
[Music]
5 months
later, as you can see, with this simple
method from a small orchid, it has now
grown healthy and full of vitality.
[Music]
What do you think about my
semi-hydroponic orchid growing method?
Please write your comments and feedback
to let me know.
[Music]
Um, have you tried applying any method
from the video on the channel yet? Don't
hesitate to leave a comment and share
your feelings. I'm very eager to hear
your experiences and suggestions.
[Music]
After 6 months, from a small orchid
planted in a semi-hydroponic pot, the
plant has now matured and bloomed
brilliantly.
[Music]
This is a wonderful method that helps
busy people satisfy their passion for
growing orchids without having to worry
about watering, fertilizing, or daily
[Music]
care. With this semi-hydroponic growing
technique, orchids maintain their fresh
color longer and can stay on the stem
for more than 6 months before the petals
start to
wilt. I hope this content will be very
helpful for those of you growing orchids
at
[Music]
home. Uh if you find the content good
and meaning, don't forget to like,
share, so many people know about it and
subscribe to support me. Thank you for
always being with me.
[Music]
Thank you for watching the video. I
always pray that God blesses all of you.