Welcome to our garden where every leaf
and every flower is nurtured with
patience and sincere love.
Each moment with the orchid pot becomes
a relaxing and inspiring experience.
Watching the soft young roots slowly
stretch out and the petals gently
unfold. You will feel the delicate
beauty that nature bestows.
Uh today I want to share with you a
secret that is simple yet very
effective. helping wilted and weak
orchids quickly revive.
[Music]
This is an orchid that once bloomed
beautifully, but now it has withered and
become so stunted that it seems beyond
saving. Some even think it should be
thrown away, but with just a little
patience and love, a miracle can still
happen.
[Music]
Watch and see how I take care of this
orchid.
[Music]
First, gently check the orchid's root
system. You may notice that many roots
are dried out or severely damaged. This
is the reason why the plant is weakened
and unable to absorb enough water and
nutrients.
[Music]
The next step is to cut off the damaged
roots. Uh, this helps the plant stop
wasting energy on dead roots and instead
focus on nourishing and developing new,
healthier ones.
[Music]
Removing weak roots also creates more
space in the pot, allowing new roots to
grow and develop more strongly. When the
roots are healthy, the entire plant will
gradually regain its vitality.
[Music]
If the roots are not cleaned and treated
properly, the plant will have difficulty
recovering even with regular watering
and fertilizing.
Removing weak roots not only helps the
plant focus on nourishing new roots, but
also prevents the spread of harmful
fungi and bacteria. This is an important
step to protect the orchid from root rot
and create a clean environment for its
recovery.
For wilted flowers, cutting them off is
necessary so the plant no longer wastes
energy maintaining what has already
faded. This allows the orchid to focus
on nourishing its roots and leaves,
preparing for a healthier new growth
cycle.
[Music]
The same applies to old yellow leaves.
They can no longer photosynthesize
effectively and may become breeding
grounds for bacteria or fungi. Removing
them will help the plant stay airy,
reduce the risk of disease, and
encourage it to focus on nourishing
healthy new shoots.
[Music]
Next, rinse the roots thoroughly with
clean water. This helps remove dirt, old
fertilizer residue, and any remaining
damaged root parts.
This is an important step to clean the
entire root system and provide the best
conditions for the plant to recover and
grow again.
[Music]
Washing the roots helps remove bacteria,
mold, or insect eggs that may still
cling to the roots after the plant has
weakened, thereby reducing the risk of
disease spreading to the new roots.
Cleaning away the buildup of mineral
salts or old fertilizer residue helps
the roots absorb water and nutrients
more easily after repotting.
Which country are you watching this
video from? Leave a comment below and
let me know. I really want to connect
and chat with with all of you around the
world.
[Music]
Next, I will use a fresh aloe vera leaf
because aloe vera is very effective in
helping wilted or stunted orchids
recover.
Cut the aloe vera flesh into small
pieces and add it to 300 ml of room
temperature water. Then blend the
mixture to create a natural solution
that helps restore the roots and
stimulate the plant's growth.
Aloe vera contains a high water content
and soothing gel providing essential
moisture for dry or weak roots. When the
roots are adequately hydrated, the plant
can absorb nutrients more easily and
begin the recovery process.
[Music]
Next, strain the blended aloe vera
mixture through a sieve or thin cloth to
remove the pulp, keeping only the
liquid. This helps the roots absorb it
more easily and prevents residue from
sticking during the soaking process.
[Music]
Aloe vera gel contains natural compounds
with mild antibacterial and antifungal
properties that help protect the roots
from rot or infection when the plant is
still weak, acting as a gentle yet
effective natural protective layer.
Place the orchid leaves in a cup and
pour the strained aloe vera juice over
them.
Soak for about 20 minutes to allow the
leaves to absorb the nutrients. helping
to restore cells and support the plant's
regeneration process.
This method provides the plant with the
necessary moisture and nutrients,
helping wilted orchids recover more
quickly.
[Music]
After soaking for 20 minutes, gently
remove the orchid and use a soft cloth
to wipe off any remaining aloe vera gel
on the leaves. This helps keep the
leaves airy, prevents moisture buildup,
and creates better conditions for the
plant to continue recovering.
Wiping the orchid leaves dry helps
prevent water accumulation that can
cause leaf rot while also helping the
plant adapt more easily when returned to
its growing environment.
[Music]
Dissolve one tablespoon of honey into
one liter of room temperature water.
Honey is a natural antibacterial agent
while also providing energy and
effectively stimulating new root growth.
Uh, honey contains beneficial enzymes,
vitamins, and minerals that help
stimulate new root growth. Thanks to its
natural antibacterial properties, honey
also protects the roots from infection,
creating an ideal environment for the
plant to recover quickly and grow
healthier.
[Music]
Now, mix the honey water with the
previously prepared aloe vera juice.
This combination creates a natural
solution that both nourishes and
protects the orchid roots.
And here is vitamin B1, an essential
component that helps restore wilted
leaves and stimulate new root growth.
Supplementing with B1 at the right time
will strengthen the orchid's resistance
and bring about stronger vitality.
[Music]
Vitamin B1 helps enhance the plant's
immunity, especially during periods of
stress or weakness. So, the recovery
process happens faster, helping the
plant regain stability and continue
growing.
[Music]
Then pour this mixture into a cup or
small container and soak the orchid
roots in it for about 20 minutes. This
is the ideal time for the roots to
absorb nutrients and be naturally
stimulated to grow.
[Music]
After soaking for about 20 minutes,
gently remove the orchid and plant it in
a new pot.
I use moss to grow orchids because it
retains moisture well, allows good air
circulation, and is ideal for orchids in
the recovery stage. Moss is a great
material for maintaining stable moisture
for orchid roots. It holds water while
remaining breathable, providing ideal
conditions for new roots to grow without
the risk of rot.
Repotting orchids creates the best
conditions for the plant to grow. A well
ventilated, clean pot and growing medium
provide an ideal environment for the
roots to absorb nutrients from fresh
moss.
The soft texture of moss is ideal for
newly grown orchid roots. Young roots
can attach and grow easily without
damage or obstruction.
Some types of moss, especially Pete
moss, also have mild antibacterial
properties that help limit the growth of
mold and bacteria in the growing
environment, keeping the area around the
roots cleaner.
From now on, water the orchid once every
10 days with the honey, aloe vera, and
vitamin B1 mixture. This will help the
plant maintain moisture, recover
quickly, and stimulate the growth of
healthy new roots.
[Music]
On regular days, if you notice the
growing medium is dry, simply water or
mist the orchid to maintain moisture.
Providing this gentle moisture helps
keep the orchid fresh and healthy
without causing root rot.
[Music]
Then place the orchid pot in a spot with
gentle sunlight. Soft sunlight provides
enough energy for the plant to grow
without burning the leaves or causing
damage from excessive heat.
[Music]
You can use the remaining mixture to
water your other common types of
orchids.
This will help stimulate root growth and
promote the development of new shoots,
improving the plant's overall health and
growth.
You can see that my orchid cared for
using this method has grown many new
roots and flowers.
[Music]
The appearance of a new flower is not
only a sign that the orchid is growing
healthily, but also a sweet reward for
your patients and dedicated care.
[Music]
An orchid regularly cared for with a
honey, aloe vera, and vitamin B1
solution will develop a strong root
system with roots firmly attached to the
growing medium.
[Music]
When watering, pour the solution into a
watering can and water slowly so that
the solution evenly penetrates the
growing medium.
[Music]
Uh it is best to water in the early
morning or late afternoon avoiding the
hot weather during the day so the plant
does not suffer heat shock and can
absorb nutrients more effectively.
[Music]
Uh to maintain effectiveness water with
the honey, aloe vera and vitamin B1
solution once every 10 days.
[Music]
What do you think about my natural
fertilizer method and caring for these
small orchids?
Don't hesitate to leave a comment and
share your thoughts. I truly look
forward to hearing your feedback and
experiences.
[Music]
And here is the result after 3 weeks of
care using this natural fertilizer.
[Music]
The orchid leaves have become greener
and firmer, showing that the plant is
absorbing nutrients well and growing
healthily.
Many new roots have appeared, indicating
that the orchid is in a vigorous growth
stage.
[Music]
A well-developed root system will help
the plant absorb nutrients and water
more effectively.
[Music]
I will continue watering this orchid
with the natural fertilizer mixture of
honey, aloe vera, and vitamin B1 every
10 days to maintain the plant's healthy
growth.
Um, then remember to place the plant in
a spot with gentle light, not too
strong, so it can photosynthesize well
without leaf burn.
[Music]
The result after the next 3 months is
that the orchid has grown very well with
with many new roots and healthy leaves.
[Music]
It can be seen that the natural care
method using honey, aloe vera, and
vitamin B1 has proven to be very
effective.
Uh the orchid is growing many new roots,
showing that its living environment and
care routine are very suitable.
[Music]
The old roots have grown much longer,
indicating that the plant is absorbing
nutrients very well and growing
vigorously.
[Music]
Uh, as the plant's root system develops,
it helps absorb water and nutrients more
effectively, leading to greener,
healthier, and more vibrant leaves.
Healthy leaves allow the plant to
photosynthesize more efficiently,
producing more energy for the growth of
roots, stems, and flowers.
Uh, we should remove yellow leaves
because they can no longer
photosynthesize and may become a place
for harmful fungi and diseases to
accumulate.
Um, if you haven't subscribed yet,
please click the subscribe button and
support my channel. Your support is a
great motivation for me to keep creating
more interesting and useful videos.
Care for your orchids with all the love
and gentleness in your heart, and nature
will always reward your efforts with
lush green leaves, strong roots, and
beautiful flowers.
Thank you all for watching. Wishing you
a joyful and energetic day. Goodbye and
see you in the next videos.