It's a great pleasure to welcome you to
the happiness garden where we explore
together the gentle and magical beauty
of
nature. Today I will repot the orchid
with you and share a simple, easy to do
care method at home using completely
natural fertilizer that brings very
noticeable effects on the plant's
growth.
[Music]
This care method not only helps the
plant recover after repotting, but also
promotes vigorous orchid growth with
strong roots and naturally lush shiny
green
leaves. Especially the flowers will
bloom large, vibrant, and stay on the
stem for a long time before the petals
fall. This is the highlight that every
orchid lover looks forward to.
Let's get
[Music]
started. Before repotting, we need to
disinfect the growing medium to ensure
it is disease-free and safe for the
plant before replanting.
[Music]
The best way to disinfect the growing
medium is to soak it in hot water, which
effectively removes harmful bacteria and
[Music]
fungi. I soak the pine bark in hot water
for about 2 hours to disinfect the
growing medium. When soaking, the water
penetrates deeply inside, helping the
pine bark not to dry out when planted
and maintaining suitable moisture for
the plant's
[Music]
growth. The first ingredient I use to
make natural fertilizer is turmeric
powder.
[Music]
Take one spoon of turmeric powder. Then
mix it with 0.5 L of boiling water.
[Music]
Cover the lid and wait for the water to
cool completely before
[Music]
use. The next ingredient I use to make
natural fertilizer is
rice. Take three spoons of rice.
[Music]
Then mix three spoons of rice with 0.5 L
of room temperature
water. Then wait about 1 hour for the
rice to absorb the
water. Um after about 1 to two years,
the orchid growing medium will rot,
losing its ability to drain water and
allow air circulation due to long-term
use. Therefore, we need to replace the
medium to help the plant grow better.
[Music]
This rot is a sign that the orchid's
roots are suffocating. So, the growing
medium needs to be replaced to save the
plant. Additionally, if you see the
orchid's roots have become too crowded,
the orchid grows slowly, or the growing
medium is no longer loose and airy, it's
also time to repot and replace the
medium.
[Music]
You can see that the growing medium
holds too much water, causing many old
roots to suffocate and rot. If the pot
is not changed in time, the rot can
gradually spread to the stem and leaves,
weakening the
[Music]
plant. Please comment and let me know
which country you are watching the video
from. It's wonderful that we can chat
together from all around the world.
[Music]
Because the growing medium has rotted
and lost its irration, water cannot
drain out, causing the roots to easily
become water logged. Hugged and
[Music]
rot. If you haven't subscribed to the
channel yet, please hit the subscribe
button to support me and not miss any
orchid growing tips. It's wonderful to
have you along for the journey.
[Music]
Uh to prevent the orchid from going into
shock after repotting and changing the
growing medium, I keep about one quarter
of the old medium to plant together with
the new medium.
[Music]
We need to cut off all damaged roots and
overly old roots to help the orchid grow
healthier. Cutting off damaged roots
helps remove infected or rotten root
parts, thereby preventing the spread of
harmful fungi and bacteria to the rest
of the plant.
[Music]
Cutting off old roots helps stimulate
the plant to grow stronger new roots
while also creating airy space in the
pot, allowing the roots to easily absorb
nutrients and oxygen.
[Music]
After the water cools, we filter out the
residue to get clear turmeric water that
is cleaner and easier to use.
[Music]
Stir well so that the nutrients from the
rice completely dissolve into the water.
Then strain the rice water and mix it
with the prepared turmeric
[Music]
water. Then dilute the mixture with 2 L
of clean water before use. Uh this helps
the fertilizer absorb easily and be
safer for the plant.
[Music]
Take.5 L of the diluted solution for
later
[Music]
use. Then soak the orchid roots in the
diluted solution for about 20 minutes.
This helps disinfect and stimulate
strong new root growth.
[Music]
Then take out the pine bark and let it
drain before planting the orchid.
[Music]
After the pine bark has drained, we
proceed to plant the orchid into the new
pot.
[Music]
For orchids with many roots like this, I
use a small plastic pot as a basket
placed at the bottom of the pot before
planting, helping the roots stay airy
and grow better.
[Music]
With this planting method combined with
pine bark as the growing medium, the
time between repotting and changing the
medium will be longer. It may take 2 to
3 years before needing to repot and
replace the medium again.
[Music]
To prevent the orchid from shaking and
affecting the roots, I Use a
plasticcoated steel rod as a support to
keep the plants standing firmly.
[Music]
If you encounter any difficulties during
the orchid growing process, don't
hesitate to comment for me. I am always
ready to support you so you can grow
healthy orchids that bloom abundantly.
[Music]
Besides English dubbing, we have now
created French, German, Italian,
Spanish, Portuguese, Japanese, Hindi,
and Indonesian versions to help you
listen to and understand the content
more easily.
[Music]
To listen to the languages, open the
video and click on settings, the gear
icon to select the appropriate audio
language. For languages without dubbing,
we have created subtitles so you can
read and understand the content.
[Music]
Then put the fertilizer mixture into a
spray bottle for easy use.
[Music]
Then spray the mixture on both the top
and underside of the orchid leaves for
better
[Music]
absorption. You spray the mixture onto
the aerial roots that have not been
soaked, helping the roots absorb
nutrients and grow better.
Spraying on the leaves helps wash away
dust, fungal diseases, and insect larvy
residing on the leaves, especially on
the underside and leaf crevices.
[Music]
Then use a soft cloth to gently wipe off
the water droplets on the leaves and
leaf crevices to keep the leaves
[Music]
dry. Uh this helps keep the orchid
leaves clean, limits the development of
fungal diseases, and keeps the plant
healthier.
After planting, you should place the
orchid pot in a spot with gentle
sunlight and avoid watering for one week
to help the plant adapt and reduce
stress after
repotting. Uh after one week, you start
watering and fertilizing with natural
fertilizers like I shared on the channel
two to three times per month for the
orchid.
[Music]
And here is the orchid from the same
batch that I repotted and changed the
growing medium
[Music]
earlier. Um, you can see the orchid
leaves are sturdy and healthy and the
flowers bloom in many clusters on the
same branch.
The orchid petals are soft and delicate
like velvet with bright colors shining
under gentle sunlight. Each petal curves
gracefully creating a gentle yet elegant
beauty.
The orchid roots are thick, strong,
ivory colored, and freely extending
within the growing medium. The roots are
soft yet very tough, helping the plant
anchor firmly and effectively absorb
water and nutrients to nourish the
entire plant.
When you care for the orchid with all
the love you have for plants, you will
be rewarded with the plant's radiant
beauty and vigorous
vitality. The vibrant flowers blooming
all year round in the garden will help
you feel joy and peace
everyday. I hope you will enjoy this
video. If you find it useful, don't
forget to like and subscribe to the
channel so you won't miss the next
shares uh about caring for orchids
naturally and
simply. Thank you all for watching the
video. I always pray that God blesses
each and every one of