hello everyone welcome to the happiness
Garden
channel in today's video we will explore
how to take care of orchids from the
small stage all the way to full bloom
using only natural
fertilizers if you love plants and want
to grow healthy beautiful orchids don't
miss the simple yet effective tips and
techniques in this
video let's get started
this is a baby Orchid that I previously
propagated from a phenopsis orchid
Branch cut off damaged roots and
leaves cutting off damaged Roots helps
remove rotting non-developing Roots
prevents the spread of diseases and
stimulates the growth of new healthy
Roots cutting off damaged leaves helps
prevent the spread of diseases reduces
the risk of infection and allows the
plant to focus its energy on healthy
[Music]
parts then plant the Orchid in a new pot
so the Orchid grows faster
[Music]
the bottom of the pot is planted with
chopped Pine bark to help drain water
easily uh this prevents the roots from
becoming water
logged please comment to me which
country you're watching the video from
it's great that we can chat together
from all over the
[Music]
world then spread a layer of moss on the
surface of the pot to help retain
moisture better
Moss helps beneficial microorganisms
grow to protect roots from
[Music]
rot then we make natural fertilizer for
this orchid
to make this fertilizer I need ripe
[Music]
bananas take right banana peel and cut
it into small
pieces uh banana peels are a source of
potassium phosphorus and essential
minerals helping to stimulate root
growth and enhance the orchid's
flowering ability
then put the banana peel into the
jar next I need
coffee take three teaspoons
[Music]
then add 1 liter of boiling
water close the lid and wait for the
water to cool
[Music]
after the water cools stir well so that
the nutrients are completely dissolved
in the water
then filter out the
residue step one
use this water to thoroughly wipe the
top and bottom of the
leaves wiping orchid leaves with banana
peel water provides nutrients stimulates
photo synthesis and keeps the leaves
vibrant
[Music]
put this water in a spray bottle and
spray the entire orchid
spraying banana peel water provides
potassium phosphorus and minerals
stimulating root growth and flowering in
orchids step
three water this water into the Orchid
pot watering with banana peel water
provides potassium phosphorus and
minerals helping orchids develop strong
roots and Bloom
well coffee soaked water improves soil
acidity enhances nutrient absorption and
promotes overall plant
growth then soak in water for 20 minutes
soak for about 20 minutes then take it
out and put it in a place with lots of
light do the above three steps every 10
days
results after 3
weeks uh the baby orchids have grown
healthier and have Greener leaves
continue to care for orchids with
natural fertilizer every 10
[Music]
days continue wiping the top and bottom
of leaves helps remove dirt plaque and
small insects helping the plant
photosynthesize better and grow
healthily uh and if you haven't
subscribed to the channel yet please
click the Subscribe button to support me
and don't miss any Orchid growing tips
truly great company
after cleaning the leaves you can spray
the natural fertilizer mixture on the
entire Orchid including the leaves stem
and
Roots don't forget to spray the
underside of the leaves as this is where
insects or fungi can easily grow
when applying the mixture to the roots
and growing medium make sure to apply
enough to saturate the roots without
letting the water sit too long as this
can cause root
rot make sure that the growing medium
still drains well to prevent the plant
from water logging this will help the
Orchid grow healthy with strong roots
and support the next blooming cycle
after watering soak in this water for 20
[Music]
minutes then take it out and place it in
a place with plenty of
light to spread the light more properly
[Music]
results after 5 months
the orchid has matured and has flower
[Music]
buds leaves are strong and sturdy
the orchid has grown three new flower
branches
[Music]
then you continue to care for the Orchid
with this natural fertilizer
[Music]
do all three steps every 10
days if you encounter any difficulties
in growing orchids don't hesitate to
comment for me I'm always ready to
support you so you can grow healthy
orchids that bloom beautifully
[Music]
when spraying the mixture you should
spray it in the early morning or late
afternoon so that the mixture does not
evaporate too quickly under the sun
watering in the early morning or late
afternoon will help the fertilizer
mixture be absorbed better avoid
watering during intense sunlight hours
because it can easily cause Leaf
burns after watering with the fertilizer
mixture you should gently wipe off any
water remaining on the leaves especially
the underside to prevent mold or Leaf
[Music]
rot you should place the Orchid pot in a
spot with gentle indirect light
so the plant can photosynthesize
better take care of your Orchids with
all the love you have for plants and
you'll be rewarded with beautiful
flowers that you've nurtured
yourself don't forget to subscribe to
the happiness Garden channel so you
don't miss out on more helpful videos
thank you for watching and I wish you
success and joy with your orchid
[Music]
garden see you in the next video