Welcome to the little garden called
Happiness, where flowers are cared for
with love and passion.
[Music]
Today, I want to share with you a simple
but very effective method using natural
fertilizer that helps orchids develop
strong roots and exceptionally healthy
green leaves.
Your orchid will produce many flower
spikes, and when blooming, the flowers
will be vibrant in color, lasting long
on the stem before gently wilting.
[Music]
The first ingredient I use to make
natural fertilizer is pure coffee
powder, a nutrient-rich source that is
very good for the healthy development of
orchids.
Take one spoon of pure coffee powder
into a bottle. Then mix it with half a
liter of boiling water to create a
nutrient solution for orchids.
[Music]
Stir the mixture well. Cover it with a
lid and let the water cool completely
before using.
[Music]
Next, take half a liter of room
temperature water and put it into
another glass.
[Music]
Then add one spoon of baking yeast into
that glass of water.
[Music]
The last ingredient I use is oatmeal
powder, a rich source of important
nutrients that helps orchids grow
stronger and healthier every day.
[Music]
Add one spoon of oatmeal powder together
with the baking yeast into the glass.
[Music]
Stir the mixture well and then let it
sit for a few hours to allow the
fermentation process to take place.
[Music]
After 2 hours, when the water has
cooled, stir well and then strain out
the coffee grounds to collect The
solution.
[Music]
Dilute the solution with water at a 1:1
ratio to safely use it for orchids.
Step one, use a soft cloth to soak the
diluted coffee solution. Then gently
wipe both the upper and lower surfaces
of the leaves.
This method helps clean dust off the
leaves while also providing nutrients to
make the leaves healthier and greener.
[Music]
Be sure to wipe the underside of the
leaves thoroughly as this is where dust
often accumulates and pests are more
likely to attack.
[Music]
When the leaf surfaces are cleaned
regularly, harmful mold and bacteria
will have little chance to develop,
thereby helping protect the plant from
unwanted diseases.
If you see leaves that are wilted,
yellow, or damaged, you need to remove
them immediately to help the plant
maintain its health and prevent the
disease from spreading to other leaves.
Properly wiping the leaves also helps
stimulate gas exchange on the leaf
surface, supporting better respiration
and enhancing the overall vitality of
the plant.
Clean leaves help the plant absorb light
better, thereby promoting efficient
photosynthesis, which helps the plant
grow strong and healthier every day.
Uh please comment and let me know which
country you are watching the video from.
It's wonderful that we can chat together
from all around the world.
If you haven't subscribed to the channel
yet, please click the subscribe button
to support me and never miss any orchid
care tips. It's wonderful to have you
along for the journey.
When caring for orchids, if you see the
leaves at the base and the leaf tips
turning yellow, it is often a sign that
the plant is lacking water or has
damaged roots, causing it to to not
absorb enough water and lack nutrients,
especially nitrogen.
When caring for orchids, if you see the
leaves at the base and the leaf tips
turning yellow, it is often a sign that
the plant is lacking water or has
damaged roots, causing it to not absorb
enough water and lack nutrients,
especially nitrogen.
[Music]
Step two, pour the diluted coffee
solution into a spray bottle.
Then spray the solution evenly onto the
upper and lower surfaces of the leaves
as well as the root area.
Spraying the coffee solution helps
provide many natural nutrients to the
plant, thereby stimulating orchids to
grow strong and healthier every day.
The compounds in coffee also help
enhance the plant's ability to resist
pests, naturally protecting it from
harmful agents.
When sprayed on the leaves, coffee helps
clean the surface, creating favorable
conditions for more efficient
photosynthesis, allowing the plant to
absorb energy better from light.
The coffee solution also helps improve
moisture for both roots and leaves,
keeping the plant fresh and preventing
it from drying out.
Step three, strain the liquid from the
fermented oatmeal solution, then mix it
with the coffee solution to create a
natural nutrient mixture for orchids.
Then use this mixture to water each
orchid pot directly, helping the plant
absorb nutrients easily and effectively.
The coffee oatmeal mixture provides a
rich source of natural nutrients helping
orchid roots grow stronger and absorb
nutrients more effectively.
Uh the lightly fermented mixture gently
stimulates the growth of beneficial
microorganisms in the growing medium
creating a healthy living environment
for the roots.
Regularly watering with this mixture
helps boost the plant's resistance,
effectively preventing common orchid
diseases.
When properly nourished from root to
tip, the plant will have enough energy
to prepare for a new blooming season,
full, vibrant, and long-lasting.
The nutrients in oatmeal and coffee help
the leaves stay lush, shiny, and healthy
while also supporting the growth of new
shoots and leaves.
After each time of applying liquid
fertilizer, you should soak the orchid
pot in this mixture for about 20 minutes
to allow nutrients to deeply penetrate
the roots, helping the plant absorb more
effectively.
Step four, use a soft cloth to gently
soak up the remaining liquid fertilizer
on the leaves and leaf axles, helping
keep the leaves clean and preventing
damage.
[Music]
Wiping the leaves also helps keep the
leaf surfaces dry and ventilated,
preventing water accumulation that can
cause leaf rot or damage.
Wiping off water droplets on the leaves
helps prevent the growth of mold and
bacteria, protecting orchid leaves from
harmful diseases.
Cleaned leaves help the plant breathe
better, creating favorable conditions
for efficient gas exchange and
photosynthesis.
Uh, perform these four care steps for
your orchid two to three times each
month to ensure your orchid stays
healthy and grows well.
[Music]
After soaking for 20 minutes, take the
orchid pot out and place it in a spot
with gentle sunlight to allow the plant
to photosynthesize, helping it absorb
nutrients more effectively.
[Music]
Now, let's take a look at the results
after 2 weeks of caring for the orchids.
You can see the orchid has developed
very large and healthy new roots, a sign
of recovery and good growth.
[Music]
Healthy new roots will help the orchid
absorb nutrients and water more
effectively, thereby promoting the
plant's overall development.
[Music]
Uh strong roots also help the plant
anchor firmly to the growing medium,
maintaining stability for the orchid to
grow vigorously over time.
[Music]
In addition, well-developed roots help
the plant increase its reproductive
capacity, creating favorable conditions
for flowering and producing new shoots
more effectively.
[Music]
When cared for with this fertilizer,
flower buds become healthier, develop
evenly, and have the potential to bloom
more brilliantly.
When cared for with this fertilizer, the
petals will be smooth and firm with
vibrant colors that stay fresh longer.
I hope you will like this video. If you
find it useful, don't forget to hit like
and subscribe to the channel so you
won't miss future shares on how to care
for orchids naturally and simply.
[Music]
Thank you for watching the video. I
always pray that God blesses all of you.