Hello
friends. Today we will take care of
orchids with natural fertilizer from
[Music]
lemon. More precisely, lemon peel
contains a lot of vitamin C and
essential oils which are very beneficial
for orchid care, supporting the plant's
healthy growth from roots to leaves and
flowers.
Choose one
[Music]
lemon. Then just take the shell.
If you haven't subscribed to the channel
yet, please click the subscribe button
to support me and not miss any orchid
growing tips. It's great to have
company.
[Music]
Chopped. In addition to the English dub,
we've now created dubs in French,
German, Italian, Spanish, Portuguese,
Japanese, Hindi, and Indonesian to help
you hear and understand the content.
Videos are
easier. Uh to listen to the language,
open the video and click the settings
gear icon to select the appropriate
audio
language. Then puree with two cups of
water equivalent to about 500 ml of
[Music]
water. Please comment to me which
country you are watching the video from.
It's great that we can chat together
from all over the world.
[Music]
filter out residue.
Take 100 ml of juice from lemon peel
about 1/3 a cup.
[Music]
Add water to get one liter of solution.
First
[Music]
way, clean the leaves with a solution of
the juice from the lemon peel.
[Music]
This protects them from
pests. Wipe the underside of the leaves
carefully because this is where fungi,
bacteria, and insects often gather to
harm the orchid.
[Music]
second way.
Spray the solution on the entire orchid.
[Music]
This helps wash away dirt and eliminate
fungal diseases, bacteria, and harmful
insects.
[Music]
Spray this mixture on orchids every 2
weeks. But do not spray on flowers and
buds.
because wet flowers will quickly fall
[Music]
off. Third
way, now we water this solution to take
care of the roots.
Lemon peel acidifies the orchid juice
which contributes to better absorption
of nutrients.
[Music]
And essential oils repel pests and
protect orchid leaves and roots from
harmful bacteria.
[Music]
or soak the orchid pot in this solution
for 30 minutes. It will be better.
[Music]
Do this every 2 weeks and the orchid
will always be
[Music]
protected. If you don't use all of it,
you can freeze the juice from the lemon
zest for later use.
[Music]
Now, let's see the results after caring
for orchids with natural
fertilizer. After three times of use,
the roots grow very well.
[Music]
branched roots develop to help the
orchid absorb more nutrients.
[Music]
Leaves are clean, always green, and free
from
[Music]
pests. Help orchids photosynthesize
better.
[Music]
Flower buds grow and do not
fall. Flowers bloom brightly and stay
fresh.
[Music]
Flowers stay on the branch for up to 6
months before
[Music]
falling. Hope this sharing will help you
a
lot.
Subscribe to my channel to support me
and don't miss any tips on my channel.
[Music]
Next, we will explore a simple method
for creating a beautiful flower season
and impressing with a fertilizer easily
found around the house.
[Music]
Surely you are wondering how to help
your flower plants grow strong and
vibrant, right?
[Music]
This simple method helps your orchids
stay green and have lots of buds. The
buds always grow plump.
[Music]
Flowers bloom well and last a long
time. New roots are always growing.
helps orchids absorb nutrients
[Music]
best. Now, let's make fertilizer
together. This is garlic powder that
every home has, right?
[Music]
Take one teaspoon of garlic powder and
add one liter of boiled
[Music]
water. Then wait for it to cool before
using.
[Music]
Then filter out the residue.
After filtering, use a towel to wipe the
top and bottom of the leaves with this
water.
[Music]
Garlic has antibacterial properties, so
it helps eliminate fungi and insects on
leaves very
[Music]
well. In addition, garlic also has many
natural minerals necessary for orchid
growth.
[Music]
Apply once a month for better protection
and growth.
[Music]
If you do this regularly, your orchids
will always be green and disease-free.
[Music]
Next, you can also spray this water on
the entire
[Music]
orchid. U this also helps provide
nutrients through the leaves to the
[Music]
orchid. Um you should thoroughly spray
both the underside of the leaves and the
leaf
[Music]
interstases because that is where
insects and fungi often reside causing
harm to orchids.
[Music]
Finally, you use this water to care for
the roots.
Water each orchid pot with about 10
tablespoons of garlic soaking
[Music]
water. This and the way you spray you
apply it every 2 to 3 weeks.
[Music]
Garlic contains natural compounds that
have antibacterial and antifungal
properties. Helps protect orchids from
pests and other harmful agents.
[Music]
Garlic powder also helps strengthen the
plant's natural immune system and
reduces the risk of
[Music]
infection. Nutrients found in garlic
such as potassium and phosphorus.
Nitrogen provides essential nutrients
for orchid growth.
[Music]
Uh after 1 month of of fertilizing with
garlic powder, the plant has grown many
new roots.
Uh, this will help the orchid more
easily absorb more
[Music]
nutrients. When new roots grow a lot, it
is necessary to combine the use of other
types of organic fertilizers such as
fish protein and soy protein. Follow my
instructions to help orchids absorb a
variety of
[Music]
nutrients. If you encounter any
difficulties during the orchid growing
process, don't hesitate to comment. I am
always ready to support you so you can
grow healthy orchids and bloom lots of
[Music]
flowers. Using garlic powder as
fertilizer helps orchids grow strongly.
[Music]
Orchids grow many flower stems at the
same time in the same orchid pot.
[Music]
Orchids become more vibrant and have a
characteristic fragrance.
[Music]
Now I share how to care for Phelinopsis
orchids that bloom continuously from
season to
[Music]
season. In the summer, orchids often rot
like this.
This is a disease caused by
[Music]
bacteria. It spreads very quickly, but
don't
[Music]
worry. Take one liter of water at at
room temperature.
This is an anti-rot medicine for
cabbage. Its composition includes steepy
[Music]
40%. It will remove bacteria very
quickly. You only put in 1/4 of the
tablet.
[Music]
Put it in a spray bottle and spray it
all over the orchid.
[Music]
Uh, I intentionally did not remove the
rotten leaves to show you how steamy
[Music]
works. Any rotten areas need to be
sprayed more.
spray even disease-free
[Music]
leaves. After spraying, leave the orchid
pot in a cool place and do not water for
one
[Music]
[Applause]
week. See results after 1
[Music]
week. All leaves affected by bacterial
rot are dry.
[Music]
Do you see the effectiveness of steamy
against bacteria that cause orchid leaf
rot?
[Music]
Uh, the rotten orchid has recovered and
grown new leaves.
[Music]
After recovering from the disease,
recovery care is needed to help the
orchid grow and bloom
quickly. This is a multivitamin.
Dissolve one tablet in one liter of
[Music]
water. Uh wait for the vitamins to
dissolve and then add 2 L of water to
get 3 L of great fertilizer.
[Music]
Use cotton soaked in this water to wipe
the
[Music]
leaves.
Helps supplement nutrition and clear
[Music]
stamata. Helps orchids photosynthesize
better. Strong orchid leaves increase
resistance to fungi and insects.
[Music]
Or you can also spray this liquid
fertilizer on the entire orchid.
Um, this method works as well as mopping
leaves.
[Music]
Spraying evenly at the base is very good
for
orchids. But don't spray it on the
flowers because if the flowers are wet,
they will quickly fade.
Now you take care of the
roots. You water this liquid fertilizer
on the orchid
[Music]
roots. This helps orchids absorb the
most nutrients.
Because the roots are the main nutrient
absorbers of the
[Music]
orchid. For infected plants, do this
every 2
[Music]
weeks. With normal orchids, you do this
once every 1 to 2 months.
[Music]
Um, helps orchids grow very quickly and
increase
[Music]
resistance. Uh, it is best to soak the
orchid pot in this water for 30 minutes
and then take it out.
[Music]
After only 2 weeks of care, the orchid
has grown many new roots.
[Music]
Many flower buds grow on the same tree.
Thank you for watching the video. Good
luck and see you in the next videos.