Hello everyone. In this video, I will
share a very simple method of
propagating orchids from flower spikes
so you can easily grow new orchids at
home. If you haven't subscribed to the
channel yet, please click the subscribe
button to support me and not miss any
orchid growing tips. It's wonderful to
have you along for the journey. Let's
get started.
[Music]
After blooming, the best time to
propagate orchids from flower spikes is
for the following
[Music]
reasons. After the flowers fade, the
flower stem remains fresh and healthy.
During this time, the flower stem does
not wither, allowing the plant to easily
develop new shoots. The flower stem can
still provide nutrients for the
propagation process.
[Music]
This node has not yet bloomed. So
sprouting from this node is very
[Music]
easy. Um we discard this part because it
has already bloomed and can no longer
sprout.
[Music]
trim the cut to avoid bruising the
orchid
[Music]
cutting. If the cut is bruised, the
orchid cutting is very likely to rot.
Um, which country are you watching this
video from? Please comment and let me
[Music]
know. It's wonderful that we can chat
with each other from all over the world.
[Music]
Take some ground coffee powder.
Then sprinkle pure ground coffee powder
onto the
cut. Ground coffee contains natural
antibacterial and antifungal compounds.
These compounds help prevent harmful
bacteria and fungi from entering the cut
on the orchid stem, reducing the risk of
rot and disease.
[Music]
Then take one full spoon of pure ground
coffee powder and put it into the
[Music]
bottle. Add one liter of boiling water.
steep and leave
[Music]
overnight. After one night, take it out
and strain out the coffee grounds.
Coffee contains natural compounds such
as chlorogenic acid and polyphenols
which have antibacterial and antifungal
effects. Soak the orchid cutting in the
coffee water for 10 minutes.
[Music]
Uh, soaking the orchid cutting in the
coffee solution helps prevent harmful
bacteria and fungi from entering the
stem, protecting it from common diseases
after cutting.
Then use a cotton ball soaked in this
coffee water to gently and thoroughly
wipe the top and bottom surfaces of the
orchid
leaves. Coffee water contains natural
compounds such as chlorogenic acid and
polyphenols that have antibacterial and
antifungal properties.
Uh when you wipe the orchid leaves with
coffee water, these compounds help kill
bacteria, mold, and other pathogens,
reducing the risk of infection or leaf
rot.
Then use the coffee water to water this
orchid
pot. Coffee water contains essential
minerals and nutrients such as nitrogen,
potassium, magnesium, and phosphorus.
These nutrients support plant growth,
helping the orchid grow vigorously,
especially during its vigorous growth
stage.
[Music]
After watering, soak the orchid pot in
this coffee water for about 20
[Music]
minutes. After soaking for 10 minutes,
take out the orchid cutting.
[Music]
scrape off the protective layer to help
the cakey sprout more easily.
[Music]
Take an elev. Aloe vera leaf and apply
the gel onto the cakey
chute. Aloe vera gel contains vitamins
and minerals such as vitamins's A, C, E,
and amino acids that stimulate the
growth of cakey
shoots. These nutrients provide energy
and nourishment for the shoots, helping
them grow healthy and quickly.
Aloe vera gel has excellent moisturizing
properties, helping keep the cakey buds
sufficiently hydrated without causing
excess
wetness. This is very important in
stimulating chute growth without leading
to rot caused by excessive moisture.
[Music]
Put cotton wool into a glass jar.
Place the orchid
[Music]
here. Spray water every 3 days to keep
the orchid cutting moist.
Create an air vent between the inside
and outside of the
jar. Place it in a cool, airy spot. And
remember to spray water every 3 days to
keep the orchid cutting moist.
[Music]
After soaking for about 20 minutes, take
the orchid pot out and place it in a
well-lit
[Music]
area. After soaking for about 20
minutes, take the orchid pot out and
place it in a well-lit area.
You can see that the cakey orchid plant
has
[Music]
sprouted. This orchid has grown new
young roots.
[Music]
Continue spraying water on the orchid
cutting every 3 days.
[Music]
After another 3 weeks,
You can see that the kei orchid has
developed but still hasn't grown roots.
[Music]
After this recovery period, you can see
that the mother orchid's leaves are
healthier and
[Music]
greener. More new roots have
grown.
Continue spraying water on the orchid
cutting every 3 days.
[Music]
after the next month.
The orchid shoot is growing very
healthily.
[Music]
With this simple method, you can
propagate orchids at home.
[Music]
And you can also see that the mother
orchid has grown new flower buds for the
next blooming season.
Now I'm planting the orchid into a new
pot so the baby orchid can grow in an
outdoor environment.
plant the orchid using small pine bark
and a little moss on the surface of the
pot.
Water the plant to keep the baby orchid
moist.
Hope you like the
[Music]
video. If you find the content good and
meaningful, don't forget to like, share.
So many people can know and subscribe to
support me. Thank you for always being
with
me. Thank you for watching the video.
Wishing you luck and success in life.