[Music]
Welcome to the happiness garden. Your
orchid is blooming, but its leaves are
rotting. Don't worry. Today, I'm sharing
a natural way to handle it, helping
prevent the rot from spreading while
keeping the flowers fresh for longer.
[Music]
Let's get started.
You can see this is an orchid with
leaves severely rotting due to fungal
disease. If not treated promptly, the
rotting leaves can spread to other parts
of the plant, affecting its overall
health.
While the orchid is still blooming
beautifully, the question is how to
completely handle the leaf rot without
affecting the flowers on the stem. Don't
worry, watch this entire tutorial and
you'll be able to deal with this
situation easily and safely for both the
leaves and the flowers.
If you haven't subscribed to the
channel, click the subscribe button to
support me and not miss any orchid
growing tips. It's wonderful to have you
along.
Leave a comment to let me know which
country you are watching this video
from. It's wonderful that we can chat
together from all around the world.
Now, we need to remove the rotting
leaves and roots.
[Music]
But before cutting, it's important to
disinfect the pruning tools with rubbing
alcohol to ensure that fungi or bacteria
do not spread to the healthy parts of
the plant.
These rotting leaves contain a lot of
bacteria, so removing them as quickly as
possible is very important. If left for
too long, the bacteria can spread to
healthy leaves and roots, affecting the
overall vitality of the plant.
By removing them in time, you can
prevent the spread, protect the orchid's
continued growth, and keep the flowers
on the stem looking fresh and beautiful.
[Music]
It's best to destroy these rotting
leaves using a disinfectant or dispose
of them outside in the garden, avoiding
leaving them near healthy plants.
Make sure to remove all the rotting
parts and cut slightly beyond the rotten
area to ensure no bacteria or or damaged
tissue remains. Cutting a little extra
will help the orchid recover better and
prevent the rot from spreading to other
healthy parts.
[Music]
Next, check the roots by gently
squeezing each one. If any root is soft,
mushy, or hollow inside, it's a sign
that the root has rotted and should be
cut off immediately.
Timely identification of these damaged
roots is very important as it helps you
remove the diseased parts, prevent the
spread and protect the remaining healthy
root system. When the healthy roots are
preserved, the orchid will continue to
absorb nutrients effectively and
maintain steady growth, keeping the
flowers fresh and beautiful.
[Music]
Ow.
Uh-huh.
Since the orchid has flowers on the
stem, I won't be changing the growing
medium at this time. Instead, we'll wait
until the flowers fade and then change
the medium to avoid affecting the
blooming process and the plant's health.
Next, sprinkle cinnamon powder on the
cut. This helps the cut heal quickly
because cinnamon has antibacterial and
antifungal properties, preventing
bacteria or fungi from entering the new
tissue.
[Music]
Then place the orchid pot in a well
ventilated area for 3 days and do not
water it. This allows the cut to dry
completely in the medium to reduce
moisture, creating an ideal environment
to prevent fungi and bacteria from
growing.
[Music]
After 3 days without watering, when the
cuts have completely dried, the orchid
will be in a safer condition.
At this point, you can confidently
continue with the next care steps
without worrying about affecting the
flowers on the stem. Allowing the plant
to rest during this stage not only helps
the wounds heal, but also gives the
orchid time to regain strength and
prepare for more sustainable growth.
[Music]
The first ingredient I choose to make
natural fertilizer for orchids is aloe
vera leaves. You only need one fresh
aloe vera leaf as it contains many
beneficial nutrients for the plant,
especially helping to restore roots and
make the leaves naturally shiny and
green.
The next ingredient is honey, and you
only need one small teaspoon. Honey not
only has natural antibacterial
properties, but also helps stimulate the
growth of new roots and enhances the
orchid's ability to absorb nutrients.
[Music]
The next ingredient is vitamin B1. You
only need three tablets of 2.5 millig
each. Vitamin B1 helps stimulate root
growth, strengthen resistance, and
support the orchid's recovery after
pruning or environmental changes. When
dissolved together with aloe vera and
honey, this mixture provides the
essential energy and nutrients that help
the orchid grow strong from roots to
leaves and produce longerlasting, more
beautiful blooms.
After preparing all the ingredients, add
them all into one liter of clean water.
[Music]
Next, blend the mixture thoroughly.
Blending helps release the nutrients in
aloe vera, honey, and vitamin B1 to the
fullest, allowing them to dissolve
easily into the water. As a result, when
used, the orchid can absorb the
nutrients more quickly and benefit from
natural, long-lasting care.
[Music]
After blending, you need to strain out
the residue to get a clearer and
smoother solution. This step helps the
liquid absorb more easily into the roots
and leaves when watering or spraying,
while also preventing blockage on the
surface of the growing medium.
[Music]
Step one, pour this liquid fertilizer
mixture into a spray bottle.
[Music]
Then gently spray evenly over the roots
and the surface of the orchid's growing
medium. Misting in this way allows the
nutrients to penetrate deeply into the
roots, providing the necessary moisture
and energy for faster absorption.
This is a simple yet effective way to
nourish the plant from the base, helping
the roots grow strong and the leaves
stay naturally shiny and green.
[Music]
When you you spray the solution only on
the roots and the growing medium without
spraying it on the stems and leaves, the
plant won't have water accumulating on
the leaf surface. This is very important
because uh standing water is the main
cause of leaf rot in orchids.
This way you provide enough nutrients to
the roots while keeping the leaves dry
and healthy, helping the plant grow
steadily and the flowers last longer.
Step two, use a soft cloth soaked in the
mixture. Then gently wipe both the upper
and lower surfaces of the leaves.
[Music]
When you wipe the leaves with a mixture
of aloe vera, honey, and vitamin B1, the
natural nutrients will be absorbed
directly through the leaf surface,
making the leaves greener, shinier, and
full of vitality.
Aloe vera provides natural moisture to
prevent the leaves from drying out,
while honey forms a a thin protective
layer that helps the leaves retain water
longer.
[Music]
Regularly wiping the leaves helps remove
dust, bacteria, and mold from the
surface, allowing light to reach them
more easily. When the leaves are clean
and bright, photosynthesis becomes more
efficient, helping the plant absorb
energy better and grow more vigorously.
[Music]
Honey has natural antibacterial
properties while aloe vera contains
antifungal compounds that help limit the
growth of bacteria and fungal diseases
on the leaves. Wiping the leaves with
this mixture creates a natural
protective layer. helping the orchid
resist humid environments where mold
easily develops.
[Music]
Vitamin B1 in the mixture plays a role
in stimulating metabolism, helping the
plant absorb nutrients more effectively.
When the leaves are healthy, nutrient
transport throughout the plant also
improves, which in turn promotes
stronger root growth and results in more
abundant, longerlasting blooms.
You should spray and wipe the leaves
with this mixture once a week. This
frequency allows the orchid to absorb
nutrients regularly while keeping the
leaves clean, glossy, and healthy.
You can pour the remaining mixture into
a larger spray bottle to use for other
healthy orchids in your garden.
You can pour the remaining mixture into
a larger spray bottle to use for other
healthy orchids in your garden.
Uh this is a great way to provide extra
natural nutrients to your entire orchid
garden, helping all the plants grow
evenly and beautifully.
When cared for with such a nutrient-rich
solution, the roots become stronger, the
leaves greener, and the flowers last
longer, creating a garden full of
vitality.
The nutrients from aloe vera, honey, and
vitamin B1 will nourish the roots,
thicken the leaf tissues, and help the
plant become more resistant to weather
changes and pests.
When you care for them regularly like
this, your entire orchid garden will
always stay fresh, full of energy, and
bloom continuously throughout the year.
That is the simple happiness every
orchid lover wishes to have in their own
garden.
[Music]
And here is the result after 3 weeks of
care. You can clearly see that the
leaves have become glossier, thicker,
and stronger than before.
[Music]
The previous cuts have also completely
dried with no signs of rot or mold.
The orchid now looks healthy, vibrant,
and full of life. The flowers remain on
the stem without wilting. A clear proof
of the effectiveness of this gentle yet
incredibly beneficial natural care
method.
In addition, you can see that many new
roots have started to grow. The light
green or bright white root tips indicate
that the plant is absorbing nutrients
well and recovering strongly.
When the roots grow strong like this,
the plant becomes more stable, absorbs
water and nutrients more efficiently,
and its leaves become greener while the
flowers last longer.
[Music]
And here is the result after the next 2
months. You can see that the orchid has
fully recovered with no signs of leaf
rot remaining.
And especially the three flower spikes
have grown vigorously and bloomed with
bright, longlasting and vibrant flowers.
This is the wonderful result of patient
and natural care. When you give your
orchid love and proper attention, it
will always return that care with its
most radiant beauty.
Um, what do you think about the way I
revived this little orchid? Don't
hesitate to leave a comment and share
your thoughts. I'd love to hear your
feedback and experiences.
[Music]
Um, I hope you enjoyed this video. If
you found it helpful, don't forget to
like and subscribe so you won't miss
future tips on how how to care for
orchids naturally and simply.
Thank you so much for watching. I truly
appreciate your time and support. Don't
forget to like, subscribe, and share if
you enjoyed this video. Wishing you a
wonderful day filled with joy and
blooming orchids. See you in the next
video.