Welcome to my garden to help you have
more choices in caring for orchids at
home using natural fertilizers made from
ingredients already available in every
household kitchen. It helps your orchids
grow vigorously and bloom brilliantly
all year round in your garden or on your
balcony. If you haven't subscribed to
the channel yet, please click the
subscribe button to support me and never
miss any orchid growing tips. It's truly
wonderful to have you with me on this
journey.
Let's get
started. To make fertilizer for orchids,
now I use
beer. Um, recently the method of using
beer to water plants has been widely
spread among bonsai enthusiasts as a way
to help plants grow green and flower
more. If you're interested in this
topic, let's try using beer to make
fertilizer for
orchids. Four spoons of beer.
[Music]
dilute in 1 k2 liter of water at room
temperature. First
way, irrigate the root
[Music]
evenly. Leave me a comment letting me
know which country you're watching from.
It's wonderful that we can connect and
chat with each other from all around the
[Music]
world. How to water orchids will help
plants grow better everyday thanks to
the formula containing sugar and starch
water. These ingredients in beer contain
high nutrient
content. After soaking into the
substrate, it will form an energy source
for orchids.
[Music]
This will be a clean fertilizer for
orchids, helping plants grow better.
[Music]
This will be a clean fertilizer for
orchids, helping plants grow
[Music]
better. Beer can repel insects harmful
to orchids, protecting the safety of the
entire orchid.
Uh the characteristic beer smell will
keep animals like snails bees away
thereby helping the plant to grow
well. Do this with your orchid once a
month.
[Music]
Second
way, pour this water into a spray
bottle.
[Music]
Spray evenly on the surface of the
substrate. Beer contains many beneficial
phytonutrients that including minerals,
sugars, and proteins.
[Music]
These substances will help plants grow
and improve health quickly.
[Music]
Beer also contains protein which is an
essential nutrient for plant growth.
[Music]
Next
When eating bananas, don't rush to throw
away the shell.
[Music]
Use the white side of the banana
peel. Clean the surface of the leaves.
[Music]
Clean both the top and bottom of the
leaves. Do this once a month.
[Music]
Let's see the
result. My orchids are cared for by this
[Music]
method. Leaves thrive. Big sturdy
leaves. Leaves are not attacked by
insects.
[Music]
Due to enough nutrition, there are many
flower buds.
[Music]
The natural phosphorus content in beer
helps orchids easily absorb like so the
roots grow very strongly.
[Music]
The natural potassium content in beer
makes it easy for orchids to absorb, so
flower buds develop more.
[Music]
Potassium and sugar and beer help
flowers bloom longer.
[Music]
Um, potassium is a substance that helps
carry water from the root to the flower.
Because the water is transported enough,
the flowers will stay fresh for a long
time. The flowers can bloom for about 3
to 6 months before fading.
When orchids are healthy and
wellnourished, they have the ability to
bloom multiple times a year, bringing
vibrant beauty and freshness to your
garden throughout all four
seasons. I hope this video will be very
helpful for you, making it easier and
more effective than ever to take care of
orchids at home.
If you find it helpful, don't forget to
click like, share the video so uh more
people can discover it and remember to
subscribe to the channel to support me
and give me more motivation to create
even more useful
videos. In addition to the English
voiceover, we have now created French,
German, Italian, Spanish, Portuguese,
Japanese, Hindi, and Indonesian versions
to help you listen and understand the
content more easily.
Additionally, our video also includes
subtitles in various languages from
around the world, making it easy for you
to follow along and understand the
[Music]
content. Thank you for watching. I
always pray that God blesses all of you.