Welcome everyone to my beloved little
garden where I share simple yet
heartfelt things for my beautiful orchid
pots. Today I will share with you how to
make a simple natural fertilizer at home
to help restore the or the orchid after
it has finished blooming so the plant
can continue to grow healthily and
prepare for the next blooming.
Um, you can see that my orchid has many
spent flower stems, but don't worry,
it's a normal sign and we can help the
plant recover
better. We need to remove all the wilted
petals so the plant can focus its energy
on developing roots and leaves,
preparing for the next blooming.
[Music]
The unopened buds can be stimulated to
produce new flower stems here, helping
the plant bloom continuously throughout
the
year. As for the buds that have already
bloomed, they cannot bloom again. So, we
just need to take good care of the
remaining buds.
[Music]
Next, take about 250 ml of water into a
cup. Next, you need to prepare baking
soda. This is the main ingredient that
helps adjust the pH in the orchid pot
and prevent some harmful fungi and
bacteria. Just about a/ teaspoon of
baking soda is enough. No need for too
much as we only need the right amount to
achieve the desired effect without
harming the plant.
Next, you need neem oil. Neem oil helps
repel insects and prevent bacterial and
fungal diseases, helping to protect the
orchid plant and keep it
healthy. Just one teaspoon of neem oil
is enough. This amount of oil will
create an effective solution without
overloading the plant.
Stir well to ensure that the neem oil
and baking soda dissolve completely into
the water, creating a uniform solution
ready to
use. Step one, use a soft cloth to soak
up this mixture and gently wipe both the
top and bottom of the leaves, helping to
remove dust and small insects while also
protecting the leaves from diseases.
[Music]
Neem oil can help maintain the natural
moisture of the leaves, preventing them
from drying out and keeping the leaves
soft and fresh.
The combination of baking soda and neem
oil not only helps remove insects, but
also creates a protective layer on the
leaves, helping the plant effectively
resist pests and diseases.
After wiping the leaves, pour this
mixture into a spray bottle. Make sure
the spray bottle is clean and ready to
spray evenly on the leaves and the
orchid's growing medium.
After wiping the leaves, pour this
mixture into a spray bottle. Make sure
the spray bottle is clean and ready to
spray evenly on the leaves and the
orchid's growing
medium. When sprayed on the leaves, this
mixture helps remove dirt and small
insects, protects the leaves from
diseases, and helps the plant
photosynthesize more
effectively. When sprayed on the stem,
it helps prevent the growth of bacteria
and fungi, keeping the stem healthy and
preventing it from rotting or getting
damaged.
[Music]
When sprayed on the roots and growing
medium, it helps balance the pH in the
medium, promoting better root
development and more effective nutrient
absorption.
Step three, use a soft cloth to absorb
the excess water on the leaves and
between the leaf veins, helping the
leaves dry quickly and preventing mold
from
developing. Uh, please comment and let
me know which country you're watching
the video from. It's wonderful that we
can chat with each other from all around
the world.
After that, place the orchid pot in a
spot with gentle sunlight and good
airflow. Do not water it for 3 days to
allow the plant time to absorb the
nutrients and recover
naturally. Next, we will prepare another
very special natural fertilizer for
orchids. You only need a few familiar
ingredients. Ripe banana, garlic, honey,
and warm
water. Take one ripe banana and slice it
into thin pieces. Bananas provide plenty
of potassium and natural nutrients that
help stimulate strong flowering in the
plant.
Um, then put the sliced banana into a
clean jar. A glass or plastic jar will
work as long as it has a tight fitting
lid for fermentation.
[Music]
Next, take three cloves of garlic and
chop them finely. Garlic helps with
antibacterial and antifungal properties
and boosts the orchid's resistance.
[Music]
If you haven't subscribe to the channel
yet, please hit the subscribe button to
support me and not miss any orchid
growing tips. It's truly wonderful to
have you along on this journey.
After slicing, add the garlic to the jar
along with the banana.
[Music]
The next ingredient is one teaspoon of
dry yeast. The dry yeast will help
ferment the mixture, creating enzymes
that are beneficial for the orchid's
growth.
Uh the next ingredient is honey. Add
about 1 teaspoon of honey which will
enrich the mixture with nutrients and
support the fermentation process.
[Music]
Finally, add 0.5 L of warm water. The
warm water helps dissolve the
ingredients and stimulates the
fermentation process
[Music]
quickly. We should not fill the jar
completely with water leaving some space
at the top uh because fermentation will
produce gas.
This space allows the mixture to avoid
overflowing as gas is created during the
fermentation
process. Then close the lid and place
the jar in a cool airy spot for 3 weeks.
After this time, the mixture will
ferment and produce GE, growth enhancer,
ready to be used for the orchids.
[Music]
And here is the GE product I made 3
weeks ago. So, it's ready to be applied
to the orchids.
[Music]
Take 20 ml of GE and dilute it with one
liter of water. This mixture will
provide nutrients for the orchid,
helping the plant grow strong and bloom
longer.
[Music]
Step four, use a soft cloth to soak up
this mixture and wrap it around the
unopened buds to help stimulate the
growth of new flower stems. The GE will
provide nutrients to help these buds
develop and bloom in the future.
[Music]
Step Four, use a soft cloth to soak up
this mixture and wrap it around the
unopened buds to help stimulate the
growth of new flower stems. The GE will
provide nutrients to help these buds
develop and bloom in the
future. Just water each pot with about
10 tablespoons of the GE mixture. Uh,
this amount is enough to provide
nutrients to the plant without
overwatering and causing root rot.
[Music]
Uh, in addition to the English
voiceover, we have now created
voiceovers in French, German, Italian,
Spanish, Portuguese, Japanese, Hindi,
and Indonesian to help you listen to and
understand the content more
easily. For languages without
voiceovers, we have created subtitles so
you can read and understand the content.
Then pour this mixture into a spray
bottle.
Step six, spray this mixture over the
entire orchid pot, including the leaves,
stem, roots, and growing medium.
Spraying helps evenly distribute
nutrients, stimulating the plant to grow
and bloom
continuously. When you spray it on the
leaves and roots, it helps the orchid
easily absorb essential nutrients from
the GE mixture, supporting healthy
growth and strengthening the root
system.
Spraying on the stem and unopened nodes
helps stimulate the orchid to bloom
regularly, contributing to beautiful and
long- lasting flowering
periods. The GE mixture helps repel
harmful insects and supports disease
prevention, making the orchid plant
healthier. Wait 20 minutes before
removing the cloth wrapped around the
nodes. This amount of time is enough for
the nutrients to be absorbed and to
stimulate the nodes to develop new
flower
spikes. Wait 20 minutes before removing
the cloth wrapped around the nodes. This
amount of time is enough for the
nutrients to be absorbed and to
stimulate the nodes to develop new
flower spikes.
[Music]
After 20 minutes, remove the cloth
wrapped around the nodes and repeat once
a week. This helps stimulate the growth
of new flower
[Music]
stems. After soaking the orchid pot for
about 20 minutes, remember to take it
out. This helps the plant absorb
nutrients effectively without causing
water
logging. Step seven, use a cloth to
absorb the excess water on the leaves
and leaf axles. This helps prevent water
from accumulating, avoiding leaf rot and
keeping the leaves dry and well
ventilated.
[Music]
Um, after wiping the leaves, place the
orchid pot in a spot with gentle
sunlight. This helps the plant recover
and grow naturally without being
affected by harsh sunlight.
Use any remaining mixture to spray on
orchids that are currently blooming.
This helps the flowers last longer and
maintains the plant's
health. Um, the GE mixture helps boost
the orchid's resistance, allowing the
plant to defend against environmental
stressors like intense sunlight and
drought.
The nutrients in this mixture promote
root development, helping the orchid
absorb water and nutrients more
effectively. The GE mixture provides
nutrients that help the orchids leaves
grow strong, shiny, and fresh, giving
the plant a healthy appearance.
The nutrients in GE not only help the
current flowers last longer, but also
stimulate the buds that haven't bloomed
yet, encouraging the orchid to flower
continuously. Using GE fertilizer to
care for orchids is very beneficial, but
it should be done about twice a month.
This allows the plant to absorb
nutrients effectively without causing
overfertilization.
[Music]
Now, let me show you the results after
after one month of care with natural
[Music]
fertilizer. You can see that the orchid
has grown many new roots, which proves
that the natural fertilizer has helped
the plant grow healthily and absorb
nutrients better.
[Music]
The leaves have become greener, shinier,
and stronger compared to before using
the natural
fertilizer. The orchid has grown a new
leaf, which proves that the care method
and natural fertilizer are working very
well for the plant's development.
[Music]
And you can also see the flowers lasting
much longer, which proves that the
natural fertilizer helps the flowers
stay fresh for a longer time.
[Music]
In addition, new flower stems have
emerged from the buds that I had
stimulated when applying the natural
fertilizer a month ago.
[Music]
Uh, other orchids when treated with
natural fertilizer show larger flower
petals and multiple flower stems on the
same plant.
[Music]
Uh other orchids when treated with
natural fertilizer show larger flower
petals and multiple flower stems on the
same
plant. How do you think about the way I
revived my weak orchid? Please leave a
comment and share your suggestions with
me.
Uh, if you encounter any difficulties
while growing orchids, don't hesitate to
leave a comment. I'm always ready to
support you so you can grow healthy
orchids with lots of beautiful
blooms. If you find the content helpful
and meaningful, don't forget to like,
share so more people can know about it,
and subscribe to support me. Thank you
for always being with me.
I always pray that God blesses all of
you. Goodbye and see you next time.