Hello everyone. Today I'm going to share
with you a simple way to make natural
fertilizer at home, which will help your
orchids grow healthy, lush, and bloom
beautifully throughout the
garden. Thanks to this natural
fertilizer, the roots and leaves of the
plant will stay healthy, which in turn
helps the orchid produce not only more
flowers, but also longerlasting blooms
that retain their color and stay on the
stem for a long time before fading.
The method is very simple. Anyone can do
it using familiar ingredients found
right in the
kitchen. Let's get
started. As you can see, this is an old
orchid with many leaves at the base
starting to turn yellow and gradually
fall off. This is a sign that the plant
is weak and needs proper care to
recover. To help the plant recover, we
need to cut off the yellow leaves,
withered leaves, and especially any
leaves showing signs of
[Music]
disease. After removing the yellow and
withered leaves, we continue by cutting
off any damaged, rotting, or injured
roots.
This will prevent the plant from
spreading any diseases and allow it to
focus its nutrients on the remaining
healthy roots and
leaves. To identify damaged roots,
gently squeeze them. If the roots feel
soft, mushy, or have a foul odor, it
means they are rotting and should be cut
off
immediately. This helps stop the spread
of disease and protects the remaining
healthy roots.
Uh, please comment and let me know which
country you're watching the video from.
It's amazing that we can chat with each
other from all over the
world. If you haven't subscribe to the
channel yet, please hit the subscribe
button to support me and make sure you
don't miss any orchid growing tips. It's
wonderful to have you as a companion on
this journey.
After trimming all the damaged leaves
and roots, we place the orchid in a
cool, wellventilated area and let it
rest overnight. This gives the plant
time to recover before we start
fertilizing and continuing
[Music]
care. Today to make natural fertilizer
for the orchid, I will be using coffee.
Take three tablespoons of pure coffee
and add it to a
bottle. Coffee is not only a great
source of nutrition for the plant, but
it also helps increase the acidity of
the soil, allowing the plant to absorb
nutrients more
effectively. Pour one liter of boiling
water to dilute the coffee.
Then let it sit overnight to cool
naturally, allowing the coffee to fully
dissolve in the water.
The next ingredient is wheat
flour. Uh wheat flour provides
additional nutrients for the plant,
especially important minerals like
phosphorus and magnesium which help the
orchid grow
healthier. Take one teaspoon of wheat
flour, then add it to one liter of water
at room temperature to dilute it.
Then let this solution sit overnight at
room temperature. This allows the
components in the wheat flour to fully
blend together, creating a highly
effective fertilizer for the orchid.
After letting it sit overnight, strain
out the coffee grounds before using the
solution. Stir the strained coffee
solution well to ensure the nutrients
are fully blended into the water, ready
to provide nourishment for the orchid.
In addition to the English voiceover, we
have now created voiceovers in French,
German, Italian, Spanish, Portuguese,
Japanese, Hindi, and Indonesian to help
you listen to and understand the content
more easily.
[Applause]
Uh for languages without voiceovers, we
have created subtitles so you can read
and understand the content.
Step one, use a soft cloth to soak up
the coffee solution and gently wipe both
the top and bottom of the orchid leaves.
As you can see, the leaves of the plant
are very dusty and dirty. This not only
reduces the plant's ability to
photosynthesize, but also hinders the
absorption of nutrients through the leaf
surface.
Therefore, cleaning the leaves is a very
important step before moving on to the
next stages of
care. Wiping orchid leaves with the
coffee solution helps strengthen their
resistance as coffee prevents attacks
from harmful fungi and bacteria that
commonly appear on the leaf surface.
This helps deliver nutrients directly
through the leaf surface. As coffee
contains nitrogen and minerals that
promote lush, healthy foliage from the
inside
out. Wiping orchid leaves with the
coffee solution helps strengthen their
resistance as coffee prevents attacks
from harmful fungi and bacteria that
commonly appear on the leaf surface.
When the leaves are healthy, they help
nourish the entire plant, stem, roots,
and flowers, leading to more abundant
blooms that last
longer. Um, to help the orchid grow
healthy, you should wipe the leaves with
the coffee solution once a week during
the first month. After that, you can
reduce the frequency to once a month to
maintain the health of the leaves and
the
plant. Step two, pour the coffee
solution into a spray bottle. Using a
spray bottle helps you easily mist the
solution onto other parts of the orchid,
such as the stem and roots, allowing the
plant to absorb nutrients optimally.
Then spray the coffee solution onto the
front and back of the leaves, the leaf
axles, the stem, and the roots of the
orchid.
Make sure to spray evenly so that the
solution penetrates all parts of the
plant, helping the orchid absorb the
full nutrients from the
coffee. The components in coffee
stimulate root development, providing
the orchid with a solid foundation to
absorb nutrients more effectively.
Regularly providing nutrients through
the coffee solution by spraying helps
the orchid stay healthy, which in turn
promotes longer lasting and fresher
blooms. You can spray the coffee
solution on the orchid once a week
during the first month to ensure the
plant absorbs all the nutrients. After
that, reduce the frequency to one to two
times a month to maintain the health of
the plant.
Then you should spread a thin layer of
moss on top of the orchid
pot. Moss not only helps retain moisture
in the soil, but also keeps the orchid
hydrated, especially in dry
environments. At the same time, the moss
layer enhances the appearance of the
orchid pot.
[Music]
Next, stir the wheat flour solution
well. Then, mix it with the coffee
solution that you prepared earlier to
create a perfect fertilizer for the
orchid.
When mixing, make sure to strain it
carefully to remove the wheat flour
residue, leaving only the clear liquid.
[Music]
Step three, water the orchid. pot with
the coffee and wheat flour
mixture. After thoroughly mixing the two
solutions, gently water the soil around
the roots of the
orchid. The coffee and wheat flour
mixture provides essential nutrients
such as nitrogen, phosphorus, and
potassium, helping the orchid grow
strong from the leaves to the roots.
Um, wheat flour improves the soil
structure, making it more airy and
loose, creating favorable conditions for
the orchid's roots to grow and absorb
nutrients. The nutrients in coffee and
wheat flour promote strong root
development, providing the orchid with a
solid foundation for sustainable growth.
Uh this mixture helps protect the orchid
from fungal diseases, bacteria, and
harmful insects, keeping the plant
healthy and preventing health
issues. When provided with the necessary
nutrients from wheat flour and coffee,
the orchid will grow strong, leading to
more even and longerlasting
blooms. Then soak the orchid pot in this
mixture for about 20 minutes.
[Music]
Then remember to remove the orchid pot
and allow the soil to drain completely.
This helps prevent water logging and
keeps the plant
healthy. Step four, use a soft cloth to
absorb any excess water in the leaf
axles.
This helps prevent water from staying on
the leaves for too long, avoiding rot or
creating conditions for mold to
develop. Gently wipe off any excess
water to ensure the orchid stays dry and
healthy.
After absorbing the excess water from
the leaf axles, place the orchid pot in
a spot with gentle sunlight so the plant
can photosynthesize
[Music]
well. Now let's take a look at the
results after using this mixture for
care for 2 weeks.
You can see that the leaves have become
shiny, green, firm, and healthy. Clearly
showing strong growth after using this
mixture. The orchid is thriving with no
more yellowing or wilting leaves.
Instead, it has a vibrant, lush green
layer of leaves full of vitality.
The plant is growing strong sustainably
and will be ready for the next blooming
cycle. New roots have developed, making
the orchid more stable and able to
absorb nutrients more effectively.
The strong development of the root
system forms a solid foundation that
nourishes the entire ire orchid. It
helps the plant not only stay healthy
but also build enough inner strength to
produce vibrant, long-lasting and lively
blooms. New roots help the plant absorb
nutrients from the soil and fertilizer
more quickly and efficiently,
contributing to the nourishment of the
entire stem, leaves, and flower buds.
[Music]
New roots help the plant anchor more
firmly to the growing medium, increasing
its resistance to changing weather
conditions and harmful environmental
factors.
[Music]
The new flower spike has grown
remarkably larger and longer than
before, signaling that a vibrant
blooming period is just around the
corner.
This vigorous growth is the result of
proper care and the natural nutrients
the plant has been provided
with. Take care of your orchid with all
your love and patience. Just like
nurturing a little miracle in your very
own
garden. Every green leaf, every new
root, every blooming flower is the sweet
result of sincere care.
As long as you nurture with love, the
orchid will respond with gentle beauty
and enduring
vitality. As long as you nurture with
love, the orchid will respond with
gentle beauty and enduring vitality. Let
every moment of care become a joy
because with nature, love always sprouts
and grows.
If you found this video helpful and love
learning how to care for orchids, don't
forget to like and share it with your
friends and family so everyone can can
take care of their orchids
healthily. Make sure to subscribe to the
channel and hit the notification bell so
you never miss out on the latest videos
on orchid care and other interesting
tips.
Make sure to subscribe to the channel
and hit the notification bell so you
never miss out on the latest videos on
orchid care and other interesting tips.