Welcome to a little corner full of love
where orchid petals bloom and joy is
nurtured every day. This is our
happiness garden. In this video, I will
continue to share with you a simple way
to use natural fertilizer to help revive
orchids that are weak or sick so they
can recover from roots to leaves.
Let's get started. In summer, when
humidity and temperature rise, growing
orchids often comes with the risk of
fungal infections leading to root rot
and leaf rot. Uh, one of the common
diseases that can quickly weaken
orchids.
Uh, these rotting leaves often contain a
large number of fungal spores. If not
treated in time, uh, they can spread and
damage the entire orchid plant.
When you notice signs of disease in your
orchid, you should quickly isolate the
pot from the garden or place it away
from other healthy orchids to prevent
the spread and create favorable
conditions for recovery.
[Music]
Let me know in the comments which
country you're watching this video from.
It's wonderful that we can connect and
chat with each other from all around the
world.
[Music]
If you haven't subscribed yet, please
hit the subscribe button to support me
and never miss any orchid growing tips.
It's truly wonderful to have you along
on this journey.
[Music]
Then promptly cut off all the rotting
parts such as damaged leaves, roots, or
pseudo bulbs to prevent the fungus from
spreading further and to help the plant
focus on recovery.
[Music]
As you can see, the roots have been
completely damaged due to prolonged
water logging. This is the main reason
why the orchid becomes weak and more
susceptible to disease.
[Music]
Cut off all the rotted roots and stems,
keeping only the healthy parts to give
the orchid the best chance. the best
chance to recover.
[Music]
In addition to the English voiceover, we
have now created versions in French,
German, Italian, Spanish, Portuguese,
Japanese, Hindi, Dutch, Polish, Korean,
and Indonesian to help you listen and
understand the content more easily.
To listen in your preferred language,
open the video and click on settings,
the gear icon, to select the appropriate
audio language.
[Music]
When cutting off the rotting leaf, I
accidentally damaged the leaf base as
well. This is something that's sometimes
hard to avoid when handling weak
orchids.
So, I decided to remove this leaf as
well to prevent the risk of spreading
disease and to help the plant recover
better.
[Music]
After that, I gently rinse the entire
orchid with water to remove any
remaining fungus and to clean the cut
areas.
[Music]
Next, I let the orchid dry completely in
a well ventilated environment before
proceeding with the next care steps.
To make fertilizer that helps the orchid
recover, I use rice. Um because rice
contains a lot of starch and natural
nutrients that are very beneficial for
root development.
I use 3 teaspoon of rice. This amount is
just enough to create a gentle yet
nutrient-rich fertilizer mixture for the
orchid.
Then I add the rice to one liter of
clean water and let it sit for one day
to allow natural mild fermentation which
creates beneficial microorganisms that
help the orchid roots absorb nutrients
more effectively.
[Music]
Then I use a soft cloth to gently wipe
off any remaining water on the leaves
and stem of the orchid.
[Music]
Then sprinkle a bit of cinnamon powder
on the cut areas to disinfect, prevent
fungus, and help the cuts heal faster.
[Music]
I place the orchid in a cool, airy spot
for one day to let the cuts dry
completely and allow the plant to adjust
before moving on to the next step.
After soaking for one day, I stir the
mixture well so that the nutrients from
the lightly fermented rice fully
dissolve into the water, creating a
microch solution for the orchid.
[Music]
Next, I strain the mixture to get the
clear liquid, making it easier to use
and preventing residue from sticking to
the roots.
[Music]
Um, the next ingredient I use to combine
with the lightly fermented rice water is
vitamin B1, a nutrient that helps
stimulate root growth and supports quick
recovery of the orchid.
[Music]
I add three tablets of vitamin B1, each
containing 0.25 gram to boost resistance
and support the orchid in quickly
sprouting new roots.
[Music]
Step one, use a soft cloth to soak up
the mixture. Then gently wipe the entire
stem, leaves, and base of the orchid so
the nutrients can be directly absorbed
into each part.
[Music]
Wiping the orchid with this mixture
helps gently disinfect and clean the
surface of the leaves, stem, and base,
preventing the growth of harmful fungi
and bacteria.
[Music]
Uh this method also provides nutrients
and stimulates the plant to absorb them
directly through the leaves and stem
helping it recover faster and
encouraging new root growth.
[Music]
Step two, soak the orchid's base in this
mixture for about 20 minutes to give the
roots time to absorb the nutrients and
beneficial microorganisms.
The mixture helps the damaged areas heal
quickly while promoting the growth of
strong new roots thanks to the natural
nutrients and vitamin B1.
[Music]
After soaking for about 20 minutes, I
begin preparing the necessary tools to
proceed with the recovery and care of
the orchid.
[Music]
I gently take the orchid out of the
mixture and dry off any remaining water
on the stem and leaves.
[Music]
Then I wrap a piece of jute twine around
the base to create an artificial root
system.
[Music]
I pour clean water into the pot, making
sure it doesn't touch the stem to avoid
the risk of stem rot.
[Music]
The water level in the pot is set to be
about 1 cm below the stem. The juke
twine wrapped around the base will draw
the water upward, keeping the stem
evenly moist and creating ideal
conditions to stimulate new root growth.
[Music]
Every 5 days, soak the artificial roots
and the orchid stem in the mixture of
lightly fermented rice water and vitamin
B1 for about 20 minutes to provide
nutrients and stimulate consistent root
growth.
[Music]
After that, simply place the orchid back
into the original pot of water and
continue maintaining stable humidity to
support the root growing process.
Place the orchid in a spot with gentle
sunlight and good air flow to enhance
photosynthesis. This will help the
rooting process occur faster and more
vigorously.
[Music]
And here's the result after 1 month.
You can see that many new roots have
grown densely. This shows that the
orchid has recovered well and is now
growing strong from within.
[Music]
These new roots will help the orchid
absorb water and nutrients more
effectively, providing a solid
foundation for continued growth and
preparation for its next blooming cycle.
[Music]
And you can also see the leaves have
become glossy green and full of
vitality. Additionally, the orchid is
growing new leaves which shows that.
[Music]
What do you think about my method for
restoring weak orchids? Please leave
your comments and share your thoughts
with me.
To help the orchid grow healthy and
bloom brilliantly in the next season,
you should repot it into a larger pot so
the roots have enough space to develop.
I choose a pot with drainage holes at
the bottom to ensure water does not
accumulate, keeping the orchid roots
healthy and preventing water logging.
[Music]
I use crushed pine bark as the main
growing medium combined with about 10%
moss uh to help retain moisture and
create a well-errated environment for
the roots to develop better.
[Music]
Uh when planting, gently place the
orchid into the pot to avoid damaging
the newly growing roots.
Then I secure the orchid to a support
stick to keep the stem upright, helping
the roots anchor firmly and grow
steadily.
I spread a bit of moss on the surface of
the orchid pot to help retain moisture
in the growing medium and create a
favorable environment for the young
roots to grow faster.
[Music]
After planting, you can lightly water
the potting medium to keep it moist,
helping the orchid settle in quickly and
begin to grow.
[Music]
You need to observe carefully. Only when
the roots have firmly attached to the
growing medium and the plant has
stabilized uh should you start
fertilizing the orchid.
Don't forget to place the orchid pot in
a spot with gentle sunlight and good air
flow to support photosynthesis,
promote fast root development, and keep
the leaves healthy and green.
With patience and proper care, your
orchid will make a strong recovery, grow
lush and green again, and soon bloom
with vibrant, lively flowers.
If you find the content helpful and
meaningful, don't forget to like, share
so more people can see it and subscribe
to support me.
Thank you for taking the time to watch.
Wishing you good health and lots of
beautiful orchids in your little garden.
See you in the next video.