Welcome to my channel. Here you will
find simple yet effective orchid care
tips that help your plants grow healthy
and bloom beautifully right at home.
Each video is created for easy
application whether you are a beginner
or experienced.
In this video, I will continue to share
simple yet very effective methods giving
you more options for caring for orchids
at home using organic fertilizer.
[Music]
This method not only supports the
propagation of new plants, but also
helps flowers bloom abundantly, last
longer, and hang brightly on the stems
for a long time before fading.
If you haven't subscribed to the
channel, please hit the subscribe button
to support me and not miss any orchid
growing tips. It's wonderful to have you
along.
Please comment and let me know which
country you are watching the video from.
It's wonderful that we can chat together
from all around the world.
To make this fertilizer, I use one
teaspoon of rice.
[Music]
Then soak the rice in a cup of water
about 300 millimeters for 30 minutes to
allow the essence from the rice uh to
dissolve and prepare for the next step.
[Music]
Then soak the rice in a cup of water
about 300 ml and then blend it until
smooth.
After blending, pour the mixture and
strain it through a sie to remove the
residue, keeping only the smooth liquid
ready to be used as fertilizer for
orchids.
[Music]
Then mix the filtered solution into 10
cups of water, approximately 3 L, to
create a liquid fertilizer mixture
sufficient for watering orchids at home.
[Music]
Next, add 3 tablespoons of GE ginger
solution to the mixture. GE ginger has
antibacterial properties, helping
protect the roots and leaves of orchids
while also stimulating healthy plant
growth.
[Music]
First method, use this liquid fertilizer
mixture to water directly onto the
orchid roots and growing medium, helping
the plant absorb nutrients quickly and
grow healthily.
[Music]
Fertilizer made from rice water combined
with GE ginger solution provides all the
necessary nutrients and amino acids
supporting strong orchid growth. In
particular, this method helps stimulate
rapid sprouting, bringing fresh vitality
to the orchids.
[Music]
Rice not only provides nutrients but
also helps develop beneficial
microorganisms, creating a natural
protective layer for orchid roots,
preventing root rot. pot and maintaining
plant health.
Apply this method once a month to
provide full nutrients and boost the
orchid's resistance, helping the plant
stay healthy and bloom beautifully.
[Music]
Second method,
you can pour this liquid fertilizer
mixture into a spray bottle, allowing it
to be evenly sprayed onto the leaves and
stems while providing nutrients quickly
and effectively.
[Music]
Spray this fertilizer over the entire
orchid, including the leaves and stems,
so the plant can absorb nutrients
directly.
This method is similar to using folure
fertilizer, helping the plant grow more
balanced and healthier.
When spraying, make sure to cover both
the upper and lower surfaces of the
leaves. The underside of the leaves is
often where insects and bacteria
concentrate their attacks first. So
thorough spraying helps protect the
plant more effectively.
This fertilizer can be used to care for
most types of orchids including
phelinopsis, catala, dendrobium,
simidium, and many other varieties,
helping the plant stay healthy and bloom
beautifully.
You should apply this method one to two
times a month to provide full nutrients
and boost the orchid's resistance,
helping the plant stay healthy and grow
well.
Third method, um, use a cloth to soak up
the fertilizer mixture and gently wipe
both the upper and lower surfaces of the
leaves, allowing nutrients to be
absorbed directly while cleaning the
leaf surface, preventing dust and
bacteria.
[Music]
These are pests that harm orchids.
Wiping the leaves with the fertilizer
mixture helps effectively eliminate
insects, protect the plant from threats,
and keep the leaves clean and healthy.
Um, after wiping, the leaf surface will
always be clean and the stamata
unobstructed. This helps orchids
photosynthesize better, absorb light and
nutrients effectively, thereby growing
healthy and blooming beautifully.
When this method is applied regularly,
orchid leaves will not only be clean but
also healthy, reducing pests and harmful
insects. At the same time, the plant
will absorb nutrients better, roots will
grow strong, and flowers will bloom
evenly and last longer, bringing vibrant
beauty to your orchid growing space.
And here is the result. After one month
of care with natural fertilizer, you
will see the roots develop healthily and
produce many new roots, creating a
strong foundation for the orchid to
absorb nutrients and grow
comprehensively.
These new roots not only help the orchid
anchor firmly to the growing medium, but
also increase its ability to absorb
water and nutrients, thereby supporting
lush green leaves and more vibrant
blooms. When the roots are healthy, the
orchid will grow comprehensively,
robustly, and be ready for the next
flowering cycles.
And here is the result after the next
two months.
You can see that the orchid has grown
many new offshoots from the mother
plant. Each one healthy and developing
day by day.
These offshoots will continue to mature
and bloom in the future, promising to
bring even more vibrant and fresh
flowers to your orchid growing space.
When applying natural fertilizers or
care methods regularly, not only the
mother plant but also the offshoots grow
vigorously with lush green leaves and
strong roots.
Um, this creates a foundation for the
next blooming cycles, bringing a vibrant
and colorful space to your garden.
This not only opens up a new generation
of orchids, but also ensures that the
offshoots will bloom beautifully,
continuing the life and vibrancy of the
mother plant.
[Music]
And here is the result after the next 3
months. You can see many stems in the
same pot, forming a dense, lush, and
healthy orchid cluster.
This even growth helps the plant absorb
nutrients better while bringing vibrant
and lively beauty to your orchid growing
space.
The blooming orchids look truly vibrant
with smooth petals, bright and rich
colors.
Each flower maintains its longevity,
blooming for many days, allowing you to
enjoy the fresh beauty of the orchids
for a long time.
With regular care, using natural
fertilizer, the orchid not only blooms
beautifully, but also grows
comprehensively from roots, stems, and
leaves to flowers, ensuring long lasting
vitality for the plant.
Thank you for watching until here, and
don't leave yet. Stay tuned for part two
of the video where I will continue to
share useful tips to help you easily
propagate felinopsis at home effectively
and quickly.
Welcome to part two of the video. In
this part, I will guide you through
simple yet effective steps to propagate
Phelinopsis at home, helping you expand
your orchid collection without much
effort. After the orchid has just
dropped all its petals, this is the best
time to propagate from the flower spike.
At this point, the mother plant has
completed its flowering process and is
ready for a new growth phase, helping
the offshoots grow healthy and
effectively.
[Music]
Then take one clove of garlic and
squeeze out the juice. The garlic juice
will be used as a natural solution to
provide antibacterial protection,
safeguard the flower spike, and support
the orchid propagation process
effectively.
[Music]
If you haven't subscribed to the
channel, please hit the subscribe button
to support me and not miss any orchid
growing tips. It's wonderful to have you
along.
Please comment and let me know which
country you are watching the video from.
It's wonderful that we can chat together
from all around the world.
[Music]
Next, use a cotton swab to dip into the
garlic juice and apply it directly onto
the node that needs stimulation to grow
an orchid offshoot. The garlic juice
will help provide antibacterial
protection, safeguard the spike, and
naturally stimulate the formation of new
shoots.
Only the nodes that have not yet bloomed
can sprout and grow into orchid
offshoots. So, you should apply the
garlic juice only to the young unopened
nodes. This ensures that the new shoots
will grow healthy and easily develop
into offshoots.
[Music]
Then use a transparent plastic wrap to
cover the part of the flower spike where
the node you want to stimulate into an
orchid offshoot is located. This helps
retain moisture, protect the young chute
from insects and bacteria, and create an
ideal environment for the offshoot to
develop.
Make a small hole for ventilation,
allowing the chute to receive enough
oxygen and preventing moisture that can
cause rot or fungus.
uh creating the best conditions for the
orchid offshoot to grow.
[Music]
And here's the result after 3 weeks of
care.
[Music]
You can see that the spot where the
garlic juice was applied has formed a
very healthy orchid offshoot. However,
at this stage, the offshoot has not yet
developed visible leaves or roots. This
is an early sign that the new chute is
beginning to grow and is ready for the
next stages of development.
[Music]
And here's the result after the next 2
months.
You can see that the orchid offshoot has
grown very healthily on the flower spike
with leaves starting to open clearly and
young roots forming.
This is an important step showing that
the new chute is ready to develop into
an independent plant in the future.
Note, throughout the process of
stimulating the node to grow into an
orchid offshoot, place the orchid pot in
a shaded area with high humidity as this
helps the young shoot form and develop
easily.
Conversely, if the orchid pot is placed
in a sunny area with low humidity, the
plant is more likely to produce flowers
instead of an offshoot.
[Music]
I have also applied this little tip to
another orchid and you can see the
result is that many healthy orchid
offshoots have formed on the flower
spike.
This simple yet effective method helps
propagate phelinopsis easily and
naturally at home.
Be persistent in applying these methods
and gradually you will have a thriving
and vibrant orchid garden just like
mine. Each offshoot will grow healthy,
bloom beautifully, and bring joy when
cared for at home.
I hope you enjoy this video. If you find
it useful, uh don't forget to hit
subscribe and share so that many others
can also learn these effective orchid
care and propagation tips.
[Music]