Welcome to the happiness garden, where
every leaf and every flower tells its
own story. Here we learn together how to
care for plants, observe every small
signal that nature sends, and feel the
joy of watching the plants grow day by
day.
Uh, every step of care, no matter how
small, brings new life. And it is the
love for the plants that helps them
bloom brilliantly.
Let's explore together the simple yet
highly effective secrets to keep your
garden always full of vitality and
happiness.
Today I want to share with you how to
care for newly purchased orchids so that
they quickly adapt to their new
environment and grow healthily. Every
step from choosing a pot, checking the
roots to watering and gently fertilizing
is very important to prevent the plants
from experiencing stress.
After bringing your orchid home, let it
rest for a few hours in a well
ventilated place to reduce the stress
caused by transportation.
Once the plant has settled, you should
check the roots and the growing medium
to see if they are healthy or need
replacing so the plant has the best
environment to grow. Although simple,
this step is very important because
healthy roots help the plant absorb
nutrients effectively and bloom
beautifully later.
[Music]
First, I will trim the damaged roots,
the parts that are rotting or dry, so
the plant does not waste energy on roots
that are no longer alive.
[Music]
Upon initial inspection, I found that
the moss medium was still loose, so a
complete replacement was not necessary.
However, since moss retains quite a lot
of moisture, this is really only
suitable for industrial orchid gardens
where the water amount is very precisely
controlled.
When planting at home, to help the plant
grow more healthily, I will remove about
half of the moss, which not only
prevents the roots from being water
logged, but also creates more space for
the plant to breathe and absorb
nutrients better.
After removing about half of the moss, I
will proceed to plant the orchid in a
new pot. I choose a pot with drainage
holes at the bottom and a moderate size,
not too wide nor too tight, so the roots
have enough space to grow while still
retaining proper moisture. Choosing the
right pot size is very important as it
helps the plant grow evenly and prevents
water logging or nutrient deficiency.
To supplement the growing medium, I
choose crushed pine bark because when
combined with moss, it creates a perfect
balance between irration and moisture
retention.
[Music]
Pine bark provides space for the roots
to grow, preventing water logging while
the moss still supplies enough moisture
for the plant. This combination helps
the orchid grow healthily with strong
roots, green leaves, and prepares it for
the upcoming flower buds.
[Music]
Uh when adding pine bark into the pot,
gently tap the sides of the pot to help
the medium settle evenly around the
roots without crushing or damaging them.
This ensures the roots are firmly
secured while still maintaining the
necessary erration for the plant to
absorb nutrients and grow healthily.
These small but careful actions create a
solid foundation for the orchid to bloom
beautifully later.
[Music]
Leave me a comment letting me know which
country you're watching from. It's
wonderful that we can connect and chat
together from all around the world.
These are orange slices, a wonderful
ingredient for making natural fertilizer
for orchids. You only need a small
slice, but it provides enough nutrients
to help the plant grow healthily.
[Music]
Using natural fruits like oranges is not
only safe, but also helps the plant
absorb nutrients effectively, promoting
green leaves and vibrant blooms.
[Music]
If you haven't subscribed to the channel
yet, click the subscribe button to
support me and not miss any orchid care
tips. It's wonderful to have you along
on this journey.
Next, squeeze the juice from the orange
slice, preparing for the next step in
making natural fertilizer for orchids.
Orange juice is rich in vitamins and
minerals, helping the plant absorb
nutrients quickly and grow healthily.
Even a small amount is enough to nourish
green leaves and stimulate vibrant
blooms.
[Music]
After squeezing the juice, dilute it
with about one liter of water to create
a gentle nutrient solution for the
orchid. Diluting it allows the plant to
absorb nutrients safely, preventing a
too concentrated solution from harming
the roots.
With just this simple solution, you
provide the essential vitamins and
minerals, helping the leaves stay lush
and preparing the plant for vibrant
blooms.
Method one, use a soft cloth soaked in
the diluted orange juice solution. Then,
gently wipe both the top and bottom
surfaces of the leaves.
This allows the nutrients to be absorbed
directly through the leaves while also
cleaning dust and bacteria, creating the
best conditions for healthy leaf growth.
Handle each leaf carefully so the plant
feels gentle care and absorbs nutrients
effectively.
When you wipe the leaves with the
diluted orange juice solution, it allows
nutrients to be absorbed directly into
the leaves, providing essential vitamins
and minerals.
This stimulates healthy, lush leaf
growth and enhances photosynthesis,
helping the plant absorb light more
effectively.
Wiping the leaves also helps remove
dust, bacteria, and tiny insects on the
leaf surface. This keeps the leaves
clean and well ventilated, reducing the
risk of disease and creating favorable
conditions for vibrant, healthy blooms.
After wiping each leaf, let the plant
rest for a while so the solution can be
absorbed evenly and the leaves dry
naturally.
This not only helps the leaves absorb
nutrients better, but also prevents
water from pooling, which could harm the
roots or flower buds.
[Music]
Method two, you can directly water this
natural fertilizer mixture onto the
roots and growing medium. This allows
the nutrients to penetrate down to the
roots where the plant absorbs them best
while also softening the medium and
balancing moisture.
Oranges contain many important vitamins
and minerals helping the roots grow
healthily and enhancing the plant's
overall nourishment.
Uh in addition, the solution softens the
growing medium making the soil and moss
more airrated while balancing the
moisture around the roots. When the
medium is sufficiently airy, the roots
won't be water logged or suffocated,
allowing the plant to grow evenly and
healthily.
Finally, evenly watering this mixture
also promotes nutrient absorption
throughout the entire plant, helping the
leaves stay lush and preparing the
flowers to bloom brilliantly.
After watering the mixture, leave the
orchid pot undisturbed for about 20
minutes. um allowing the roots and
growing medium to absorb the nutrients
from the solution evenly.
[Music]
Method three, you can also pour the
mixture into a spray bottle and lightly
mist the plant. This allows the solution
to cover the leaves, flowers, and even
small roots, ensuring nutrients are
absorbed comprehensively.
Spraying the diluted orange juice
mixture allows nutrients to be absorbed
directly onto the surfaces of the
leaves, flowers, and small roots,
providing essential vitamins and
minerals. This promotes lush green
leaves and boosts the overall vitality
of the plant.
[Music]
In addition, spraying evenly helps clean
dust and bacteria from the leaves while
creating a natural protective layer.
When the leaves are clean and well
ventilated, the plant absorbs light
better and reduces the risk of disease.
Finally, spraying the solution also
nourishes the plant from multiple
angles, stimulating the roots, leaves,
and flower buds to develop evenly. As a
result, the orchid becomes healthy,
vibrant, and ready to bloom brilliantly
in a short time.
[Music]
After soaking for about 20 minutes,
remember to remove the orchid pot from
the solution.
If there is still water on the leaves,
gently wipe off the excess with a soft
cloth.
Once the leaves are dry and clean, your
orchid is ready for the next care steps.
Carefully following each step like this
helps the orchid grow comprehensively
from roots to leaves and flowers,
bringing joy as you watch the plant
thrive day by day.
[Music]
Then place the orchid pot in a spot with
gentle sunlight, enough for the plant to
photosynthesize without burning the
leaves. Soft light helps the leaves stay
lush and the roots grow healthily while
supporting nourishment and preparing for
vibrant blooms. Choose a wellventilated
location, avoiding strong winds or
overly hot areas so the plant
experiences an ideal environment and
develops fully.
[Music]
And here is the result after one month
of care.
You can see the leaves have become
glossy and sturdy, reflecting the new
vitality the plant has gained from
careful care. Healthy leaves are not
only visually appealing, but also help
the plant photosynthesize effectively,
nourish the roots, and prepare for the
fresh flower buds about to bloom.
[Music]
Many new healthy roots have grown,
showing that the plant is absorbing
nutrients very well and developing
comprehensively from roots to leaves.
[Music]
The appearance of these fresh new roots
also signals that the previous care
steps from the growing medium, watering
with the solution to providing light are
all proving effective.
When the roots are healthy, the plant
will continue to grow vigorously,
preparing for the flower buds about to
bloom brilliantly.
[Music]
Seeing this recovery, you will
appreciate the effectiveness of each
careful care step. From preparing the
growing medium, wiping the leaves,
watering with the solution to placing
the plant in gentle sunlight.
[Music]
And here is the result after 3 months of
care with natural fertilizer. You can
see the orchid has grown healthily with
sturdy leaves, roots firmly anchoring
into the growing medium and the pot.
What's remarkable is that the orchid has
developed two flower spikes, each
carrying many vibrant blooms, displaying
fresh, lively colors.
This result shows that careful
step-by-step care from preparing the
growing medium, watering with the
solution, wiping the leaves to placing
the plant in gentle light has brought
complete vitality to the plant.
Seeing the orchid bloom brilliantly
after 3 months of care, you will feel
the joy and satisfaction of nurturing
the plant step by step with your own
hands. Using natural fertilizer is not
only safe but also helps the plant grow
sustainably from roots and leaves to
flowers.
Be patient and take the time to observe
and care for the plant bit by bit and
you will see its vitality restored day
by day. Each blooming flower is a
wonderful reward for your love and
dedicated care.
I hope that through this video you have
seen the power and effectiveness of
caring for orchids with natural
fertilizer.
Try applying these simple steps at home.
Patiently observe and nurture your
plants everyday.
When you take the time to carefully, the
plant will respond with strong vitality,
lush green leaves, and brilliant blooms.
Remember, caring for orchids is not just
a technique. It is joy, patience, and
love for nature. Start today and enjoy
the happiness of watching each flower
bud unfold before your eyes.
Uh, thank you for watching the video. If
you found the content useful and
meaningful, support me by liking and
sharing it so more people can enjoy it.
And if you haven't subscribed to the
channel yet, don't forget to hit
subscribe so you won't miss the upcoming
orchid care tips. Goodbye and I wish you
joy, happiness and wonderful experiences
with your garden.
[Applause]