Welcome to the happiness garden, where
every passing moment carries a sense of
peace, and each orchid pot tells us a
new story about vitality and gentle
beauty.
Today, I continue to share how to revive
orchids after they finish blooming.
Because once the vibrant flowers fall,
the plant enters a stage where it needs
special care to regain energy and begin
a new, stronger growth cycle.
After the orchid has finished blooming,
you should cut off the old flower spike
as it dies because this helps the plant
refocus its energy, nourish the roots,
and prepare for the healthy new shoots
that will appear soon.
Next, you need to trim off the damaged
roots because removing the weak parts
will help the plant absorb nutrients
more easily and create space for new
roots to grow more vigorously. Okay.
You should also cut off the old and
damaged leaves because they can no
longer nourish the plant and only drain
energy that the orchid could use to
develop fresher and healthier new
leaves.
Uh, please let me know in the comments
which country you're watching the video
from. It's wonderful that we can connect
with each other from all around the
world.
And if you haven't subscribed to the
channel yet, please hit the subscribe
button to support me and not miss any
orchid growing tips.
It's wonderful to have you with me.
After pruning, place the orchid pot in a
cool, airy spot and let the plant rest
for about 2 to 3 days, 2 3 days without
watering, so the cuts have time to dry
and heal completely before moving on to
the next stage of care.
After 3 days without watering, we will
begin preparing natural fertilizer for
the plant to provide a gentle yet
effective source of nutrients, helping
the orchid regain its vitality and soon
produce strong new root sprouts.
You just need to add 3 teaspoon of rice
into the bottle. This will be the main
ingredient to create a natural and
gentle source of nutrients that the
orchid can absorb very easily.
Add 500 ml of water to the bottle and
let it sit for a few hours, allowing the
rice to ferment slightly and create a
natural source of nutrients that helps
the orchid recover quickly and grow more
vigorously.
[Music]
After the mixture has fermented, strain
out the residue and keep the clear
liquid as this is the pure nutrient that
the orchid can absorb easily and safely.
[Music]
Next, add another 500 ml of water to the
filtered liquid, helping the solution
become gentler and suitable for watering
orchids without worrying about nutrient
shock.
[Music]
Step one, use a soft cloth soaked in the
diluted fertilizer mixture. Then gently
wipe both the upper and lower sides of
the leaves. This method helps remove
dust, improves nutrient absorption, and
stimulates more effective
photosynthesis.
Wiping the leaves with lightly fermented
rice water helps remove the thin layer
of dust on the leaf surface, allowing
light to reach directly and making
photosynthesis more efficient, helping
the plant recover faster and become
healthier.
The fermented rice water mixture
provides a thin layer of nutrients on
the leaf surface, helping the leaves
retain natural moisture, become softer
and shinier, and improve gas exchange,
supporting the plant's overall growth.
The enzymes and minerals in fermented
rice water help strengthen the leaves
resistance, reduce the risk of fungal
diseases on the surface, and create
conditions for the leaves to grow
greener, thicker, and healthier day by
day.
Step two, pour the diluted mixture into
a spray bottle. Then gently mist both
the upper and lower sides of the leaves.
This helps the nutrients spread evenly,
absorb more quickly, and allows the
leaves to receive the full benefits of
the naturally fermented solution.
Spraying the entire orchid with the
fermented rice water mixture helps wash
away any remaining dust after wiping the
leaves, making the leaf surface cleaner
and clearer, allowing the plant to
absorb light optimally and carry out
photosynthesis more effectively.
When sprayed evenly over the stem,
leaves, and aerial roots, the lightly
fermented solution creates a thin layer
of nutrients uh that helps retain
natural moisture, prevents the plant
from drying out, and supports a faster
and more stable recovery process.
The minerals and enzymes in fermented
rice water help strengthen the overall
resistance of the plant, limit the
growth of fungal diseases on the leaf
and stem surfaces, and create a
favorable environment for the orchid to
promote the healthy development of new
roots and new leaves.
Step three, take an eggshell that has
been completely dried. Then crush it
into small pieces to make natural
fertilizer.
The calcium in the eggshell will help
the orchid recover better and support
strong root development.
After crushing it, sprinkle the eggshell
over the surface of the orchid pot to
provide a natural source of calcium that
helps stabilize the growing medium while
supporting strong root development,
allowing the roots to anchor firmly and
absorb nutrients more effectively during
the recovery stage.
Additionally, when sprinkled over the
roots and the surface of the pot, Hot
eggshells help repel snails as the tiny
sharp edges prevent them from crawling
over, protecting the orchid's young
roots more safely throughout the
recovery process.
[Music]
Step four, use the diluted fertilizer
mixture to water directly onto the roots
and growing medium, helping the plant
absorb nutrients naturally from below
and stimulating stronger root growth
every day.
Watering the liquid fertilizer mixture
directly onto the roots and growing
medium provides nutrients quickly and
evenly throughout the root system,
thereby promoting the orchid's recovery
and growth after blooming.
The liquid solution penetrates deep into
the growing medium, helping maintain
stable moisture around the roots,
creating an ideal environment for
healthy new root growth and increasing
the absorption of water and essential
minerals.
Regularly watering with liquid
fertilizer also stimulates beneficial
microorganisms in the growing medium,
supporting the decomposition of organic
matter, improving the medium structure,
and creating a favorable environment for
the orchid to grow vigorously.
Step five, if water remains on the
leaves after spraying and watering,
gently blot it with a dry cloth to
prevent prolonged moisture that can
cause mold, keeping the leaves clean and
dry and creating conditions for the
orchid to grow healthily.
Depending on your schedule, you can
carry out each step separately or
combine all five steps to care for the
orchid. And it is recommended to apply
this about two to three times per month.
Regular use of this natural fertilizer
will help the plant recover quickly,
keep the leaves glossy and green, and
the roots strong, ready for the next
blooming cycles.
After finishing the care, place the
orchid pot in a spot with gentle
sunlight, enough for the plant to
photosynthesize without burning the
leaves, helping the orchid absorb energy
and grow steadily each day.
And here are the results after 3 weeks
of caring for the orchid with natural
fertilizer made from lightly fermented
rice water.
You can see that the leaves have become
glossy and sturdy while the roots have
grown vigorously providing a solid
foundation for the new shoots and
upcoming.
>> The glossy healthy leaves show that the
orchid is absorbing nutrients
effectively with both the root system
and leaves developing well while the
care environment and natural fertilizer
are truly meeting the plant's needs.
Healthy leaves are an important
foundation for the orchid's overall
development because when they
efficiently absorb light and nutrients,
the plant has enough energy to nourish
the roots, new shoots, and prepare for
the next vibrant flowers.
[Music]
As long as you follow the right methods
and patiently care for them, your garden
will soon be filled with the vibrant
colors of orchids. Each pot showcasing
its own beauty, bringing joy and a sense
of happiness every day.
And the most wonderful thing is when the
orchid is healthy from roots to leaves,
you will see that it not only blooms
regularly but also maintains longlasting
flowers, keeping your garden vibrant and
full of life.
I hope you enjoy this video. If you find
it helpful, don't forget to hit like and
subscribe to the channel so you won't
miss future tips on caring for orchids
naturally and easily.
Thank you so much for watching. I truly
appreciate your time and support. Don't
forget to like, subscribe, and share if
you enjoyed this video. Wishing you a
wonderful day full of joy and blooming
orchids. See you in the next