hello
everyone in today's video I will
introduce you to a new natural
fertilizer that enhances nutrition for
[Music]
orchids with this product you can easily
care for your orchids at home helping
them grow strong and Bloom for a long
[Music]
time let's explore the details
together this phenopsis orchid has
finished
blooming after the Orchid blooms it will
weaken because it has previously
concentrated on nutrients to
flour however the tree can still grow
strongly if properly cared
for cut off old branches helps the plant
concentrate its energy
[Music]
when you cut off Old Flower stems the
plant won't waste energy nourishing
wilted
parts then remove damaged leaves to help
prevent disease
removing damaged leaves helps stop the
spread of fungi pests and other
pathogens that can harm the
[Music]
plant then cut off all damaged roots
removing damaged Roots help stop the
growth of harmful fungi and bacteria
protecting the plant's
Health this Leaf was broken at the pedo
but the leaf was still fresh so I didn't
cut it off
then we make fertilizer for this
Orchid do you have red
beetroot take one slice of red radish
like this and cut it into small slices
red bead is rich in vitamins and
minerals supplying essential nutrients
for orchids and promoting plant growth
using red beet as fertilizer helps
retain moisture in the growing medium
creating favorable conditions for orchid
roots to
thrive next I took a ripe banana and cut
it into thin slices
[Music]
bananas are rich in potassium which is
essential for flowering and overall
growth of
[Music]
orchids then put bananas and red
radishes into the jar
[Music]
add 500 M warm water
cover tightly and leave in a cool place
for 3 weeks to create a GE fermented
fertilizer product that is very good for
orchids
this is a GE natural fermented
fertilizer product from red red radish
and banana that I made 3 weeks
ago good products have the aroma of ripe
bananas take 50 m of the mixture
[Music]
add 2 L of water which is approximately
53 Gall us
mix GE with 2 L of water
[Music]
step
one water this liquid fertilizer for
orchid
pots the liquid fertilizer made from red
beet and bananas contains various
vitamins minerals and Trace elements
offering diverse nutrition for orchids
applying liquid fertilizer promotes root
development enhancing the plant's
ability to absorb water and
nutrients after watering soak the Orchid
pot in this fertilizer solution for
about 20 minutes so that the roots can
absorb more water and nutrients
step
two use a soft cotton pad to gently wipe
the top and bottom of the orchid leaves
with this water
keeping the leaves clean allows the
plant to photosynthesize more
effectively promoting growth and
[Music]
flowering the GE water made from red
beet and bananas directly supplies
vitamins and minerals to the leaves
supporting plant
[Music]
growth wiping the leaves with GE water
encourages the growth of beneficial
microorganisms enhancing the overall
health of the plant
[Music]
cleaning the leaves can help reduce the
presence of pests and mold protecting
the plant's
[Music]
Health G water provides moisture to the
leaves helping the plant stay fresh and
prevent drying
[Music]
out step three
if you have many Orchid pots you can put
this water in a spray
[Applause]
bottle then spray the entire orchid
spraying GE water on leaves cleans the
surface facilitating a more effective
photosynthesis
process spraying GE water on the roots
quickly supplies essential vitamins and
minerals for the plant's growth
step
four wiping off excess water reduces the
risk of mold and bacterial growth
protecting the plant's health
wiping off excess water helps Leaf
fertilizer absorb more quickly into the
leaves optimizing nutrient
uptake dry leaves facilitate better gas
exchange supporting the respiration
processes of both roots and leaves
wiping off excess water helps Leaf
fertilizer absorb more quickly into the
leaves optimizing nutrient
uptake perform the above four steps one
to two times per month
then place the Orchid pot in a place
with enough light for the Orchid to
photosynthesize and metabolize
[Music]
well results after 2 months
new Roots grow abundantly and
healthily healthy Roots allow the plant
to absorb water and essential minerals
more effectively supporting overall
growth
[Music]
new Roots contribute to strong plant
growth facilitating the formation of new
chuts and
leaves this orchid has grown two new
flower branches
[Music]
new Roots enhance drainage in the
growing medium preventing water logging
[Music]
strong roots provide the energy needed
for the plant to produce flowers and
fruits boosting reproductive capacity
[Music]
this Orchid was watered with this liquid
fertilizer so the roots develop many new
roots
[Music]
take care of your Orchids with all the
love you have for plants and you will be
rewarded with beautiful
blooms thank you for watching the video
wishing you the best in your plant care
and see you next time goodbye