[Music]
Welcome to the happiness
garden to help weak orchids recover and
grow stronger. Today I will continue
sharing how to make natural fertilizer
and how to care for the plant to support
fast
recovery. To restore it, first check and
remove all the damaged leaves.
Diseased leaves can be a source of
spreading fungi, bacteria, or viruses to
other parts of the plant or to nearby
plants. Timely removal helps control the
disease from the
[Music]
beginning. Rotten leaves often
accumulate water and create an ideal
environment for bacteria and fungi to
grow.
Uh removing them helps keep the base of
the plant well ventilated, preventing
prolonged moisture that can cause root
and stem
rot. Additionally, once the removal is
done, the plant will look neater,
cleaner, and healthier without the
presence of yellowing or decaying
leaves. Next, we check the growing
medium and the roots to see if they are
the cause of the orchid rot.
Uh use your fingers to gently squeeze
the roots. If the root is firm, it is
still fresh. But if it is soft, it has
already
[Music]
rotted. Then cut off all the damaged
roots.
Rotten roots are often breeding grounds
for bacteria or fungi. If not removed,
the rot can quickly spread to healthy
roots, weakening the plant or even
causing it to
[Music]
die. When the damaged roots are removed,
the plant will sense the need to grow
new roots to absorb water and nutrients.
As a result, the plant will push out new
root shoots more quickly and more
vigorously. If you haven't subscribed to
the channel yet, please hit the
subscribe button to support me and not
miss any orchid growing tips. It's
wonderful to have you along on this
[Music]
journey. Do you have any
oranges? Now I will grate the orange
peel to make fertilizer to help restore
weak
orchids. Orange peel contains essential
oils and lemonine which have
antibacterial properties and can inhibit
mold growth. These are the main culprits
causing root and stem rot in orchids.
[Music]
Orange peel is rich in vitamin C and
antioxidants, which can help boost the
plant's resistance, repair damaged
cells, and promote the regeneration of
new
roots. After grating, I put the orange
peel into a blender and add about 300 ml
of water.
[Music]
Then blend it finely in the water.
[Applause]
Let me know in the comments which
country you're watching from. It's
wonderful that we can connect and chat
from all around the world.
After blending the orange peel with
water, straining out the residue is a
very important step. It makes the
mixture more pure and safer for the
orchid.
If the orange peel residue is left
behind, it can stick to the roots or the
base of the plant, causing blockage and
retaining moisture for too long, easily
leading to rot
again. After straining out the residue,
dilute the orange peel solution with one
liter of clean water to create a mixture
with a safe and suitable concentration
for helping the orchid recover.
Then add 1 teaspoon of baking
soda. Uh, baking soda has a mild
alkaline property that helps neutralize
the acidic environment caused by fungal
diseases.
When combined with the natural essential
oils from orange peel, the mixture
becomes more powerful in eliminating
fungi and bacteria.
After mixing the diluted orange peel
solution with baking soda, the first
step you should take is to use a soft
cloth to soak up the mixture and
carefully wipe both the upper and lower
surfaces of the leaves.
This gentle antibacterial mixture will
kill bacteria and fungi on the leaves
without harming the leaf tissue, helping
the leaves become healthier and
shinier. When the leaves are clean, the
plant absorbs light more effectively,
helping it recover faster and grow
stronger after
[Music]
rotting. Additionally, orchid leaves may
harbor fungi, bacteria, or pests hiding
on the underside. Wiping the leaves
helps clean the surface and prevents the
spread of
diseases. Then place the orchid pot into
a basin and pour the mixture over the
roots, making sure they are thoroughly
soaked.
This makes it easier for you to pour the
mixture and ensures the roots are evenly
soaked. Make sure all the roots,
especially the base, are fully submerged
in the solution. This is the area most
vulnerable to fungal and rot attacks.
This is the ideal time for the active
compounds in the orange peel and baking
soda to take effect, eliminating
pathogens and cleaning the
[Music]
roots. After pouring, soak the orchid
pot in this mixture for about 20
minutes. Then we prepare fertilizer for
the orchid to stimulate the growth of
new roots and new shoots.
To make the recovery fertilizer, I take
3 tablespoons of
[Music]
oats. Then add it to one liter of water.
Then cover it and wait for 20 minutes to
allow the nutrients from the oats to
dissolve into the
[Music]
water. Then proceed to strain out the
oat residue.
[Music]
Use a fine strainer or clean cloth to
filter out the oat water.
[Music]
Discard the oat pulp and keep only the
clear liquid. This is the part rich in
nutrients that the roots can absorb most
[Music]
easily. The next ingredient I need is
vitamin B1 which is excellent for
stimulating root growth and new shoots
in orchids.
Vitamin B1 thamine plays a role in
activating enzymes that help the plant
increase cell production at the root
tips, thereby promoting faster growth of
new
[Music]
roots. Add three tablets of vitamin B1
into the container and stir well until
they are completely dissolved in the
water.
[Music]
After soaking for 20 minutes, remember
to take the orchid pot out.
The water used to soak the orchid should
be discarded and not reused as it may
contain harmful fungi or pathogens.
Step two, use a soft cloth to soak up
the oatmeal and B1 mixture. Then
carefully wipe the orchid
leaves. Orchid leaves can absorb
nutrients through the epidermis,
especially easily absorb substances like
vitamins and sugars from oatmeal.
[Music]
Orchid leaves can absorb nutrients
through the epidermis, especially easily
absorbed substances like vitamins and
sugars from
oatmeal. Clean leaves help the plant
photosynthesize better, increasing its
ability to produce nutrients to nourish
the roots and new
shoots. Uh, after wiping the leaves, we
water this mixture onto the orchid
roots.
Vitamin B1 helps activate the
development of young root tissues,
especially after the plant has been
damaged by root rot or
pruning. Oat water contains plenty of B
vitamins, natural sugars, and minerals,
making it a gentle source of nutrients
that is easily absorbed through the
roots. Then, soak the orchid pot in this
mixture for about 10 minutes.
After soaking the orchid pot in the
mixture for 10 minutes, take it out and
place the plant in a spot with diffused
light, such as near a window with a
sheer curtain or under a canopy with
indirect sunlight.
And here is the result after 1 month of
caring for the orchid with natural
fertilizer. You can see that my orchid
has grown many new
roots. The growth of new roots is the
clearest sign that the plant has
recovered.
Orchids only grow new roots when they
sense that their environment is safe,
has enough nutrients, and receives the
right amount of
light. And the orchid has also grown a
new baby
shoot. The baby shoot is a clear sign
that the mother plant is healthy and has
enough energy to produce the next
generation.
This is the stage when the orchid begins
natural propagation. A very positive
sign in its recovery and growth
process. Today's baby shoot is the
future flower
spike. If cared for properly, over time,
the baby plant will grow into a new
orchid branch capable of blooming on its
own.
You see, after just one month of
patiently caring with natural
ingredients, the orchid has not only
grown new roots, but is also confidently
reaching upward with a fresh, hopeful
little baby shoot.
Uh, I will continue to care for this
orchid with the natural fertilizer
mixture of oats and B1 once every 2
weeks to nourish healthy roots and
support strong growth of the new chute.
Uh, I will continue to care for this
orchid with the natural fertilizer
mixture of oats and B1 once every 2
weeks to nourish healthy roots and
support strong growth of the new
chute. After each time you apply this
natural fertilizer, don't forget to wipe
the leaves clean using the same
nutrient-rich
mixture. Um, step by step, gently but
consistently, you will witness your
orchid come back to life and grow
stronger day by
day. Uh, then remember to soak the
orchid pot in this mixture for about 20
minutes so the roots can fully absorb
the nutrients from the oatmeal and B1.
Then take the orchid pot out and place
it in a spot with gentle sunlight. This
soft light will help the plant
photosynthesize better, boost its
metabolism, and thereby support root
growth, shoot development, and overall
healthy
[Music]
growth. And here is the result after the
next 3 months.
The orchid has grown so much. Its leaves
are lush green and the roots are strong
and
healthy. And most especially, it has
sprouted two brand new flower spikes
full of life and energy.
This proves that the orchid not only
recovered successfully but also entered
a vigorous growth phase and bloomed
again. The method of caring with natural
fertilizer made from oats and vitamin B1
is effective, safe, and suitable for
orchids after root rot or leaf damage.
[Music]
You can now remove this old leaf so the
orchid can concentrate its nutrients on
the flowers that are about to bloom.
[Music]
with gentle care, tenderness, and love,
you can absolutely help your orchid
revive and bloom beautifully as it once
did. Wishing you continued joy and
perseverance as you care for each leaf
and every tiny root of your orchid.
Let each day together be a moment of
relaxation, healing, and deep
affection. Even though the journey of
care may be slow at times, the reward
will always be sweet. Just like the
orchid petals that bloom wide after many
days of waiting, may your orchid stems
always stay vibrant, healthy, and bring
you happiness every single day.