Welcome to my
channel. When you buy an orchid or
someone gives it to
[Music]
you. Um, you need to do the following.
Leave the orchid in a cool place for a
few hours to let it adapt to the new
climate. If you haven't subscribed to
the channel yet, uh please support me by
pressing the subscribe button and
ringing the bell to stay updated and not
miss any orchid growing tips.
If the growing medium is moss or small
wood chips, it is only suitable for
industrial orchid
[Music]
gardens. Because moss retains a lot of
moisture, many plant roots rot due to
water
[Music]
logging. Which country are you watching
videos from? Please comment for me.
[Music]
It's great that we can chat together
from all over the
world. The humidity was too high, so the
leaves were also infected with black
mold.
[Music]
Uh therefore you need to remove all moss
or old growing medium.
[Music]
Because this type of substrate is only
suitable for industrial orchid gardens
that can control special humidity.
[Music]
Then you cut off all damaged
roots. In addition to the English
voiceover, my channel also offers
voiceovers in French, German, Italian,
Spanish, and Portuguese.
You can go to the settings to choose the
voice over in the language that suits
you. How to select the audio language on
YouTube. One, open the video and click
on settings, the gear icon. Two, select
subtitles CC. Three, click on audio and
choose the language you want, English,
frutch, italiano, espanol or
Portuguese. Then you cut off all damaged
roots.
[Music]
Then you take one aloe vera leaf.
And take a clove of garlic.
[Music]
Put all the aloe vera and garlic in a
jar and soak it with 2 L of water.
[Music]
Put all the aloe vera and garlic in a
jar and soak it with 2 L of water.
[Music]
30 minutes later.
Soak the roots in this solution for 30
[Music]
minutes. Garlic and aloe vera help
stimulate root growth and effectively
fight harmful insects and fungi.
[Music]
Spraying this solution on the entire
orchid will help repel insects,
eliminate fungal diseases, and keep the
leaves green.
[Music]
Then clean the black mold stains with
this solution.
[Music]
Uh, this helps prevent orchids from
recurring mold.
[Music]
Now I recycle used plastic containers to
make orchid pots.
[Music]
I put a layer of pummus on the bottom of
the orchid
[Applause]
[Music]
pot. This helps keep the bottom of the
orchid pot clear so the roots don't get
water logged.
[Music]
For the top, I use dried pine bark as a
growing
[Music]
medium and mix in some dry moss.
When planting, cushion the substrate
tightly so that the roots do not move.
[Music]
Insert the flower branch into the right
position to help prevent the orchid from
shaking.
[Music]
After planting, let it dry for 5 days
before
watering. That is the wonderful thing I
want to share with you in part one of
the video. And don't rush to leave the
video because part two will make it more
interesting for you with how to care for
orchids to help them bloom all year
[Music]
round. Welcome to part two of this video
on Happy Garden channel. Happiness
Garden Channel specializes in sharing
tips for caring for orchids using
natural fertilizers, promoting
sustainable growth, abundant blooms, and
environmental protection. If you love
orchids as much as I do, subscribe to my
channel to support me and never miss any
tips. Today, I'm sharing how to make a
natural fertilizer from garlic that's
both simple and effective for your
orchids.
[Music]
I just need a clove of
garlic. Garlic promotes harmonious
growth and lush, long-lasting flowering
of
[Music]
orchids. It repels most pests and kills
spores of fungi, viruses, and bacteria.
[Music]
Substances in garlic water strengthen
the immune system of
[Music]
orchids. I pour crushed garlic with one
liter of hot water.
[Music]
And this is turmeric powder which rich
in vitamins and minerals potassium,
calcium, magnesium, sodium, phosphorus,
iron, manganese, copper, selenium, and
zinc. Increases plant resistance to
fungi and diseases while stimulating
growth and flowering.
[Music]
Uh, incubate until the water cools so
that the nutrients from the garlic and
turmeric starch are completely dissolved
in the water.
[Music]
After the water cools, we filter it to
remove sediment.
[Music]
Fertilizer for orchids must be carefully
filtered so that organic fragments do
not rot in the substrate.
Guys, please write a comment letting me
know which country you're watching my
video from. Yeah, the
France. It's great to know that we can
communicate worldwide.
[Music]
Uh to know if it's time to water
orchids, I look at the color of the
roots. When the orchid roots have a
light silver color, it's time to water
the orchid.
If the roots are bright green, you
should wait until the roots turn pale
silver before
[Music]
watering. If you water when the roots
are still green, the roots will easily
become water logged and cause root rot.
[Music]
My maids are tired and
sleeping. And the cat seems to be
hunting down the mice that are
destroying my
orchids. Orchids grown in pots with
drainage
holes. I water this one to two times a
month.
Soak the roots in this water for about
20 minutes to help the roots absorb
nutrients best.
Um the finished infusion for orchids
helps strengthen the immune system,
promotes the development of the root
[Music]
system. This water is also very good
when sprayed on orchids.
Spraying your orchids with garlic and
turmeric water will protect them from
diseases, pests, and boost their immune
system.
[Music]
Spray the entire orchid from leaves to
roots. But you should not water the
flowers because wet flowers will quickly
fall off.
Do it one to two times a
month. If you have a very humid climate,
orchids are susceptible to leaf base
rot. To prevent orchids from rotting at
the base of the leaves, you can use
cotton balls to protect them.
[Music]
Now, spray the cotton with garlic and
turmeric
water and spray it on your orchids to
protect them from diseases, pests, and
boost the immune system.
Leave the cotton there for 20 minutes,
then remove it.
[Music]
Then you take the clear water above.
If you don't have access to spraying
orchids, you can wipe the leaves with a
cotton pad soaked in this
[Music]
water. We'll help remove mineral salts
still attached to the leaf surface.
[Music]
helps orchid leaves avoid burning when
exposed to
sunlight. Uh this not only clears the
dust but also provides them with
nutrients and protects them from
diseases and pests.
Thoroughly wipe both the top and bottom
of the
leaf. Do this one to two times a month.
[Music]
Uh, it is enough to keep the orchid in
this water for 20 minutes.
[Music]
[Applause]
Soaked in this water, the roots will
change from silver to purple blue like
this.
[Music]
Then place the orchid pot in a warm
place with lots of diffused light so the
orchid will grow quickly.
[Music]
After 20 minutes, remove the cotton ball
and place the orchid pot in a warm place
with lots of diffused
[Music]
light
result. Um, the leaves are always green
and shiny like
this. The roots are green, large, and
healthy.
Thanks to the clean leaf surface, orchid
leaves photosynthesize
[Music]
better. When orchids have enough light
for photosynthesis, they will always be
healthier than usual.
Thanks to this care, the orchid produces
many
[Music]
flowers. Vibrant flower colors.
Orchids bloom all year round, flowering
very long and
[Music]
boldly. Hope you like this video.
Thank you for viewing. Good luck and
success in life.
[Music]
Welcome to part three of the
video to give you more options for
taking care of your orchids at home
using organic fertilizer. In this video,
I continue to share methods for making
natural fertilizer from everyday kitchen
ingredients you can find in your
home.
Subscribe to the video so you don't miss
any tips on my
[Music]
channel. Number
one, to make this fertilizer, you need
apples.
[Music]
Apples contain potassium, an important
mineral for orchid
[Music]
growth. Potassium helps orchids develop
stronger leaves, roots, and flowers.
Uh, I took the apple peel and put it in
a
bottle. Soak in boiled water and leave
overnight.
Please comment to me which country
you're watching the video
from. It's great that we can chat
together from all over the
[Music]
world.
Number
two, to make this type of fertilizer,
you need more
[Music]
eggshells. If you haven't subscribed to
the channel yet, please subscribe to
support me and not miss any orchid care
tips.
[Music]
Soak the eggshells in boiled water and
leave overnight.
[Music]
Leave overnight.
After one night, filter the water.
[Music]
So we of fertilizer from apples and
eggshells. First
[Music]
method, water this fertilizer solution
on the orchid
[Music]
roots.
Eggshells provide natural calcium which
is very good for orchids. They help
orchids stay healthy and increase
resistance.
[Music]
Apple peels contain a lot of phosphorus
which is also an important nutrient for
orchid
growth.
[Music]
Especially during the flowering and
flower development stage.
[Music]
Do this one to two times a month to
supplement nutrition and increase the
orchid's resistance.
[Music]
Second
method, spray this fertilizer on the
entire orchid.
[Music]
This method is similar to using folure
fertilizer.
[Music]
Calcium and eggshells helps orchids stay
healthy and increases their resistance
to pests.
[Music]
Apples contain nitrogen, an essential
nutrient that helps orchids develop
healthy green growth and enhances their
ability to photosynthesize.
[Music]
Do not spray on flowers because wet
flowers will easily fall off.
[Music]
Third
method. Clean the leaf surface with this
liquid fertilizer.
[Music]
The leaf surface will always be clean
and
[Music]
airy. Orchids will photosynthesize
better.
[Music]
Fertilizing regularly, one to two times
month will help keep the leaves
[Music]
healthy. Number
three, you can reuse eggshells and apple
peels to make fertilizer again.
[Music]
Let's check out the results
together. This type of fertilizer
stimulates rooting very quickly.
[Music]
After one month of use, you will see
great
[Music]
results. Many flower buds develop and do
not fall.
[Music]
Blooming flowers stay on the branches
for a long time before fading.
[Music]
Flowers can remain on branches for up to
6 months before falling.
[Music]
Thank you for watching the video. Good
luck and see you in the next videos.
[Music]