Welcome to the happiness garden where we
explore the gentle beauty of nature
together and find joy in the simple
things everyday.
Today I want to share with you a gentle
method making natural fertilizer by hand
combined with simple care so that your
orchid can bloom continuously throughout
all four seasons while staying healthy
and never becoming exhausted.
[Music]
Um, you can see that this orchid of mine
has produced many blooms on a single
spike. And what's special is that
multiple flower spikes have grown from
the same plant, creating a vibrant and
lively beauty.
However, when the orchid channels all
its nutrients to support the vibrant
blooms and keep them fresh on the spike,
that's also the moment when it faces a
problem, one that I'm about to share
with you right now.
[Music]
Here's the thing. You might notice that
even though the flowers are still fresh
and beautiful, the leaves have started
to soften and become weak. Right?
If we don't know how to care for and
restore the plant at the right time, not
only will the leaves wither, but the
orchid's roots will also gradually
weaken, causing the plant to lose
strength after each blooming cycle.
If your orchid is experiencing the same
condition, don't worry because there's
still a simple way to help it recover
and continue growing strong.
First, you need to gently remove the
wilted flowers so that the plant doesn't
waste nutrients on the faded blooms.
This helps the plant focus on nourishing
its roots, leaves, and the remaining
fresh blooms on the spike so they can
stay vibrant for longer.
If there are damaged roots or leaves,
you should trim them off immediately.
Removing weakened or rotten parts helps
prevent the spread of disease and allows
the plant to focus all its energy on
recovery and growth.
Bananas are rich in natural potassium,
an essential element that effectively
helps wilted orchids recover and plays a
vital role in the formation and
maintenance of blooms.
Before using bananas as fertilizer, we
need to wash them thoroughly to remove
any chemicals and preservatives that may
remain on the peel.
[Music]
This not only helps protect the orchid
from the risk of toxicity or damage, but
also makes the composting process more
effective and safer.
[Music]
Let me know in the comments which
country you're watching from. It's
wonderful that we can connect and chat
with each other from all around the
world.
[Music]
And if you haven't subscribed to the
channel yet, please hit the subscribe
button to support me and never miss any
a orchid growing tips. It's truly
wonderful to have you along on this
journey.
[Music]
In addition to the English voiceover, we
have now created versions in French,
German, Italian, Spanish, Portuguese,
Japanese, Hindi, Dutch, Polish, Korean,
and Indonesian to help you listen and
understand the content more easily.
To listen in your preferred language,
open the video and click on settings,
the gear icon to select the appropriate
audio language.
[Music]
When eating bananas, don't be quick to
throw away the peel. Make use of it as a
natural fertilizer. This is a simple,
cost-effective, and eco-friendly way to
nourish your orchid everyday.
[Music]
Um, to make the fertilizer, simply chop
the banana peel into small pieces.
Cutting it up helps the peel decompose
faster and release nutrients more
effectively for the plant to absorb.
[Music]
The rich potassium content in banana
peels helps the plant transport water
and nutrients from the roots to the
farthest parts like leaf tips and flower
spikes with ease, keeping the plant
healthy and the blooms fresh for longer.
[Music]
Place the chopped banana peel into a
clean glass bottle. Using a glass bottle
ensures a safe composting process
without reacting with plastic while also
making it easier to observe and clean
after use.
Next, pour about 500 ml of warm water
into the bottle. The warm temperature
will stimulate fermentation, helping the
banana peel break down faster and
release nutrients more effectively for
the plant to absorb more easily.
The next ingredient you need to add is
molasses. It's a natural source of sugar
that promotes fermentation, nourishes
beneficial microorganisms, and enhances
the breakdown of the banana peel.
Just add about one teaspoon of molasses.
This small amount is enough to activate
the fermentation process and create a
favorable environment for microorganisms
to work effectively.
The final ingredient you need to prepare
is flour. Flour provides starch, an
excellent energy source for
microorganisms, helping the fermentation
process take place more vigorously and
quickly.
[Music]
Add about 1 teasp of flour. Then stir
the mixture well so the ingredients
blend together.
Finally, seal the bottle and place it in
a cool, wellventilated area away from
direct sunlight to ensure the
fermentation process takes place
steadily and effectively.
[Music]
Uh during the f first week, you should
open the bottle and stir the mixture
once a day to release the gas produced
during fermentation.
This helps prevent pressure buildup and
ensures the fermentation process occurs
safely and effectively.
Keep the bottle in a cool, well
ventilated place. After about 10 days,
the mixture will be fully fermented, and
you'll have a natural fertilizer made
from banana peels, rich in nutrients and
excellent for orchids.
And this is the bottle of fertilizer I
fermented from banana peels 10 days ago.
You can see that the color has turned
golden brown with a mild characteristic
fermented fermented smell. This
indicates that the fertilizer is now
ready to be used for your orchids.
Use a measuring tool to take out 50 ml
of fertilizer from the fermented bottle.
[Music]
After measuring out 50 ml of fertilizer,
dilute it with one liter of clean water.
This dilution makes the solution
gentler, suitable for orchids, and
prevents root shock.
[Music]
Step one, use a soft cloth to soak up
the diluted fertilizer solution. Then
gently wipe both the upper and lower
surfaces of the leaves.
[Music]
When wiping the leaves with the diluted
fertilizer solution, nutrients from the
banana, such as potassium and trace
elements, are absorbed directly through
the leaf surface. This helps the plant
take in nutrients more quickly,
especially during recovery or while
supporting blooming.
[Music]
Clean leaves allow light to pass through
more effectively, improving
photosynthesis.
Regularly wiping the leaves removes dust
from the surface, helping the plant
generate energy to grow strong and
healthy.
The fermented banana peel fertilizer
contains beneficial microorganisms that
help inhibit the growth of harmful fungi
and bacteria.
Wiping the leaves with this solution
creates a natural protective layer for
the plant.
[Music]
Orchid leaves after being wiped with the
fertilizer solution will become shinier
and more vibrant. This is also a great
way to make your plant look healthier
and more radiant in your living space.
You only need to wipe the leaves with
this fertilizer solution about one to
two times a month. This gentle frequency
is enough to provide regular nutrients,
keep the leaves clean and healthy, and
support the plant's sustainable growth.
Step two, pour a portion of the diluted
fertilizer solution into a clean spray
bottle. Using a spray bottle allows you
to distribute the solution more evenly
over the entire plant, especially around
the roots and growing medium without
causing water logging.
Next, gently spray the solution onto the
upper and lower surfaces of the leaves,
the stem, roots, and even the growing
medium. This method ensures that the
entire plant is evenly nourished from
leaves to roots, supporting its recovery
and promoting more complete growth.
Spraying the solution onto the leaves,
stem, roots, and growing medium allows
the orchid to absorb nutrients in a
comprehensive way. Not only the roots,
but also the leaves and stem are
nourished, helping the plant stay
healthy and have enough energy to keep
blooming.
The fermented banana peel solution
contains beneficial microorganisms that
help prevent mold and pests. At the same
time, spraying also helps cool the plant
on hot days and maintain stable moisture
levels for healthy growth.
After the blooming period, orchids often
become weakened. Spraying fertilizer
rich in potassium and trace elements
from banana peels helps the plant
recover faster, strengthens the roots,
regenerates new leaves, and prepares for
the next blooming cycle.
However, you should avoid spraying the
solution directly on the flowers as wet
blooms tend to drop their petals easily.
Keeping the flowers dry not only helps
them last longer, but also preserves
their vibrant and fresh color throughout
the blooming period. This is a small but
very important tip to keep your orchids
looking beautiful and longlasting.
[Music]
Step three, use the remaining solution
to water directly at the base of each
orchid pot. This method allows the roots
to absorb nutrients slowly and
effectively, nourishing the plant from
within and stimulating strong root and
leaf growth.
[Music]
When watering this mixture at the base,
nutrients like potassium and trace
elements will soak deeply into the
roots, helping them grow strong, bright
white, and spread widely. Healthy roots
are the essential foundation for the
plant to absorb water and nutrients more
effectively.
Fermented banana peel fertilizer
provides natural energy that helps the
plant recover quickly after blooming. At
the same time, it stimulates the plant
to prepare for a new growth cycle,
resulting in the next blooms being more
uniform, vibrant, and longerlasting.
[Music]
Um, you only need to water with this
mixture about twice a month. This
frequency is enough to provide
consistent nutrition, helping the plant
recover after each blooming cycle
without causing excess or harming the
roots.
Step four. After spraying and watering,
use a clean, dry cloth to absorb any
remaining solution on the leaf surfaces
and in between the leaf joints.
[Music]
This helps keep the leaves dry and airy,
preventing prolonged moisture buildup
that could lead to leaf rot or create
favorable conditions for fungal
diseases.
Be sure to handle the leaves gently to
avoid damaging tender new growth or
breaking any leaves.
Um, you should gently wipe from the base
of the leaf toward the tip using a dry
cloth to absorb any remaining moisture
on the upper surface, underside, and
between the leaf joints.
[Music]
After completing the care steps, place
the orchid pot in a spot with gentle
sunlight and good ventilation.
Remember, no matter how good the
fertilizer is, if the plant lacks light,
its ability to absorb nutrients will
still be limited. Light is a crucial
factor that helps orchids
photosynthesize, develop roots and
leaves, and prepare for future blooming
cycles.
When you care for your orchid with all
the love and patience you have for
plants, the orchid will feel it. And in
return, you'll be rewarded with vibrant,
long-lasting blooms and a garden full of
life.
I hope you enjoy this video. If you find
it helpful, don't forget to like and
subscribe so you won't miss future tips
on how to care for orchids naturally and
simply.
Thank you for watching until the end of
the video. Wishing you joy and success
on your journey of caring for your
beloved orchids. See you in the next
video.