Hello everyone. It is such a joy and
happiness to welcome you to visit my
little lovely garden. A place where joy
and simple things are
nurtured. Today I would like to share
with you how to revive withering flower
buds and the secret to helping your
orchids bloom beautifully multiple times
a
year. You can see that although this
orchid of mine is blooming beautifully,
many flower buds have unexpectedly
withered.
There are many reasons that can lead to
this situation. Lack of water or
overwatering, excessive or insufficient
light, unstable temperature, using
inappropriate fertilizers, or the attack
of diseases and
pests. And right now, I will share with
you how to fix this issue in a simple
and effective way.
First, remove all the rotten and
withered bud buds from the orchid to
help the plant recover
[Music]
better. If you haven't subscribed to the
channel yet, don't forget to hit the
subscribe button to support me and never
miss any helpful orchid growing tips.
It's wonderful to have you as a
companion on this journey.
[Music]
Um, please leave a comment to let me
know which country you are watching the
video from. It's wonderful that we can
chat together from all over the world.
Uh in addition to the English voiceover,
we have also prepared voiceovers in
French, German, Italian, Spanish,
Portuguese, Japanese, Hindi, and
Indonesian so that you can listen and
understand the content more
easily. For the languages that do not
have a voiceover yet, we have added
subtitles so you can easily read and
understand the content.
Then trim off the flowers that have
wilted or rotted. This will help the
orchid recover and grow stronger.
Um, next we need to check the potting
medium and the condition of the orchid's
roots to ensure the plant is still
healthy.
Uh through the preliminary check, I
found that the potting medium and the
orchid's roots are still quite good and
healthy. Then I proceed to trim off the
damaged roots to help the orchid recover
better.
Trimming off the damaged roots helps the
orchid regenerate its vitality,
promoting the growth of new, healthy
roots. And this also helps improve the
plant's ability to absorb water and
nutrients.
[Music]
Next, remove the yellow and damaged
leaves so the orchid can focus its
energy on healthier growth.
[Music]
As you can see, the black spots on the
yellow leaf stems and withered leaves
are where the disease clusters, waiting
for the opportunity to strike more
aggressively when the orchid is weak.
[Music]
Therefore, removing these leaves is
crucial to prevent the spread of
diseases and help the orchid recover
quickly.
[Music]
After finishing the trimming, we will
proceed to make fertilizer to help the
orchid recover and grow stronger.
To make natural fertilizer, I will use
turmeric powder, a great ingredient that
not only helps revive the roots, but
also disinfects the potting medium,
creating a favorable environment for the
plant to
grow. Take one teaspoon of turmeric
powder, then mix it with one liter of
hot water and stir well.
[Music]
Then let the mixture cool for a few
hours so The turmeric powder fully
dissolves into the in to the
water. Next, I use wheat flour as
fertilizer for the orchid. Um, providing
the necessary nutrients for the plant to
grow healthily.
Take one teaspoon of wheat flour. Then
mix it with one liter of room
temperature water and stir well.
Then let the mixture sit for a few hours
to allow the wheat flour to completely
dissolve in the water.
After the water cools, I proceed to
filter out the residue to obtain pure
turmeric water solution.
Filtering the turmeric water is an
important step to remove impurities,
making the solution pure and easier for
the orchid to absorb.
Uh once the filtration is complete, we
will proceed with the steps of caring
for the orchid using natural fertilizer
to help the plant grow
[Music]
healthy. Place the orchids base into a
cup. Then soak the potting medium and
roots in the turmeric water mixture for
about 20 minutes to help disinfect the
medium and eliminate root damaging
[Music]
fungi. Thanks to the anti-inflammatory
and antioxidant properties of turmeric,
soaking the orchid helps the plant stay
healthy and improves its ability to
resist harmful environmental
[Music]
factors. Turmeric water contains natural
compounds that help stimulate the growth
of new roots while enhancing the plant's
ability to absorb nutrients and
water. Soak. Soaking in turmeric water
helps prevent the growth of bacteria and
fungi that cause root rot, one of the
common causes of orchid
[Music]
damage. Step two, use a soft cloth to
soak in the turmeric water mixture and
gently wipe both the top and bottom of
the leaves.
[Music]
This helps remove dirt, bacteria, and
mold that could harm the plant. It keeps
the orchid clean and
[Music]
healthy. The turmeric water mixture.
When absorbed through the leaves,
provides essential nutrients to
strengthen the plant's
[Music]
resistance. Regularly wiping the leaves
not only keeps the orchid clean, but
also helps the leaves grow strong,
maintaining their natural beauty and
shine.
Careful wiping helps eliminate potential
pathogens, preventing infections or leaf
rot. You you should perform this step
for your orchid once a month to maintain
its health and effectively prevent
diseases.
Next, mix the wheat flour water with the
turmeric water thoroughly to create a
nutrient-rich natural fertilizer for the
orchid.
[Music]
Then we proceed to replant the orchid
into a new pot to create a clean
environment. that is conducive to the
plant's recovery and
growth. Pine bark chips are the type of
potting medium I usually use when
repotting orchids as it helps retain
moisture well, drains quickly, and
provides an ideal environment for root
growth.
After replanting, we spray the mixture
of turmeric water and wheat flour
solution evenly onto the orchid.
This solution helps stimulate root
growth, providing a solid foundation for
the orchid to develop long-term and
sustainably. When the orchid is weak or
stressed, spraying this mixture helps
provide essential nutrients, allowing
the plant to recover quickly and grow
better.
Spraying this mixture also helps wash
away dirt and impurities from the
leaves, keeping the orchid clean and
making it easier for the plant to absorb
nutrients. You should spray this mixture
one to two times a month to maintain the
orchid's health, help the plant grow
stronger, and effectively prevent
diseases.
After evenly spreading the turmeric and
flour mixture onto the orchid, we
continue by watering this mixture
directly onto the orchid's
roots. Watering helps the roots absorb
nutrients quickly, stimulates strong new
root growth, and also supports the
recovery of previous damage.
This is an important step to help the
orchid quickly regain its vitality and
continue growing healthily.
Uh you should perform this process
regularly one to two times a month to
maintain the orchid's health and keep it
lush and full of vitality.
Then use a soft cloth to gently blot the
water remaining on the leaf surfaces and
between the leaf joints to help the
leaves dry faster, reduce the risk of
fungal diseases, and keep the orchid
clean and healthy.
After wiping, you should place the
orchid pot in a spot with gentle
sunlight and good ventilation.
This helps the plant receive enough
light for photosynthesis without being
damaged by direct sunlight, thereby
supporting the orchid's recovery and
growth
optimally. Now, let's take a look at the
results after 3 weeks of caring for the
orchid with natural fertilizer.
As you can see, after 3 weeks of care
with natural fertilizer, many more
flowers have bloomed, bringing vibrant
beauty to the
orchid. Um, the remarkable recovery of
the plant with fresh new blooms is proof
of the great effectiveness of this care
method, helping the orchid not only stay
healthy, but also bloom continuously.
And the orchid has grown new very
healthy leaves.
Um, not only the flowers but the the
leaves have also become much sturdier
and greener than
before. The leaves not only look fresh
but also appear strong, promising a long
and beautiful blooming season.
[Music]
This remarkable change proves the
excellent effectiveness of caring for
orchids with natural fertilizer, helping
the plant recover quickly and grow
[Music]
healthily. I hope you enjoyed this
video. If you liked it, don't forget to
hit the like button and share it so more
people can discover
it. And if you haven't subscribed yet,
don't forget to hit the subscribe button
to support me and never miss any orchid
care tips. It's amazing to have you
along on this journey of taking care of
orchids. Thank you so
much. Wishing you a garden that's always
lush, full of life, and filled with
beautiful blooming orchids.
[Music]