hello
[Music]
everyone um Do You Love orchids and want
to care for them at home so they grow
strong and Bloom
beautifully let's explore how to care
for your orchid pot using natural
fertilizers helping your plants grow
vigorously and Bloom consistently
without the use of
chemicals watch the video to discover
simple and effective tips today
[Music]
this is a pot of phenopsis orchids
renowned for their beauty and
longlasting
blooms when caring for orchids it is
essential to promptly remove any damaged
leaves from the Orchid
pot this Leaf is damaged by bacteria um
if not removed promptly the infection
can spread rapidly to other parts of the
[Music]
plant remove it immediately from the
garden to prevent the bacteria from
spreading to other
plants then cut off all damaged roots
[Music]
cutting off damaged roots from the
Orchid pot is crucial because it helps
remove rotten and infected Roots
preventing bacteria and fungi from
spreading this ensures the healthy Roots
can continue to absorb water and
nutrients promoting strong and vibrant
growth this helps the plant grow
healthier and absorb nutrients more
effectively
now let's make a natural fertilizer to
take care of this
[Music]
Orchid then leave the Orchid pot
overnight to allow the cut to dry
completely this helps prevent any
potential infections or rot from develop
in at the cut
area to make this natural fertilizer you
need one cigarette
wet tobacco can serve as a natural
fertilizer for orchids due to its
nicotine and organic compounds which can
help stimulate growth and improve
resistance to pests however it should be
used carefully and in small amounts to
Aid avoid harming the
plant these elements help stimulate
plant growth and enhance their
Vitality these elements help stimulate
Vitality uh the compounds in tobacco can
help reduce the damage caused by harmful
insects and prevent bacterial and fungal
diseases thus protecting your orchids
put in jar
add 500 M of water at room
temperature leave overnight for
nutrients to completely dissolve in
water
[Music]
next I need bananas to make natural
fertilizer bananas are always my choice
as natural fertilizer for orchids
use one ripe banana peel cut into thin
slices banana peels are an excellent
natural fertilizer for orchids due to
their high content of potassium
magnesium and phosphorus these nutrients
help orchids grow vigorously increase
stress resistance and promote blooming
put the banana peel in the
jar then add 1 ler of room temperature
water next to make natural fertilizer we
need rice
add 3 tpoon of
rice cover the pot and leave overnight
for nutrients to mix into the
water uh after one night the nutrients
should have fully mixed into the
water stir vigorously so that the
nutrients dissolve into the
water then filter out the residue
step
one um gently wipe the top and bottom of
the leaves thoroughly with this water
wiping orchid leaves with tobacco soaked
water helps enhance the plants
resistance to pests and bacteria the
nicotine in tobacco has antibacterial
and antifungal properties preventing the
growth of fungi bacteria and harmful
insects for
[Music]
however it is important to dilute the
tobacco water and use it carefully to
avoid harming the
[Music]
plant step two
um then you put this water in a spray
bottle and spray the entire Orchid
[Music]
thoroughly spraying orchid leaves with
tobacco soaked water enhances pest
resistance due to nicotine's
antibacterial and antifungal
properties it also provides nutrients
helping the plant absorb vitamins and
minerals better promoting growth and
protecting it from harmful factors
step
three then filter the water to soak
banana peels and
rice which country are you watching
videos from please comment
below it's great that that we can chat
together from all over the world
then water each pot of your Orchids with
this
water watering Orchids with banana peel
soak and rice R water provides essential
nutrients such as potassium magnesium
phosphorus and vitamins helping orchids
grow vigorously and Bloom
beautifully a banana peel soak
stimulates root development while rice
water provides amino acids and minerals
to strengthen the plant
step
one wiping orchid leaves dry after folar
fertilization helps prevent water from
accumulating on the leaves reducing the
risk of mold and bacteria growth
it also prevents Leaf burn from sunlight
reflecting off leftover water while
keeping the leaves clean and allowing
better
photosynthesis perform the above four
steps every 10 days for your orchid
pot place the Orchid pot in a place with
plenty of light but avoid direct
sunlight for the Orchid to grow
[Music]
results after 2
months leaves grow Greener and glossier
the orchid has grown many new
roots and this Orchid pot also produces
many new flower
branches for
for take care of your Orchids with all
the love for plants and you will be
rewarded with vibrant blooms every
day don't forget to like share this
video And subscribe to thean channel for
more plant care
tips thank you for watching and see you
in the next
video wishing you great success in
caring for your orchids and having
beautiful pots of flowers