I'm very happy to welcome you to my
little garden where every flower is
cared for with all my love and
patience. Today I will continue to guide
you on how to revive weak orchids, those
that have become exhausted after
blooming so so they can regain their
vitality, grow healthily, and get ready
for a vibrant next blooming
season. You can easily notice that this
orchid is wilting. If not revived in
time, it is very likely that the plant
will
[Music]
die. When you notice that the orchid is
wilting, the first and most important
step is to immediately check the growing
medium and the root system, as these are
the key factors that will help the plant
recover. After checking, I found that
the orchid has a lot of rotting roots.
So, we need to cut off all the damaged
roots so that the plant can recover and
grow
back. Removing the damaged roots helps
stop the spread of fungi and bacteria
while also creating favorable conditions
for new healthy roots to grow. This in
turn helps the orchid recover quickly
and continue to
thrive. Next, we need to remove the
yellowing and wilting leaves as this
will help the plant focus its energy on
recovering and developing healthier
parts.
[Music]
Next, we need to cut off the old flower
stems as this will help the plant focus
its nutrients on developing new parts,
supporting the recovery process, and
preparing for the next blooming season.
[Music]
After cutting off the damaged roots, we
wash the plant under running water to
remove dirt, bacteria, and mold while
also cleaning the growing medium. This
creates a better environment for the
plant to absorb water and nutrients more
easily.
Now we will prepare fertilizer to help
restore the health of the orchid,
providing the necessary nutrients for
the plant to grow strong again.
To make natural fertilizer, I use one
teaspoon of sugar, which provides a
natural energy source for the
plant. Then dilute it with one liter of
water to create a fertilizer solution
that is easy for the plant to absorb.
[Music]
After preparing the solution, pour it
over and soak the orchid leaves for
about 20 minutes. This helps provide
nutrients directly to the plant, aiding
in the recovery of wilted leaves and
stimulating the growth of new leaves.
This process will help revive the wilted
leaves, making them fresher and
healthier by replenishing energy and
essential nutrients.
Next, take one liter of water to prepare
the second natural fertilizer, which
will provide additional nutrients for
the orchid.
Then add one teaspoon of dry yeast,
which helps stimulate the decomposition
process and improve the soil quality,
creating a favorable environment for the
plant's
growth. Next, add 1 teaspoon of flour.
The combination of flour and yeast in
the water will create a nutrient-rich
environment, helping to promote the
growth of beneficial microorganisms,
improve the fertility of the growing
medium, and support the orchid's quick
recovery.
[Music]
Then wait for about 20 minutes to allow
the solution to react, helping the
ingredients in the fertilizer blend
together and work at their
best. After soaking the wilted leaves
for about 20 minutes, be sure to remove
them and avoid leaving them in the
solution for too long as this can cause
water logging, making the leaves prone
to rotting and less effective at
absorbing
nutrients. Then use a soft cloth to
gently wipe off all excess water,
helping to prevent long-term moisture on
the leaves. create conditions for the
plant to recover quickly and reduce the
risk of
[Music]
mold. Please let me know which country
you're watching the video from. It's
it's amazing that we can chat together
from all around the world.
Now we will mix the solutions together
to create a perfect blend that will
provide nutrients for the
orchid. When mixing, be sure to filter
out any sediment to ensure the solution
is smooth and easily absorbed by the
plant without hindering the nutrient
absorption process.
[Music]
Then soak the orchid roots in this
mixture for about 20 minutes. This helps
provide nutrients directly to the roots,
promoting the recovery process and
encouraging the strong growth of new
roots.
The remaining mixture can be used to
water the other orchids in the garden,
providing additional nutrients and
supporting healthy growth for all the
plants. Just water each pot with about 5
to 10 tablespoons of this mixture,
enough to provide nutrients without
causing water logging.
[Music]
this natural fertilizer helps stimulate
the roots to grow quickly. Just like the
strong growth of this
[Music]
orchid, this natural fertilizer not only
helps revive the weakened orchid, but
also supports healthy orchids in the
garden, promoting strong growth,
encouraging root development, and
keeping the plants lush, lush, and
thriving.
[Music]
This natural fertilizer not only helps
revive the weakened orchid, but also
supports healthy orchids in the garden,
promoting strong growth, encouraging
root development, and keeping the plants
lush, lush, and thriving.
[Music]
If you haven't subscribed to the channel
yet, don't forget to hit the subscribe
button to support me and never miss any
useful orchid care tips. It's wonderful
to have you with me on this journey.
[Music]
In addition to the English voiceover, we
have now created voiceovers in French,
German, Italian, Spanish, Portuguese,
Japanese, Hindi, and Indonesian to help
you listen and understand the content
more
easily. For languages without
voiceovers, we have created subtitles so
you can read and understand the content.
[Music]
For languages without voiceovers, we
have created subtitles so you can read
and understand the content.
Uh at the bottom of the pot, I place a
few pieces of foam to improve drainage,
creating conditions for the orchid roots
to grow easily and preventing water
[Music]
logging. I insert a plasticcoated metal
stake into the foam. After planting the
orchid, we can secure the plant,
ensuring it stays steady and doesn't
shift during its growth
process. I insert a plasticcoated metal
stake into the foam. After planting the
orchid, we can secure the plant,
ensuring it stays steady and doesn't
shift during its growth process.
[Music]
I spread a layer of moss on top of the
pot to help retain moisture for the
plant, protect the roots from direct
sunlight, and create stable conditions
for the orchid's growth.
[Music]
I spread a layer of moss on top of the
pot to help retain moisture for the
plant, protect the roots from direct
sunlight, and create stable conditions
for the orchid's growth.
[Music]
From now on, water the orchid with this
fertilizer mixture once a week to
provide continu continuous nutrients
helping the plant recover quickly and
grow
healthily. On regular days when the
growing medium is dry, simply water the
orchid to maintain moisture, helping the
plant stay hydrated without wilting.
Then place the orchid pot in a spot with
gentle sunlight, ensuring the plant
receives enough light without the risk
of leaf burn, creating the best
conditions for its
growth. Now, let's take a look at the
results after 3 weeks of caring for the
orchid with natural fertilizer.
[Music]
You can see that many new roots have
sprouted, indicating that the orchid is
recovering well and growing strongly.
[Music]
Although the leaves are still wilted, as
new roots develop, the plant will
gradually recover and start growing new
leaves, making it stronger and
healthier.
Continue watering the orchid with this
fertilizer mixture once a week to
maintain strong growth and help the
plant produce new roots and grow
healthily.
And here is the result after 2 months of
recovery with natural
fertilizer. As you can see, although the
leaves are still wilted, they have
become much sturdier compared to before,
showing that the plant is gradually
recovering.
The orchid has even grown a new flower
spike, indicating that the recovery
process is progressing very well. This
shows that the plant is gradually coming
back to life. Not only recovering its
leaves, but also starting to show signs
of strong growth, such as the appearance
of a new flower spike.
[Music]
I continue to water the orchid with this
natural fertilizer mixture once a week,
providing regular nutrients to help the
plant grow healthily and produce
beautiful flowers.
Once the orchid has developed enough
roots and is securely anchored in the
medium and pot, we can remove the tying
string to prevent it from constricting
the plant, allowing it to continue
growing naturally.
[Music]
And here's the result after 3 months of
recovery. As you can see, after 3 months
of recovery, the orchid has fully
revived.
As you can see, after 3 months of
recovery, the orchid has fully
revived. The leaves are now vibrant and
full of life, showing that the care
method has been incredibly effective,
helping the plant grow strong and
healthy once
again. What do you think about the way I
revived my weak orchid? Feel free to
leave a comment and share your thoughts
with me.
Um, the flower buds are plump and ready
for the next bloom. With the vibrant
flowers about to bloom, the orchid now
shows a remarkable recovery and promises
to bring a colorful season of
flowers. If you found the content
helpful and meaningful, don't forget to
like, share, and subscribe to support my
channel. Thank you for always being with
[Music]
me. Thank you for watching the video. So
I also pray that God blesses you and
everyone.