Welcome to the happiness garden where we
take care of our beloved orchids
together and find joy in the simplest
things in nature.
Today I will share how to replace the
growing medium and repot the orchid. An
important step to help the plant recover
after a long period and grow stronger.
This creates the conditions for the
orchid to grow new roots, have lush
green leaves, and even bloom all year
round if cared for properly.
[Music]
After buying an orchid, once the flowers
fade, the plant often falls into a
weakened state. The leaves begin to turn
yellow, the roots gradually weaken, and
the plant appears lifeless.
After buying an orchid, once the flowers
fade, the plant often falls into a
weakened state. The leaves begin to turn
yellow, the roots gradually weaken, and
the plant appears lifeless.
First, cut off the old and withered
flower spike. This helps the plant stop
wasting energy on the faded part and
instead focus its energy on restoring
roots and leaves and preparing for the
next blooming cycle.
[Music]
Next, gently remove the soft plastic pot
that is commonly used in industrial
orchid nurseries.
You can see that because the growing
medium hasn't been changed for a long
time, the roots have become suffocated
and lack ventilation. This causes many
roots to rot and turn black, losing
their ability to absorb water and
nutrients, which weakens the plant over
time.
Some roots may appear hollow or slightly
soft on the outside. Um, this is a sign
that they were previously damaged but
are still trying to keep growing.
You may also notice red mold appearing
on the old leaf sheets. Um, this is a
sign that the growing environment is too
humid and lacks proper ventilation.
If not treated in time, the mold can
spread and affect both the stem and
roots of the plant.
[Music]
When growing orchids, always follow the
principle, moist but not wet growing
medium. This ensures the roots have
enough moisture to grow while still
staying well ventilated, preventing
water logging, root rot, and fungal
diseases.
With this type of growing medium, you
can see that it retains too much water.
This keeps the area around the roots
constantly wet wet, which can suffocate
them, deprive them of oxygen, and lead
to gradual rotting. Therefore, replacing
it with a more suitable medium is
essential for the plant to recover and
grow healthily.
[Music]
I will remove all the old growing medium
from the roots. This step helps
eliminate any decayed, moldy, or disease
carrying material while also allowing
the roots to breathe and absorb
nutrients better when replanted in the
new medium.
[Music]
Next, I will trim off any damaged roots
that are rotting, blackened, or hollow
inside.
Next, I will trim off any damaged roots
that are rotting, blackened, or hollow
inside.
Removing the weak roots prevents the
plant from wasting energy, allowing it
to focus on nourishing the remaining
healthy roots and stimulating new root
growth.
[Music]
If you haven't subscribed to the channel
yet, please hit the subscribe button to
support me and never miss any orchid
growing tips. It's wonderful to have you
along on this journey.
[Music]
Next, gently remove the red mold
attached to the old leaf sheets.
If left for too long, these mold patches
can spread and harm the stem. Cleaning
them off helps the plants stay well
ventilated and prevents the pathogens
from returning.
Leave a comment and let me know which
country you're watching from. It's
wonderful that we can connect and chat
from all around the world.
[Music]
After trimming and cleaning the roots,
rinse the entire plant under running
water.
Uh, this step helps remove any remaining
dirt, bacteria, and pathogens while
thoroughly cleaning the stem and roots
before replanting in the new growing
medium.
After rinsing, place the orchid in a
cool and well ventilated area to let it
dry completely.
To make a natural fertilizer that helps
the plant recover faster, I use a small
aloe vera leaf.
Aloe vera contains many nutrients and
natural antibacterial properties, making
it excellent for stimulating root growth
and healing cuts after root trimming.
After chopping the aloe vera leaf and
placing it in a jar, I add about 500 ml
of clean water.
Then I blend the mixture to extract the
maximum amount of nutrients from the
aloe vera leaf.
[Music]
Then I blend the mixture to extract the
maximum amount of nutrients from the
aloe vera leaf.
Next, I dilute the filtered solution
with clean water to make a total of one
liter. Diluting it makes the solution
gentler, safe for the roots, and
suitable for repeated use without
harming the plant.
Next, I will add a small amount of
vitamin B1 to the solution. This
familiar nutrient helps stimulate root
growth, boost resistance, and support
the plant's quick recovery after
repotting or root trimming.
I use three tablets of vitamin B1 each
containing 2.5 mg.
Then I stir the solution well to fully
dissolve the vitamin B1 in the aloe vera
water. This ensures the nutrients are
evenly distributed, helping the plant
absorb them more effectively when used.
Then I place the orchid roots into a
clean cup.
Next, I pour the aloe vera and vitamin
B1 mixture into the cup and soak the
orchid roots for about 20 minutes.
[Music]
This soaking time is enough for the
roots to absorb the nutrients, soothe
the cuts, and naturally stimulate new
root growth.
[Music]
While waiting for the roots to soak, you
can use a soft cloth dipped in the
mixture to gently wipe both the top and
bottom surfaces of the leaves.
[Music]
Wiping the leaves with the aloe vera and
vitamin B1 solution helps remove dust
and long-standing mold patches on the
leaf surface. When the leaves are clean
and well ventilated, the plant can
photosynthesize better and is less
likely to be attacked by pests and
diseases.
Both aloe vera and vitamin B1 contain
nutrients that can be absorbed through
the leaf surface. Wiping the leaves with
this solution helps the plant quickly
take in nutrients, supporting its
recovery and growth after repotting or
trimming.
The nutrients in aloe vera can soften
leaf tissue, making the leaves shinier,
more flexible, and healthier. This is a
natural way to improve the plant's
appearance without using chemicals.
Um, the combination of aloe vera and
vitamin B1 not only nourishes the plant
but also boosts its resistance, helping
it cope better with changing
environmental conditions, especially
during the recovery phase.
[Music]
While waiting for the roots to soak, I
take the opportunity to prepare a new
pot for planting the orchid.
[Music]
I make drainage holes at the bottom of
the pot and choose a moderately sized
pot that gives the roots enough space to
grow while still maintaining proper air
flow.
[Music]
After soaking the roots for about 20
minutes, I take the orchid out and
gently place it into the new pot that
has been prepared.
[Music]
The growing medium I use is clean pine
bark that has been thoroughly sterilized
before planting.
Uh, this type of medium provides good
drainage, retains just the right amount
of moisture, and creates a well
ventilated environment for healthy root
growth, making it ideal for orchids
after repotting.
When planting, you need to gently pack
the pine bark around the roots to secure
the plant in place.
[Music]
Do not press too tightly. Let the medium
just hold the plant steady while still
ensuring good air flow, allowing the
roots to grow and breathe easily.
[Music]
Finally, you can spread a thin layer of
dry moss over the surface of the pot.
This moss layer helps retain moisture in
the growing medium, reduces rapid water
evaporation, and also gives your orchid
pot a natural and tidy appearance.
[Music]
To prevent the orchid from wobbling
after planting, I prepare a small
plasticcoated steel stake to support and
stabilize the stem.
[Music]
This helps the plant stand firm, giving
the roots time to grow strong and
healthy in the new growing medium.
[Music]
After planting, place the orchid pot in
a cool, well ventilated area, avoiding
direct sunlight for 3 days.
During this time, avoid watering to give
the roots time to adapt and prevent rot
caused by excessive moisture.
[Music]
After the 3-day resting period, we begin
watering the orchid.
After
[Music]
the 3-day resting period, we begin
watering the orchid.
Method one, put the solution into a
spray bottle. This allows you to easily
spray the solution evenly onto the
leaves and around the base of the plant,
providing nutrients effectively.
[Music]
Then spray the solution thoroughly on
both the top and underside of the
leaves. This helps the nutrients absorb
evenly, cleans off dust, and strengthens
the health of the orchid leaves.
When the leaves are clean and fully
nourished, the plant absorbs light more
efficiently, leading to healthier growth
and more consistent flowering.
You should spray this mixture about
twice a month. Additionally, you can
alternate with other natural fertilizers
to provide complete nutrients, helping
the orchid develop comprehensively and
sustainably.
[Music]
Method two, you can directly water this
mixture onto the roots and growing
medium.
Watering the mixture directly supplies
essential nutrients to the roots. Aloe
vera and vitamin B1 stimulate new root
growth, enhance the ability to absorb
water and nutrients, thereby helping the
plant grow stronger.
This natural solution helps maintain
moderate moisture and balance the
microorganisms in the growing medium. Uh
as a result, the environment around the
roots becomes clean and well ventilated,
limiting the growth of fungi and harmful
agents.
You should water this mixture about
twice a month. Additionally, you can
combine it with other natural
fertilizers to provide complete
nutrients and help the plant develop
more comprehensively.
After watering or spraying the solution,
you should wipe off any excess water on
the leaf surfaces and in between the
leaf joints.
This helps prevent prolonged moisture,
reduces the risk of mold, and keeps the
plant dry, clean, and healthy.
After
that, place the orchid pot in a spot
with gentle sunlight and good air
circulation.
Soft light in the morning or afternoon
helps the plant photosynthesize well,
supports the recovery process, and
naturally encourages the growth of new
roots and leaves.
[Music]
And here's the result after 6 weeks. You
can see that the orchid has started to
grow many new roots. The leaves are
greener and healthier. And the plant is
full of vitality.
This orchid has even grown a new leaf at
the top. This is a sign that the plant
is actively growing and adapting well to
its new environment after being properly
cared for.
And this larger orchid over here has
also grown a new leaf at the very top.
[Music]
The leaves have also become much greener
and glossier than before. This is a
clear sign that the plant is absorbing
nutrients well and growing stronger day
by day.
When the leaves are healthy, the plant
can photosynthesize more efficiently,
generating more energy to nourish the
roots, develop the stem, and prepare for
the next blooming cycle.
Green leaves are a sign that the plant
is in a balanced and vibrant state.
And you can also see that the orchid has
started to grow many new roots.
These healthy roots will help the plant
absorb water and nutrients more
effectively, providing a strong
foundation for long-term growth.
That's why roots are often called the
heart of the orchid. When the root
system is healthy, the orchid has the
vitality to thrive, grow new leaves,
bloom, and shine in its own unique way.
[Music]
You can see that when orchids are
planted in a clear plastic pot, it's
easy for us to observe the root
development process.
When the roots grow along the sides of
the pot, you'll be able to tell whether
the plant is thriving or if its care
routine needs adjustment.
[Music]
What do you think about the way I
revived this small orchid? Don't
hesitate to leave a comment and share
your thoughts. I'd love to hear your
feedback and experiences.
Uh if you find this content helpful and
meaningful, don't forget to hit like,
share it so more people can benefit, and
subscribe to support the channel.
Thank you for always being with me on
this journey of caring for these beloved
orchids.
When you care for your orchid with all
your love, just as you would for animals
or any living being around you, the
orchid will feel it.
With patience, understanding, and love,
the plant will come back to life, grow
strong, and bloom beautifully as a
gentle way of responding to your care.
[Music]
Stay with me in the upcoming videos
where I'll share more simple yet
effective tips and experiences in orchid
care. Every orchid pot is a little story
and you are the one who writes the
radiant ending to that story.
Believe that as long as you pour love
into every drop of water, every gentle
touch on a leaf, your orchid will
respond with wonders. Because caring for
plants is also how we learn to be
patient, gentle, and slow down in the
rush of life.
See you in the upcoming videos where
where together we'll nurture not only
our orchid pots but also joy and peace
in life. Thank you for always being here
helping me grow a happiness garden every
day.