Hello friends nice to meet you on my
Channel today I will share how to make
natural fertilizer from ingredients
available in the kitchen helping to make
the most of nutrients to care for
orchids to grow
healthily we help orchids grow strongly
and Bloom brilliantly with large
beautiful petals and bright
colors if you haven't subscribed to the
channel yet please click the Subscribe
button to support me and not miss any
Orchid growing and tips it's great to
have
company let's get
started carrots contain many vitamins
and minerals especially vitamin a beta
carotene which helps improve plant
[Music]
Health in addition to the English dub
we've now created dubs in French German
Italian Spanish Portuguese Japanese
Hindi and Indonesian to help you hear
and understand the content more
easily cut into small
[Music]
slices please comment to me which
country you are watching the video from
it's great that we can chat together
from all over the world
then put the carrot peels into the
[Music]
jar add 4 cups of boiled water about 1
liter
[Music]
do you mean coffee as an ingredient for
fertilizer or are you asking if I
personally have
coffee add one
[Music]
teaspoon stir well so that the coffee
and carrot mixture dissolve olves into
the
water do you have pets please comment to
me how you like
[Music]
it incubate and wait until the water
cools
[Music]
2 hours
later the water has cooled
[Music]
filter out residue
add four cups of water about 1
[Music]
liter method one
water the Orchid pots with this
[Music]
water try not to water your orchids too
much but don't let them dry out either
[Music]
on average I water my orchids every 1 to
two
[Music]
weeks antioxidants vitamins in coffee
juice and and vitamins in carrot peels
will combined to create an excellent
liquid fertilizer for plants
um this type of fertilizer helps
stimulate new Roots very well at the
same time it has the ability to keep the
Orchid growing environment
[Music]
moist soaking this water for 20 minutes
so the roots can absorb more water and
nutrients
[Music]
method
two use soft cotton soaked in carrot
juice and coffee water to wipe orchid
leaves carrot juice contains many
vitamins and minerals which help nourish
the leaves and improve their health and
color uh compounds and carrots and
coffee help orchids increase their
resistance to diseases and
[Music]
insects wiping leaves with soft damp
cotton helps keep leaves moist
minimizing stress caused by drought
wiping leaves helps remove dirt and
impurities improving the plant's
photosynthetic
ability clean leaves absorb light better
thereby promoting effective
photosynthesis uh put this water in a
spray bottle
then spray the entire
orchid leaves that are provided with
moisture and nutrients will function
more effectively in the photosynthesis
process uh the combination of nutrients
in coffee and carrots will help
stimulate strong flowering of
orchids the ingredient in coffee juice
also support the growth of a very strong
root
[Music]
system but you absolutely should not
spray it on flowers because wet flowers
will quickly lose their blooms
[Music]
when orchids are water logged the flower
buds also fall off
[Music]
after soaking for 20 minutes take out
the Orchid pot then place it in a place
with lots of scattered light so the
Orchid can photosynthesize
[Music]
now we invite you to admire the results
after caring for orchids with natural
fertilizers in your
[Music]
garden um if you care for it with this
fertilizer or combine it with other
organic fertilizers I have shared on
this channel
make sure your orchids will grow
strongly and Bloom many
[Music]
flowers big beautiful bright
flowers the root system develops
strongly
[Music]
every tree grows healthier and blooms
more take care of your Orchids with all
the love you have for plants
[Music]
and you will definitely be rewarded by
watching the orchids in your garden
bloom all year
[Music]
round hope you like this video please
comment how you like it below the video
[Music]
hope you like this video please comment
how you like it below the
[Music]
video goodbye and see you again in the
next
[Music]
videos welcome to my
channel uh to help you have many choices
when caring for orchids at home with
organic fertilizer in this video I
continue to share new
[Music]
methods please subscribe to the video so
you don't miss any tips on my
[Music]
channel now let's get
started to make this organic fertilizer
you need coffee or coffee grounds
[Music]
I use three teaspoons
add 1 liter of boiled water
[Music]
incubate until
cool after the water cools filter to
remove residue
[Music]
add water to make 5 L of coffee solution
next add 1 teaspoon of baking soda
[Music]
first method
water this fertilizer Solution on the
Orchid
[Music]
Roots coffee contains many minerals and
organic matter helps provide Orchid
nutrition
[Music]
it contains nitrogen potassium and
phosphorus important nutritional
elements for orchid growth
[Music]
uh baking soda bicarbonate soda has the
ability to increase the pH level in
Orchid pots this is helpful in reducing
acidity if you use too much chemical
fertilizer
[Music]
baking soda has the ability to kill
insects and fungi that damage
[Music]
plants second method
spray this fertilizer on the entire
orchid
[Music]
this method is similar to using foler
[Applause]
[Music]
fertilizer you can use it as a natural
pesticide to protect orchids from
insects and diseases
[Music]
third method
clean the leaf surface with this
fertilizer
[Music]
solution the leaf surface will always be
clean and an ARA with stom orchids will
photosynthesize better
[Music]
please see the
results please see the results
[Music]
uh because of enough nutrition the
flowers bloom more brilliantly
[Music]
many flowers bloom on the same
Branch the flowers stay on the branches
for a long time before fading
[Music]
thank you for watching the video wish
you luck and success in
life thank you for watching the video
wish you luck and success in life