Welcome to my channel. I always want to
bring you the simplest and most natural
choices to care for orchids at home. In
today's video, I will share new tips.
These tips will help your orchids not
only stay healthy, but also bloom more
brilliantly everyday.
When the flowers wilt, you should cut
off the withered flower stems so the
orchid can focus nutrients on nourishing
other parts to grow healthily.
If you are new to the channel, don't
forget to subscribe so you won't miss
any useful tips about growing and caring
for orchids. It's it's wonderful to
accompany you on this journey.
[Music]
Cut off immediately the flowers and buds
that have wilted to help the orchid
focus nutrients to grow better.
[Music]
Please comment and let me know which
country you are watching the video from.
It's wonderful that we can chat together
from all around the world.
[Music]
Remove immediately the yellow leaves and
rotten leaves to help the orchid grow
healthier.
[Music]
Prune the damaged roots to help the
orchid grow better.
[Music]
after pruning and cleaning the orchid,
we will proceed to fertilize naturally
to take care of the plant.
[Music]
To prepare fertilizer for orchids, I use
2 tablespoons of coffee powder in a cup.
This is a simple but very effective
ingredient that helps the plant grow
healthier.
I add 500 ml of boiling water into the
cup to dissolve the coffee powder,
creating a nutrient solution for the
orchid.
[Music]
After mixing, I let the solution rest
for about 2 hours before use so that the
nutrients can absorb evenly and work
best for the orchid.
[Music]
Next, I take 2 tsp of dry yeast and put
it into another cup to prepare for the
next step in making natural fertilizer
for the orchid.
[Music]
I add 500 ml of warm water to the dry
yeast to activate it, helping the
fermentation process work better and
enhancing the nutrient effectiveness for
the orchid.
After adding warm water, I tightly cover
the cup and let the yeast rest for about
2 hours before use so the yeast can
fully activate to nourish the orchid.
Um, after 2 hours, when the water has
completely cooled, we filter out the
residue to obtain a clear coffee
solution ready to be used as fertilizer
to help the orchid grow healthily.
[Music]
In addition to English dubbing, we have
now created French, German, Italian,
Spanish, Portuguese, Japanese, Hindi,
Dutch, Polish, Korean, and Indonesian
versions to help you listen to and
understand the content more easily.
To listen to a language, open the video
and click on settings, the gear icon to
select the appropriate audio language.
Please comment and let me know which
country you are watching the video from.
It's wonderful that we can chat together
from all around the world.
[Music]
Next, I use a soft cloth soaked in the
coffee solution to gently wipe the
orchid leaves. This method helps remove
dust, mold, and harmful insects, keeping
the leaves clean and healthy.
This fertilizer contains natural
compounds that can prevent the growth of
some bacteria and fungi that cause
diseases on orchids. Thanks to this, the
plant is better protected, reducing the
risk of harmful diseases.
[Music]
Please kindly let me know which type of
orchid you are growing. I really want to
make a care guide video just for you.
[Music]
Be sure to carefully wipe the underside
of the orchid leaves as this is where
fungi, bacteria, and insects often
gather and grow the most. Directly
affecting the plant's health.
[Music]
Uh the underside of the leaf is where
insects, fungi, and bacteria attack,
creating brown and black spots. As the
disease develops, new wounds spread and
become more visible. on the upper side
of the leaf.
You should wipe the leaves when they are
still healthy, showing no signs of
disease, uh to help protect them from
early attacks by fungi, bacteria, and
insects.
[Music]
Then you mix the activated yeast
solution with the filtered coffee
solution, creating a natural fertilizer
that helps the orchid grow better.
[Music]
Next, you add one liter of clean water
to the mixture of yeast and coffee
solutions to dilute and balance the
nutrients before using it for the
orchid.
Method one, put the solution mixture
into a spray bottle for convenient
spraying on the leaves and stems of the
orchid, helping the fertilizer absorb
evenly and more effectively.
Um, when you spray this mixture on the
leaves and stems of the orchid, the
nutrients are quickly absorbed through
the leaf surface, helping the plant
strengthen its resistance and grow
healthier. At the same time, the thin
film on the leaves also helps retain
moisture and protect the plant from
harmful agents in the external
environment.
[Music]
Spraying this natural mixture also helps
clean the leaf surface, removing dust,
mold, and harmful insects. This helps
reduce the risk of disease for the
orchid, keeping the plant fresh and
vibrant, contributing to beautiful and
longerlasting flowers.
[Music]
You should spray this mixture on the
orchid about twice a month. Maintaining
this regularly will help the plant
continuously absorb nutrients, boost
resistance, and effectively prevent
pests and diseases.
[Music]
Method two, you use this mixture to
water directly at the base and roots of
each orchid. This method helps deliver
nutrients deep into the soil,
stimulating strong root growth and
better nutrient absorption.
[Music]
When watering this mixture directly onto
the base and roots of the orchid, the
nutrients will penetrate deeply into the
soil, stimulating healthy root
development. Healthy roots help the
plant absorb water and nutrients more
effectively, thereby promoting the
overall growth of the orchid.
[Music]
After watering, letting the orchid pot
soak in the mixture for 20 to 30 minutes
helps the solution penetrate deeply into
the roots and soil, nourishing the plant
better.
Then you take the orchid pot out and
place it in a spot with gentle sunlight.
The soft light helps the plant absorb
nutrients better without causing stress
or leaf burn.
You should fertilize the orchid
regularly twice a month. This helps
provide continuous nutrients supporting
the plant to grow healthy and bloom more
beautifully.
And here is the result after 3 weeks of
care.
You can easily see many new roots have
started to grow, proving that the plant
is recovering and growing very well.
[Music]
Um, you can see that the petals still
cling firmly to the stem. Not only not
wilted, but also maintaining their
bright and fresh colors for a long time.
The leaves become greener and firmer,
showing the plant's health and strong
growth.
[Music]
Thick and healthy roots help the orchid
absorb nutrients from the soil to the
fullest, allowing the flowers to firmly
attach to the stem and produce many
healthier new buds.
[Music]
Uh the root system plays a very
important role in the development of the
orchid. The plant's health largely
depends on how well the roots are cared
for and developed.
[Music]
Uh when the orchid is provided with
enough nutrients, the flower stems will
continuously grow and sprout new buds,
bringing brilliant beauty to the plant.
These orchid pots are also cared for
with this special mixture. And you can
easily see their roots growing very
healthy and vibrant.
[Music]
Not only the roots in the growing
medium, but also the orchid's aerial
roots grow strongly, contributing to
increased nutrient absorption and
maintaining the plant's vitality.
[Music]
The root system becomes denser, creating
a solid foundation for the orchid to
grow healthy and resilient.
[Music]
What do you think about how I make
natural fertilizer and care for these
small orchids?
Don't hesitate to leave a comment and
share your opinion. I really look
forward to hearing your feedback and
experiences.
If you find the content valuable and
meaningful, don't forget to like and
share. so many people can know about it
and subscribe to support me.
[Music]
Um, if you encounter any difficulties in
growing orchids, don't hesitate to
comment for me. I am always ready to
support you so that you can grow healthy
orchids that bloom abundantly.
Thank you very much for watching.
Goodbye and wish you always happiness
and health alongside the brilliant
orchids in your garden.
[Music]