hello
everyone welcome to my
Channel today I'm excited to continue
sharing with you a new organic
fertilizer that helps orchids grow fully
and bloom more
flowers if you haven't subscribed to the
channel yet please click the Subscribe
button to support me and not miss any
Orchid growing tips it's great to have
company let's get started
do you have
[Music]
potatoes wash the potatoes and peel them
like
[Music]
me then don't throw away the peel but
keep it as fertilizer
[Music]
potato peels are an excellent source of
nutrients for
orchids when recycled into fertilizer
potato peels provide essential vitamins
and minerals that help the plants grow
stronger in addition to the English dub
we've now created dubs in French German
Italian Spanish Portuguese Japanese
Hindi and Indonesian to help you hear
and understand the content videos are
[Music]
easier cut the potato skin into small
pieces they also improve soil moisture
and structure creating better conditions
for the Orchid roots to thrive
[Music]
next I need eggshells
like uh take two eggshells and make them
crumble
eggshells are a valuable source of
nutrients for
orchids um when crushed and used as
fertilizer eggshells provide calcium
which which helps strengthen root
structure and support plant growth
then put all the ingredients into the
[Music]
jar add four cups of boiled water about
liter incubate and wait for the water to
cool
[Music]
2 hours
later after cooling filter this water
[Music]
add four cups of water about 1 liter
step
one use a soft cotton to absorb this
water and gently wipe the top and bottom
of the leaves
thoroughly wiping orchid leaves with
fermented water from potato peels and
eggshells offers numerous benefits for
the
plants this fermented water is rich in
vitamins and minerals enhancing Leaf
vitality and stimulating photosynthesis
uh the calcium from eggshells
strengthens cell structure making the
leaves sturdier and reducing the risk of
disease
remove yellow and damaged
leaves Additionally the fermented water
provides moisture to the leaves aiding
the plant in better nutrient
absorption the wiping process also
removes dust and potential pathogens
keeping the leaves clean and healthy
which ultimately boosts the plant's
growth potential
which country are you watching videos
from please comment and let me know no
it's nice that we can chat together from
all over the world
step
two put this water in a spray
bottle then spray the entire orchid
then spray the entire
Orchid this fermented water is rich in
vitamins minerals and beneficial
microorganisms which help enhance the
plant's resistance
the calcium from eggshells supports root
development and improves cell structure
making the leaves sturdier
regular use of this solution will help
orchids Thrive Bloom beautifully and
last
longer step
[Music]
three uh water this water into each
Orchid
[Music]
pot watering Orchids with fermented
water from potato peels and eggshells
provides numerous practical
benefits this fermented water is rich in
vitamins minerals and beneficial
microorganisms supplying essential
nutrients to the plants
[Music]
the calcium from eggshells not only
strengthens root structure but also
supports plant
[Music]
growth apply the three steps like the
video to your orchids one to two times a
month
[Music]
then you soak the Orchid pot in this
water for 20 minutes so that the roots
can absorb more water and nutrients
after soaking for 20 minutes take out
the Orchid pot and place it in a place
with plenty of light to
grow orchids require light to carry out
photosynthesis which helps convert light
energy into chemical
[Music]
energy now we invite you to join us in
seeing the
[Music]
results um with this method new Roots
spread very quickly after only one
[Music]
month new Roots help the plant absorb
water and essential minerals from the
environment ensuring a steady supply of
nutrients for growth
[Music]
uh new Roots often host beneficial
microorganisms that improve nutrient
metabolism and stimulate plant
[Music]
growth new Roots can quickly adapt to
different environmental conditions
allowing orchids to survive and thrive
in challenging situations
[Music]
some Roots can store nutrients providing
the plant with a reserve during times of
need especially during dry
[Music]
periods to ensure Healthy Growth keep
the following points in mind orchids
generally need moderate light avoiding
harsh sunlight place them in a spot with
bright light but shielded from direct
midday
[Music]
Rays orchids need about 12 to 14 hours
of light daily you can use LED lights if
natural light is
insufficient if the leaves turn yellow
or light green the plant may be lacking
light conversely if the leaves are
sunburned reduce direct sunlight
exposure
sometimes you may need to relocate the
plant to ensure it receives adequate
light without
damage using organic fertilizers helps
the plant absorb light and nutrients
more
effectively thank you for watching the
video if there is anything you don't
understand don't hesitate to comment to
me so I can guide you further