welcome to my
channel if you have a wilted Orchid like
this don't rush to throw it
[Music]
away um now I share how to recover
quickly with natural
[Music]
fertilizers please remove inor organic
fertilizers and damaged
[Music]
Roots because the roots do not rot I
keep the old planting material to help
the Orchid recover
[Music]
quickly and remove all yellow and rotten
leaves
[Music]
which country are you watching videos
from please comment for
[Music]
me oh it's great that we can chat
together from all over the world
[Music]
if you haven't subscribed yet please
subscribe to support me and to not miss
any Orchid growing tips
[Music]
now you need to soak the entire orchid
in water at room temperature for 1
hour this helps to quickly restore
wilted roots and
leaves awaken the ability of fresh roots
and leaves to absorb
[Music]
water place in a cool place for 1 hour
now you take 1/3 teaspoon of sugar
[Music]
mix with 500 mm of water at room
temperature then take 500 milon of warm
water
[Music]
add 1 teaspoon of dry yeast yeast used
to make bread
[Music]
wait 1 hour for the yeast to develop
before using it as
fertilizer after soaking for 1 hour take
the Orchid out
[Music]
then soak the leaves in sugar water for
30 minutes
[Music]
no
after soaking for 30 minutes take the
Orchid
[Music]
out nutrients and sugar penetrate the
leaves helping wilted leaves recover
quickly
[Music]
now mix the sugar water with the dry
yeast
[Music]
solution uh this will create a natural
fertilizer that will stimulate strong
rooting and plant recovery
[Music]
soak the Orchid root in this water for
30 minutes will help stimulate rooting
extremely quickly
[Music]
the remaining liquid fertilizer is used
to water Orchid
[Music]
pots water each Orchid pot with 10
tablespoons
[Music]
this fertilizer helps stimulate root
growth a strong root system will help
the Orchid absorb nutrients
[Music]
best doing this one to two times a month
will be very good for the Orchid
[Music]
wa
water the Orchid roots with this
microbial fertilizer solution beneficial
microorganisms will grow in the Orchid
pot helps protect Orchid roots from rot
caused by fungi and bacteria
[Music]
this type of ferer also helps balance
the pH level in Orchid pots help
stimulate Orchid roots to grow and not
be damaged by
[Music]
acid after soaking for 30 minutes take
the Orchid out
[Music]
The Roots have become juicier and
Greener I use pine bark to grow orchids
[Music]
cover the surface of the Orchid pot with
a little Moss helps retain moisture
better
[Music]
then apply this microbial fertilizer to
the orchids every 2
weeks uh will create beneficial
organisms in the growing environment and
stimulate Orchid roots
uh on weekday you just need to spray
mist to keep it moist and water when the
substrate is
[Music]
dry then place the Orchid pot in a cool
place with enough light for the orcan to
recover
[Music]
results after 1
month after only one month Orchid Roots
have grown a lot and are
[Music]
healthy um these new Roots will help the
Orchid absorb nutrients and water best
[Music]
and gradually the leaves will become
fresh again
[Music]
take 1/5 teaspoon of sugar
[Applause]
[Music]
and take 1/5 teaspoon of dry
yeast mix with 300 mm warm water
[Music]
and wait until the water cools to room
temperature then use this microbial
fertilizer to water every 2
[Music]
weeks this type of fertilizer is
especially good for weak stunted Orchids
with underdeveloped Roots because it
does not Shock weak orchids like
chemical
[Music]
fertilizers um placing it in a place
with light sunlight will be best for
[Music]
orchids after the next 1 month
um the orchid has completely recovered
[Music]
the leaves are normal green and
thick the roots are very fat and have
many new roots
[Music]
hope the video will help you a
lot if you find it interesting please
like share and subscribe to my support
Channel thank you for
watching good luck and see you in the
next
videos Hello
friends in my hand is a withered
dendrobium Orchid and in this video I
will share how you can propagate any
dendrobium
Orchid we cut off the spots that have
bloomed
[Music]
only keep these three parts for
propagation because they still have
dormant buds at the
nodes drip melted wax onto the cut to
protect it from absorbing water
preventing the cut from rotting
which country are you watching this
video from please leave a comment for
me it's amazing that we can chat with
each other from all around the world
[Music]
peel off the protective film of the
sleeping sprout
[Music]
use one sprig of chopped fresh
ginger if you haven't subscribed to the
channel yet click the Subscribe button
to support me
[Music]
500 M of boiled
water wait one
[Music]
day so orchids in ginger water for 30
minutes soak moss in ginger water for 30
minutes
[Music]
I use recycled plastic boxes to make
miniature green houses to help propagate
orchids
[Music]
faster there's a vent here
put the Orchid in a miniature greenhouse
and spray it with moisture once a
[Music]
week uh place in a bright place and
avoid direct sunlight
21 days after
[Music]
continue misting to keep moisture and
keep in a light place avoid direct
[Music]
sunlight after 10 next day
continue misting to keep moisture and
keep in a light place avoid direct
sunlight after two next weeks
[Music]
I hope this video will be very helpful
for you in taking care of orchids at
home
[Music]
plant in pots to let the Orchid adapt
and grow in the outside environment
[Music]
if you find it interesting please
subscribe to the channel like share to
let more people
[Music]
know my videos have subtitles in
different languages please select the
appropriate language to understand the
video content
[Music]
clearly remember to plant the root
higher than the pot so that the Orchid
does not have root
rot that's all I want to share with you
in this
video now goodbye and see you in the
next videos
[Music]
Hello
friends nice to meet you on my
channel you see here a withered Orchid
maybe it's because you didn't water it
or due to direct sunlight shining on the
Orchid
[Music]
um if you want orchids to be nourished
and grow quickly please watch this video
[Music]
carefully now I will share this amazing
trick with
you you need one aloe vera leaf
[Music]
which country are you watching the video
from please comment
below it's wonderful that we can chat
together from all around the
world this aloe vera gel is great for
Reviving orchids
now apply aloe vera gel on the top and
bottom of the
[Music]
leaf aloe vera gel has a very good
moisturizing
[Music]
effect in addition aloe vera also
contains vitamins a b and c and minerals
such as nitrogen phosphorus and
[Music]
potassium uh do this every 5 days and
leave the Orchid pot in a cool place for
3 weeks
[Music]
next take 1 liter of warm water and put
it in the
[Music]
bottle then take one spoon of rice and
soak it in this water for about 30
minutes let the nutrients in the rice
completely dissolve into the water
[Music]
chop the remaining aloe vera leaves into
small pieces
[Music]
then puree with 300 mm of water
filter out residue then add 2 L of water
at room temperature
[Music]
after soaking for 30 minutes filter this
rice water
[Music]
mix rice water with aloe vera
juice so I ended up with about 3 lers of
this wonderful liquid manure solution
[Music]
cover the pot with moss to retain
moisture
[Music]
better now you use the solution to water
the Orchid every 5 days
[Music]
soak the Orchid pot in this water for 2
hours
after soaking for 2 hours remember to
lift the Orchid pot and place it in a
cool place to let the Orchid
[Music]
recover 2 weeks later
fertilize after 2 weeks for fresher
orchid
[Music]
leaves new Roots develop very
well many new roots are growing
[Music]
new Roots will help transport water and
nutrients from the roots to the
stem if the leaves are provided with
enough water and nutrients from the
roots the leaves will gradually become
Lush again
[Music]
1 month
later you see the leaves are very fresh
[Music]
and the Orchid grows a new Leaf
after the next two
[Music]
months the orchid has grown two branches
two
[Music]
buds but the leaves at the base have
turned yellow so I will cut off these
yellow leaves
[Music]
uh instinctively when an orchid buds if
the plant lacks nutrients that the base
leaves will turn yellow and fall off to
provide nutrients for the buds to
develop
now I need to supplement the orchid's
nutrition by taking three spoons of
[Music]
rice uh then soak in 2 L of water at
room temperature
[Music]
and wait 30 minutes for the nutrients to
completely dissolve in water before
[Music]
using 30 minutes
later add 3 tspoons of milk
[Music]
rice water and milk are excellent
sources of nutrients for orchids to
[Music]
grow now you water the Orchid with this
solution once a week to help the Orchid
recover quickly
[Music]
after the next 1 month
after 3 to four times of applying liquid
fertilizer from milk and rice water the
Orchid had many
[Music]
roots hope the video will help you a
lot if you like the video remember to
hit like share and subscribe to support
[Music]
me uh thank you for watching the video
wish you luck and see you in the next
videos