Hello everyone. I am very happy to
welcome you to my channel.
Today I will share how to help orchid
plants recover quickly when they face
rot.
[Music]
With just simple ingredients available
in every family's kitchen, we can easily
revive and help orchid plants affected
by rot to grow back quickly.
And then the flowers will bloom
brilliantly again, continuing to shine
in your beautiful garden.
Let's get started.
For orchid plants that have rotted like
this, don't rush to throw them away.
You can notice that in this spot, there
are always many harmful molds and
bacteria.
[Music]
When signs of rot appear, it spreads
quickly, and if not treated in time, the
orchid can be seriously damaged or even
die.
[Music]
We need to completely remove the damaged
leaves.
[Music]
Uh this helps prevent the spread of
disease uh while also allowing the
orchid to focus on recovering and
developing healthier parts.
Because the orchid is very weak, we need
to cut off the flower stems to reduce
the burden, helping the plant
concentrate nutrients and energy on
faster recovery.
Please comment to let me know which
country you are watching the video from.
It's wonderful that we can chat together
from all over the world.
[Music]
Uh you can see mold on the growing
medium has started to develop which
creates a high risk of root rot for the
orchid.
Since the orchid has been planted in
this pot with the growing medium for a
long time, we need to completely remove
the old medium and replace it with a new
pot.
[Music]
Then proceed to cut off all the damaged
roots.
This helps prevent the growth of fungi
and creates conditions for healthy new
roots to develop, contributing to the
orchid's recovery process.
[Music]
Um, when you see this leaf has naturally
dried, we don't need to cut it off, but
should leave it as it is.
[Music]
Next, we need to wash thoroughly to
completely remove dirt and harmful
bacteria.
If you haven't subscribed to the channel
yet, please hit the subscribe button to
support me and not miss any orchid
growing tips. It's wonderful to have you
along for the journey.
[Applause]
[Music]
to disinfect and stimulate root growth.
I use natural lemon water
[Music]
I dilute lemon water with one liter of
water to create a mild solution that is
safe for the orchid.
[Music]
Then soak the orchid's roots in the
diluted lemon water solution for about
20 minutes to gently disinfect and
stimulate new root growth.
[Music]
Lemon water contains citric acid and
natural antibacterial agents which help
clean orchid roots, prevent bacteria and
mold, and stimulate healthy new root
growth.
[Music]
The leftover lemon water can be further
diluted with water at a 1:1 ratio to
create a light watering solution, which
both disinfects the growing medium and
supports the recovery process, safely
and naturally, stimulating orchid
growth.
[Music]
Then you can use this solution to spray
on other healthy orchids in the garden,
helping to prevent fungal diseases and
boost the plant's resistance.
[Music]
Uh you can absolutely use this solution
to spray on small orchids, mature
orchids as well as orchids that are
blooming, helping to protect and nourish
the plants comprehensively.
[Music]
For orchids that are blooming, this
fertilizer helps keep the flowers fresh
longer on the stem because it provides
essential nutrients while also enhancing
the plant's health, helping the flowers
maintain color and freshness for a
longer time.
[Music]
Uh besides spraying the upper surface of
the leaves, you also need to pay
attention to spraying thoroughly on the
underside of the leaves as this area is
often damp, creating favorable
conditions for fungi and harmful insects
to gather and develop.
And you should avoid spraying directly
on the flowers because when the flowers
get wet, the petals will quickly wilt
and fade.
[Music]
After soaking in the solution for about
20 minutes, take the orchid out and
gently blot with a soft cloth to wipe
off the water droplets on the roots and
stem.
[Music]
Then use melted candle wax to drip onto
the cuts. This helps prevent water from
seeping in, protects the wounds from
infection, and prevents rot on the
orchid.
[Music]
Next, plant the orchid into a new pot
with drainage holes at the bottom to
ensure the plant does not become water
logged and helps the roots develop
healthier.
After that, I choose to use dry pine
bark as the growing medium for planting
the orchid.
After planting with dry pine bark, we
should not water immediately. This will
allow the bark to absorb the remaining
moisture from the roots, keep the roots
dry, and reduce the risk of rot.
[Music]
After planting, place the orchid pot in
a cool, wellventilated area for about 3
days and do not water.
This helps the plant adjust to the new
environment, allows the cuts to dry
completely, and gives the roots time to
adapt, thereby reducing the risk of
fungal infection and rot.
After 3 days, once the orchid adjusts,
start light watering or use diluted
liquid fertilizer to support recovery
and growth.
[Music]
Take 2 tablespoons of rice and mix with
half liter of water, stirring well to
create a natural, gentle, and
nutrient-rich liquid fertilizer. Perfect
for recovering and nourishing orchids
after treatment.
[Music]
Before
applying the liquid fertilizer, spread a
thin layer of moss on the orchid pot
rim.
This helps retain moisture in the
growing medium while creating an ideal
environment for the fertilizer to absorb
evenly and the orchid to absorb
nutrients more effectively.
Then water the orchid with rice water
two to three times a month. This is a
simple but very effective way to provide
natural nutrients and promote healthy
orchid growth.
[Music]
After applying the liquid fertilizer,
soak the orchid pot in this solution for
about 20 minutes.
Uh this helps the growing medium and
roots absorb nutrients more deeply while
cleaning and strengthening the root
system supporting a faster and more
effective recovery.
[Music]
After soaking for about 20 minutes, take
the orchid pot out and place it in a
spot with gentle sunlight to provide the
right temperature that naturally and
effectively promotes recovery.
[Music]
And here is the amazing result after one
month of caring for and recovering the
rotten orchid using the natural
fertilizer method.
[Music]
You can see the orchid has revived with
a new very healthy chute growing clearly
demonstrating the effectiveness of care
and recovery using natural fertilizer.
[Music]
And the orchid has also grown many new
healthy roots, helping to strengthen the
nutrient absorbing system and create a
solid foundation for the plant's
long-term growth.
Uh, what do you think about my method
for recovering weak orchids? Please
leave your comments and feedback to let
me know.
I continue to care for the orchids using
liquid fertilizer made from rice water.
[Music]
When the roots are strong, you can
switch to caring with different natural
fertilizers and alternate their use.
[Music]
This method helps the orchid absorb a
diverse range of essential nutrients
leading to more comprehensive and
sustainable growth.
[Music]
Each time after applying liquid
fertilizer, remember to soak the orchid
pot in the solution for about 20
minutes.
[Music]
Then remember to place the orchid pot in
a spot with gentle sunlight because
without enough light, the orchid cannot
metabolize and absorb nutrients
effectively, slowing down the recovery
and growth process.
And here's the result after 3 months of
caring for and recovering the weak
orchid using natural fertilizer.
[Music]
You can see that the root system has
developed healthily uh looking fresh and
full of vitality
and the leaves have also become glossy
and firm reflecting the plant's strong
vitality after the recovery period.
Thus, with just a few simple steps and
readily available household ingredients,
we can completely restore orchids at
home effectively, safely, and
economically.
[Music]
If you find the content helpful and
meaningful, don't forget to like, share
so more people can benefit and subscribe
to support me. Thank you for always
being with me.
[Music]
Uh, if you face any difficulties during
the orchid planting process, don't
hesitate to leave a comment. I'm always
here to support you so you can grow
healthy orchids with lots of beautiful
blooms.
Each time you revive an orchid, little
by little over the years, you will build
a vibrant garden full of colorful
orchids, bringing joy, peace, and
natural beauty that inspires your living
space.
[Music]
Thank you all for taking the time to
watch the video. I always pray that God
blesses everyone with many blessings and
peace.
Welcome to my channel.
Phelinopsis orchids are known for their
ability to keep flowers on the stem for
a long time. The flowers are beautiful,
so they are loved by many people around
the world.
[Music]
If you haven't subscribed to the channel
yet, please hit the subscribe button to
support me and not miss any orchid
growing tips. It's wonderful to have you
along.
Let's get started.
To make a hanging orchid garden, I
recycle old plastic bottles into
planting pots. This method not only
helps reduce plastic waste and protect
the environment, but also creates
beautiful and unique orchid pots.
[Music]
If you also love orchids, try doing it
like me. Simple yet full of inspiration.
[Music]
Uh this is a great way for busy people
to still satisfy their passion for
growing orchids without worrying about
daily maintenance and care.
[Music]
With this method, you won't need to
water yet. that the flowers will
continue to bloom all four seasons.
[Music]
Please comment and let me know which
country you are watching the video from.
It's wonderful that we can chat together
from all over the world.
[Music]
wash with water and antibacterial soap.
[Applause]
[Music]
Making holes helps. Ventilate so that
orchid roots grow better.
[Music]
Use high water absorbent cotton fabric
to make the wick.
[Music]
Insert the water absorbing wick into the
orchid pot.
[Music]
Uh, this is the hook for hanging the
orchid pot.
I make holes to hang the orchid pot
hooks here.
[Music]
Uh these are plastic beads commonly used
for hydroponic vegetable growing. I use
them as the growing medium for orchids.
[Music]
This wick has the task of drawing water
from the lower layer up, keeping the
growing medium at an ideal moisture
level for the orchid to grow fast.
[Music]
Now I plant the orchid seedlings into
the semi-hydroponic orchid pots.
[Music]
after planting you water.
With this method, you only need to water
once and then you can be assured no need
to water again.
[Music]
The wick draws water from below, helping
the orchid pot always maintain stable
moisture.
When the water runs out, you just need
to add water or replace it after each
time you spray natural fertilizer on the
orchids.
Then you hang the orchid pot in a place
with gentle sunlight.
[Music]
The most suitable temperature for
orchids is from 20 to 30°.
[Music]
You should spray natural fertilizer on
the orchids about two to three times a
month as I've shared on the channel.
[Music]
5 months later,
as you can see, with this simple method
from a small orchid, it has now grown
healthy and full of vitality.
[Music]
What do you think about my
semihydroponic orchid growing method?
Please write your comments and feedback
to let me know.
[Music]
Um, have you tried applying any method
from the video on the channel yet? Don't
hesitate to leave a comment and share
your feelings. I'm very eager to hear
your experiences and suggestions.
[Music]
After 6 months, from a small orchid
planted in a semihydroponic pot, the
plant has now matured and bloomed
brilliantly.
[Music]
This is a wonderful method that helps
busy people satisfy their passion for
growing orchids without having to worry
about watering, fertilizing, or daily
care.
[Music]
With this semi-hydroponic growing
technique, orchids maintain their fresh
color longer and can stay on the stem
for more than 6 months before the petals
start to wilt.
I hope this content will be very helpful
for those of you growing orchids at
home.
Uh if you find the content good and
meaning don't forget to like, share. so
many people know about it and subscribe
to support me. Thank you for always
being with me.
[Music]
Thank you for watching the video. I
always pray that God blesses all of you.