Welcome to the happiness garden, where
we together explore the secrets of
caring for ornamental plants and enjoy
the natural beauty around us.
[Music]
If you have an anththerium or any indoor
ornamental plant that has rotted like
this, don't rush to throw it away. Right
now, I will guide you step by step on
how to treat and save the plant, helping
it recover to full health so you can
still enjoy lush greenery and vibrant
vitality in your living space.
First, we need to cut off all damaged or
rotting leaves so that the plant can
focus its energy on recovering the
remaining parts.
You can see that all the leaves are
damaged with no green leaves left for
the plant to photosynthesize.
This may seem worrying, but don't worry
because with proper care, the plant
still has a chance to revive and grow
again.
Next, we check the roots.
[Music]
You can see that the roots are infected
with mold with a soft surface and
discoloration which prevents the plant
from absorbing nutrients. Early
detection will help us treat it in time,
protect the healthy roots, and give the
plant a chance to recover.
We need to remove all the old growing
medium as it may contain mold and
bacteria harmful to the roots. This
helps clean the environment around the
roots, creating favorable conditions for
the plant to recover and grow strong
again.
[Music]
Please leave a comment and let me know
which country you're watching from. It's
wonderful that we can connect and chat
with each other from all around the
world.
Then we cut off all the damaged roots,
the soft and rotting parts.
[Music]
We only keep the healthy roots like this
firm and bright in color. These roots
will be an important foundation for the
plant to recover to recover and grow new
shoots in the coming time.
[Music]
Then rinse the roots with water,
completely removing the old soil and any
remaining rotting root fragments. This
helps the roots stay clean, airrated,
and ready to absorb nutrients when
replanted.
If you haven't subscribe to the channel
yet, click the subscribe button to
support me and not miss any orchid
growing tips. It's wonderful to have you
along on this journey.
[Music]
Next, pour water into a cup of about 500
ml, preparing to mix the disinfecting
solution.
[Music]
I use lemon to mix because the natural
acid in lemon effectively disinfects
removing mold and bacteria on the roots.
At the same time, lemon is gentle and
does not harm the healthy roots,
creating good conditions for the plant
to recover.
[Music]
Squeeze about one teaspoon of lemon
juice to mix into the cup of water.
[Music]
Uh, this amount of lemon is just enough
to make the disinfecting solution
effective, protecting the healthy roots
and gently removing mold, helping the
plant recover better.
[Music]
Then pour the diluted lemon water
mixture in, soaking the entire roots and
stem for about 20 minutes.
[Music]
This soaking helps disinfect effectively
remove any remaining mold and bacteria
while protecting the healthy roots,
creating favorable conditions for the
plant to revive.
[Music]
While waiting for the soaking, we
prepare the new growing medium.
The first ingredient is coconut husk
chips used for planting. 50% coconut
husk helps retain moisture, provides
irerration for the roots, and creates an
ideal environment for the plant to grow
healthily.
The next ingredient is sand or organic
soil, making up about 50% of the
planting mixture. This component helps
the plant drain well while also
providing essential nutrients for the
roots and leaves, creating balanced
growth conditions.
[Music]
Then mix all the ingredients thoroughly.
This ensures a uniform growing medium
retaining moisture while providing
irerration creating an ideal environment
for the roots to grow strong and
healthy.
You can check the growing medium by
squeezing it in your hand. If it gently
crumbles when released, it is a sign
that it has the right irration and
moisture retention. This will help the
roots grow naturally without water
logging or nutrient deficiency.
After soaking for 20 minutes, we take
the antherum out and plant it in a new
pot.
This allows the roots to be in a clean,
nutrient-rich environment, providing the
best conditions for the plant to recover
and grow new shoots.
[Music]
When planting, gently place the roots in
the center of the pot, making sure they
are spread out evenly and not bent or
compressed. This helps the roots grow
naturally, absorb nutrients better, and
allows the plant to settle quickly in
its new environment.
[Music]
After spreading the soil, gently tap the
sides of the pot so the growing medium
settles evenly around the roots. This
helps the plant stand more firmly,
ensures good rootto soil contact, and
prepares the roots to absorb water and
nutrients, supporting quick recovery.
After planting, place the plant in a
cool, airy spot for one day and do not
water it. This helps the plant stabilize
in its new environment.
After one day, we proceed to fertilize
the plant.
[Music]
To help the plant quickly grow new
shoots from the mother stem, I use
coconut water because it contains many
natural nutrients, vitamins, and
minerals that help the roots and new
shoots grow healthy while also boosting
the plant's vitality. Hey,
[Music]
what you
Take about 100 milllers of coconut water
to mix.
[Music]
Dilute the coconut water with 300 ml of
water. Diluting helps distribute the
nutrients evenly, providing just enough
for the plant to absorb without causing
shock, supporting healthy growth of
roots and new shoots.
After mixing, use this solution to water
directly onto the roots and growing
medium. This helps the nutrients
penetrate deeply, allowing the roots to
absorb effectively while also supporting
the sprouting of new shoots and the
plant's quick recovery.
[Music]
Coconut water when applied to the plant
provides vitamins, minerals, and natural
sugars, stimulating strong root growth
and faster sprouting of new shoots. At
the same time, it boosts the plant's
vitality, keeping stems and leaves
healthy, creating a foundation for the
next growth season.
After watering, place the plant in a
spot with gentle sunlight. Soft light
allows the plant to photosynthesize just
enough, stimulating root and new chute
growth without shocking the plant.
Uh, and here is the result after 3 weeks
of recovery.
You can see that the plant has started
to grow new shoots from the mother stem,
signaling strong vitality and a
successful recovery. These new shoots
will develop into healthy leaves and
flowers in the coming time.
This shows that with proper care, the
plant can recover strongly from the
damaged parts.
I continue to fertilize the plant with
natural fertilizer.
Um, I choose rice to make fertilizer for
the next stage. Rice provides natural
sugars and some essential nutrients,
helping the roots grow strong, promoting
quick sprouting of new shoots, and
maintaining the plant's long-lasting
vitality.
Just two teaspoons of rice are enough.
This amount provides gentle nutrients,
allowing the plant to absorb effectively
without overloading while stimulating
healthy growth of roots and new shoots.
Add 500 ml of water to the rice.
Diluting helps the nutrients from the
rice distribute evenly, making them
easier to absorb, supporting healthy
growth of roots and new shoots, while
maintaining the plant's long-asting
vitality.
[Music]
Uh after mixing, you can pour the
solution into a spray bottle. This helps
evenly apply the nutrients to the roots,
stem, and new shoots, ensuring the plant
absorbs effectively and grows healthily.
Then spray evenly onto the new shoots
and growing medium. This helps the
nutrients penetrate deeply, stimulates
rapid growth of new shoots while
nourishing the roots and creating
favorable conditions for the plant to
recover strongly.
[Music]
uh then spray evenly over the new shoots
and growing medium. This helps the
nutrients penetrate deeply, stimulates
rapid growth of new shoots while
nourishing the roots and creating
favorable conditions for the plant to
recover strongly.
Do this twice a month, alternating with
regular watering.
Remember
to place the plant in a spot with gentle
sunlight. Soft light allows the plant to
photosynthesize just enough, stimulating
root and new chute growth without
burning the leaves or shocking the
plant.
[Music]
And here is the result after 6 weeks of
recovery.
You can see the shoots growing stronger,
leaves lush and green, and roots robust,
showing that the plant has fully
recovered and is ready for the next
growth stage.
[Music]
As the new shoots grow stronger, you
will clearly see vitality radiating from
every leaf, root, and new sprout.
This shows that with patience and proper
care, the plant can fully recover and
continue to thrive, bringing joy and
rewarding results to plant lovers.
[Music]
Seeing the new shoots emerge, you will
feel the joy and satisfaction of
watching the plant come back to life and
bloom with vitality.
[Music]
Every time you care for, water or
fertilize the plant, it is an act of
sewing trust and hope. Watching the
plant recover and grow day by day, you
will see your efforts rewarded, and the
joy from the garden will radiate back to
you.
How do you find my way of reviving the
plant? Don't hesitate to leave a comment
and share your thoughts. I'd love to
hear your feedback and experiences.
Um, I hope this video will be helpful
for you in caring for indoor plants.
With these simple yet effective steps,
you can fully revive and nurture your
plants to grow healthily, bringing joy
and greenery to your living space.
If you find the content helpful and
meaningful, don't forget to like, share,
and subscribe so more people can know
about it and support me. Thank you for
always accompanying me, caring for and
enjoying the beauty of indoor plants at
home.