Hello orchid lovers. Welcome to the
happiness garden channel.
Today I will show you how to make
natural fertilizer that is both simple
and effective.
This fertilizer will help your orchids
grow sustainably and bloom for a longer
time.
[Music]
Now, let's get started.
This orchid has finished blooming. If
not properly cared for, the plant can
become stunted and grow slowly. So,
post-flowering care is very important to
help the plant recover and prepare for
the next blooming cycle.
[Music]
First remove all damaged, rotting or
dried roots.
[Music]
This will allow the orchid to focus its
energy on healthy parts for growth.
This process also helps stimulate the
plant to grow new roots and prepares it
for the next growth cycle.
[Music]
After removing damaged roots, we will
proceed to cut off all unhealthy leaves.
[Music]
Next, cut off the old flower stems so
the plant can focus its energy on
growing new roots and leaves.
[Music]
Old flower stems usually no longer have
the ability to grow and can cause the
plant to waste energy if left attached.
Sprinkle a layer of cinnamon powder onto
the cut areas to disinfect and prevent
infection.
[Music]
Next, leave it overnight without
watering to allow the cuts to heal
completely.
[Music]
Now take one spoonful of cinnamon powder
and add it to a jar to prepare a natural
fertilizer.
[Music]
Mix the cinnamon powder with one liter
of boiling water to create a natural
fertilizer solution.
[Music]
Cover the lid and let it sit overnight
to ensure the nutrients from the
cinnamon powder are fully dissolved in
the water.
[Music]
The second ingredient I use is
breadcrumbs, which are rich in nutrients
and great for the growth of orchids.
[Music]
Mix one liter of warm water with 2 tsp
of breadcrumbs to create a natural
nutrient solution.
[Music]
Let it sit overnight to ensure the
nutrients from the breadcrumbs are fully
dissolved in the water.
[Music]
After one night, strain out the residue
to obtain clean and clear cinnamon
water.
[Music]
Uh, what country are you watching this
video from? Leave a comment to let me
know.
[Music]
It's so wonderful that we can connect
and chat with each other from all over
the world.
[Music]
Step one, use a soft cotton pad soaked
in the cinnamon water and gently wipe
the top and bottom surfaces of the
leaves.
This method helps eliminate fungi,
pests, and harmful insects from the
plant.
[Music]
This method also cleans the leaves,
allowing them to photosynthesize more
effectively, which improves the plant's
overall nutrient exchange.
[Music]
If you haven't subscribed yet, click the
subscribe button to support my channel.
[Music]
Step two, pour this cinnamon water
solution into a spray bottle.
[Music]
Then spray the solution over the entire
orchid to remove dust, mold, and any
pests clinging to the plant.
[Music]
This method also stimulates the plant's
natural resistance, helping it grow
stronger and better withstand diseases.
[Music]
Step three, use a soft cloth to wipe off
any excess water from the leaves to
prevent mold and bacterial growth.
Wiping off water helps the leaves dry
quickly, improving the plant's ability
to photosynthesize and exchange
nutrients.
[Music]
Reduces the risk of the orchid getting
sick due to prolonged damp conditions.
[Music]
Uh, step four, add a thin layer of moss
on the surface of the orchid pot to to
retain moisture and create a better
growing environment for the plant.
[Music]
This moss layer also helps maintain
moisture balance and prevents the plant
from losing water too quickly in dry
conditions.
[Music]
Now I mix the cinnamon water solution
with the breadcrumbs water solution
together.
[Music]
After mixing, we will have a natural
nutrient solution that is excellent for
the growth of orchids.
[Music]
Step five. From now on, water this
mixture on your orchids once every 10
days.
This solution stimulates the growth of
new roots, allowing the plant to absorb
nutrients more effectively.
[Applause]
[Music]
encourages the growth of new shoots and
flowers, allowing the orchid to bloom
for a longer period.
[Music]
After watering, you should soak the
orchid pot in this mixture for about 20
minutes to get the best results.
[Music]
You can use the leftover mixture to
water other regular orchids as well. It
will be very beneficial for their growth
too.
[Music]
Um, this solution is very beneficial,
but you should only water the plant
every 10 to 15 days to avoid
overfeeding.
[Music]
After watering, soak the base of the
orchid pot in this mixture for about 20
minutes.
[Music]
Then take the orchid pot out and place
it in a spot with gentle sunlight to
allow the plant to photosynthesize well,
improving nutrient exchange.
[Music]
Uh keep in mind uh this fertilizer is
very beneficial but without sufficient
sunlight the plant won't be able to
synthesize nutrients effectively.
[Music]
Uh the results after 10 days.
Can you see the new leaves have grown
longer than before, which shows that the
plant is growing very well.
[Music]
New roots have also grown quite a lot,
which will help the orchid recover and
grow vigorously in the coming time.
[Music]
And you can see the leaves have become
stronger and greener, which is a sign
that the orchid is growing healthily.
[Music]
I will continue to water this natural
fertilizer mixture on the plant every 10
days to ensure the orchid grows
sustainably.
[Music]
On regular days, if the potting medium
is dry or the environment is too dry,
you should simply water or mist lightly
to maintain humidity for the orchid.
[Music]
After that, remember to place the pot in
a spot with gentle sunlight to allow the
orchid to photosynthesize effectively.
[Music]
the results after the next 45 days.
You can see that the new leaves have
grown longer and are healthy.
[Music]
And two new flower stocks have emerged,
promising another vibrant blooming
season ahead.
[Music]
Uh the leaves have become stronger and
grown exceptionally well after being
cared for with this natural fertilizer
mixture.
Uh the roots have grown out of the
orchid pot which is a sign that the
orchid is growing very vigorously.
[Music]
And this is the result. After 90 days of
recovery from a pot of orchid that had
finished blooming, the plant has revived
strongly and is now growing two new
vibrant flower spikes. This is a
welldeserved reward for patience and
daily care.
[Music]
Because it was properly cared for, the
plant's root system has grown strong and
produced many new roots. These roots
will continue to spread, anchoring
firmly into the growing medium, creating
a solid foundation to nourish the
blooming and soonto bloom flowers on the
spike.
[Music]
The roots are considered the heart of
the orchid because they are the first
part to absorb water and nutrients from
the environment such as fertilizer and
moisture in in the growing medium
helping to sustain the entire plant. If
the roots are weak or damaged, the plant
will lack nutrients leading to yellowing
leaves, rotting crown, and inability to
bloom.
[Music]
What do you think about the way I
revived this orchid after it finished
blooming? Don't hesitate to leave a
comment and share your thoughts. I'd
love to hear your feedback and
experiences.
[Music]
Thanks to the healthy root system, the
plant not only blooms regularly, but
also develops lush, thick green leaves,
a sign that the orchid is in its best
growing condition.
[Music]
And the most wonderful result is the new
flower buds slowly beginning to open,
promising a brilliant and long-lasting
blooming season.
Each flower bud is like a small gift
from nature, signaling that the plant is
full of vitality.
When properly cared for, the flowers not
only bloom evenly, but also retain their
vibrant color and last longer,
brightening up the space around you.
Every small step of progress from the
plant is the result of devoted care. As
long as you are patient, any orchid will
respond with its own unique beauty.
[Music]
This is why monitoring the condition of
the roots is always important. Uh, when
the roots are healthy, every other part
of the plant will naturally enter a
harmonious growth cycle.
I hope you enjoy this video. If you find
it helpful, don't forget to hit like and
subscribe to the channel so you won't
miss upcoming tips on how to care for
orchids naturally and simply.
[Music]