welcome to this video this is a Dendrobium orchid
a type of orchid that is said to be beautiful
and has a gentle fragrance
in this video I share an easy way to propagate the most
beautiful orchids in the world
um if you haven't subscribed to the channel yet
please subscribe so you don't miss any tips and share
so as many people know
let's get started
I cut this old orchid for propagation
cut again so the cut is flat and will not rot further
applying cinnamon powder to the cut
helps the wound heal quickly and not rot
then wait a day for the cutting to dry completely
before planting the orchid
please comment to me
which country you are watching the video from
it's great that we can chat together
from all over the world
one day later
take 1 aloe Vera leaf and cut it into thin slices
aloe Vera gel is very good at restoring wilted orchids
and reviving baby orchids
then
take 2 cloves of garlic and cut them into thin slices
garlic has antibacterial and antiseptic properties
that help protect orchids from rotting
put garlic and aloe Vera in the jar
and add 500 milliliters of water
the cut is completely dry
soaking in this water for 30 minutes
helps stimulate germination and rooting
recycle used plastic bottles as orchid nursery tools
then
put the dry orchid branches into this plastic bottle
place the bottle here and insert moss around it
to help retain moisture
water regularly to keep the environment moist
this helps the orchid germinate faster
then put it in a cool place
and wait for the orchid to revive
45 days later
with this method after only 45 days old
withered orchid branches have been revived
now I cut them out to plant in pots
I plant with pine bark soaked in antiseptic
to prevent the tree from rotting
adding a little moss helps retain moisture
and protect the roots better
then you water it to keep it moist and take care of it
like other normal orchids
thank you for watching the video
wishing you luck and happiness in life
welcome to my channel
when the last phalenopsis orchids are about to fall
this is the right time to cut branches
to propagate phalenopsis orchids from flower stems
these nodes still contain dormant buds
so they can be used to propagate orchids
from flower spikes
and these nodes have already bloomed
so cut them off
as they can no longer be used for propagation
after that I use a potato
to create a substance that helps propagate orchids
quickly
potatoes contain many substances
necessary for the growth of orchids
I will recycle potato peels into organic fertilizer
pour 1 liter of hot water into the jar
then brew until the water cools
need to peel off the protective film
of the sleeping sprout
this will help the sprouts grow faster
apply potato gel to the sleeping sprouts
this helps stimulate sprout growth
next apply toothpaste on the cut
helps cuts heal faster
wrap with thinly sliced potatoes
this helps moisturize and awaken dormant sprouts
leave for 6 hours
to let the nutrients from the potatoes penetrate inside
take 1 teaspoon of cinnamon powder
add 1 liter of hot water
after the water cools filter to remove sediment
soak terracotta beads and aquaponic resin
beads in cinnamon water solution for 30 minutes
soak the moss in the cinnamon solution for 30 minutes
recycle used boxes into orchid sprouting tools
conduct orchid nursery
spray moisturizer every three days
place in a cool place
when cool filtered remove residue
um watering this liquid fertilizer for orchids
one to two times a month will be very good
the sleeping sprouts have awakened
continue spraying water
and leave in a cool place for the sprouts to grow
after next one month
the sprout has grown leaves
continue spraying water
and leave in a cool place for the sprouts to grow
after the next two month
small orchids grow very quickly
with this simple way
you can propagate orchids at home easily
hope the video will help you a lot
now I will plant it in a pot
so the orchid can grow in the outside environment
uh if you find the video meaningful
please like share and subscribe to support me
so my channel can reach 10 million subscribers soon
then nurture the
orchid with water and organic fertilizer
as I shared on the Happiness Garden Channel
and take care of it
with all the love you have for the plant
in return it will bring you beauty and growth
wishing you success and happiness in life
goodbye and see you in the next video!