Welcome to my channel, a place that
spreads the love for orchids. Today, I
will share a simple method to revive
weak orchids until they recover and
bloom beautifully again.
Uh, if you haven't subscribed to the
channel yet, please hit the subscribe
button to support me and not miss any
orchid growing tips. It's wonderful to
have you with me.
Uh, this is an orchid that has rotted
and usually people throw it away
thinking it can no longer recover.
[Music]
This orchid has had all its upper leaves
rot away, leaving only one small leaf
near the base that is still fresh and
green.
[Music]
Rotting orchids often start from
waterlogged roots which allow fungal
diseases to easily develop and spread
gradually causing the entire plant to
rot.
And this orchid is no exception. It
rotted because the roots had been water
logged for a long time.
To check whether the roots are rotten,
uh simply squeeze them gently. If the
roots feel soft and hollow inside, it's
a sign of rot. On the other hand, if
they are still firm and solid, it means
the roots are healthy.
[Music]
Because many of the roots are water
logged and rotten, the growing medium is
no longer suitable. Therefore, we need
to completely remove the old medium to
prevent the spread of fungal diseases.
[Music]
After removing the growing medium, cut
off all the damaged and rotten roots to
help the plant stay disease-free and
recover more easily.
[Music]
In addition to the English voiceover,
we've also created versions in French,
German, Italian, Spanish, Portuguese,
Japanese, Hindi, Dutch, Polish, Korean,
and Indonesian to help you listen and
understand the content more easily.
[Music]
To hear your preferred language, open
the video and click on settings, the
gear icon, to select the appropriate
audio language.
Leave a comment and let me know which
country you're watching from. It's
wonderful that we can connect and chat
from all around the world.
[Music]
You can see there's a fairly large
dormant bud here. When properly revived,
this bud will grow into a baby orchid,
also known as a kei, emerging from the
mother stem.
[Music]
After cutting off the damaged roots,
rinse the entire orchid with water to
remove any remaining dirt and pathogens.
[Music]
After rinsing, place the orchid in a
well ventilated area to let it dry
completely before the next step.
[Music]
Next, prepare some used coffee grounds.
This simple ingredient is rich in
nutrients, has mild disinfectant
properties, and can stimulate new root
growth, helping the plant recover more
quickly.
Put one spoonful of used coffee grounds
into a clean jar.
[Music]
Then pour in about 500 ml of boiling
water to extract the nutrients from the
coffee grounds.
Stir well. Cover the jar and let the
solution cool completely before use.
[Music]
Once the water has cooled, stir it again
to help the nutrients in the coffee
grounds dissolve more thoroughly into
the water.
Next, strain out the residue to obtain a
clear solution ready to use for the
orchid.
[Music]
Place the orchid in the coffee solution
and soak it for about 20 minutes to
mildly disinfect and stimulate root
growth.
[Music]
After soaking for about 20 minutes,
gently take the orchid out and place it
in another clean cup to continue with
the next recovery steps.
[Music]
The next ingredient I've chosen to make
natural fertilizer is banana. A familiar
fruit that's rich in essential nutrients
for the growth of orchids.
So, you can see this banana is overripe.
Don't worry, even spoiled bananas like
this can still be used to make natural
fertilizer that's great for orchids.
[Music]
Slice one banana into thin pieces so the
nutrients can dissolve more easily when
soaked in water.
[Music]
Uh, place the banana slices into a clean
glass jar to prepare for the next step
of soaking and fermenting.
Next, pour about one liter of warm water
into the jar.
[Music]
Be sure to leave some space in the jar
so that as the solution fermentss, it
has room to expand without overflowing.
[Music]
The final ingredient I need is a bit of
vodka. It helps support the fermentation
process and prevents harmful bacteria
from developing in the solution.
Add about 60 mm of vodka to support the
fermentation process and keep the
solution stable and free from spoilage.
Stir all the ingredients well to allow
them to blend together before
fermenting.
Seal the jar tightly and place it in a
cool, well ventilated area for about 10
days. After this period, you'll have
banana GE solution, a natural fertilizer
that's excellent for orchids.
[Music]
And here is a bottle of banana GE that I
made 10 days ago. Now it's ready to use
for the orchid.
[Music]
Take about 30 mlers of banana GE to
dilute it, preparing it as a fertilizer
to water the orchid.
Well- fermented banana GE will have a
beer-like aroma and a layer of white
foam on top. This indicates the presence
of beneficial microorganisms formed
during the fermentation process.
Then add one liter of clean water to
dilute the banana GE solution before
using it on the orchid.
[Music]
Pour the diluted banana GE solution uh
into a cup and soak the orchid for about
10 minutes to absorb nutrients and
support recovery.
The banana GE mixture not only provides
nutrients but also helps stimulate new
root and cakey growth, supporting a
stronger recovery for the orchid.
[Music]
The remaining diluted coffee and banana
GE solutions can be mixed together to
create a blend for soaking the growing
medium or watering the orchid directly
to supplement nutrients.
[Music]
Place the pine bark into a clean basin.
Then pour in the prepared mixture and
soak it for about 10 minutes to clean
the wing growing medium and add
beneficial microorganisms before
planting the orchid.
[Music]
The remaining mixture can be poured into
a spray bottle for easy care and
spraying on other orchids in the garden.
[Music]
Spraying this mixture on blooming
orchids will help provide extra
nutrients, extend the freshness of the
flowers, and support the plant's overall
health.
Regularly spraying this fertilizer also
helps boost the orchid's resistance,
reduce the risk of fungal attacks, and
improve the plant's ability to adapt to
environmental changes.
[Music]
After soaking for about 10 minutes, take
out the growing medium and get it ready
for the next step, planting the orchid
into the pot.
Prepare a pot with good drainage holes
and a moderate size just enough to fit
the root system snugly. The pot should
not be too large as this can cause water
retention and increase the risk of root
rot.
Uh before planting, you can place a few
small pieces of foam at the bottom of
the pot to improve irerration, support
drainage, and help prevent root rot.
[Music]
After completing all the preparation
steps, gently take the orchid out of the
cup and plant it into a new pot.
Carefully arrange the roots to keep the
plant stable, allowing the roots to grow
well and the plant to recover more
effectively.
[Music]
Um, when planting, slowly add pine bark
around the base of the plant. Gently
press it with your fingers to fill the
gaps between the roots, but don't pack
it too tightly so the roots still have
space to breathe and grow easily.
You can spread a thin layer of moss on
the surface of the pot. This layer helps
retain moisture for the roots and
creates a cooler, more stable
environment for the plant during its
recovery phase.
[Music]
After planting, you can reuse the same
banana GE solution that was used to soak
the orchid and gently water it around
the base.
This helps provide extra nutrients and
supports the plant in adapting morphing
more quickly to its new environment.
[Music]
And then place the orchid pot into a
tray and pour clean water into the tray
just like I'm doing. This method helps
maintain gentle moisture for the roots
from below, creating favorable
conditions for recovery and new root
growth.
Next, place a clear plastic pot over the
orchid pot to create a humid
greenhouse-like environment.
Uh, this helps maintain stable humidity,
supports faster recovery, and stimulates
the growth of new roots and shoots.
Be sure to place the orchid pot in a
cool, wellventilated area with gentle
light, avoiding harsh sunlight. So the
plant can photosynthesize and recover
more quickly.
[Music]
And don't forget to mist the plant
whenever the growing medium starts to
dry out. Maintaining consistent moisture
will help the orchid grow steadily and
encourage uh faster development of new
roots.
[Music]
And here is the result after 2 weeks.
Um you can see the dormant bud has
awakened and is gradually developing
into a baby orchid. A cake growing from
the mother stem.
[Music]
Remember to change the water in the tray
every 1 to 2 weeks to keep it clean,
reduce bacteria, and help the roots grow
strong and healthy.
And don't forget to mist the plant to
maintain moisture whenever the growing
medium starts to dry out, ensuring the
plant always has the necessary humidity
for recovery and growth.
Keep the orchid pot in a spot with
gentle sunlight and good air flow. Um, a
softly lit environment will help the
plant photosynthesize efficiently and
promote faster growth of roots and
keies.
[Music]
And here is the result after 2 months.
You can see that the baby orchid growing
from the mother stem, the kei, has grown
larger with strong, healthy roots and
firm leaves. A promising sign of
recovery.
[Music]
With this simple method, a seemingly
dying, rotting orchid has now revived
and produced a healthy, vibrant baby
orchid. Right from the mother stem,
you can see the roots of the baby orchid
have firmly attached to the growing
medium. This is the perfect time to
start adding natural fertilizer to
support fast, healthy growth and prepare
the plant for its next growth phase.
To to care for the baby orchid during
this stage, I use rice, a familiar and
nutrient-rich ingredient to make natural
fertilizer that helps the plant grow
strong from roots to leaves.
Put one spoonful of rice into about 500
ml of clean water. The rice will release
natural nutrients that nourish the roots
and stimulate the orchid's growth.
[Music]
Stir well to dissolve the nutrients from
the rice into the water, creating a
simple yet nutrient-rich solution for
the orchid.
Water the orchid with this natural
fertilizer mixture about twice a month
to provide consistent nutrients, helping
the plant grow steadily and stay
healthy.
You can also alternate with other
organic fertilizers to provide a variety
of nutrients, helping the orchid grow
more fully and build stronger
resistance.
[Music]
Uh because the young orchid already has
strong roots firmly attached to the
growing medium, you no longer need to
cover it with a clear plastic pot from
now on. Just place the orchid pot
outdoors in a spot with gentle sunlight
and good ventilation. And that will be
enough for the plant to continue growing
well.
And here is the result after 6 months.
You can see that the young orchid
growing from the mother plant has now
developed into a healthy, mature orchid
and has even bloomed with two vibrant
flower spikes. a well-deserved result
for a journey of loving care.
The leaves have also turned dark green
and become firm, a sign that the plant
is growing healthily and steadily.
[Music]
What do you think about this method of
reviving a weak orchid? Feel free to
leave a comment and share your thoughts
with me.
In addition to the English voiceover, we
have also created French, German,
Italian, Spanish, Portuguese, Japanese,
Hindi, Dutch, Polish, Korean, and
Indonesian versions to help you listen
and understand the content more easily.
Um, to listen in your language, open the
video and click on settings, the gear
icon, to select your preferred audio
language.
[Music]
The soft flower spikes rise full of
vitality, bearing vibrant colors like a
sweet gift the orchid offers after its
miraculous recovery journey.
[Music]
If you encounter any difficulties during
the orchid growing process, don't
hesitate to leave a comment. I'm always
here to support you so you can grow
healthy orchids that bloom beautifully.
[Music]
From an orchid that once seemed beyond
saving, with just simple ingredients and
a bit of patience, we have witnessed a
truly miraculous recovery. I hope this
little journey inspires you to love
caring for orchids even more and always
believe that with enough love, the plant
will find its own way to bloom.
Thank you for watching until the end of
the video. I wish you happiness,
patience, and success in your journey of
caring for your beloved orchids. See you
in the next videos. Goodbye.