Welcome to the Happiness Garden channel.
Are you worried because your orchid
looks wilted? Its leaves are wrinkled
and lifeless? Don't give up just yet.
In this video, I will show you how to
revive your orchid right at home with
just a few simple steps and natural
ingredients available in your kitchen.
No need for chemicals, no need for
expensive products. Just a little
patience and love for your plant and
you'll see the magic happen.
In the summer when the weather becomes
hot and the humidity in the air rises,
orchids become very vulnerable.
This is the time when fungal diseases
become active and your orchid is at risk
of root rot or leaf rot if not cared for
properly.
Uh if you encounter this situation,
quickly remove the damaged leaves to
prevent the disease from spreading to
the rest of the plant.
Timely action will give your orchid a
better chance to recover faster.
Waterlogged roots are also one of the
main causes of rot in orchids.
When the roots can't drain properly,
they become soft, darkened, and easily
attacked by bacteria and fungi.
Therefore, we need to check the root
system regularly, especially after heavy
watering or prolonged rainy weather.
Protecting healthy roots is the best way
to keep your orchid thriving.
[Music]
You can see the entire root system has
become hollow inside. This indicates the
roots are dead and can no longer absorb
water or nutrients.
Therefore, I will cut across the orchid
stem and remove all the damaged roots.
The goal is to keep the upper part of
the stem where one green leaf still
remains at the top.
In addition to the English voiceover, we
have now created voiceovers in French,
German, Italian, Spanish, Portuguese,
Japanese, Hindi, Dutch, Polish, Korean,
and Indonesian to help you listen and
understand the content more easily.
To listen in your preferred language,
open the video and click on settings,
the gear icon, to select the appropriate
audio language.
Leave a comment and let me know which
country you're watching from. It's
wonderful that we can connect and chat
from all around the world.
[Music]
We will use this part to help the orchid
recover and start a new journey.
After that, I gently rinse the remaining
stem and leaf with clean water.
This step helps remove bacteria and
fungal spores still clinging to the
surface of the stem, making the recovery
process more effective.
[Music]
To make fertilizer that helps revive the
orchid, the first ingredient I use is an
onion.
Onions have natural antibacterial
properties which help prevent fungal
diseases and stimulate the growth of new
roots.
[Music]
If you haven't subscribed yet, please
hit the subscribe button to support me
and never miss any orchid growing tips.
It's truly wonderful to have you along
on this journey.
[Music]
I make use of onion peels by placing
them in a jar to create a recovery
fertilizer for the orchid.
Because onion peels contain many
nutrients, especially antioxidants and
natural sulfur, they help fight bacteria
and stimulate root growth. This is a
simple, effective, and very economical
method.
After that, I add the onion peels to
about one liter of boiling water.
The high temperature helps extract the
nutrients from the onion peels, creating
a natural solution that helps the orchid
recover quickly and safely.
Then I cover the lid and let the water
cool completely.
This allows the essence from the onion
peels to infuse into the water, creating
a natural nourishing solution for the
orchid.
[Music]
The next ingredient I need is rice.
Rice is rich in B vitamins and natural
minerals which are excellent for
stimulating root growth and helping the
plant recover more strongly.
[Music]
I take about 3 teaspoon of rice then add
it to 500 ml of room temperature water.
Soak the rice for a few hours to let the
nutrients release into the water,
creating a natural and safe root
boosting solution.
[Music]
After 2 hours of soaking, we gently stir
the rice water. This helps the nutrients
from the rice dissolve uh better into
the water, increasing its effectiveness
as a fertilizer for the orchid.
[Music]
After that, we strain out the remaining
residue. Only keep the clear rice water
to use as a root nourishing solution for
the orchid.
[Music]
The filtered rice water is gentle and
safe for the plant, helping the orchid
absorb nutrients easily.
[Music]
Once the onion water has cooled, we
strain out the onion peel residue. Only
keep the clear water which contains many
natural nutrients beneficial for the
plant.
After that, I mix this onion water with
the filtered rice water to create a
blended fertilizer solution, which is
excellent for reviving and stimulating
the orchid's growth.
[Music]
Step one, use a soft cloth and gently
soak it in the prepared fertilizer
mixture.
Then gently wipe it over the surface of
the orchid leaves.
This helps the leaves absorb nutrients
directly while also cleaning off dust
and preventing fungal diseases.
[Music]
Onions have antibacterial properties
which help eliminate bacteria and mold
on the leaf surface. This prevents the
disease from spreading and creates a
clean environment for the plant to
recover.
[Music]
When the leaves are clean, the stamata
stay clear, allowing the plant to absorb
water and nutrients from the environment
more easily. Rice water rich in B
vitamins also helps the leaves become
brighter and healthier, supporting the
recovery process from the top of the
plant.
[Music]
Step two, pour the mixture into a clean
glass or jar. Then soak the orchid stem
in the solution for about 20 minutes.
The mixture contains many nutrients like
sulfur from the onion and B vitamins
from the rice water which help stimulate
root cell activity and support the rapid
formation of new roots.
Onions have natural antibacterial
properties which help cleanse the base
of the plant and and prevent bacteria
and mold from invading.
The remaining mixture can be used to
water other healthy orchid pots in the
garden.
Uh the nutrient-rich mixture helps
orchid roots grow vigorously, enhancing
their ability to absorb water and
nutrients from the growing medium.
[Music]
The essence from onions has strong
antibacterial properties, helping
prevent fungal diseases and boosting the
plant's natural immunity.
Rice water contains B vitamins and
minerals that help the leaves become
smoother, thicker, and shinier over
time.
When the roots and leaves are healthy,
the orchid will accumulate enough
energy, getting ready for the budding
process and blooming more beautifully.
You can apply this method to your orchid
twice a month,
or you can put the mixture into a spray
bottle and use it to mist other orchid
pots in your garden.
[Music]
Uh you spray evenly and gently over the
entire leaf surface, especially on the
underside of the leaves where pests
often reside.
Avoid spraying too much water to prevent
water logging and creating an
environment for fungi to grow. Repeat
spraying regularly every 2 weeks or as
needed by the plant.
When the leaves are evenly misted, they
absorb nutrients faster, helping the
plant grow well from leaves to roots.
The mixture has natural antibacterial
properties, helping remove dust and
bacteria from the leaf surface, keeping
the leaves clean and healthy.
After spraying, it's best to gently dab
the water droplets on the leaves with a
soft cloth, especially in the leaf
crevices.
[Music]
This helps prevent excessive moisture,
avoiding conditions that promote fungal
growth.
[Music]
Uh to speed up the recovery process, I
reuse a plastic cup as a tool for
propagating the orchid.
[Music]
Recycling not only saves costs, but also
helps protect the environment and
provides a convenient space for the
plant to recover in a compact setup.
[Music]
After soaking for about 20 minutes, I
gently take the orchid out of the
solution.
Next, use a soft cloth to dry the stem
and leaves, helping the plant stay clean
and airy, ready for the next step in the
recovery process.
You need to prepare a clean support
stick
and you also need to prepare a clean
soft piece of cloth.
And now let's take a close look at each
step and follow along with how I do it.
[Music]
After that, place the orchid already
secured with the support stick into the
clear cup you've prepared.
[Music]
After that, pour clean water into the
cup, making sure the water level just
barely touches the orchid stem.
[Music]
This helps prevent the base of the plant
from becoming water logged while still
providing enough moisture to safely
stimulate the growth of new roots.
[Music]
After that, cover the cup with the
prepared lid that has ventilation holes
to retain moisture, giving the orchid an
ideal recovery environment. Humid
enough, but not suffocating.
[Music]
Uh, place it in a cool, well ventilated
spot with sufficient light for the
orchid to recover, avoiding direct
sunlight so the plant can regenerate
energy and slowly grow new roots and
leaves.
[Music]
And here is the result after 3 weeks.
Let's take a look together.
[Music]
You can see the orchid has started
growing new roots slowly reaching out in
search of life.
[Music]
What do you think of the way I revived
this little orchid? Feel free to leave a
comment and share your thoughts. I'd
love to hear your feedback and
experiences.
Remember
to change the water once a week to keep
the environment clean and reduce harmful
bacteria for the orchid.
[Music]
I continue to propagate the orchid in
the prepared growing cup, ensuring
proper humidity and light conditions so
the plant can keep developing new roots
and leaves.
In addition to the English voice over,
we have now created versions in French,
German, Italian, Spanish, Portuguese,
Japanese, Hindi, Dutch, Polish, Korean,
and Indonesian to help you listen and
understand the content more easily.
To listen in your preferred language,
open the video and click on settings,
the gear icon, to select the appropriate
audio language.
[Music]
Continue to place the growing cup in a
cool, well ventilated area with gentle
light to help the orchid recover.
quickly and grow steadily.
[Music]
And here is the result after 6 weeks.
[Laughter]
[Music]
You can see the orchid has grown many
more healthy roots thanks to the idea
humid environment and consistent care.
The plant is gradually coming back to
life beautifully.
[Music]
And the orchid has even grown a new
leaf. This shows that the plant is
recovering well and is ready to enter
the next stage of growth.
[Music]
Once the orchid has developed a healthy
root system and firm green leaves, we
can plant it in a pot so it can continue
growing in an outdoor environment. This
helps the plant gradually adapt to
natural conditions and get ready for the
next blooming season.
[Music]
Choose a medium-sized pot that fits the
size of the orchid and most importantly
has drainage holes. This helps prevent
water logging that can cause root rot
and provides a well ventilated
environment for healthy growth.
[Music]
At the bottom of the pot, I add a layer
of foam to improve ventilation and
drainage. I also use the foam to anchor
the support stick, helping to keep the
orchid upright and stable as it grows in
its new pot.
[Music]
The growing medium I use is finely
chopped pine bark that has been
carefully treated and sterilized. It
helps reduce fungal diseases and
provides a well ventilated, moisture
retaining environment for healthy orchid
root development.
[Music]
Place the orchid in the center of the
pot, gently guiding the roots downward.
[Music]
Add the pine bark medium around the
roots, gently shaking the pot so the
bark fills all the gaps.
[Music]
Keep the base of the orchid slightly
above the surface of the medium. This
prevents me this prevents water logging.
And don't pack the medium too tightly so
the roots can breathe and grow freely.
Gently tie the orchid stem to the
support stick placed in the pot to keep
the plant stable.
[Music]
After repotting, take care of your
orchid consistently by misting the
medium and leaves to maintain moisture.
Avoid overwatering to prevent root rot.
After about 1 to two weeks, once the
plant has adapted, you can start
applying a mild fertilizer to encourage
healthy root and leaf growth.
[Music]
As long as you stay patient and care for
each orchid with love everyday, little
by little, you'll grow a stunning orchid
garden filled with vibrant blooms all
year round.
I hope you enjoyed this video. If you
found it helpful, don't forget to give
it a like and subscribe to the channel
so you won't miss the next natural and
simple orchid care tips.
Thank you for watching the video until
the end. Wishing you good health,
happiness, and lots of orchids blooming
beautifully all year round. See you in
the next video.
[Music]