Welcome to the place where the beauty of
nature touches your everyday.
If you want your orchids to bloom
beautifully and stay healthy, in this
video I will share how to care for
orchids using natural fertilizers that
you can make right in your own kitchen.
Your orchid will produce many new flower
spikes on the same plant with strong,
dense roots that grip firmly.
The petals will be vibrant, fresh, and
spread their fragrance throughout the
space, bringing a sense of peace and
happiness to everyone around.
Do you have tofu? Tofu contains a lot of
protein and natural minerals, helping
orchids grow healthier and stronger.
Just about 10 g of tofu is enough to
provide nutrients for the orchid.
Put into a cup of water and blend the
tofu until smooth.
[Music]
[Applause]
strain out the residue to get a smooth
solution.
Then dilute the fertilizer mixture with
about 12 cups of water to make a
moderate orchid watering solution.
Uh remember to dilute the solution
before watering the orchid. If the
solution is too concentrated, the
orchid's roots may be damaged and uh the
plant will have difficulty absorbing
nutrients.
Method one, water this mixture directly
onto the roots and the plant's medium.
This method helps the nutrients
penetrate deeply into the roots,
stimulating the orchid to grow healthily
and produce many new flower spikes.
Watering this mixture helps improve the
overall health of the orchid. The leaves
will be lush and strong. And this method
also prevents yellowing or wilting
caused by nutrient deficiency.
[Music]
The mixture also stimulates roots to
grow strong, dense, and firmly attached
to the medium, allowing the plant to
absorb water and nutrients more
effectively, contributing to consistent
flowering.
[Music]
Please comment and let me know which
country you are watching this video
from. It's wonderful that we can connect
and chat together from all around the
world.
[Music]
Um, if you haven't subscribed to the
channel yet, please hit the subscribe
button to support me and not miss any
orchid growing tips. It's wonderful to
have you along for the journey.
[Music]
Uh, you can soak this type of fertilizer
for about 10 to 20 minutes. This method
helps the plant's roots absorb maximum
nutrients and grow healthier.
Method two, put the mixture into a spray
bottle and evenly mist the entire
orchid. This method helps the leaves
absorb nutrients, the plant grow
vigorously, and the flowers stay fresh
longer.
Spraying the mixture helps the orchid
leaves directly absorb essential
nutrients, allowing the plant to grow
healthy and better resist pests and
diseases.
[Music]
Spraying the mixture also creates a
natural protective layer on the leaf
surface, preventing yellowing, wilting,
or drying caused by nutrient deficiency.
[Music]
Spraying the mixture also helps enhance
the plant's metabolism, promoting even
growth of roots, leaves, and flowers,
resulting in an overall healthy and
vibrant appearance.
[Music]
And now I will share the second method
to make fertilizer from tofu, allowing
you to store it longer and use it when
needed.
[Music]
This time you need about 20 g of tofu to
prepare the fertilizer mixture.
[Music]
Put it into a cup of water, then blend
it together with the tofu until smooth.
[Music]
Then pour the mixture into a clean
bottle. to prepare for fermentation.
[Music]
Remember to leave some space at the top.
This ensures the fermentation process
occurs safely, preventing overflow or
pressure buildup in the bottle.
Then add 1 teasp of yeast to the
mixture. You can also use dry baking
yeast as a substitute if you like.
[Music]
Then add 3 tsp of brown sugar to the
mixture. This helps the fermentation
process occur faster and prevents the
mixture from spoiling as the sugar
provides food for the yeast to work
effectively.
Stir the mixture well so that all the
ingredients are fully combined and the
yeast can work effectively.
Next, close the bottle and leave it in a
cool ventilated place for about 1 month
for the mixture to ferment completely.
[Music]
And here is the bottle I have fermented
for 1 month. Now the mixture is ready to
be diluted into a nutrient solution and
used to water the orchids.
[Music]
I take about 3 tablespoons of the
fermented mixture to prepare a nutrient
solution for the orchids.
[Music]
Then dilute the fertilizer mixture with
about 12 cups of water to make a
moderate orchid watering solution.
Method one, use a soft cloth to soak up
the mixture and gently wipe both the top
and bottom surfaces of the orchid
leaves.
[Music]
Wiping the leaves helps the nutrients
penetrate directly into the leaves,
supporting photosynthesis and enhancing
the plant's vitality.
This method also cleans dust from the
leaves, prevents mold and pests, and
keeps the orchid healthy.
Additionally, wiping the leaves evenly
makes them glossy and strong, improves
their ability to absorb light, and
contributes to more vibrant flowering.
[Music]
Um, if you do this one to two times a
month, the orchid leaves will always be
glossy and disease-free, helping the
plant grow healthy.
Method two, water the diluted fertilizer
mixture directly onto the orchid's roots
and growing medium.
[Music]
Method two, water the diluted fertilizer
mixture directly onto the orchid's roots
and growing medium.
When fermented, tofu becomes a
nutrient-rich organic fertilizer, ready
to nourish the orchid.
This is a natural source of nutrients
that helps orchids grow healthy, develop
strong roots, and bloom for a long time.
[Music]
For orchids that are currently blooming,
watering with this fertilizer mixture
helps the flowers last longer, maintain
vibrant colors, and keeps the plant
healthy.
[Music]
And here is the result after 1 month of
care. You can see many new roots growing
strong and firmly attached to the
medium.
These new roots will help the plant
absorb nutrients better, grow healthy,
and produce more beautiful flowers in
the next season.
And with strong roots, the orchid will
be better able to resist pests,
maintaining stable and sustainable
growth over time.
[Music]
This type of fertilizer also helps the
orchid produce many new flower spikes on
the same plant.
[Music]
And here is the result after the next 2
months. You can see up to six flower
spikes about to form buds on the same
orchid.
[Music]
With an orchid that has so many flower
spikes, it will bring a vibrant and
long-lasting bloom season while also
enlivening the surrounding space.
With an orchid that has so many flower
spikes, it will bring a vibrant and
long-lasting bloom season while also
enlivening the surrounding space.
The blooming flowers not only make the
plant more beautiful but also bring joy
and a sense of relaxation to everyone
around.
How do you think my orchids have fared
uh using natural fertilizer made from
tofu?
Don't hesitate to leave a comment and
share your thoughts. I'm really looking
forward to hearing your feedback and
experiences.
When you care for your orchid with love
and dedication, the plant will respond
with vibrant flowers, strong roots, and
balanced growth, creating a living space
full of vitality.
[Music]
I hope you enjoy this video. If you find
it helpful, don't forget to like and
subscribe to the channel so you won't
miss future tips on caring for orchids
naturally and easily.
Thank you for watching. Wishing you many
relaxing moments in your orchid garden
and the joy of enjoying the vibrant
beauty of the flowers.