Hello friends.
[Music]
Uh when you plant a lot of orchids, you
will not be able to avoid rotten
orchids.
You see, my orchid has been infected
with a fungus.
[Music]
If not treated promptly, the orchid may
die.
[Music]
Leave a comment to let me know which
country you're watching the video from.
It's wonderful that we can connect and
chat with each other from all around the
world.
Even though it's rotten, it's still
fresh when cut across.
[Music]
It is also a favorable condition for the
spread to respawn faster.
[Music]
We need to cut off the branches and
remove all the rot.
[Music]
Then rinse with water.
Take one cup of room temperature water
about 300 ml.
[Music]
Mix one tablespoon of unsweetened fresh
milk into the water.
[Music]
Add one vitamin B1 tablet.
Then wipe the top and bottom of the
leaves.
[Music]
This water mixture has a disinfecting
effect.
Helps get rid of fungal diseases.
[Music]
Then use this mixture of water, B1, and
milk to soak the orchid root for 20
minutes.
[Music]
If you haven't subscribed to the channel
yet, please hit the subscribe button to
support me and not miss any orchid
growing tips. It's wonderful to have you
along on this journey.
The rest is used to spray other normal
orchids.
[Music]
helps get rid of a fungal diseases and
supplement necessary nutrients for
orchids.
[Music]
After soaking for 20 minutes, take out
the branches and dry the cut.
[Music]
Use toothpaste. Applying it on a cut
will help it heal faster and protect
orchids from rot.
[Music]
While waiting for it to dry, I recycle
old plastic. containers to make tools to
revive orchids.
[Music]
Uh, use industrial cotton to put it in
the pot.
[Music]
Then let the orchid in.
Next, every 3 days, spray moisturizing
mist with normal water.
[Music]
Then put the orchid pot in a cool place.
The most suitable temperature for
reviving orchids is from 20 to 30° C.
1 month later,
[Music]
the orchid has rooted very well. Like
and grow one more young leaf.
B1 stimulates rooting very well.
[Music]
Milk contains natural calcium to help
orchids stay strong and increase
resistance.
[Music]
What do you think about the way I
revived my weak orchid? Please leave a
comment and share your thoughts with me.
[Music]
Now I grow orchids in pots with moss so
that it adapts to the outside
environment.
[Music]
If you find it interesting, please like,
share and subscribe to support my
channel.
Wish you all success and happiness in
life.
See you in the next videos.
The roots are likened to the soul of the
orchid.
Orchids grow healthy thanks to healthy
roots.
Um, if the roots are healthy, the orchid
will also grow many flower buds.
[Music]
In this video, I will show you how to
make orchids grow roots and flower buds
quickly.
[Music]
You need one fresh ginger, about 50 g.
Cut ginger into small pieces.
[Music]
Please comment to me which country you
are watching the video from. It's great
that we can chat together from all over
the world.
[Music]
Put in a jar. recommended plastic jar.
Add 3 tablesp of sugar. Any sugar will
do.
Add in 100 ml of filtered water.
[Music]
Add in 100 milllers of beer. Any beer is
fine.
[Music]
Um, leave a comment to let me know which
country you're watching the video from.
Um, it's amazing that we can chat with
each other from all around the world.
Cover and keep in a dark place for 1
month.
Open the lid once every 3 days to let
the gas out.
[Music]
One month later,
uh, the smell of GE ginger is fermented,
so it's very fragrant.
[Music]
The ratio of mixing is 3 ml of G ginger
for one liter of water.
[Music]
If you haven't subscribe to the channel
yet, please click the subscribe button
to support me and not miss any orchid
growing tips. It's great to have
company.
[Music]
First way,
soak cotton balls in water mixed with
ginger. G E.
[Music]
Place cotton balls soaked in GE ginger
between the leaves.
Helps keep moisture and GE ginger
stimulates rooting and flower sprout
differentiation very quickly.
Change this cotton once every 3 days.
[Music]
On normal days when the cotton is dry,
you just need to mist it with water to
keep it moist.
[Music]
Use this water to wash the top and
bottom of the leaves. Helps provide
nutrients through leaves, clean stamata,
eliminate harmful insects and fungi, and
help orchid photosynthesis the best.
[Music]
Wipe the orchid leaves with GE ginger
once a month so that orchids are best
protected and developed.
[Music]
way three.
Use GE ginger water to water orchids.
[Music]
Uh yeast brewed from fresh ginger has
the effect of stimulating sprouting,
strong rooting, repelling insects,
killing fungi, stimulating buds, and
stimulating growth.
GE ginger also helps orchids increase
their ability to absorb nutrients from
the fertilizer you fertilize them.
Only do this one to two times a month.
Do not use too much as it will affect
the growth of orchids.
[Music]
See the results.
After one week of use, new roots grow
very quickly.
[Music]
These roots will help the orchid absorb
nutrients more easily and more.
Orchids grow well or not thanks to the
photosynthesis of roots and leaves.
[Music]
How effective do you think my natural
orchid fertilizing method is? Please
leave a comment and share your thoughts
with me.
[Music]
If you find the content helpful and
meaningful, don't forget to like, share
so more people can know and know about
it and subscribe to support me.
Thank you for always being with me.
[Music]
When the orchid is healthy, after the
orchid branch blooms, the last flowers,
then there will be new flowers that
flowers that will continue to grow.
[Music]
My video features voiceovers in six
languages: English, French, German,
Spanish, Portuguese, and Italian.
Additionally, I have subtitles in
various other languages around the world
for you to choose from.
[Music]
With this simple way, you can do it
yourself to take care of orchids at home
at very low cost and convenience.
[Music]
Uh, hope the video content will help you
take better care of orchids at home.
Thank you for watching the video.
Wishing everyone good luck and an
abundance of love.