Hello everyone. Very happy to see you
again on the happiness garden channel.
Today I will share more tips for caring
for orchids at home using natural
methods helping you have more options to
nurture your plants. With these methods,
your orchids will bloom all year round
with large petals and vibrant colors.
while the plants will also grow strongly
with many new roots, firm leaves and
stems, and a lush green appearance full
of vitality.
And if you haven't subscribed to the
channel, please click the subscribe
button to support me and not miss any
orchid growing tips. It's wonderful to
have you along.
Let's get started.
To make this type of fertilizer, I will
use lemon. Lemon is very rich in
vitamins and minerals, so I always
choose it when caring for orchids,
helping the plants grow healthy with
lush green leaves and blooms all year
round.
[Music]
Leave a comment to let me know which
country you're watching from. It's
wonderful that we can chat with each
other from all around the world.
[Music]
I will take the peel of a lemon and cut
it into small slices.
Lemon peel contains many important
nutrients such as vitamin C, potassium,
and calcium, helping orchids grow
healthy and boost their resistance.
In addition to the English voiceover, we
have now created French, German,
Italian, Spanish, Portuguese, Japanese,
Hindi, Dutch, Polish, Korean, and
Indonesian voiceovers to help you listen
and understand the content more easily.
To listen in your language, open the
video and click on settings, the gear
icon, to select the appropriate audio
language.
[Music]
Then I put the lemon peel into a clean
jar and pour in about 4 cups of room
temperature water, equivalent to about
one liter. This is an important step to
extract the nutrients from the lemon
peel, helping the natural fertilizer
work at its maximum effectiveness for
the orchids.
After pouring the water, I seal the jar
tightly and let it sit for 2 hours so
the nutrients from the lemon peel can
fully infuse into the water.
This is my lovely companion. How about
you? Do you have any pets?
[Music]
Two hours later, I gently stir the jar
to fully dissolve the valuable nutrients
from the lemon peel, creating a solution
rich in vitamins and minerals.
[Music]
Then I strain out the clear liquid and
prepare for the next step. Ready to
create a nutrient-rich natural
fertilizer for the orchids.
[Music]
Next, we will use baking soda. I will
take one spoon of baking soda and mix it
with the strained lemon peel solution,
creating a nutrient-rich mixture for the
orchids.
Baking soda is a wonderful ingredient
providing many benefits when caring for
orchids, helping the plants stay
healthy, preventing fungal diseases, and
supporting long-lasting blooms.
[Music]
Then I add about four cups of water,
equivalent to about one liter, to the
baking soda and lemon water mixture, uh,
creating a nutrient-rich natural
fertilizer solution ready to help the
orchids grow healthy.
[Music]
Uh when caring for orchids, you should
regularly monitor the roots. Uh when you
see the roots turn white and the medium
is dry, that's when we need to water to
keep the orchids healthy and growing
well.
[Music]
Now, I will evenly water this mixture
onto each orchid pot, helping the plants
absorb all the nutrients, grow healthy,
and bloom beautifully.
[Music]
Lemon peel contains mild acidity and
natural essential oils, helping to
adjust the pH of the growing medium,
creating an ideal environment for
orchids to grow healthy, absorb
nutrients optimally, and bloom
beautifully.
[Music]
Baking soda helps adjust the pH of the
growing medium, creating a slightly
alkaline environment that is very
beneficial for orchid growth, helping
the roots stay healthy and absorb
nutrients better.
[Music]
I do this about one to two times a
month, just enough for the orchids to
receive the necessary nutrients without
being overloaded.
The compounds in lemon peel have
antibacterial and antifungal properties,
helping protect orchids from diseases,
keeping their roots, stems, and leaves
healthy.
[Music]
Baking soda contains sodium and
bicarbonate, providing some important
minerals that help orchids grow healthy
with strong roots and better nutrient
absorption.
After watering, you can soak the entire
orchid pot in this mixture for about 20
minutes. This method helps the roots
absorb maximum nutrients while
preventing root rot, keeping the orchids
healthy and full of vitality.
[Music]
Step two, I will pour this solution into
a spray bottle. This is the preparation
step to easily spray the nutrients
evenly onto the orchids, helping the
leaves and flowers absorb them better.
[Music]
After putting it into the spray bottle,
you can spray the solution directly onto
the leaves, stems, and growing medium of
the orchids. This helps the plants
absorb nutrients quickly while also
protecting them from fungal diseases and
keeping the leaves glossy and healthy.
The compounds in lemon peel have
antibacterial and antifungal properties
combined with the mild alkalinity of
baking soda, helping prevent fungal
diseases, protect the leaves and roots,
and keep the orchids healthy.
Spraying this mixture helps balance the
pH on the surface of the leaves and
growing medium, creating a favorable
environment for the roots to absorb
nutrients better while promoting healthy
plant growth.
When spraying this mixture onto the
leaves and flowers, the orchids can
directly absorb the vitamins and
minerals from the lemon peel and baking
soda. This helps the leaves stay glossy,
the flowers last longer, and the petals
become more vibrant.
Um, regularly spraying this mixture
helps the orchids increase their
resistance, reduce the risk of root rot,
leaf wilting, or common diseases,
keeping the plants full of vitality and
ready to bloom consistently.
I spray this mixture about one to two
times a month, which helps the plants
absorb enough nutrients while avoiding
making the leaves too wet.
However, you should not spray directly
on the flowers. When the flowers get
wet, the petals will wilt and fall
quickly, reducing the blooming time and
the beauty of the orchid pot.
[Music]
Step three, use a soft cloth to soak up
the solution and gently wipe both the
top and underside of the leaves.
You may notice some black spots on the
leaves, which are mold. When orchids are
planted densely, they are prone to black
mold. Wiping the leaves with this
mixture a few times will gradually
reduce and eventually completely remove
the mold, keeping the leaves clean and
healthy.
[Music]
In addition, this method also helps
quickly remove white powdery spots on
the leaves. At the same time, wiping the
leaves with the mixture also removes
dust, creating conditions for the plant
to photosynthesize more effectively,
keeping the orchids green, healthy, and
growing well.
[Music]
Using baking soda helps orchids increase
their resistance, grow healthy with
lush, firm leaves ready to withstand
harmful agents.
[Music]
The black mold spots on the leaves will
not disappear immediately, but after a
few applications of this method, they
will gradually disappear completely,
restoring clean and healthy leaves for
the orchids.
The the essential oils from lemon peel
also help repel some types of insects,
protecting the orchids from pests and
keeping the leaves, stems, and flowers
healthy.
Uh the compounds in lemon peel have
antibacterial and antifungal properties,
helping protect orchids from diseases,
keeping the leaves, stems, and roots
healthy.
[Music]
Thanks to these properties, using the
lemon and baking soda mixture not only
provides nutrients, but also prevents
fungal diseases, helping the orchids
grow comprehensively from roots to
leaves and flowers.
With this care method, you will see the
orchids grow healthy, produce many
roots, have glossy green leaves, and
bloom evenly, lasting throughout the
year.
[Music]
Do not underestimate natural
fertilizers. They are as effective as
synthetic mineral fertilizers, but safer
for the plants and the environment.
Initially, the plants may grow more
slowly compared to inorganic
fertilizers, but once the nutrients are
fully absorbed, they will grow
sustainably healthy and longlasting.
Do this one to two times a month to help
protect the orchids, keeping them
healthy and growing sustainably.
On my channel, I share many great ways
for you to make natural fertilizers
yourself, helping you care for orchids
at home effectively and safely. Give
them a try and see the remarkable change
in your plants.
[Music]
After soaking for about 20 minutes,
gently lift the orchid pot out and place
it in a spot with diffused light so the
plant can continue photosynthesizing and
recover in the best way.
Uh remember that no matter how well you
fertilize, if the orchids do not receive
enough light, they will still be
stunted, have yellowing leaves, and
struggle to bloom. Light is the key
factor that helps the plants
photosynthesize and grow healthy.
Sunlight helps orchids carry out
photosynthesis, thereby converting the
nutrients in the fertilizer into the
energy needed for the plant's growth.
Thanks to light, the plant can absorb
and use the nutrients we provide to the
fullest.
[Music]
With just natural, easy to find
ingredients, caring for orchids becomes
simple, safe, and still incredibly
effective. Be patient in applying this
and you will get to admire lush, vibrant
orchids blooming beautifully right in
your own home.
Uh, I hope this video will be truly
helpful and make it easier for you to
care for orchids at home, keeping them
healthy and blooming beautifully.
If you find the content helpful and
meaningful, don't forget to like, share
so more people can know about it and
subscribe to support me. Thank you for
always being with me.
Thank you for watching today's video.
Wishing you joy, happiness, and many
healthy orchid pots blooming beautifully
all year round. See you again in the
next video.