Welcome to Happiness Garden, the place
that brings joy and relaxation to your
soul.
If you want to take care of orchids at
home so that the plants are always
healthy and the flowers bloom
abundantly, lasting long on the stem
before wilting, please watch this video
until the end.
In this video, I will share a new
organic fertilizer made from ingredients
easily found in your kitchen, helping
new roots and flower buds grow strong
and continuously.
If you are just starting out, don't
forget to subscribe to the channel so
you won't miss any great tips on how to
grow and care for orchids.
[Music]
This is dried bay leaf, an ingredient
you can easily find at supermarkets or
on e-commerce websites.
You use 10 bay leaves, then crush or cut
them into small pieces for use.
In addition to English voiceover, we
have now created voiceovers in French,
German, Italian, Spanish, Japanese,
Hindi, Dutch, Polish, Korean, and
Indonesian to help you listen to and
understand the content easily. To listen
to the language, open the video and
click on settings, the gear icon to
select the appropriate audio language.
[Music]
Next, add 500 ml of boiled water to the
mixture.
[Music]
Please comment and let me know which
country you are watching the video from.
It's wonderful that we can connect and
chat together from all around the world.
[Music]
Cover the lid and let the mixture
ferment until the water is completely
cool.
Next, we will move on to the ingredient
rice.
Take 3 tablesp of rice. Then soak them
in 500 ml of room temperature water.
[Music]
Cover the lid and leave it undisturbed
for 1 hour.
[Music]
After the water cools, strain out the
sediment and then mix the rice rinse
water with the soaked bay leaf water to
create an effective natural fertilizer
mixture.
[Music]
Add one liter of clean water to dilute
the fertilizer mixture.
[Music]
Method one, you directly water this
mixture onto the roots and growing
medium to help the plant absorb
nutrients better.
Um, when you water this mixture onto the
roots and growing medium, the organic
nutrients from the rice and bay leaves
will help stimulate strong root
development.
The orchid roots will become healthier,
denser, and more capable of absorbing
nutrients effectively, thereby helping
the plant grow comprehensively and
sustainably.
[Music]
The mixture also helps enhance the
ability to resist harmful fungi and
bacteria thanks to the natural
antibacterial compounds found in bay
leaves. This helps the orchid avoid many
common diseases, keeping the plant
healthy and maintaining the beauty of
the flowers for a longer time.
[Music]
Apply this mixture one to two times a
month to provide essential nutrients
while also helping protect the orchid
from pests and harsh environments.
This will keep the orchid healthy,
promote good growth, and produce more
vibrant blooms each season.
[Music]
After watering, you should leave the
orchid pot and soak the roots in this
mixture for about 20 minutes. This
method helps the nutrients penetrate
deeply into the roots, increasing
nourishment efficiency and stimulating
strong growth of the orchid.
[Music]
Method two, you put this fertilizer
mixture into a spray bottle to easily
mist the leaves and stems of the orchid,
helping provide nutrients directly and
supporting the photosynthesis process
more effectively.
[Music]
Spray thoroughly on both the top and
underside of the leaves to ensure the
nutrients penetrate evenly and help the
leaves absorb them optimally, thereby
enhancing the health and overall growth
of the orchid.
[Music]
It is best to spray one to two times a
month, preferably in the morning. This
way, by noon, when the sunlight hits,
the leaves will be dry with no water
droplets remaining, helping to prevent
fungal diseases and keep the plant
healthy.
When spraying the mixture onto the
leaves, the nutrients are absorbed
directly through the leaf surface,
helping to quickly and effectively boost
nutrition. This supports the
photosynthesis process, making the
orchid leaves lush green and healthier.
[Music]
The mixture also creates a thin
protective film on the leaf surface,
helping to prevent the invasion of pests
and harmful bacteria. Thanks to this,
the orchid can better withstand harsh
environmental conditions.
[Music]
Uh, when the orchid roots turn pale
silver, it's time to water the orchid.
[Music]
Regularly spraying the mixture helps
maintain the necessary moisture on the
leaf surface, preventing the leaves from
drying out and wilting. This not only
protects the leaves, but also helps the
orchid maintain its fresh color and
long-lasting vitality.
After watering, the roots will turn
green, a sign that the plant has
absorbed enough moisture to grow
healthily.
[Music]
Method three, use a soft cloth or cotton
ball soaked in this mixture. Then gently
wipe thoroughly both the top and
underside of the leaves.
This method helps clean dust while
directly providing nutrients, keeping
the orchid leaves fresh, healthy, and
shiny.
[Music]
You should wipe the leaves at least once
a month to keep them clean, well
ventilated, and better able to absorb
nutrients, helping the orchid grow
healthier, and more vibrant.
[Music]
Um, wipe thoroughly both the top and
underside of the leaves to remove dust
while also helping eliminate insects and
fungi that could harm the orchid,
keeping the plant healthy and growing
well.
Uh, when the leaves are clean, the
stomata open more easily, helping the
plant carry out photosynthesis more
efficiently and grow healthier.
[Music]
This method not only helps clean dust
off the leaves, but also provides
nutrients directly through the leaf
surface, similar to fertilizing the
orchid via its leaves, helping the plant
absorb quickly and grow better.
[Music]
This is a red spidermite egg cluster.
You need to clean it up immediately
before they hatch into tiny mites that
harm the orchid.
[Music]
Never underestimate natural fertilizers.
They deliver effects similar to
synthetic mineral compounds, but are
safer for the plants and the surrounding
environment.
[Music]
Natural fertilizers need time to take
effect, helping plants grow sustainably
and maintain long-lasting vitality.
[Music]
After soaking for 20 minutes, gently
take the orchid pot out of the mixture
to continue normal care.
After fertilizing the plant, I place the
orchid in a spot with gentle sunlight to
help it photosynthesize effectively.
No matter how good the fertilizer is,
without enough light, the orchid will
grow slowly and won't reach its optimal
health.
And here's the result. After 3 weeks of
care with this natural fertilizer,
you can easily see the strong growth of
healthy new roots, which proves that the
care method and natural fertilizer are
clearly effective for the orchid.
[Music]
When the root system is healthy, the
orchid will absorb nutrients through the
roots in the best and fastest way,
supporting the plant's overall
development.
[Music]
How do you think my care for the small
orchids in my garden is going? Don't
hesitate to leave a comment and share
your opinion. I'm really eager to hear
your feedback and experiences.
[Music]
If you encounter any difficulties during
the orchid growing process, don't
hesitate to comment for me. I am always
ready to support you so that you can
grow healthy orchids that bloom
abundantly.
[Music]
Uh this type of fertilizer not only
provides nutrients but also protects the
leaves helping them maintain a fresh
green color and a healthy shiny surface.
[Music]
Maintain the temperature for the orchid
at around 20 to 25° C during the day and
15 to 18° C at night. This temperature
difference helps stimulate the orchid to
bloom and preserves the flower color
longer.
[Music]
I hope you will enjoy this video. If you
find it helpful, don't forget to hit
like and subscribe to the channel so you
won't miss future shares on how to care
for orchids naturally and simply.
[Music]
And I also hope you will like this
natural fertilizer fermentation recipe
and see its effectiveness when applying
it to your orchid.
Thank you for watching. Goodbye and wish
you always happiness and health
alongside your beautiful orchid pots.
[Music]
Yeah.