[Music]
Welcome to the happiness garden.
You can see in my hands an orchid whose
leaves are completely damaged.
[Music]
And have you ever faced a situation
where your orchid has lost all its
leaves while the flowers remain fresh
and vibrant?
It's really hard to decide because if
you cut off the blooming flowers, it
feels like such a waste.
[Music]
But if we keep them, we also need to
know how to care for the plant so it
doesn't become exhausted and can still
recover from the roots. Um, in this
video I will share how to keep the
flowers fresh for longer while helping
the orchid regain strong vitality.
[Music]
First, you need to remove the old pot if
it no longer provides enough space for
the roots to grow.
As you can see, the cramped pot space
combined with an overly wet environment
has caused many of the orchids roots to
develop dark brown rot spots.
uh these roots are not only ineffective
at absorbing nutrients but can also
spread disease to the healthy roots.
Therefore, treating the rotten roots and
creating a well ventilated environment
for the plant is an important step for
the orchid to recover and grow strong
again.
[Music]
Therefore, we need to quickly remove the
damaged roots to prevent the spread of
disease and help the plant focus its
nutrients on the healthy roots. This
will create the right conditions for new
roots to grow strongly while also
enhancing the orchid's ability to absorb
water and nutrients. Once the roots are
healthy again, the orchid will have a
solid foundation for lush green leaves
and more vibrant blooms.
[Music]
After removing the damaged roots, we
should only discard about half of the
old growing medium, not all of it.
Keeping some of the medium helps retain
beneficial microorganisms and supports
the new roots to anchor firmly and grow
well. This also reduces transplant
shock, creating a stable environment for
the orchid to gradually recover and
continue blooming beautifully.
[Music]
Uh you need to carefully clean the rot
on the stem to prevent it from spreading
to the healthy parts. This creates
favorable conditions for the orchid to
revive uh while also helping any new
shoots growing from the mother plant
develop strongly.
When both the stem and roots are
healthy, the orchid will recover
quickly.
[Music]
Next, remove the flowers that are about
to wither, which helps the plant focus
its energy on developing new roots and
leaves. By cutting off the old blooms,
the orchid no longer has to distribute
nutrients to the flowers, allowing the
roots and leaves to recover more
quickly.
[Music]
Next, I will use lemon to make a
solution that helps disinfect and
sterilize both the growing medium and
the orchid before replanting.
[Music]
Then squeeze about 1 teaspoon of lemon
juice. This lemon juice will be mixed
with water to create a mild disinfectant
solution that is gentle and safe for
both the roots and the stem.
[Music]
Dilute the lemon juice with about 2 L of
clean water to create a gentle solution.
This solution is strong enough to
disinfect but still safe for the roots
and stems without harming the parts that
are recovering.
Then gently pour this mixture over the
roots and the growing medium um allowing
the solution to soak in evenly and
thoroughly clean the areas at risk of
infection.
[Music]
This step helps eliminate any remaining
bacteria and mold while also refreshing
the growing medium, creating favorable
conditions for new healthy roots to
grow. When the roots are protected from
the start, the plant will recover
quickly and keep the flowers fresh on
the stem for a longer time.
[Music]
In addition, soaking with the lemon
solution also helps remove and repel uh
insects hiding in the growing medium.
This is very important because insects
can damage young roots and cause
diseases for the plant. When the growing
medium is completely cleaned, the orchid
will have a safe and well ventilated
environment to grow new roots and
recover quickly.
[Music]
Um, please leave a comment to let me
know which country you are watching
from. Uh, it's wonderful that we can
chat together from all around the world.
And if you haven't subscribed to the
channel yet, please hit the subscribe
button to support me and never miss any
orchid care tips. It's wonderful to have
you along.
[Music]
You can soak for about 20 minutes to
completely disinfect the growing medium,
stimulate healthy new root growth, and
effectively repel insects.
Next, the growing medium used for
replanting also needs to be carefully
treated before use.
[Music]
Then pour the diluted lemon water
mixture in to soak the growing medium.
This soaking helps eliminate fungi,
bacteria, and even tiny insects hiding
in the medium that are hard to see with
the naked eye.
When the medium is completely cleaned,
it will become a safe environment,
allowing the new roots to anchor firmly
and grow vigorously after replanting.
Now we will prepare the fertilizer to
help the orchid recover quickly after
replanting. This is an important step to
provide nutrients for the plant, helping
the new roots grow strong and the leaves
turn green again.
Take about 3 teaspoon of rice and put
them into a clean jar to prepare for
making natural fertilizer.
Then add about one liter of clean water
to dissolve the ingredient.
[Music]
And the final ingredient is banana GE.
Take about 50 ml of banana GE and add it
to the mixture to ferment together.
Banana GE is very rich in potassium and
phosphorus, which help stimulate root
growth and make future blooms more
vibrant. When combined with the other
ingredients, the fertilizer solution
becomes nutritionally balanced,
supporting the plant's full recovery
after replanting.
[Music]
Uh, seal the jar tightly and let the
mixture rest for about 1 day to allow
the fermentation process to occur. this
time helps activate the nutrients and
make them make them easier for the
orchid to absorb.
[Music]
After soaking for about 20 minutes,
gently take the growing medium out and
let it drain completely before
replanting.
This step ensures the medium has the
right moisture level, not too wet to
prevent the new roots from rotting.
[Music]
Then gently take the orchid out as well
and let the remaining old medium on the
roots drain. This helps prevent the
plant from being too wet when
replanting, reducing the risk of root
rot during the recovery stage.
[Music]
When the growing medium is dry enough,
we proceed to replant the orchid so that
the roots can easily anchor and absorb
nutrients, helping the plant recover
quickly and grow strong.
At the bottom of the pot, I place a few
pieces of foam to create ventilation,
keeping the roots airrated and reducing
water logging.
[Music]
At the same time, I use these foam
pieces to secure the support stick,
helping to stabilize the flower spike
when planting.
This way, the orchid stands firm. The
roots can easily attach to the new
medium and grow more evenly, allowing
the plant to recover quickly and bloom
again sooner.
[Music]
Then gently fill the growing medium
around the base of the plant. When
filling, be careful not to pack it too
tightly so the roots still have space to
breathe and grow freely.
At the same time, avoid leaving the
medium too loose as the plant won't
stand firmly and may wobble, causing
damage to the young roots. A moderate
firmness will keep the plant stable,
creating a well ventilated environment
with balanced moisture for the roots.
[Music]
After replanting, place the orchid pot
in a cool, well ventilated area and
avoid direct sunlight for about 1 day.
During this time, do not water so the
roots have time to stabilize and get
used to the new medium.
[Music]
After fermenting for about 1 day, stir
the mixture well to evenly distribute
the nutrients.
[Music]
This helps the ingredients blend
completely, activates the nutrients, and
creates a nutrient-rich fertilizer
solution ready to nourish the orchid.
[Music]
Next, strain out any remaining sediment
in the solution. This makes the solution
clear, easy to apply, and ensures the
nutrients are effectively absorbed by
the plant without clogging the roots.
[Music]
Um, after straining out the sediment,
use this solution to water directly onto
the roots and growing medium. Watering
will provide ample nutrients for the
young roots and improve the medium's
moisture to an optimal level.
[Music]
As the roots absorb nutrients from this
natural fertilizer, the orchid will
quickly recover, grow vigorously, and
prepare for the development of new
plants on the mother plant while keeping
the flowers fresh for a long time.
[Music]
After watering, you can leave the orchid
pot soaking in this mixture for about 20
minutes. The soaking time allows the
solution to penetrate deeply into the
roots and growing medium, enhancing
nutrient delivery and supporting faster
root recovery.
You can pour the remaining mixture into
a spray bottle to use on other orchids.
[Music]
Uh for orchids that are currently
blooming like this, after spraying, the
leaves will become sturdier and help
support the flowers on the stems for a
longer time.
Um, the nutrients from the solution help
increase the vitality of the leaves
while providing energy to prevent the
flowers from dropping prematurely.
When both the leaves and flowers are
healthy, the orchid will maintain its
vibrant beauty for a long time, uh,
bringing complete joy to the caretaker.
After soaking for about 20 minutes, take
the orchid pot out and place it in a
spot with gentle sunlight for
photosynthesis.
Remember, no matter how good the
fertilizer is, if the plant lacks light,
it cannot fully synthesize the necessary
nutrients. Gentle light helps the leaves
absorb energy, stimulates healthy root
and leaf growth, and also supports the
flowers in staying fresh and vibrant.
And this is the result after two weeks
of care.
You can see that the orchid has grown a
small new plant from the mature stem of
the mother plant. This shows that the
care and recovery method we applied has
truly been effective, helping the mother
plant recover while simultaneously
producing a healthy new generation.
[Music]
And you can see that the flower petals
on the stem are still fresh and show no
signs of wilting. This demonstrates that
the orchid not only recovered its roots
and developed a new plant from the
previously damaged mother stem, but also
maintained strong vitality for the
flowers thanks to the nutrients from the
natural fertilizer and the ideal care
environment.
[Music]
Continue
caring for the orchid using the
fermented rice and banana GE fertilizer
or other natural fertilizers I've
introduced on the channel at a frequency
of twice a month.
Regular fertilization like this ensures
the plant is always supplied with
adequate nutrients, helping the roots
grow strong, the leaves stay green, and
the flowers bloom for a long time. By
maintaining this care routine, the
orchid will be healthy overall and ready
for the next rounds of vibrant blooms.
[Music]
and here is the result after 2 months of
care.
You can see that the new orchid
sprouting from the mature stem of the
mother plant, which was previously
rotted and lost all its leaves, has now
grown strong and healthy. This shows
that with proper care and suitable
natural fertilizer, the orchid not only
recovers but also grows vigorously,
ready to produce green leaves.
[Music]
The mother plant's root system along
with the roots of the new plant has also
grown strong, allowing full absorption
of nutrients to nourish the young plant
and maintain the vitality of the flowers
on the stem. When the roots are healthy,
the orchid can efficiently take up water
and minerals, supporting lush green
leaves and longlasting, vibrant blooms.
And you can see that the flower petals
not only remain intact, but also produce
many new blooms, all fresh and vibrant.
This shows that the orchid is growing
comprehensively with healthy leaves,
roots, and flowers thanks to the
nutrients from natural fertilizer and
proper care. When the plant maintains
such strong vitality, you can enjoy the
long-lasting beauty and freshness of
each flower on the stem.
[Music]
Today's video comes to an end. I hope
these tips will be very helpful for you
in effectively caring for orchids at
home. When applied correctly, your
orchid will be healthy with lush green
leaves and vibrant blooms bringing you
joy everyday.
[Music]
If you enjoyed the video, please like
and share it so more people can learn
how to care for healthy blooming
orchids.
This also gives me more motivation to
share even more useful tips.
Thank you so much for accompanying me
and caring for the orchids.