Welcome to the happiness garden. Today I
will share with you how to grow orchids
using the inverted planting method. This
is a technique that helps orchids grow
healthily and bloom regularly all year
round. With this method, the roots will
have better air circulation, helping to
absorb nutrients effectively, thereby
making the plant more vigorous and the
flowers bloom more brilliantly. Let's
get started.
If you have a weak or weak orchid that
you've been caring for a long time, but
it still doesn't grow or bloom, then
follow this method of
[Music]
mine. First, we need to check the
orchid's root system to see if there are
any
problems. Because the roots are the most
important part that determines the
overall health of the plant. If they are
rotten, dry, or no longer functioning
well, the plant will have a hard time
growing. Healthy roots are usually ivory
white or fresh green, while damaged
roots are brown, black, or
mushy. Then cut off all the damaged
roots.
You can see that the roots of this
orchid are almost completely rotten,
causing the plant to lose its ability to
absorb water and nutrients from the
[Music]
environment. Cutting off the damaged
roots helps prevent the spread of root
rot disease, thereby protecting the
healthy remaining roots of the plant.
After treating the roots, you should
also cut off the wilted leaves, damaged
leaves, or those showing signs of
disease. Old, dry, or rotten leaves not
only spoil the appearance, but also
consume a lot of the plant's energy
without providing any benefits.
Removing damaged leaves helps the plant
concentrate nutrients on the healthy
parts while also reducing the risk of
disease spreading from the leaves to
other
[Music]
parts. When the plant is cleaned up like
this, the recovery and growth process
will happen faster.
[Music]
After cutting off the damaged roots and
leaves, the next step is to wash the
entire plant with clean
water. This helps remove dirt,
impurities, and any remaining bacteria
or fungi on the stem, roots, and leaves
of the
[Music]
plant. Please comment and let me know
which country you are watching this
video from. It's wonderful that we can
chat together from all around the world.
[Music]
Next, take about 0.5 L of clean water
and pour it into a cup or small
container to prepare the nutrient
solution for the orchid.
[Music]
Then add about a/ teaspoon of pure honey
into the cup of water.
[Music]
And finally, add three vitamin B1
tablets into the cup of water.
[Music]
Stir the mixture in the cup until the
honey and vitamin B1 are completely
dissolved in the water. This way you
have a very good natural fertilizer
solution that helps promote the healthy
growth of the orchid.
[Music]
Then soak the entire orchid in the
natural fertilizer solution you just
prepared for about 20
minutes. This soaking helps the
nutrients from the honey and vitamin B1
penetrate deeply into the roots and
stem, stimulating the regeneration of
new roots and restoring the plant's
health.
[Music]
Next, you will need to prepare baking
soda. Take about half teaspoon of baking
soda and dilute it with one liter of
clean water.
[Music]
The growing medium I am using for the
orchids today is moss a very common and
suitable medium for orchids because of
its good moisture retention and
irerration. However, before using it, we
need to sterilize the moss thoroughly to
remove all bacteria, mold, and pests
that may exist in the medium.
[Music]
Uh, soaking the moss in the diluted
baking solution for about 20 minutes
helps remove bacteria, mold, and pests
that may cling to the medium.
[Music]
After soaking the orchid in the solution
for 20 minutes, gently take the plant
out and use a soft cloth or clean tissue
to dry the water on the surface of the
leaves and in the leaf crevices.
[Music]
Uh this helps reduce water accumulation
that can cause rot or create favorable
conditions for fungal diseases to
develop especially in areas where water
doesn't drain easily such as leaf axles.
[Music]
Then take a small amount of cinnamon
powder and gently sprinkle it on the cut
area of the orchid stem.
[Music]
Cinnamon powder has natural
antibacterial and antifungal properties,
helping prevent infections and promoting
faster wound
[Music]
healing. And now I will proceed to plant
the orchid upside
down. Um, this is an important step in
the recovery process and in stimulating
the plant to grow stronger. Please pay
close attention to each action I perform
so you can apply it
[Music]
correctly. I take a small copper wire
stick to use as a support to fix the
orchid in place. after
[Music]
planting. This fixing is very important
because if the plant shakes during care,
the newly grown roots can be easily
damaged or broken, affecting the
recovery and growth process.
[Music]
If you haven't subscribe to the channel
yet, please hit the subscribe button to
support me and not miss any orchid
growing tips. It's wonderful to have you
along for the journey.
[Music]
Then take the soaked moss and squeeze
out the excess water so the moss is not
too wet when used as the orchid growing
medium.
Squeezing thoroughly helps the moss
retain moderate moisture, create a
breathable environment, and prevent
water logging, which helps orchid roots
grow
[Music]
healthily. For this planting method, you
need to prepare a hook to hang the
orchid pot after planting.
[Music]
Besides English dubbing, we have now
created French, German, Italian,
Spanish, Portuguese, Japanese, Hindi,
and Indonesian versions to help you
listen to and understand the content
easily.
[Music]
Then we proceed to plant the orchid
using the prepared moist moss layer.
[Music]
After planting, you should hang the
orchid pot in a place with gentle
sunlight avoiding harsh direct light so
the plant does not get stressed. Uh
during the first week after planting do
not water the plant
but after one week prepare the honey and
vitamin B1 solution again as I
instructed at the beginning of the
video.
[Music]
Then use a spray bottle to evenly mist
the honey and vitamin B1 solution over
the entire orchid and growing medium.
Even spraying helps the nutrients
penetrate deeply not only into the roots
but also onto the leaves and stem
enhancing absorption and protecting the
plant from various fungal
[Music]
diseases. Uh you only need to spray the
honey and vitamin B1 solution on the
orchid about two to three times per
month.
[Music]
And now let's take a look at the results
after 1 month of caring for the orchid
using the upside down planting method I
demonstrated.
Uh after this period you will see the
orchid clearly recovering with roots
growing strong and
[Music]
healthy. Now let's check the orchid stem
inside the growing medium together.
[Music]
Wow, you can see many new roots. It's
growing out.
[Music]
Uh with this simple care method, you can
easily see many new roots have grown
vigorously around the base of the
orchid.
[Music]
The young white healthy roots are a
clear sign that the plant is recovering
well and absorbing nutrients
effectively.
[Music]
Stimulating root growth not only helps
the plant anchor firmly to the growing
medium, but also increases its ability
to absorb water and nutrients, making
the plant healthier and bloom more
regularly. This is proof of the
effectiveness of the upside down
planting method I just shared.
After carefully checking the orchid
roots and seeing that the new roots have
grown strong, I proceed to replant the
orchid using the moist moss layer.
[Music]
After replanting, from now on, you
should continue caring for the orchid
using the liquid fertilizer mixture made
from honey and vitamin B1.
[Music]
Apply this liquid fertilizer to the
orchid two to three times per month.
That will be enough.
[Music]
toe. Remember to hang the orchid pot in
a spot with gentle sunlight, such as
near a window or under a tree canopy, so
the plant can photosynthesize
effectively.
[Music]
After 3 months of care, the orchid has
grown vigorously with strong roots, lush
green leaves, and especially it has
bloomed with many vibrant
[Music]
flowers. The fully bloomed,
long-lasting, and brightly colored
flowers are clear proof of the
effectiveness of the upside down
planting method combined with with the
natural fertilizer made from honey and
and vitamin B1.
[Music]
I hope this video will bring you lots of
useful knowledge to help you care for
your orchids at home easily and
effectively. Uh with this simple yet
effective method, you can completely
help your orchid grow healthy, bloom
regularly, and maintain its long-lasting
[Music]
beauty. Uh if you find the content
helpful and meaningful, don't forget to
like and share so more people can know
about it and subscribe to support me.
Thank you for always being by my
side. Thank you all for watching and I
wish you success with your orchid
garden.