Hello everyone.
Today I'm excited to share a wonderful
way to care for your orchids using
natural fertilizer made from everyday
kitchen ingredients.
[Music]
This simple trick will help your orchids
grow strong and bloom longer.
[Music]
Let's dive into how to make this easy
fertilizer that anyone can create.
To create natural fertilizer for
orchids, I need one ripe banana.
[Music]
Cut banana into thin slices.
Bananas are rich in potassium, an
essential mineral that improves plant
health, enhances stress resistance, and
stimulates blooming.
[Music]
When bananas decompose, they provide
easily absorbable nutrients for plants,
promoting rapid growth for orchids.
[Music]
Bananas provide food for beneficial
microorganisms in the soil, helping
balance the microbial ecosystem and
promoting root growth.
[Music]
Then you put the bananas in the jar.
Please comment to me which country you
are watching the video from. It's great
that we can chat together from all over
the world.
[Music]
Add 1500 mm warm water.
If you haven't subscribed to the channel
yet, please subscribe to support me and
not miss any orchid care tips.
[Music]
Next, I use eggshells as fertilizer.
Eggshells have alkaline properties that
help balance soil pH, creating an ideal
environment for orchids.
[Music]
Great.
Eggshells supply other minerals such as
magnesium and phosphorus which are
essential for plant growth.
[Music]
Put 2 tbsp of eggshell powder into the
jar.
Uh, in addition to the English dub,
we've now created dubs in French,
German, Italian, Spanish, Portuguese,
Japanese, Hindi, and Indonesian to help
you hear and understand the content.
Videos are easier.
Then place in a cool place for 3 weeks
to create fermented GE fertilizer from
bananas and eggshells, which is very
good for orchids.
[Music]
This is a GE product fermented from
bananas and eggshells that I made 3
weeks ago.
Take 50 mil of GE fermentation solution.
[Music]
Uh, a good product after fermentation
must have the aroma of banana.
[Music]
mix with 2 L of water.
Method one.
Water this liquid fertilizer into each
orchid pot.
[Music]
Uh this solution delivers a rich supply
of essential nutrients to the plants
including uh potassium from bananas and
calcium from eggshells promoting healthy
growth.
[Music]
Um, the nutrients in the solution
encourage the blooming process, leading
to more vibrant and longerlasting
flowers.
[Music]
The fermented solution enhances soil
fertility, creating a conducive
environment for root development and
beneficial microorganisms.
Do this once every two weeks.
Method two.
If you have many orchid pots, you can
put this solution in a spray bottle.
[Music]
Then spray the entire orchid.
Spraying the solution delivers nutrients
directly to the leaves and other parts
of the plant, supporting overall growth.
The ingredients in the solution promote
photosynthesis, making leaves greener
and healthier.
Spraying this solution helps the plant
improve its resilience to harsh
environmental conditions such as heat or
drought.
The fermentation solution encourages the
growth of beneficial microorganisms on
the leaf surface, supporting overall
plant health.
[Music]
Uh the combination of nutrients and
beneficial microorganisms helps reduce
the risk of diseases and pests. on the
plant.
With these benefits, spraying the
fermented solution from bananas and
eggshells will be an effective method
for caring for and protecting orchids.
[Music]
Standing water can create a favorable
environment for mold and disease
development, especially in humid
conditions.
[Music]
Wet leaves can reduce the efficiency of
photosynthesis due to light being
reflected or absorbed ineffectively.
[Music]
Drying them enhances photosynthesis.
If the fertilizer solution contains
concentrated nutrients, standing water
can lead to leaf burn when exposed to
direct sunlight.
[Music]
Um, dry leaves allow for better
absorption of nutrients through the leaf
surface.
[Music]
Wiping off excess water helps maintain
the overall health of the plant,
avoiding issues caused by high humidity.
Uh do this one to two times a month and
you will get great results.
[Music]
Uh after soaking for about 20 minutes,
take the orchid pot out and place it in
a place in a place with lots of
scattered light so the orchid can
photosynthesize. Well,
[Music]
let's see the results.
Orchid leaves are always sturdy and
shiny green.
[Music]
new roots develop and the root system
remains healthy and rot-free.
[Music]
Strong roots help plants absorb water
and nutrients from the growing medium
effectively.
[Music]
A healthy root system helps plants
resist disease and harsh environmental
conditions.
[Music]
Roots also store energy supporting the
plant through different stages of
growth.
Well-developed roots facilitate
effective gas exchange, enhancing the
plant's respiratory ability.
[Music]
When orchids have healthy roots, the
flowers have bright colors, symmetrical
shapes, and are not deformed.
[Music]
Flowers will bloom profusely and
simultaneously without falling
prematurely.
[Music]
The plant will produce more flower buds,
resulting in a greater number of flowers
blooming each flowering season.
[Music]
Thank you for watching the video.
Wishing you luck and success in life.
Welcome to the happiness garden where
every plant tells a story of care,
patience, and joy blossoming every day.
Each orchid is a masterpiece with
vibrant colors and long-lasting blooms.
These wonderful qualities make orchids
always capture the hearts of flower
lovers around the world.
Uh, in this video I will share with you
many easy tips for caring for orchids at
home so you can enjoy vibrant blooms all
year round.
Let's get started
to make this magical fertilizer. First,
prepare 3 L of clean water in a clean
container, ready for the next steps.
Please comment and let me know which
country you are watching the video from.
It's wonderful that we can connect and
chat together from all around the world.
[Music]
Next, you can use expired milk or
leftover milk from the fridge. A great
way to avoid waste and help your orchids
grow.
Just about 1 tsp of milk, equivalent to
around 15 ml, is enough for this recipe.
Next, simply stir the milk into the
water until the mixture is fully
blended.
Next, we will add a little lemon juice
to the mixture.
You can choose either a yellow lemon or
a green lime. Both provide excellent
results.
[Music]
You only need 1/3 tablespoon of lemon
juice for the mixture to be perfectly
balanced.
[Music]
Next, stir the mixture well so all the
ingredients are fully blended.
[Music]
If you haven't subscribed to the channel
yet, please hit the subscribe button to
support me and not miss any orchid
growing tips. It's wonderful to have you
along for the journey.
The first method is to use a soft cloth
to soak up the mixture and gently wipe
both the top and underside of the leaves
so the plant can absorb the nutrients
best.
[Music]
By wiping the leaves, the orchid will
stay clean, photosynthesize more easily,
and have better air circulation, helping
the plant grow healthier.
Thanks to their antibacterial and
disinfectant properties, milk and lemon
will help you effectively eliminate
fungi and harmful insects from your
orchids.
[Music]
Moreover, wiping the leaves with the
milk and lemon mixture also helps the
orchid leaves become naturally shiny,
looking fresher and healthier.
[Music]
Uh, in the long run, caring for the
leaves with the milk and lemon mixture
helps orchids grow stronger with
healthier roots, thicker and greener
leaves, while also increasing their
ability to bloom regularly and for
longer.
[Music]
Looking at the orchids after wiping
their leaves with the milk and lemon
mixture, you will see sturdy, glossy
leaves full of vitality. A clear proof
of the effectiveness of this method.
[Music]
The second method is to put the mixture
into a spray bottle and evenly spray it
onto the leaves, stems, and roots of the
orchid.
[Music]
Spray the mixture evenly on both the top
and underside of the leaves so the plant
can absorb the nutrients optimally.
This spraying method also helps clean
dust and remove insects on the leaves,
especially on the underside where pests
often hide.
Additionally, spraying the mixture on
the leaves helps the orchid leaves
become naturally shiny, improves
photosynthesis, and enhances the overall
health of the plant.
Uh if you maintain regular leaf
spraying, the orchids will always stay
clean with fewer pests and fungi,
allowing them to grow healthily and
bloom more consistently.
[Music]
By caring for the leaves properly, the
orchids will be healthy from roots to
leaves, ready for vibrant blooms in the
coming seasons.
You should spray or wipe the leaves
regularly about twice a month to keep
the orchids healthy and growing well.
[Music]
The third method is to water the mixture
onto the roots and growing medium,
helping the plant uh absorb nutrients
from root to tip.
[Music]
When watering the diluted milk and lemon
mixture onto the roots and growing
medium, the orchid not only receives
nutrients directly, but is also
protected from fungi and harmful
insects. Milk and lemon provide
antibacterial and disinfectant effects
right at the base while keeping the
roots healthy for overall plant growth.
Um, when watering, make sure the milk
and lemon mixture spreads evenly over
the roots and growing medium. This
method both provides nutrients and
protects the roots from pests, helping
the orchids grow healthy and bloom
better.
[Music]
With the method of watering the roots
using the diluted milk and lemon
mixture, you not only provide nutrients,
but also keep the roots and growing
medium clean, preventing fungi and
harmful insects. By doing this
regularly, your orchids will grow
comprehensively, healthy from root to
tip, and ready to bloom vibrantly all
year round.
And here are the results after applying
the natural fertilizer care method. New
roots are growing evenly. Old roots are
strong, showing that the orchid is
developing vigorously.
You can also see the shoots of the new
orchid seedlings beginning to grow,
proving the strong vitality of the
mother plant.
[Music]
Um, the new roots of the orchid look
very healthy, growing evenly and
strongly, preparing for the plant's
overall development.
Roots are often called the heart of the
plant because they determine the health,
growth, and survival of the orchid.
[Music]
When the roots are healthy, the orchid
absorbs nutrients better. The leaves
stay green, the flowers bloom
beautifully, and the plant grows
stronger day by day.
[Music]
Because roots are as important as the
heart of the plant, watering or spraying
the milk and lemon mixture helps the
roots stay healthy, allowing the orchid
to grow well and bloom more
consistently.
[Music]
Thanks to using this natural fertilizer,
your orchid will grow more flower
spikes. On the same plant, you can see
up to four new flower spikes emerging.
[Music]
The evenly growing new flower spikes
show that the orchid is strong from root
to tip with enough energy to produce
many blooms at once, making the entire
plant full of vitality and color
[Music]
with evenly growing spikes and plump
buds. You will enjoy vibrant, fresh, and
long-lasting blooms. a wonderful reward
for your patience and dedicated care.
Uh, not only are there many flower
spikes, but each bloom also opens
vibrantly with bright colors and
long-lasting beauty, bringing joy to
anyone who sees them.
The newly opened flowers are all healthy
and vibrant, making the orchid look
lively and full of energy.
These fresh and vibrant flowers are not
only beautiful but also inspiring,
proving that patience and proper care
bring excellent results. Give love to
your plants and they will respond with
radiant beauty.
Each fresh and vibrant flower is a
reward for your efforts in in caring for
the plant, reminding us that love and
patience are always rewarded with
natural beauty.
We've reached the end of today's video.
I hope you enjoyed and found the tips on
caring for orchids helpful.
[Music]
If you found this video meaningful,
don't forget to like, share, and leave a
comment so we can care for orchids
better together.
Thank you for watching. Goodbye, and may
you always be happy and joyful with your
beautiful orchids.
[Music]