welcome to my
[Music]
channel if you want your orchid to bloom
abundantly all year round this is the
video I made just for
[Music]
you so if you haven't subscribed to the
channel yet make sure to do so to
support me and not miss any great tips
on tips
365 it would be wonderful to have you
accompany me
[Music]
when the orchid has finished blooming or
the plant is stunted slow to grow and
has not yet
[Music]
bloomed cut all dry branches roots and
leaves this helps orchids Focus their
energy on Healthy
Growth removing dead parts helps prevent
disease improves air circulation and
encourages the growth of new roots and
leaves resulting in stronger and more
vibrant
[Music]
blooms then take three teaspoons
add four cups of boiled water about 1
liter of
[Music]
water then Brew until the water
cools after the water cools filter to
remove
sediment after the water cools filter to
[Music]
residue please comment to me which
country you are watching the video from
it's great that we can chat together
from all over the world
[Music]
in addition to the English dub we've now
created dubs in French German Italian
Spanish Portuguese Japanese Hindi and
Indonesian to help you hear and
understand the content more
easily then add 1 US gallon of water
about 3.8 L to the mixture
[Music]
first use this water to thoroughly wipe
the top and bottom of the
[Music]
leaves this clears dirt and removes
fungus disease and insects that damage
the
[Music]
leaves apply this method once a
month helps leaves Stay Green strong and
resistant to pests
[Music]
then you use this water to water the
Orchid
[Music]
Roots this helps Roots grow healthily
and prevents root rot
[Music]
uh coffee contains many minerals
necessary for the growth of
[Music]
orchids organic phosphorus and potassium
found in coffee help roots and flowers
develop outstandingly
[Music]
do this twice a month for your orchids
so they grow and Bloom profusely
[Music]
[Applause]
or you can also use this water to spray
the entire
[Music]
Orchid thoroughly spray spr the top and
bottom of the leaves to remove dirt and
insects from the leaf
[Music]
surface do this every 2
weeks coffee water helps repel Orchid
pests very effectively
[Music]
after spraying and soaking in this water
for about 5 minutes the insects will run
away from the Orchid
[Music]
pot uh if you encounter any difficulties
during the Orchid growing process don't
hesitate to comment I am always ready to
support you so you can grow healthy
orchids and Bloom lots of
[Music]
flowers then take the Orchid pot out and
place it in a cool place with enough
light for the Orchid to
grow 2 months
later uh orchids will be begin to sprout
and Bloom
[Music]
profusely blooming flowers have bright
colors shoe pedals will stay fresh
longer
[Music]
the flowers bloom for up to 6 months
before
[Music]
fading hopefully the video will help you
a lot in taking better care of orchids
at home
[Music]
if you find it useful don't forget to
subscribe to the channel so you don't
miss any Orchid growing
[Music]
tips uh thank you for watching the video
good luck and see you in the next videos
[Music]
hello everyone and welcome back to
happiness
Garden today I'm going to share with you
how to make a natural banana based
fertilizer that will help your orchids
grow healthily and Bloom beautifully all
year
[Music]
round if you find this information
helpful don't forget to like subscribe
and hit the notification Bell to catch
more videos
[Music]
now let's get
started to make this natural fertilizer
today I'm using one green banana that is
very rich in nutrients providing
essential vitamins and minerals to
support your orchid's Healthy Growth and
[Music]
blooming which country are you watching
this video from
let me know in the comments
[Music]
below uh it's a it's amazing that we can
chat and connect with each other from
all around the
world then I put the banana into the
blender add 300 mm of water and blend it
into a smooth mixture
[Music]
if you haven't subscribed to the channel
yet click the Subscribe button and hit
the notification Bell so you won't miss
any new videos
[Music]
pour the Blended banana mixture into a
bottle and add another 700 M of water to
create a liquid
[Music]
solution add 1 teaspoon of sugar to help
ferment the mixture and prevent it from
[Music]
spoiling finally add 1 teaspoon of yeast
to ensure the fermentation process is
perfect and prevents any spoilage
[Music]
stir well then place the mixture in a
cool well ventilated area avoiding
direct sunlight for 3 weeks
[Music]
after 3 weeks the mixture turns into an
excellent natural fermented fertilizer
for
orchids take 50 mm of the mixture
[Music]
then dilute it with 1 liter of water
step one use a soft cotton pad to soak
up the mixture and gently wipe both the
upper and lower surfaces of the
leaves this not only cleans the leaves
improving photosynthesis but also
prevents pests and diseases keeping the
plant healthy and thriving
currently my channel supports multiple
languages including English Italian
French German Portuguese and Spanish you
can go to the settings and select your
preferred language to enjoy the video
experience at its best
for countries that don't have an audio
language option available you can go to
the settings and select subtitles in the
appropriate language to better
understand the content of the video
additionally this method provides
nutrients directly through the leaves
allowing the plant to absorb them faster
and grow better
step two if you have a large number of
orchid pots you can pour the mixture
into a spray bottle
then spray the mixture over the entire
orchid plant just like fol or
fertilizing to effectively provide
nutrients through the leaves
this method also helps wash away dust
mold and insects that may be on the
surface of the leaves
[Music]
in addition spraying this mixture helps
improve the plant's Health increases its
photosynthesis ability and stimulates
the growth of roots and leaves
[Music]
step three use a soft cloth to gently
absorb any excess mixture on the leaves
to remove impurities prevent the orchids
from becoming overly damp and keep the
leaves clean and well ventilated
[Music]
this method keeps the orchids well
ventilated helping to prevent common
diseases especially rot caused by
excessive moisture
[Music]
step four water this mixture onto the
roots to provide essential nutrients
stimulate healthy root growth and ensure
they effectively absorb the necessary
elements from the soil
[Music]
simply water each pot with about 10
tablespoons of the mixture which is
enough to provide the necessary
nutrients for Healthy Growth
this fertilizer helps the roots absorb
essential vitamins and minerals to grow
strong and
healthy it stimulates the roots to grow
quickly and enhances their ability to
absorb nutrients from the soil
step one use a soft cotton pad to soak
up the mixture and gently wipe both the
upper and lower surfaces of the
leaves it maintains proper moisture
levels and prevents root rot caused by
overwatering or excessive dampness
it introduces beneficial microorganisms
to the root environment supporting
nutrient breakdown and improving
absorption
efficiency then place the Orchid pop in
a spot with gentle sunlight to allow
photosynthesis which enhances nutrient
exchange and promotes the plant's growth
which enhances nutrient exchange and
promotes the plant's
[Music]
growth follow the steps above for 10 to
15 days to ensure your orchids grow
healthy and achieve the best results
uh results after 1 to two months of care
using this natural fertilizer depending
on each plant you will see the orchids
Thrive with lush green leaves and
vibrant
[Music]
Vitality the or Roots grow strong
healthy and spread out allowing the
plant to absorb nutrients efficiently
from the
[Music]
soil Additionally the orchids develop
numerous aerial Roots which help the
plant absorb nutrients and moisture from
the air when aerial Roots grow
abundantly it indicates that the
environment in your garden is ideal and
Well Suited
[Music]
new flower buds are developing strongly
bringing hope for vibrant blooms in the
future some orchids are producing up to
four buds at the same time showing their
vitality and strong blooming
potential uh the flowers bloom large
with more vibrant and striking colors
than usual adding an alluring and
Elegant Beauty these blossoms stay on
the stem for a long time without wilting
easily creating a colorful and Lively
atmosphere in your
garden thank you for watching if you
found this information helpful don't
forget to click subscribe and hit like
to support
me I'll see you in the next video
wishing you success in caring for your
orchids and a lot of happiness