Hello everyone. To keep orchid flowers
blooming brilliantly and abundantly, the
first important thing is to help the
plant develop a really strong root
system.
When the roots are strong, the plant
will absorb nutrients better, resulting
in lush, vibrant leaves and naturally
preparing for the next blooming season.
Today I will share with you a very
simple but effective method that helps
orchid stems that have finished blooming
to revive and continue growing
vigorously.
As the plant grows stronger day by day,
more and more new flower buds will
appear, bringing vibrant beauty and full
vitality to your orchid pot.
With this simple care method, you will
see your orchids start to produce many
healthy flower buds free from fungal
diseases or insect attacks. The blooms
are longasting and if cared for
regularly, the plant can bloom all year
round without paws.
Let's get started.
To care for orchids naturally and
effectively, you can make use of an
orange peel. Orange peel contains
natural essential oils that can repel
harmful insects while also providing
many essential nutrients that help
orchids grow healthily and produce more
flowers.
[Music]
If you haven't subscribed to the channel
yet, please hit the subscribe button to
support me and not miss any orchid
growing tips. It's wonderful to have you
along.
In addition to the English voiceover, we
have now created French, German,
Italian, Spanish, Portuguese, Japanese,
Hindi, Dutch, Polish, Korean, and
Indonesian voiceovers to help you listen
and understand the content more easily.
To hear your preferred language, open
the video and click on settings, the
gear icon, to select the appropriate
audio language.
Leave a comment to let me know which
country you're watching from. It's
wonderful that we can connect and chat
from all around the world.
After finally chopping the orange peel,
place it into a clean glass jar. This is
the first step in extracting the
valuable natural essences from the
orange peel, helping the orchid absorb
nutrients gently yet effectively.
[Music]
Next, pour about one liter of boiling
water into the jar. The high temperature
will help release the essential oils and
nutrients from the orange peel more
effectively, creating a natural,
nutrient-rich solution for your orchid.
After that, simply close the lid and let
it sit until the water cools completely.
During this steeping time, the essences
in the orange peel will gradually infuse
into the water, creating a gentle yet
highly beneficial nutrient mixture for
your orchid.
[Music]
Orchids need water to live and grow.
Proper moisture helps the roots develop
quickly and allows the plant to absorb
nutrients more effectively.
A lack of water makes it difficult for
orchids to grow healthily.
Once a month, you should soak the plant
to provide deep moisture to the roots.
Pre-watering like this not only helps
soften the growing medium, but also
allows the plant to absorb nutrients
more effectively in the next care steps.
[Music]
You should soak the plant for about 20
minutes to evenly moisten both the roots
and the growing medium. This amount of
time is enough for the plant to absorb
water without becoming water logged,
helping the roots maintain the ideal
moisture level for growth.
[Music]
This method will help the plant carry
out metabolism more easily, thereby
promoting natural growth and helping the
plant maintain lasting vitality.
[Music]
After the roots have been properly
moistened, the new fertilizer will be
absorbed more quickly, allowing the
orchid to take in nutrients effectively
and grow more vigorously.
[Music]
Soaking also helps wash away excess
minerals that have accumulated over time
in the growing medium, keeping the
environment airy and clean and creating
ideal conditions for root development.
[Music]
In addition, soaking helps remove
decayed organic matter in the growing
medium, preventing fungal diseases and
keeping the root system clean and
healthy.
[Music]
That's exactly why I always recommend
watering before applying any type of
fertilizer. When the roots are already
moistened, the plant will absorb
nutrients more effectively and avoid
fertilizer shock, which is essential for
healthy and stable orchid growth.
[Music]
After soaking the plant for about 20
minutes, gently take it out of the
water.
At this point, the roots and growing
medium are sufficiently moistened and
ready for the next care step.
[Music]
And as you can see, the growing medium
has become very dirty after soaking.
This is one of the reasons why orchids
may not grow well or produce many
flowers.
Soaking like this is also a simple and
effective way to remove impurities,
clean the roots, and help the plant
absorb nutrients more efficiently.
No matter what type of pot you grow your
orchid in, regularly performing this
care step is still essential. With
proper care, the orchid will grow
quickly, stay healthy, and soon produce
many beautiful blooms.
Once the water is completely cooled,
proceed to strain out the remaining
residue. This way, we'll obtain a clear,
nutrient-rich solution that is ready to
be used safely and effectively for the
orchid.
[Music]
After that, dilute the filtered liquid
with one liter of clean water. Diluting
it will make the solution gentler, safe
for the roots, and suitable for frequent
watering of orchids.
The next ingredient we will use is
honey. This natural component is very
beneficial, helping to stimulate root
growth and boost the orchid's
resistance.
Simply add one teaspoon of honey to the
solution. This small amount is enough to
provide natural energy, help the plant
recover more quickly, and stimulate
healthy new root growth.
[Music]
The first method is to use a soft cotton
pad soaked in this mixture. Then gently
wipe both the top and bottom surfaces of
the leaves.
[Music]
Uh when wiping the leaves with the
orange peel and honey mixture, the
natural essential oils in the orange
will help clean off the dust on the
leaves while also repelling small
insects like aphids or red spider mites.
[Music]
If orchid leaves are covered in dust,
they will struggle to absorb light
effectively. Regularly wiping the leaves
with this natural mixture helps keep the
leaf surface clear, allowing the plant
to photosynthesize better, grow faster,
and stay more stable.
[Music]
Uh the honey in the mixture provides a
natural amount of sugars and mild
minerals that can be absorbed through
the leaves. This not only helps the
leaves stay green and healthy, but also
boosts the plant's resistance,
supporting the orchid in developing
strong roots and producing long-lasting
flowers.
Apply this leaf wiping method regularly
twice a month. Regular care will help
keep your orchid clean, healthy, and
blooming more brilliantly.
[Music]
As for the second method, you can use
this mixture to water the plant by
misting it.
[Music]
This method provides gentle moisture and
nutrients spreading evenly over the
stem, leaves, and roots, which is
excellent for the orchid's overall
development.
Uh, when misting, be sure to spray both
sides of the leaves evenly. Many harmful
insects tend to hide on the unders sides
of the leaves where they're less
noticeable. Spraying evenly will help
protect the plant more thoroughly.
Since this mixture contains essential
oils from orange peel, spraying it on
the plant will effectively repel harmful
insects such as spiders, aphids, and
thris. Your orchid will be protected in
a more natural and stronger way. This is
also one of the simple organic solutions
that helps you care for your beloved
orchids more easily and safely everyday.
When using organic fertilizers, it's
important to be patient. Although the
effects may not appear immediately, over
time, the orchid will gradually recover
and develop new, healthy roots, even in
plants that are very weak.
Carry out this care routine regularly,
one to two times each month. A small act
of consistency each month will bring
great vitality to your orchid.
[Music]
And the third method is to apply this
mixture directly into the orchid pot.
This approach allows the nutrients to
soak deep into the growing medium,
nourishing the roots from within and
supporting the plant's overall
development.
[Music]
When watering the mixture into the
growing medium, um, we not only provide
nutrients, but also help prevent root
rot thanks to its natural antibacterial
properties. As a result, the roots will
be protected and grow strongly, creating
a solid foundation for the orchid's
development.
After applying, leave the orchid pot in
this mixture and soak it for about 20
minutes. This amount of time is enough
for the roots to absorb the nutrients
effectively while still being safe with
no risk of water logging or damage to
the plant.
[Music]
Um, apply this method regularly every 2
weeks. You can also alternate it with
other types of organic fertilizers to
provide your orchid with a variety of
nutrients and promote more well-rounded
growth.
I always recommend prioritizing the use
of organic fertilizers. Although their
their effects may take longer to appear
compared to chemical fertilizers, once
the plant starts growing, it will be
healthier, more resilient, and lush for
the long term.
[Music]
When cared for properly like this, your
orchid will begin to show noticeable
growth in a short time. This simple yet
effective method will continue to
support and help your beloved orchids
stay healthy, develop strong roots, and
grow sustainably over time.
[Music]
After fertilizing, if you notice any
liquid fertilizer remaining on the
leaves, use a soft cloth to gently
absorb the excess moisture from the leaf
surface and between the leaf folds.
[Music]
This helps prevent fungal diseases and
keeps the plant clean and healthy.
You may notice the leaves becoming
greener and glossier.
[Music]
The best time to fertilize orchids is
early in the morning. At that time, the
plant has just rested overnight. The
weather is still cool and the humidity
in the air is still high. This is when
the roots are most active, allowing for
efficient nutrient absorption without
the risk of heat stress.
[Music]
You should avoid fertilizing at noon
when the sun is intense as the high
temperatures can cause leaf burn or heat
stress. Evening is also not an an ideal
time since the plant's photosynthesis
slows down, which can lead to water and
fertilizer lingering on the leaves,
increasing the risk of fungal diseases.
After soaking the orchid pot in the
fertilizer mixture for about 20 minutes,
gently take it out and place it in a
cool, wellventilated spot with gentle
sunlight.
[Music]
Gentle morning or late afternoon
sunlight will help the plant dry
quickly, reducing the risk of root rot
while also supporting more efficient
nutrient absorption.
[Music]
With this simple care method, you will
see new roots forming consistently.
Strong, healthy roots that are thick,
white, and firmly attached to the
growing medium are signs that the plant
is growing well and absorbing nutrients
effectively.
Not only will the roots develop, but
flower buds will also begin to form when
the plant is properly cared for. These
lovely little buds will gradually emerge
from the dormant nodes, signaling a
vibrant blooming season ahead for your
orchid.
When the flower buds are fully
developed, you'll see the orchid blooms
open with large, soft, and beautiful
petals. The wonderful thing is that that
the flowers stay on the stem for a long
time before fading, bringing lasting
beauty and prolonged joy to orchid
lovers.
[Music]
I hope you enjoy this video. If you find
it helpful, don't forget to hit like and
subscribe to the channel so you won't
miss future tips on caring for orchids
naturally and simply.
Thank you for watching the video until
the end. Wishing you good health,
happiness, and lots of orchids blooming
beautifully all year round. See you in
the next video.