welcome to my happiness Garden
channel uh if you grow many orchids it
is inevitable that the orchids will rot
due to bacteria or
[Music]
fungi my orchid has Leaf rot and stem
rot when we encounter an orchid like
this we need to cut off all rotten
leaves roots and stems
[Music]
if you haven't subscribed to the channel
yet please click the Subscribe button to
support me and not miss any Orchid
growing tips it's great to have company
[Music]
in addition to the English dub we've now
created dubs in French German Italian
Spanish Portuguese Japanese Hindi and
Indonesian to help you hear and
understand the content videos are easier
[Music]
please comment to me which country you
are watching the video from it's great
that we can chat together from all over
the
world to restore this Orchid I use two
ochre pods
[Music]
f
soak in a half US gallon of water about
[Music]
L wait 30 minutes for the gel and
nutrients from the okra to dissolve into
the
water next take one teaspoon of cinnamon
powder
soak in 1/2 US gallon of boiling water
about 2 L for 30
[Music]
minutes after 30 minutes
after 30 minutes
[Music]
wipe Orchid branches with cinnamon water
this helps eliminate fungal diseases and
harmful insects
[Music]
then incubate the roots with cinnamon
water for about 20 minutes to help
disinfect and stimulate roots to grow
and germinate
[Music]
so soak the moss in cinnamon water for
20 minutes helps eliminate fungi and
bacteria in Moss
[Music]
soak Orchid stems in Okra gel for 20
minutes
[Music]
water okra gel into Old Orchid Roots
this helps stimulate better germination
and
[Music]
rooting adding Moss helps retain
moisture
[Music]
better spray moisturizer with water once
a
[Music]
week place in a cool well-lit place
I reused a plastic container and cut a
drainage hole in the bottom
[Music]
place in a cool well-lit place
6 weeks
[Music]
later you can see that the orchid has
taken root and is very healthy
with this simple method you can easily
restore an orchid without roots
[Music]
because the roots are strong I planted
them in pots to help the plants grow
[Music]
quickly the old rout below has also
revived new Orchid sprouts
[Music]
the old Route below has also revived new
Orchid
[Music]
Sprouts wishing you success and
happiness in life goodbye and see you
again in the next videos
welcome to the happiness Garden
Channel this is where I share my passion
and experience in orchid
care in today's video I'll introduce you
to a new natural fertilizer which not
only helps orchids grow strong but also
Bloom beautifully all year round
[Music]
if you love orchids and want to discover
tips to care for
them let's get
started this is an orchid that has
finished
[Music]
blooming the petals have
withered cut off damaged leaves
please comment to me which country you
are watching the video from it's great
that we can chat together from all over
the
world uh as soon as the flower is Wilt
repot your orchid and the plant will
recover and grow
quickly um you cut off Old Flower
branches so that the Orchid can focus on
nutrition for new flower branches later
[Music]
then use coffee powder to sprinkle on
the cut to help the wound heal
[Music]
quickly then wait overnight for the cut
to heal completely before proceeding
with the with the next care
[Music]
step to make this fertilizer I use
okra okra is an excellent natural
ingredient for making fertilizer for
orchids due to its Rich nutrients
[Music]
next I use potatoes as natural
fertilizer to restore the
Orchid potatoes are rich in starch
providing essential energy for orchid
growth uh potatoes are packed with
minerals like potassium phosphorus and
vitamin B six which stimulate root
development and promote healthy Orchid
growth put the okra and chopped potatoes
in the
jar add 1 liter of water
close the
lid wait overnight for the nutrients to
dissolve into the
water next I use oatmeal as a natural
fertilizer take 3 tbsp of
oatmeal add 1 liter of water
[Music]
wait
overnight after one
night stir well so that the flour
nutrients dissolve into the water
[Music]
filter out
residue step
one use a soft cloth to gently wipe the
top and bottom of the Orchid Lea leaves
with the okra and potato soaked water
solution removes dust and residue
improving the plant's ability to
photosynthesize the okra and potato
solution supplies natural nutrients
through the leaves
leaves become shinier softer and
healthier the solution may form a
protective layer reducing the risk of
pest infestations on orchid leaves
gently wipe each Leaf both the upper and
lower surfaces ensuring the solution is
evenly
applied do it one or two times per month
for best
results this method keeps orchids clean
healthy and thriving
step
two put this solution in a spray bottle
and Mist the entire orchid
plant spraying adds moisture especially
in dry conditions
spraying ensures the solution covers the
entire plant from Roots to stems and
leaves spraying ensures the solution
covers the entire plant from Roots to
stems and
leaves forms a natural protective layer
reducing the risk of pest
infestations do it one to two times per
month for best
results step three after spraying use a
soft cloth to blot excess water from
orchid leaves
water pooling on leaves especially in
crevices can cause rot if left too
long a damp environment can attract
fungi and bacteria harmful to
orchids protects Orchid Le keeps leaves
dry glossy and
healthy this habit keeps your orchids
clean healthy and minimizes potential
pest or disease issues
step
four now I mixed the oatmeal solution
with the okra and potato solution
this mix provides amino acids
polysaccharides and natural starches to
encourage longer stronger roots
then you water the Orchid roots with
this mix
solution the solution stabilizes
moisture levels enhancing nutrient
absorption
[Music]
made from natural ingredients it's safe
for orchids and the
environment this mixture is a fantastic
natural nutrient Source helping orchids
grow robustly and Bloom
beautifully do it one one to two times
per month for best
results and I soaked the Orchid root in
this mix solution for 20
[Music]
minutes soaking softens The Roots
increasing their ability to absorb water
and nutrients
[Music]
afterward after 20 minutes take it out
and place the Orchid pot in a place with
plenty of
[Music]
light placing the Orchid in a well-lit
area helps it dry properly reducing the
risk of mold or
pests light AIDS the Orchid in
photosynthesis converting nutrients to
promote strong growth
[Music]
results after 50
days the Orchid grows two new flower
branches orchid leaves become glossier
thicker and healthier with a vibrant
green color
[Music]
now we'll check the roots
wow Orchid Roots grow very strongly this
clearly improves and enhances the
ability to absorb nutrients and water
with strong root and leaf growth the
Orchid will absorb nutrients more
efficiently from the surrounding
environment
now I'm repotting the Orchid into a new
pot for better
growth I plant with pine bark to help
retain moisture and ventilation
when planted in a new pot the Orchid
will grow faster
goodbye after planting you take care of
orchids like other normal plants
take care of your Orchids with all the
love you have for plants and you will be
rewarded with beautiful blooms a healthy
Orchid and the satisfaction of nurturing
your
plant thank you for watching and see you
in the next
videos Wishing success in caring for
your orchids and having beautiful
flowers welcome to my
channel when the flowers bloom nutrition
will focus on the
bloom so after the flowers bloom the
Orchid will weaken if you don't know how
to take care of
it so in this video I continue to share
how to make organic fertilizer to help
orchids
[Music]
Thrive let's get
started this is the Orchid after
[Music]
blooming the Orchid becomes weak and its
leaves wilt
[Music]
first remove yellow leaves and damaged
Roots this helps prevent the Orchid from
rotting further
[Music]
removing damaged Roots will help prevent
rot from spreading to healthy roots
[Music]
then cut off the wilted flower stems
then take one aloe vera leaf
[Music]
aloe vera is rich in vitamins a c e and
minerals such as calcium potassium and
magnesium which help improve plant
health and enhance
[Music]
photosynthesis apply aloe vera gel to
the cut so it doesn't rot and heals
quickly because aloe vera gel has
antibacterial and antifungal properties
it helps protect plants from diseases
[Music]
aloe vera gel helps provide moisture to
the plant helping it recover quickly
when the leaves wither
[Music]
wipe the top and bottom of the leaf
evenly
[Music]
using aloe vera gel also helps plants
reduce stress caused by changes in the
environment or care conditions uh
especially good for orchids with wilted
leaves like this plant
[Music]
which country are you watching videos
from please comment for
me it's great that we can chat together
from all over the world
[Music]
don't forget to subscribe and hit like
if you found the video helpful this will
help the channel grow and you won't miss
any orchid care tips
[Music]
applying this gel to the tree trunk will
help stimulate root growth in this
[Music]
location doing this one to two times a
month will be very good for weak orchids
then leave it for one day without
watering to help the cut heal
[Music]
completely cut the remaining aloe vera
leaves into thin slices
[Music]
then put it in a jar
add 1 liter of water at room
[Music]
temperature add 3 teaspoons of rice
rice especially rice water has many
effects in restoring wilted and weak
[Music]
orchids then incubate and place in a
cool place for one day to help the
nutrients completely dissolve
[Music]
one day
later stir well so that the nutrients
dissolve into the water
[Music]
then filter this water
add one liter of
[Music]
water add some sterilized moss on top of
the Orchid
[Music]
pot this helps Orchid pots retain
moisture better
[Music]
now water and soak the Orchid pot in
this water
[Music]
enzymes and vitamins in aloe vera gel
stimulate root growth helping the plant
absorb water and nutrients
[Music]
better aloe vera gel provides necessary
nutrients helping plants Sprout and
flour quickly
[Music]
do it twice a month
soak the Orchid pot in this water for 20
minutes to help the Orchid Roots absorb
the best
nutrients um and when soaked like this
the insects in the Orchid growing medium
will also die or run
[Music]
away next pour this water into the spray
bottle
[Music]
then spray this water on the entire
orchid
[Music]
this method is similar to fure
fertilization for
[Music]
orchids uh at the same time it also
helps wash away dirt mold and insects on
the leaf surface from there orchid
leaves will photosynthesize light better
[Music]
do it
twice after soaking for 20 minutes take
out the Orchid
[Music]
pot place it in a place with lots of
scattered sunlight so the Orchid can
photosynthesize and the plant can
[Music]
grow results after 50 days
after only 50 days many new Roots Grew
From a weak Orchid with withered leaves
and withered
[Music]
Roots orchid leaves are glossier and
greener
[Music]
when the roots develop the Orchid can
easily absorb water and
[Music]
nutrients will help orchids quickly
recover withered leaves
[Music]
harder and glossier leaves will help
with better photosynthesis and
metabolism
[Music]
when healthy orchids will continue to
grow and Bloom in in the next
[Music]
cycle hopefully the video will help you
a lot in taking care of orchids at home
[Music]
uh if you find it interesting please
like and share so more people know this
Orchid growing
[Music]
tip and if you haven't subscribed yet
please subscribe to my channel for
[Music]
support I always pray for blessings for
everyone on this
[Music]
Earth thank you for watching the video I
wish you a wonderful day and look
forward to seeing you in the next
video Welcome to my channel wishing you
a nice day to help you have many choices
when caring for orchids at home using
natural methods in this video I continue
to share new methods helps orchids bloom
continuously all year round with large
beautiful flowers the or orid grows many
new plump and healthy
[Music]
Roots let's get
started do you have
coffee put one teaspoon into the
[Music]
jar add 500 mL boiling water
stir cover brew and let the water cool
[Music]
next I need
oatmeal add 500 M boiled
water if you haven't subscribed to the
channel yet please do so to support me
and to make sure you don't miss any
Orchid growing tips on my channel
wait for the water to
[Music]
cool 2 hours
later stir
[Music]
filter out coffee
grounds which country are you watching
the video from please comment below
it's amazing that we can connect and
chat from all around the
world add 500 mL of water
[Music]
method
one use soft cotton to absorb this water
then wash both the top and bottom of the
orchid leaves helps leaves clean of dirt
mold and insects residing on leaves
[Music]
cleaning the leaves regularly will keep
your orchid Lush and shiny the stom will
open and the plant will photosynthesize
better it also helps quickly heal Leaf
damage
[Music]
coffee contains a lot of nitrogen an
important element for plant growth
nitrogen helps plants grow green and
healthy leaves
coffee has antibacterial properties and
can help repel certain
pests washing leaves with coffee grounds
helps remove dirt and impurities helping
the leaves receive light better and
photosynthesize more effectively
doing this one to two times a month will
help protect the Orchid
then pour this water into the jar
[Music]
you use a spray bottle containing the
solution and spray mist on all leaves
and roots of the
Orchid this method has the same effect
as using foler fertilizer provides
plants with nutrients that are easy to
penetrate and absorb through the leaf
surface with powerful antioxidant
compounds this type of fertilizer will
help orchids increase their
resistance protect orchids from
developing comprehensively from roots
stems and leaves promotes Buds and
Flowers to bloom
regularly water your orchid every 2
weeks this
way um you should do it in the morning
so that by noon when the sun comes up
the leaves will be
dry stir
filter and mix the oatmeal with coffee
water
method
two when the roots turn silver white
it's best to water the
[Music]
roots you water each Orchid with this
Liquid Fertilizer
coffee and oats contain many minerals
and organic substances that help provide
nutrients for orchids to grow it
contains very high levels of nitrogen
potassium and magnesium important
nutritional elements for the Healthy
Growth of orchids it stimulates orchids
to bloom early with more vibrant flowers
[Music]
uh if you water your orchids regularly
every 1 to two weeks it will be very
good
once a month you can soak the Orchid pot
in this fertilizer solution for about 20
[Music]
minutes after 20 minutes take out the
Orchid pot and place it in a place with
lots of scattered sunlight so that the
Orchid can photosynthesize and exchange
nutrients
[Music]
well please join us to see if the tree
is growing well
[Music]
after only 3 weeks many new Roots have
grown new Roots help the plant absorb
water and necessary nutrients from the
environment this is very important for
plant growth especially during the
flowering stage
Roots help keep the tree standing
creating stability and reducing the risk
of falling especially in strong wind
environments or when the tree is tall
[Music]
the growth of new Roots often stimulates
the growth of other parts of the plant
including leaves and flowers the plant
will have enough energy to grow and
[Music]
flower although roots are not directly
involved in photosynthesis they provide
water and nutrients to leaves where
photosynthesis takes
[Music]
place uh newly velop Roots often signal
that the plant is in healthy condition
creating favorable conditions for
flowering and
[Music]
blooming Roots also participate in the
plants respiration process helping to
provide oxygen to cells this is very
important for the life of the tree
Orchids with strong roots will produce
many
buds this Orchid of mine produces a lot
of buds
[Music]
when the flowers bloom they are bright
and plump the flowers stay on the
branches for a long time before
[Music]
fading hope you like this video please
comment to let me know if you like this
[Music]
video thank you for watching the video
good luck and success in life