[Music]
Welcome to a little corner full of love,
where flowers tell a story of happiness
everyday. To give you more options in
taking care of orchids at home,
especially with natural fertilizers that
help the plant grow vigorously and bloom
sustainably, today I continue to share a
new fertilizer recipe. Simple, easy to
make, and anyone can do it at home.
Um, if you haven't subscribed to the
channel yet, please hit the subscribe
button to support me and not miss any
orchid growing tips. It's wonderful to
have you
along. Let's get
started. Um, to keep the orchid fresh
and healthy, we need to regularly check
and remove old roots, yellowing leaves,
and damaged flower spikes. This is the
way to rejuvenate the plant and prepare
it for new growth.
[Music]
Damaged roots, if not cut off in time,
will weaken the plant, make it prone to
pests and diseases, and hinder the
nutrient absorption process, thereby
negatively affecting the growth and
blooming of the orchid.
[Music]
Afterwards, removing yellow and wilted
leaves will help the plant focus its
energy on nurturing healthy leaves and
more vibrant
[Music]
blooms. Please leave a comment and let
me know which country you're watching
the video from. It's wonderful that we
can connect and chat from all around the
world.
[Music]
Next, removing old flower spikes that
have finished blooming will help the
plant save energy and focus on stronger
new buds.
[Music]
We also need to remove wilted flowers so
that nutrients concentrate on the
remaining flowers on the stem, helping
the blooms last longer and the flower
spikes become bigger and plumper.
[Music]
Uh you can clearly see that the
remaining flowers on the stem become
bigger and more
vibrant. And when the fading flowers are
removed, new buds will develop uh
helping your orchid bloom for a longer
time.
[Music]
To make today's natural fertilizer, the
first ingredient I want to introduce to
you is
[Music]
tobacco. Tobacco contains nicotine, a
natural compound that can repel harmful
insects from orchids. In addition,
tobacco also helps clean the surface of
roots and leaves, creating better
conditions for the plant to absorb
nutrients.
[Music]
Take the tobacco from one cigarette and
put it into a jar. Then pour in about
0.5 L of boiling water to steep and
extract the
solution.
[Music]
Close the lid and wait for the water to
cool completely before
using. The second ingredient we will use
today is banana. Uh a familiar fruit
rich in nutrients.
[Music]
When eating bananas, don't rush to throw
away the peel. Keep it to make natural
fertilizer for orchids or other
plants. We cut the banana peel into thin
slices.
[Music]
Then put the sliced banana peel into a
jar and pour in one liter of boiling
water to steep and extract the
[Music]
nutrients.
Close the jar lid and wait for the water
to cool completely before using.
[Music]
After the water cools, strain out the
tobacco residue to collect a clear
solution ready to use for your
[Music]
orchid. Please comment and let me know
which country you are watching the video
from. It's wonderful that we can chat
together from all around the world.
[Music]
After straining, add 1.5 L of clean
water to have a total of 2 L of diluted
nutrient solution ready to use for your
orchid.
Then pour a portion of the mixture into
a spray bottle for convenient
application of the nutrients to the
orchid.
Step one, spray this mixture evenly over
the entire orchid from the leaves to the
stem and even the roots if possible.
[Music]
Be sure to spray thoroughly on both the
top and underside of the leaves as the
underside is often where insects and
fungal diseases tend to hide.
[Music]
Spraying the solution on the leaves
helps prevent pests and diseases while
also providing nutrients directly to
keep the leaves green, healthy, and
growing better.
Step two, evenly water this mixture into
each orchid pot so that the nutrients
penetrate deeply into the roots and
growing
[Music]
medium. Watering the tobacco solution on
orchids has many important effects.
First, it helps repel harmful insects
living in the growing medium, protecting
the plant from pests and diseases.
[Music]
Second, the solution also has the
ability to disinfect the growing medium,
preventing the development of fungal
diseases and keeping the growing
environment clean and safe.
[Music]
Third, the tobacco solution provides
essential natural nutrients, helping the
orchid grow strong from within.
[Music]
You can see that this tear on the leaf
is a sign that insects have been eating
the orchid
leaves. Insects love to eat tender young
leaves, then burrow into the growing
medium to gnaw on new roots. This
weakens the orchid, slows its growth,
and makes it more susceptible to
disease. When watering with the tobacco
solution, the insects hiding in the
growing medium will be forced to come
out, making it easier for you to detect
and deal with them in
time. After watering, soak the orchid
pot in the solution for about 20 minutes
to allow the nutrients to deeply
penetrate and help push insects out of
the growing medium more effectively.
You can see that after soaking the
insects hiding in the growing medium
have crawled up to the surface clearly
showing the effectiveness of the
solution.
[Music]
You can see that after soaking the
insects hiding in the growing medium
have been forced to crawl up to the
surface clearly demonstrating the
effectiveness of the solution.
[Music]
You can see this orchid pot I planted
with moss has high moisture, so it
easily attracts snails that like to hide
in this damp
[Music]
environment. During the day, when there
is sunlight, snails usually burrow into
the growing medium to eat the newly
sprouted young roots. At night, they
crawl onto the surface of the pot to
feed on the tender young leaves.
[Music]
Insects feeding on new roots and young
leaves not only make the orchid look
unsightely, but also cause diseases like
root rot and leaf rot while seriously
weakening the
plant. Removing snails and insects helps
protect the orchid from damage, prevents
diseases, and also helps the plant grow
strong and bloom more beautifully.
[Music]
With this method, after soaking for
about 20 minutes, We can easily pick up
the insects and snails without using
harmful chemicals.
[Music]
Now we strain out the residue to collect
the soaking solution from the banana
peel which is used to care for the
orchids.
[Music]
Step three, water this mixture evenly
into each orchid pot so that the
nutrients penetrate. ate deeply into the
roots and growing
[Music]
medium. The natural nutrients in banana
peel, such as potassium and phosphorus,
help orchid roots grow strong and
improve their ability to absorb water
and nutrients from the growing medium.
[Music]
Uh thanks to the abundant vitamins and
minerals in banana peel, uh orchid
leaves are wellnourished, reducing
yellowing and increasing photosynthesis
capacity.
[Music]
Potassium in banana peel is an important
element that helps orchids bloom fully,
maintain vibrant color, and last longer,
keeping your orchid pots always bright
and beautiful.
[Music]
Step four, use a soft cloth to gently
wipe off any water droplets on the
surface of the leaves and in the leaf
crevices to prevent mold and disease
from developing.
[Music]
For the tear on the leaf caused by
insects, I sprinkle a little cinnamon
powder on the cut. Uh, this helps
antibacterial, prevents infection, and
promotes faster healing of the leaf.
[Music]
This orchid was also once bitten by
insects, but the tear healed very
quickly after I sprinkled a bit of
cinnamon powder on the cut.
Step five, place your orchid pot in a
location with gentle sunlight to help
the plant photosynthesize well and grow
[Music]
healthier. Uh, everyday take a little
time to care for your orchid pots with
all the love you have for plants. In
return, you'll be rewarded with radiant
blooms and the simple joy that blossoms
from your little garden.
[Music]
I hope you enjoyed this video. If you
find it helpful, don't forget to hit
like and subscribe to the channel so you
won't miss future tips on how to care
for orchid naturally and
[Music]
simply. If you encounter any
difficulties while growing orchids,
don't hesitate to leave a comment. I'm
always here to help you grow healthy
orchids that bloom
[Music]
beautifully. Thank you for taking the
time to watch the video. Wishing you
good health and lots of joy with your
beautiful orchids. Goodbye and see you
in the next video.