hello everyone and welcome back to
happiness
Garden today I'll share with you how to
make natural fertilizer from bananas to
help your orchids grow healthy and Bloom
Bloom beautifully all year
round banana is always my choice for
making natural fertilizer to encourage
more flowers because bananas contain a
lot of potassium and natural minerals
that are very beneficial for orchids
[Music]
if you found this information helpful
don't forget to like subscribe and hit
the notification Bell to watch more
videos now let's get
started to make this natural fertilizer
today I'm using one green banana which
is rich in nutrients providing essential
vitamin and minerals to help your
orchids grow and Bloom
[Music]
healthily what country are you watching
this video from let me know in the
comments
below it's amazing that we can chat and
connect with each other from all around
the world
[Music]
next I put the banana into the blender
add 300 M of water and and blend it into
a smooth
[Music]
mixture if you haven't subscribed to the
channel yet click the Subscribe button
and hit the notification Bell so you
won't miss any new videos
uh pour the Blended banana mixture into
a bottle and add another 700 M of water
to create a liquid solution
add one teaspoon of sugar to help the
mixture ferment and prevent it from
spoiling finally add 1 teaspoon of yeast
to ensure the the fermentation process
goes perfectly and to prevent
spoilage stir well then place the
mixture in a cool dry Place avoiding
direct sunlight for 1 month
[Music]
after 1 month the mixture becomes a
wonderful fermented natural fertilizer
for orchids
[Music]
take 50 mL of the mixture which is
approximately 00132 Gall us
[Music]
then dilute it with 1 liter of water
which is approximately 0.26 417 Gall
us the nutrients and bananas help
stimulate root growth allowing the
Orchid to develop a strong root system
and grow more
vigorously bananas are rich in
pottassium vitamin B and minerals that
help promote plant growth especially
during the blooming stage
[Music]
the fermented mixture helps strengthen
the plant's immunity allowing the Orchid
to resist certain types of fungi and
bacteria uh step one use a soft cotton
pad to soak the mixture then gently wipe
both the top and bottom of the
leaves this not only cleanse the leaves
and improves the photosynthesis process
but also prevents pests and diseases
helping the plant stay healthy and grow
strong currently my channel supports
multiple languages including English
Italian French German Portuguese and
Spanish you can go to the settings and
select your preferred language to enjoy
the best video
experience um for countries without an
audio language option you can go to the
settings and select subtitles in the
appropriate language to better
understand the video content
in addition this method provides
nutrients directly through the leaves
helping the plant absorb them more
quickly and grow
better step two if you have many Orchid
pots you can pour the mixture into a
spray bottle
[Music]
then spray the mixture over the entire
orchid plant just like f your feeding to
effectively provide nutrients through
the
leaves this method also helps wash away
dirt mold and insect that may cling to
the surface of the
leaves additionally spraying this
mixture helps the plant stay healthy
enhances its ability to photosynthesize
and stimulates the growth of roots and
leaves
please avoid spraying this solution
directly on the flowers because it may
cause them to become damaged or Wilt
flowers are more sensitive to excess
moisture and nutrients which can
negatively affect their appearance and
longevity
[Music]
step three water the roots with this
mixture to provide essential nutrients
stimulate healthy root growth and ensure
the roots effectively absorb the
necessary elements from the soil
[Music]
you water the diluted mixture into the
roots and growing medium to provide the
necessary nutrients for the plant to
grow
[Music]
healthily this fertilizer helps the
plants Roots absorb essential vitamins
and minerals for Healthy Growth
it helps boost the plant's immunity
preventing common diseases caused by
bacteria and
[Music]
fungi it helps maintain the right level
of moisture and prevents root rot caused
by overwatering or excessive
[Music]
humidity step four use a soft cloth to
gently blot any any excess mixture on
the leaves to remove impurities prevent
the Orchid from becoming overly damp and
keep the leaves clean and well
[Music]
ventilated this method helps keep the
Orchid well ventilated preventing common
diseases especially rot caused by
excessive humidity
[Music]
then place the Orchid pot in a location
with gentle sunlight to allow the plant
to photosynthesize enhance nutrient
exchange and promote its
[Music]
growth follow all four steps for each of
your orchids every 10 to 15 days to
ensure they grow healthy and achieve the
best results
for orchids that have finished blooming
it's crucial to remove the old flower
spikes and any damaged Roots this allows
the plant to focus its energy on Healthy
Growth and future
[Music]
blooms this will help redirect the
plant's energy towards new New Growth
promote stronger
roots and encourage the development of
future
blooms regular maintenance like this
will ensure your orchid stays healthy
and thrives for the next blooming cycle
then I use the fermented banana
fertilizer and follow the four steps I
outlined at the beginning of this video
to care for this
Orchid if you haven't subscribed to the
channel yet please subscribe to support
my channel don't forget to like share
and hit the notification Bell so you
won't miss any new videos thank you for
your
support if you follow the steps I've
outlined your orchid will surely recover
quickly and Bloom beautifully in the
next flowering season
for orchids affected by Soft rot we need
to take a different approach to care
ensuring the plant doesn't rot further
and recovers quickly this includes
removing the affected Parts improving
air flow and using the right treatments
to help the plant
[Music]
heal properly trimming the affected
areas improving air circulation and
applying appropriate treatments are
crucial steps in helping the Orchid heal
and recover these actions will encourage
Healthy Growth and prevent further
damage
next use a soft cotton pad to soak the
fermented banana fertilizer mixture and
gently wipe both the top and bottom of
the
leaves this will help remove dust
insects and harmful fungi that could
damage the
Orchid then place the Orchid in a cool
well-ventilated area and refrain from
watering for one week to allow the plant
to recover on its own
the result after using this natural
fertilizer is that you'll notice the
leaves becoming Greener shinier and
stronger than
before the flower buds will appear in
abundance plump and won't Wilt or drop
before blooming
hundreds of flower buds have appeared
and are not falling off promising a
vibrant new blooming
season this natural fertilizer also
helps the flower petals grow larger and
stay on the stem for a long time before
wilting the flowers can stay on the stem
for up to 6 months before before the
petals
fall I hope this video will be very
helpful in taking better care of orchids
at
home if you found this helpful don't
forget to like share and subscribe to
support my
channel welcome to my
[Music]
channel in this video I share the method
of recovering weak orchids helping them
quickly take root and grow
[Music]
strongly I picked up a rotten Orchid
that someone had thrown away
[Music]
all the roots have rotted
which country are you watching this
video from please comment and let me
know uh it's wonderful that we can
connect and chat with each other from
all around the world
[Music]
this original part has completely rotted
so it can no longer be
[Music]
used wash Orchid branches with water
then take one clove of garlic and mince
it
[Music]
add 500 M of water and soak for 30
minutes letting the flour nutrition
completely dissolve in
[Music]
water after 30
minutes wiping Orchid branches with
garlic water helps disinfect and
eliminate fungal diseases
[Music]
then soak the Orchid branches in garlic
water for 10 minutes this helps
stimulate root and choot growth
[Music]
10 minutes later
because this orchid has many scars from
previous insect bites so I waited a day
for the Orchid to dry completely before
planting
[Music]
it one day
later I recycle sponges as orchid
nursery tools
[Music]
soaking the sponge in garlic water for
20 minutes helps disinfect and kill
fungus
[Music]
20 minutes
later insert the Orchid stem into the
sponge and place place it in the
[Music]
vase pour some water into the jar and
change it every time it gets
[Music]
dirty Spray moisturizer every 3 days and
place it in a cool well-lit place
[Music]
5 Weeks
Later The Roots have grown very healthy
[Music]
The Roots have grown very healthy
I planted it in a pot so the Orchid
could grow better
[Music]
if you find the video interesting please
like and share so more people know this
[Music]
tip water orchids regularly to keep them
moist
[Music]
subscribe to my channel to support me
and don't miss any tricks on my
[Music]
channel welcome to part two of this
video uh in part two of this video I
share how to care for orchids to help
them grow and Bloom
you can see that my orchids always
develop new flower stems after the old
flowers have fallen
off so my orchids bloom all year round
blooming from Branch to branch
[Music]
the flowers on the stems take a long
time to fall off they can even last up
to 6 months before the petals
[Music]
drop many flowers grow on the same tree
new Roots grow a lot to help absorb
nutrients
[Music]
best chubby flower buds
help flowers bloom long on
[Music]
branches brilliant
flowers how to make fertilizer as
follows use one small carrot weighing
about 30
[Music]
G cut into small pieces
add 1 liter of filtered
[Music]
water
puree filter out red residue
[Music]
add 1 ler of filtered
water then use cotton to soak carrot
juice and wipe both the top and bottom
sides of the leaves
[Music]
this method helps repel insects and open
the stamata the orchids will
photosynthesize and exchange nutrients
[Music]
better at the same time orchids also
absorb some nutrients through the leaves
helping keep the leaves green
[Music]
for
second
[Music]
way water this carrot for
orchids carrot juice is a good source of
nutrients for orchids including vitamins
and minerals like beta carotene
potassium magnesium and
[Music]
phosphorus uh when when the carrot juice
is poured into the Orchid pot it
provides nutrients to the orchids and
helps to promote their
[Music]
health in addition carrot juice is also
acidic which helps regulate the pH of
the Potted soil and enhances the
orchid's ability to absorb
nutrients you can soak the Orchid pot in
this carrot juice for 20 minutes
[Music]
do this one two times a
month Third
[Music]
Way Mist moisturizing carrot juice for
orchids by spraying both the top and
bottom of the leaves this helps wash
away dirt and eliminate insects on your
orchids the nutrients in carrot juice
support Orchid Health helping them
Thrive and Bloom
[Music]
beautifully however be careful not to
overwater with carrot juice as it can
clog the water channels in the Orchid
avoid spraying directly on the flowers
as this can cause them to fall off
quickly I hope this video helps you take
better care of your orchids at home and
encourages them to bloom
easily um if you find it helpful and
interesting please like share and
subscribe to support my channel thank
you welcome to part three of today's
video to give you more options for
taking care of your orchids at home
using organic fertilizer in this video I
continue to share methods for making
natural fertilizer from everyday kitchen
ingredients you can find in your
[Music]
home subscribe to the video so you don't
miss any tips on my channel
[Music]
number
one to make this fertilizer you need
[Music]
apples apples contain potassium an
important mineral for orchid growth
[Music]
potassium helps orchids develop stronger
leaves roots and
[Music]
flowers uh I took the apple peel and put
it in a bottle
[Music]
soak in boiled water and leave overnight
number
two to make this type of fertilizer you
need more eggshells
[Music]
soak the eggshells in boiled water and
leave
[Music]
overnight leave overnight
after one night filter the water
[Music]
so we have fertilizer from apples and
eggshells first method
water this fertilizer Solution on the
Orchid
[Music]
Roots eggshells provide natural calcium
which is very good for orchids they help
orchids stay healthy and increase
resistance
[Music]
apple peels contain a lot of phosphorus
which is also an important nutrient for
orchid growth
[Music]
especially during the flowering and
flower development
[Music]
stage do this one to two times a month
to supplement nutrition and increase the
orchid's resistance
[Music]
second
method spray this fertilizer on the
entire
[Music]
orid this method is similar to using
foler
[Music]
fertilizer calcium and eggshells helps
orchid kids stay healthy and increases
their resistance to
[Music]
pests apples contain nitrogen an
essential nutrient that helps orchids
develop healthy green growth and
enhances their ability to
photosynthesize
[Music]
do not spray on flowers because wet
flowers will easily fall off
[Music]
third
method clean the leaf surface with this
Liquid Fertilizer
[Music]
the leaf surface will always be clean
and
[Music]
Airy orchids will photosynthesize better
fertilizing regularly one to two times a
month will help keep the leaves
[Music]
healthy number
three you can reuse eggshells and apple
peels to make fertilizer again
[Music]
let's check out the results
together this type of fertilizer
stimulates rooting very
[Music]
quickly after 1 month of use you will
see great results
[Music]
many flower buds develop and do not fall
blooming flowers stay on the branches
for a long time before
[Music]
fading flowers can remain on branches
for up to 6 months before falling
[Music]
thank you for watching the video good
luck and see you in the next videos
[Music]