[Music]
Hello everyone. Today I'm sharing a way
to propagate orchids using a simple and
easy method that anyone can
do. Please cut across here to take the
flower spike for propagation using the
cutting method.
[Music]
When the petals have just faded, it's
the best time to take cutings for orchid
[Music]
propagation. The parts of the flower
that have already fully bloomed can no
longer be used for
propagation. And choose the raised or
protruding parts of the flower spike.
[Music]
After that, peel off this outer layer.
a new plant will begin to grow right at
this spot.
[Music]
cut again to avoid damaging the cut
surface.
[Music]
If you haven't subscribed to the channel
yet, please hit the subscribe button to
support me and not miss any orchid
growing tips. It's wonderful to have you
along. Uh make a diagonal cut here as it
will help with easier water absorption.
Next, you need to prepare an aloe vera
leaf. Choose a fresh, thick leaf that is
not damaged.
Aloe vera has antibacterial properties
and helps the orchid grow
stronger. Once you have the aloe vera
leaf, cut it into thin
slices. Let me know in the comments
which country you're watching this video
from. It's amazing that we can connect
and chat from all over the world.
[Laughter]
After cutting the aloe vera into thin
slices, place them in a cup and add
about 500 ml of water.
Um, the water will help dissolve the
nutrients from the aloe vera, creating a
supplement that aids in the healthy
growth of the
orchid. To enhance the effectiveness,
you can add a little honey to the aloe
vera water
solution. Honey helps the orchid fight
bacteria and provides extra nutrients.
Just add about 1 teaspoon of honey to
the cup and stir well to mix the
ingredients.
Leave the cup of water in a cool place
for a few hours so the nutrients from
the aloe vera and honey dissolve into
the
water. After the solution has been
soaked for a few hours, use a strainer
to filter out the residue.
You only need to keep the clear liquid
which contains the dissolved nutrients
from the aloe vera and honey to nourish
the orchid in the best way.
After filtering out the residue, soak
the orchid cutting you want to propagate
in this aloe vera and honey mixture.
uh soak it for about 20 minutes to allow
the orchid cutting to absorb the
nutrients and boost its ability to
develop strong roots. This is an
important step to ensure the cutting can
thrive during the propagation
process. You can use the remaining aloe
vera and honey mixture to water other
orchids in your garden.
[Music]
Uh this solution will provide additional
nutrients for the orchid promoting
healthy growth from the roots to the
leaves. When watering the orchids, just
apply about 10 tablespoons of the
solution to each pot.
This amount of water will be enough to
provide nutrients without causing the
plants to become water
logged. Make sure to water evenly around
the base of the plant to help it absorb
the nutrients in the best way.
In addition to the English voiceover, we
have now created voiceovers in French,
German, Italian, Spanish, Portuguese,
Japanese, Hindi, and Indonesian to help
you listen and understand the content
more
easily. For languages without a
voiceover, we have created subtitles so
you can read and understand the content.
With the aloe vera and honey nutrient
mixture, you can water the orchid about
one to two times a
month. Um, after watering, place the
orchid pot in a spot with gentle
[Music]
sunlight. Soft light will help the
orchid with photosynthesis and
metabolism, promoting strong growth and
blooming.
Avoid direct intense sunlight as it can
cause the orchid's leaves to
burn. This is the floral foam I will use
to arrange the orchid cutting.
Floral foam helps keep the orchid
cutting in place and retains moisture,
creating favorable conditions for root
development.
After preparing the floral foam, get a
clear glass cup ready for rooting the
orchid
cutting. The glass cup not only allows
you to easily observe the cutting's
growth, but also creates a good humid
environment for the
plant. After soaking the orchid cutting
in the aloe vera and honey solution for
about 20 minutes, gently remove it and
use a clean paper towel to dry it.
[Music]
After drying, drip a bit of candle wax
onto the upper cut of the orchid
cutting.
[Music]
This helps protect the cut from bacteria
and fungi while also preventing moisture
from evaporating too quickly through the
cut, helping the cutting retain internal
moisture. It's a small but very
effective tip to increase the survival
rate of orchid cutings.
[Music]
Then insert the orchid cutting into the
floral foam, making sure the base is
securely and uprightly positioned.
Next, place the floral foam into the
clear glass container. This method helps
retain moisture for the orchid cutting
while also allowing you to easily
observe root development later on.
[Music]
After placing the cutting into the
floral foam, add filtered water to the
glass container, ensuring the foam is
moist but not submerged in
water. This helps maintain the necessary
moisture for the cutting without causing
root
rot. Make sure the floral foam doesn't
dry out as orchids need moisture to
develop roots and shoots. Remember to
add water when you notice the foam
getting
dry. Then cover the glass jar to
maintain moisture for the
cutting. After that, place the orchid
cutting in a spot with gentle sunlight,
avoiding direct intense
sunlight. Just be patient and the orchid
cutting will gradually develop roots and
grow into a new plant.
[Music]
Now after 3 weeks you can see that the
orchid cutting has sprouted and
developed
roots. This shows that the cutting
process has been successful and the
orchid is growing well.
Since the chute is still small and the
roots are weak, I will continue to root
the orchid uh cutting in the glass cup
for a while longer to allow the plant to
grow stronger.
After a while of rooting the cutting,
you should change the water in the glass
cup to ensure it stays clean and free
from impurities.
You can change the water weekly or when
you notice the water in the cup becoming
cloudy. Be sure not to leave the water
in the cup for too long as this could
affect root development.
[Music]
After 5 weeks, you'll notice that the
chute has sprouted leaves and the roots
have become stronger.
Since the leaves are still weak and the
roots are young, I've decided to
continue rooting the orchid cutting in
the glass cup for a little longer so the
plant can grow stronger and develop more
steadily.
during this time. Make sure the plant
still receives gentle sunlight and that
the water remains clean.
[Music]
Once the leaves and roots have developed
stronger, I will transfer the plant to a
larger pot to continue caring for it.
[Music]
If you face any difficulties during the
orchid cutting process, don't don't
hesitate to leave a comment. I'm always
ready to support you so you can
successfully propagate healthy orchids.
After 8 weeks, the new chute is healthy
with vibrant green leaves and strong
roots. Your orchid has successfully
passed through the fragile early stage
and is now thriving.
At this point, you can transfer the
plant to a pot to continue caring for it
and allow it to fully develop.
[Music]
When transferring the orchid to a pot,
you can use pine bark chips as the
growing medium.
Pine bark helps with good drainage,
maintains the right level of humidity,
and creates an ideal environment for
orchid roots to
grow. Make sure the pot has good
drainage holes to prevent root
rot. Before placing the orchid into the
pot, spread a thin layer of moss on the
surface. This moss layer helps retain
moisture in the growing medium, creates
favorable conditions for root
development, and helps keep the orchid
stable during the early stage after
[Music]
planting. Then place the orchid on top
of the moss layer and gently pack moss
around the roots to secure the plant in
place.
Uh when the orchid is healthy and has a
strong root system, we can start
fertilizing it after repotting to
stimulate better
[Music]
growth. To make the fertilizer, I use
500 ml of water and 1 tbsp of rice. Then
let it soak for a few hours.
[Music]
This mixture will be an excellent
natural fertilizer for orchids,
especially those that have been cut from
stems and replanted in new pots.
[Music]
After soaking for a few hours, we filter
the rice water and use it to water the
orchid.
[Music]
Rice water contains many natural
nutrients that help stimulate root
growth and provide essential vitamins
for the plant.
After that, you can water the orchid
with rice water about one to two times a
[Music]
month. Regular watering will help
provide nutrients to the plant without
overwhelming it.
Be sure to observe the condition of the
plant to adjust the amount of water
accordingly. On regular days when the
substrate is dry, you just need to mist
or water the orchid
lightly. This helps maintain the
necessary moisture for the plant without
causing water logging as orchids do not
like overly wet soil.
[Music]
after 3 months. The orchid has grown
strong and sturdy from a cutting.
The roots have grown strong, the leaves
are lush and green, and the orchid is
ready for the next blooming stage. This
result proves the effectiveness of
proper care, cutting, and natural
fertilization.
[Music]
I continue to fertilize the orchid
regularly with natural rice fertilizer
twice a month, helping the plant grow
strong and maintain long-term health.
[Music]
Uh the result is that after 6 months you
can see the orchid has matured blooming
vibrant flowers that brighten up the
[Music]
space. You can see that patience is the
most important factor in the journey of
caring for orchids.
From the early days of cutting a stem to
taking care of each small stage, every
step requires time and meticulous
attention. And now, after months of
patient waiting, we have a healthy
orchid blooming brilliantly and lighting
up the
space. I hope this video will be helpful
to you in propagating orchids at home.
If you found the video useful, don't
forget to like and share it to help more
people. If you haven't subscribed to the
channel yet, don't forget to click the
subscribe button and turn on the
notification bell so you won't miss any
upcoming useful
videos. Thank you all for watching and I
wish you success with your orchids.