Hello orchid enthusiasts.
Today I'm excited to share with you how
to make homemade organic fertilizer that
helps orchids thrive from their roots,
stems, leaves to flowers with easy to
find ingredients and a simple process.
This fertilizer not only provides
essential nutrients but also protects
the environment.
Let's get started.
To fertilize orchids, I use green tea.
Green tea is not only rich in
antioxidants, but also provides
essential nutrients for plants.
Amino acids and minerals in green tea
help plants grow strongly, increase
resistance, and enhance leaf color.
[Music]
In addition, green tea also improves
soil structure and effectively retains
moisture.
Uh, take 10 g of green tea and put it in
a jar.
[Music]
Uh, take 10 g of green tea and put it in
a jar.
[Music]
cover and wait for it to cool.
1 hour later.
[Music]
Uh, if you haven't subscribed to the
channel yet, please click the subscribe
button to support me and not miss any
orchid growing tips. It's great to have
company.
[Music]
Filter out residue.
Add one liter of water about four cups.
Step one.
Use a soft cotton soaked in tea water to
gently wipe the top and bottom of the
leaves thoroughly.
Compounds in tea have antibacterial
properties helping to prevent mold and
disease.
[Music]
Tea water contains many minerals and
amino acids, helping to provide
additional nutrients to plants.
In addition to the English dub, we've
now created dubs in French, German,
Italian, Spanish, Portuguese, Japanese,
Hindi, and Indonesian to help you hear
and understand the content more easily.
Do you have pets? That's my maid.
[Music]
Cleaning dirt from leaves helps leaves
absorb light better, thereby improving
photosynthesis.
Uh tea water helps maintain moisture in
leaves supporting the growth process.
[Music]
Using diluted tea helps plants increase
resistance and fight against harmful
agents.
Which country are you watching videos
from? Please comment for me.
Uh it's great that we can chat together
from all over the world.
[Music]
In short, this not only helps the plant
stay healthy but also beautifies the
orchid leaves.
Step two,
[Music]
put diluted tea into a spray bottle.
Then spray the substrate, roots, stems,
and leaves of the orchid.
Spraying green tea water also provides
moisture, helping the leaves stay fresh
and reducing stress on the plant.
Green tea spray helps plants increase
their resistance to harmful agents,
making them healthier.
Tea water helps clean leaves, allowing
them to absorb light better and improve
photosynthesis.
Be careful not to spray on flowers.
Water standing on flower petals can
cause rot, especially in humid
conditions, leading to premature flower
deterioration.
[Music]
Standing water on flowers creates
conditions for fungi and bacteria to
grow, causing disease in the plant.
[Music]
When an orchid rots like this flower,
you need to cut it off immediately to
avoid spreading the rot to other
orchids.
To make fertilizer for the roots, I need
more grapes.
Just take two grapes and put them in a
blender.
[Music]
Add 300 mls of water, about one cup.
Grapes contain many vitamins, minerals,
and natural sugars which help provide
essential nutrients to the roots.
puree.
Then mix with green tea.
[Music]
Three,
grapes can promote the growth of
beneficial microorganisms in the soil,
support the decomposition process, and
improve soil structure.
Green tea provides minerals and amino
acids, while grapes provide vitamins and
natural sugars, helping the plant
receive adequate nutrition.
Both green tea and grapes have
antibacterial properties which help
prevent diseases and protect plants from
mold.
[Music]
Natural sugars in grapes help enhance
the roots ability to absorb nutrients.
[Music]
Grapes contain antioxidants which help
increase the plant's resistance to
harmful factors.
[Music]
Compounds in green tea and grapes help
increase the plant's resistance to
harmful agents.
[Music]
This combination helps promote the
growth of beneficial microorganisms in
the soil, improving soil structure and
moisture retention.
[Music]
After watering, soak the orchid pot in
this water for about 20 minutes.
[Music]
20 minutes later,
take the orchid pot out and place it in
a place with lots of scattered light so
the orchid can photosynthesize more.
[Music]
now. Let's see the results.
Healthy orchid roots play an important
role in absorbing nutrients and helping
the plant bloom.
[Music]
Well-developed roots help plants become
more stable, facilitating the growth of
stems, leaves, and flowers.
[Music]
Strong roots help plants retain moisture
better, which is important in
maintaining the health and growth of
orchids.
[Music]
Roots absorb nutrients necessary for
photosynthesis, helping plants have
enough energy to grow and flower.
[Music]
Strong roots also help plants resist
diseases and adverse environmental
factors, thereby supporting stable
flowering.
when absorbing enough nutrients and
light. The leaves are healthy and shiny
green.
[Music]
When the roots absorb enough nutrients
and water, the plant is able to focus
its energy on flower development,
creating beautiful and healthy flowers.
[Music]
Thus, the healthy growth of orchid roots
not only helps the plant survive but
also promotes brilliant blooming.
[Music]
Finally, dedicate your love and care to
your plant companions.
Nurture your orchids with all your heart
and you will be rewarded with their
stunning beauty.
[Music]
Goodbye for now and I look forward to
seeing you in the next videos.
[Music]
Wishing you all the luck and success in
your plant care journey.