Welcome to my channel where we explore
the beauty of orchids together and learn
how to care for them in a gentle,
natural, and loving way.
Today, I will share how to take care of
a newly purchased orchid, helping it
quickly adapt, grow strong from the
start, and avoid stress.
I bought this orchid for just $1 at a
small local flower shop. A small gift,
but full of hope for my garden.
You can see that there is still a lot of
mineral salt residue on the leaf
surface, making the leaves look dull and
lose their natural glossy green color.
Looking through the transparent pot, we
can see many new roots growing. But to
be sure the plant is truly healthy, we
still need to carefully check the
growing medium and the condition of the
roots inside.
[Music]
You can see that alongside the new roots
growing, there are also many old roots
that have become hollow and no longer
function to nourish the plant.
[Music]
Let me know in the comments which
country you are watching from. It's
wonderful that we can connect and chat
together from all around the world.
And if you haven't subscribed to the
channel yet, please hit the subscribe
button to support me and not miss any
orchid care tips. It's wonderful to have
you along.
[Music]
From a quick inspection, I see that the
growing medium is quite dry and not
water logged. However, for the plant to
grow its best, we should remove about
half of the old medium and repot the
plant into a new, larger pot.
[Music]
It's best to remove the moss in the core
as this moss retains moisture for too
long, which can easily cause the roots
to suffocate and rot.
[Music]
After that, cut off all the damaged,
rotten, and hollow roots to help the
plant stay healthy and make it easier
for new roots to grow.
[Music]
In addition to the English voiceover, we
have now created French, German,
Italian, Spanish, Portuguese, Japanese,
Hindi, Dutch, Polish, Korean, and
Indonesian voiceovers to help you listen
to and understand the content more
easily.
Uh, to listen in your language, open the
video and click on settings, the gear
icon to select the appropriate audio
language.
[Music]
Next, prepare four cups of water
equivalent to about one liter for us to
mix the solution.
[Music]
Add 1 tsp of baking soda to the water to
make the solution.
Baking soda helps clean the roots and
growing medium, eliminate bacteria and
mold, and reduce the risk of root rot
before repotting.
[Music]
Then pour this mixture in and soak both
the roots and the moss for about 20
minutes to clean them completely.
[Music]
After that, you need to treat any fungus
in the growing medium before repotting
to protect the new roots and help the
plant grow safely.
[Music]
Add it to one liter of water.
Then add 1 teasp of baking soda and stir
well.
[Music]
Soak the growing medium for about 20
minutes to eliminate fungus and
bacteria.
After soaking for about 20 minutes, take
the growing medium out, let it drain
completely, and then get ready to repot
the orchid.
Not only does it eliminate fungus, but
the baking soda solution also helps
balance the pH in the growing medium,
creating an ideal environment for strong
root growth.
If you have any difficulties during the
orchid planting process, don't hesitate
to leave me a comment. I'm always ready
to support you so you can grow healthy
orchids that bloom abundantly.
I chose a pot with drainage holes at the
bottom and a size that fits the newly
purchased orchid for repotting.
I placed a piece of foam at the bottom
of the pot along with a few smaller
pieces to secure the steak, help the
plant stand upright, and at the same
time create erration for the roots.
[Music]
Then gently repot the orchid into the
pot, preparing for the plant's new
growth phase.
[Music]
After placing the plant in the pot, add
pine bark around it to secure the plant
and help the roots get more air.
[Music]
After adding the pine bark, spread a
thin layer of moss on top of the pot to
help retain moisture in the growing
medium and create an ideal environment
for the orchid to grow.
[Music]
Next, secure the orchid to the stake to
help the plant stand upright and grow
straight, preventing it from leaning or
breaking its roots.
[Music]
After repotting, place the orchid in a
cool, airy spot for about a day without
watering, allowing the plant to
stabilize and the roots to adapt to the
new environment.
[Music]
Now I will prepare the natural
fertilizer. To make the fertilizer, put
3 teaspoon of rice into a clean jar.
[Music]
Next, add four cups of water, equivalent
to about one liter.
Close the jar and place it in a cool
airy spot for 1 day to allow the mixture
to ferment naturally.
[Music]
After one day, stir the mixture well so
the nutrients are evenly distributed and
ready for fertilizing the orchid.
[Music]
Then strain out the residue to get the
clear solution ready to be used as
fertilizer for the orchid.
[Music]
Step one, use a soft cloth to soak up
this mixture and gently wipe both the
top and bottom surfaces of the orchid
leaves.
Fermented rice water helps uh wash away
the mineral salt residue still left on
the leaves. usually from spraying
inorganic fertilizer in industrial
orchid gardens.
This way, the leaves return to their
natural green color and become
healthier.
[Music]
The vitamins, enzymes, and beneficial
microorganisms in fermented rice water
are absorbed directly by the leaves,
nourishing the plant from leaf to root,
helping it grow fully and stay lush.
Gently wiping the leaves combined with
the nutrients in rice water promotes
nutrient circulation within the leaves.
This helps the plant absorb nutrients
more effectively and enhances its
photosynthesis capacity.
Wiping the leaves not only cleans off
dust but also provides a gentle massage
reducing stress for the plant. The
leaves become shiny and the plant is
ready to grow vigorously.
[Music]
Step two, pour the fermented rice water
mixture into a spray bottle for easy
application on the orchid leaves.
[Music]
Um, when spraying fermented rice water
on both the top and bottom surfaces of
the leaves, it helps remove dust and any
remaining fungi on the leaf surface,
especially in spots that weren't
thoroughly wiped. This keeps the leaves
clean and healthy.
The vitamins, enzymes, and beneficial
microorganisms in the rice water are
absorbed by the leaves when sprayed,
allowing the leaves to take in nutrients
directly, uh, promoting photosynthesis
and boosting the plant's vitality.
Regular spraying helps form a thin
protective layer on the leaves,
preventing fungi from redeveloping and
keeping the leaves clean and shiny,
creating an ideal environment for the
orchid to grow vigorously.
Step three, water the fermented rice
water mixture directly onto the roots
and growing medium, providing natural
nutrients to the orchid from within.
Watering the fermented rice water
mixture directly onto the roots and
growing medium provides natural
nutrients, stimulates strong root
growth, enhances nutrient absorption,
and improves the overall vitality of the
orchid.
[Music]
Perform all three steps twice a month.
In addition, water the orchid whenever
the growing medium is dry and place the
pot in a spot with gentle sunlight to
help the plant grow healthy.
[Music]
And here are the results after 3 weeks
of care.
[Music]
Uh you can see many new roots have grown
healthy and ready to support the plant's
vigorous growth.
[Music]
These new roots are growing strong,
dense, and display white, pink, and
fresh green colors, indicating that the
plant is recovering and growing very
well.
They not only help the plant stay stable
in the pot, but also create a solid
foundation for the leaves and flowers to
grow in the coming weeks.
The leaves have become lush and glossy,
reflecting fresh vitality after the care
process.
Glossy green leaves help the plant
absorb light better, enhance
photosynthesis, and nourish the new
roots, young leaves, and flower buds.
What do you think about the way I care
for my newly purchased orchid? Please
leave a comment with your thoughts and
feedback for me.
If you care for your orchids with all
the love you have for plants, they will
respond with strong roots, lush green
leaves, and vibrant, lively flowers.
[Music]
The flowers will bloom, spreading
fragrance and vibrant colors as a reward
for your love and dedicated care.
They will bring joy, peace, and a sense
of accomplishment every time you admire
your orchid garden.
I hope you enjoy this video and find
useful orchid care tips to keep your
plants healthy and blooming beautifully.
If you find the content helpful and
meaningful, don't forget to like, share
so more people can see it and subscribe
to support me. Thank you for always
being with me.
Thank you for watching. Goodbye and I
wish you lots of joy with your beautiful
orchid pots.
[Music]