Welcome to my garden, where every orchid
tells its own story. In today's video,
I'll continue to share with you a simple
yet incredibly effective secret. How to
make a natural fertilizer that helps
orchids grow strong, root quickly, and
especially bloom three times more. With
just a little patience and love for your
plants, you'll see your garden filled
with gentle colors and sweet fragrances.
[Music]
Let's get started.
This is an orchid. After all, its petals
have withered, leaving only the bare
stem after its blooming season. When the
flowers fade, the plant often weakens
because it has used up all its energy to
nourish those beautiful blooms.
Therefore, if not cared for properly,
the orchid can easily become exhausted,
grow slowly, or even suffer from root
dryness and leaf yellowing. But don't
worry, with just a bit of care and
natural nourishment, you can help your
orchid recover quickly and prepare for a
new vibrant blooming season.
First, you need to gently cut off the
entire old flower spike. This helps the
plant stop wasting energy on the
withered part and instead focus on
nourishing new roots and leaves.
After that, carefully check the roots of
the plant.
You can gently squeeze each root with
your fingers. If the roots are green and
feel firm, it's a sign that they're
still healthy.
On the other hand, if the roots have
turned dark, feel soft, or are hollow
inside, it means they've rotted and need
to be cut off immediately to prevent the
rot from spreading to other roots.
Cleaning the roots will help the plant
absorb nutrients better and quickly
regain its vitality after flowering.
[Music]
Please comment below and let me know
which country you're watching from. It's
wonderful that we can connect and share
together from all around the world.
And if you haven't subscribed yet,
please click the subscribe button to
support me and not miss any orchid care
tips. It's wonderful to have you along
on this journey.
[Music]
Next, remove any damaged or yellowing
leaves. These leaves can no longer
photosynthesize and may become a hiding
place for fungi and insects. By removing
them, the plant no longer has to share
its energy with weak leaves, allowing it
to focus on nourishing the healthy ones
and stimulating stronger new shoots.
[Music]
And if the growing medium is still in
good condition, meaning it's dry, clean,
and not decomposed, then you don't need
to repot to repot the orchid.
Next, sprinkle a little cinnamon powder
over the cut areas. Cinnamon has natural
antibacterial and antifungal properties
that help the wounds dry quickly and
prevent rot from spreading.
[Music]
This is a simple yet very effective way
to protect the plant after pruning while
also stimulating the growth of stronging
of stronger new roots. Just a little
cinnamon powder can bring great power to
your orchid's revival.
[Music]
After sprinkling the cinnamon powder,
let the plant rest for about a day and
avoid watering it. This resting period
allows the cut areas to dry completely,
preventing water or bacteria from
entering and causing root rot.
Next, we'll prepare a natural fertilizer
to help the orchid recover quickly. The
first ingredient is onion, a familiar
bulb that contains many nutrients
beneficial for the plant.
Take about 20 g of onion, then cut it
into small slices so the nutrients can
easily dissolve in water. Onion helps
stimulate root growth, fight bacteria,
and restore the plant's vitality after
flowering.
After chopping the onion, put all of it
into a clean container. Then, pour in
about one liter of freshly boiled water.
The hot water will help extract the
valuable nutrients from the onion,
creating a solution rich in natural
vitamins and minerals.
[Music]
After that, cover the container tightly
and let the solution sit for about 1
day. This resting time allows the
nutrients from the onion to fully
dissolve into the water, creating a
concentrated and nutrient-rich natural
mixture.
[Music]
The next ingredient is rice, a familiar
component that provides excellent
nutrition for orchids. You only need 3
teaspoons of rice. Not too much as this
small amount already contains enough
starch and minerals to nourish the
roots. Rice helps the plant absorb
natural energy, recover quickly, and
make the leaves greener and shinier.
Then pour one liter of room temperature
water into the container with the rice
and close the lid tightly.
Let the mixture sit for about 1 day to
allow the rice to ferment slightly. This
process activates natural enzymes and
beneficial microorganisms enhancing the
nutritional value of the solution.
[Music]
After one day of resting, stir the onion
solution well so that all the nutrients
are completely dissolved.
[Music]
Next, strain out the residue to obtain
the clear liquid. This is the part that
contains the most nutrients and is safe
for the orchid roots.
After that, stir the rice water well so
that the nutrients produced during
fermentation are completely dissolved.
Next, strain out the residue and mix it
with the onion water prepared earlier.
The combination of onion and rice
creates a balanced natural fertilizer.
It not only helps fight bacteria, but
also provides energy to the roots.
Step one, use a soft cloth soaked in the
natural fertilizer mixture you just
prepared. Then, gently wipe both the
upper and lower surfaces of the leaves.
This helps the leaves absorb nutrients
directly and removes dust that has
accumulated over time.
[Music]
Uh the natural vitamins, minerals, and
enzymes in onion and rice water easily
penetrate the leaf surface, helping the
plant recover quickly with thicker,
greener, and shinier leaves.
Onion has strong antibacterial
properties that help clean the leaf
surface, eliminate bacteria and mold,
keeping the plant healthy and less prone
to diseases.
[Music]
When the leaves are clean and healthy,
the plant absorbs light more
effectively, promotes strong
photosynthesis, and activates root
growth, helping the orchid fully revive.
[Music]
Step two, after wiping the leaves,
directly water the natural fertilizer
mixture onto the roots and growing
medium.
[Music]
Um, this allows the roots to gradually
absorb nutrients, nourishing the plant
from the base to the leaves and
preparing new shoots for strong growth.
The natural mixture of onion and rice
water not only provides energy but also
stimulates the roots to anchor firmly in
the growing medium creating a solid
foundation for the orchid to bloom in
the next season.
Water gently and evenly so the
fertilizer penetrates deeply without
disturbing the roots or growing medium.
Next, take a soft cloth and soak it
evenly with the natural fertilizer
mixture.
Then, place the cloth in the leaf axles
right at the spots where you want to
stimulate the plant to produce new
flower spikes.
[Music]
The nutrients will be absorbed directly
at this point, promoting the formation
and growth of flower buds, helping them
become bigger, healthier, and more
vibrant when they bloom.
This is a simple yet very effective tip
to lay the foundation for a thriving
next flowering season.
Uh, leave the cloth soaked in fertilizer
in the leaf axle for about 20 minutes so
the nutrients can penetrate deeply into
the area that needs stimulation.
[Music]
Step four, pour the natural fertilizer
mixture into a clean spray bottle. Using
a spray bottle helps evenly distribute
the fertilizer onto the leaves, roots,
and leaf axles without harming the
plant.
When sprayed gently, the nutrients are
evenly absorbed, helping the leaves stay
lush, the roots grow strong, and
naturally stimulating the development of
flower buds.
This is the final step to complete the
care process, resulting in a vibrant
orchid ready for the new flowering
season.
Use a spray bottle to evenly mist the
fertilizer mixture over the growing
medium and roots. This allows the roots
to absorb nutrients directly while
keeping the medium adequately moist,
creating a favorable environment for
strong root growth.
When the roots are well nourished, the
orchid will recover quickly. Its leaves
will stay lush and green, and it will be
ready for new flower buds.
After spraying, let the orchid sit in
the fertilizer mixture for about 20
minutes. This period allows the
nutrients to penetrate deeply into the
roots and growing medium, effectively
nourishing the plant from the base to
the leaves.
[Music]
After soaking for 20 minutes, take the
orchid pot out.
At the same time, gently remove the
cloth from the leaf axles and let the
plant continue to rest. Do this once a
week consistently for a few weeks and
you'll see strong new flower spikes
ready for vibrant blooms. This is a
delicate care method that helps the
orchid grow evenly and bloom beautifully
without using chemicals.
Step five. After letting the plant rest
in the fertilizer mixture, if there is
any water remaining on the leaves,
gently blot it dry with a soft cloth.
[Music]
This helps prevent mold and bacteria
from growing on the leaf surface while
keeping the leaves dry and healthy.
Clean leaves absorb light better,
promote effective photosynthesis, and
support the overall growth of the
orchid. This is a small but very
important step to protect the plant's
long-term vitality.
Any remaining fertilizer mixture can be
poured into a spray bottle and used on
other orchids in your garden.
When sprayed onto the leaves and growing
medium, the natural vitamins, minerals,
and enzymes from onion and rice water
penetrate deeply into the roots and
leaves. This helps the orchid absorb
nutrients quickly, resulting in lush
green leaves and stronger roots, ready
for overall healthy growth.
Onion has natural antibacterial
properties, while fermented rice water
provides enzymes and beneficial
microorganisms.
Spraying the mixture helps prevent mold,
bacteria, and common leaf and root
diseases, keeping the orchid healthy.
[Music]
When the leaves are nourished and clean,
the plant absorbs light more effectively
and photosynthesis occurs vigorously.
The leaves become glossy, thick, and
vibrant, giving the orchid plenty of
energy to support flowers and new
shoots.
[Music]
And here are the results after 6 weeks
of the orchid's recovery.
You can see the roots growing strong and
vigorous, spreading throughout the
growing medium.
New roots emerge quickly while the older
roots remain sturdy, firmly anchoring
into the medium and pot, creating a
solid foundation for the plant.
[Music]
The leaves become glossy, firm, and full
of vitality. Inside each leaf is a rich
source of nutrients, ready to nourish
the roots and new shoots.
And especially, you can see that the
orchid has grown two new flower spikes
full of vitality. These flower spikes
are proof of the effectiveness of caring
with natural fertilizer, helping the
plant recover quickly after the old
flowers have faded.
[Music]
>> With just a few weeks of patience, the
orchid not only becomes healthy again,
but is also ready to bloom brilliantly
in the next season. This is truly a
well-deserved reward for the love and
care you give to the plant.
>> This recovery process is a wonderful
testament that with patience and proper
care, any orchid can revive and bloom
beautifully.
Don't be discouraged if your plant was
once weak or had yellowing leaves. Every
step of care, every drop of natural
fertilizer contributes to building new
vitality for the orchid.
[Music]
Gradually, with patient and proper care,
your garden will also bloom brilliantly
all year round, full of color and
vitality. You will see lush green
leaves, strong roots, and new flower
buds continuously emerging, just like my
garden, showcasing its vibrant beauty
right before your eyes.
I hope you enjoy this video and find
plenty of useful information for caring
for orchids. If you find the video
valuable, please like, share so more
people can see it, and subscribe to
support me. Your support is the
motivation for me to continue sharing
tips for growing healthy blooming
orchids in future videos. Thank you for
watching and see you in the upcoming
videos.
[Music]