Welcome to my channel where I share
gentle, natural, and easy to understand
ways to care for orchids.
Today, I will show you how to revive a
rotting orchid like this.
Uh, when the orchid has lost all its
leaves, leaving only the bare stem and a
few dry roots, don't assume it's dead.
In fact, there is still hidden life
inside waiting to be awakened. With a
little patience and love, you will see a
miracle happen. New shoots will
gradually begin to appear again.
[Music]
You can still see a few fresh roots.
That's a sign that the orchid is quietly
alive and waiting for a chance to come
back.
With proper care, these roots will
continue to grow and nourish the whole
plant back to health.
The first step is to gently inspect the
entire root system and trim away any
damaged or rotten parts.
Removing the dead roots will help the
plant focus its energy on nourishing the
healthy parts and prepare for the
recovery process.
[Music]
uh leave a comment and let me know which
country you're watching from. It's
wonderful that we can connect and chat
from from all around the world.
[Music]
After trimming the roots, you can apply
a bit of melted candle wax to the cut
areas.
This layer of wax will help protect the
wound, preventing water from seeping in
and reducing the risk of stem rot. A
small but very important step to ensure
the plant recovers safely.
[Music]
If you haven't subscribed yet, please
hit the subscribe button to support me
and never miss any orchid growing tips.
It's truly wonderful to have you along
on this journey.
[Music]
Prepare a clean container. Then add
about 2 teaspoon of cinnamon powder.
Cinnamon powder not only has natural
antibacterial properties but also helps
stimulate strong root growth, making it
very useful in the orchid's recovery
process.
[Music]
[Applause]
Next, pour one liter of boiled water
into the container. The hot water will
help extract the maximum nutrients and
essential oils from the cinnamon powder,
creating a natural solution that both
disinfects and stimulates orchid root
growth.
[Music]
After adding the boiling water, simply
cover the container and let it sit until
the water has completely cooled.
[Music]
Once the water has cooled, use a clean
cloth or strainer to remove the
remaining cinnamon powder residue.
[Music]
Careful straining will make the solution
clearer, easier to absorb, and safer to
use on orchid roots.
[Music]
Once you have the clear cinnamon
solution, gently place the orchid stem
and roots into it and soak for about 20
minutes.
This is the ideal time for the
antibacterial and growth stimulating
properties of the cinnamon to deeply
penetrate the plant tissue, helping to
protect and support effective recovery.
You can pour the remaining solution into
a spray bottle to make use of it. Um,
lightly spraying it on the leaves and
roots of other healthy orchids will help
boost their resistance, prevent fungal
diseases, and stimulate better daily
growth.
[Music]
After soaking for 20 minutes, you can
gently take the plant out and start
replanting it in a new pot.
This is the perfect time for the plant
to begin its journey of revival with a
solid foundation from the roots that
have been cleaned and protected.
You should use pine bark combined with
dry pummus to repot the plant. Uh this
growing medium mixture allows for quick
drainage, keeping the roots dry and well
airrated, which helps prevent water
logging and root rot. Uh one of the main
causes of orchid decline. You can spread
a thin layer of moss on the surface of
the pot after planting. After planting,
place the orchid pot in a cool spot with
gentle light for 3 days and avoid
watering to let the cuts dry. The roots
adapt to the medium and prevent rot.
After 3 days, you can start watering
lightly to keep the plant moist.
Uh when the growing medium is dry,
lightly mist the roots and surface of
the pot to maintain moisture. Consistent
care will help the plant recover and
grow well.
You can use a clear plastic container
with ventilation holes to cover the
orchid pot.
The stable, humid environment inside
will help the plant recover more
quickly.
And here is the result after 3 weeks of
consistent care.
If you look closely, you'll see a tiny
new shoot starting to emerge from the
stem. The first sign of this orchid
pot's hopeful journey of revival.
[Music]
And here is the result after 2 months of
attentive care.
From a stem that once seemed lifeless,
it has now revived into a vibrant young
orchid with strong roots and fresh green
leaves reaching upward day by day.
[Music]
The revival journey of this orchid is
proof that with patience and love, even
what once seemed withered can bloom
again.
Every drop of water, every ray of light,
and every day of care is a small gift
you give to the plant. and it will
respond with amazing vitality. Don't
give up because miracles often begin
with the simplest things.
[Music]
Um, I hope you enjoy this video. If you
find it helpful, don't forget to like
and subscribe so you won't miss upcoming
tips on natural and simple orchid care.
Thank you for taking the time to watch
the video. Wishing you happiness and
many healthy orchids in your living
space. Goodbye and see you in the next
videos.
Welcome to my channel.
[Music]
Today I will show you how to revive a
rotten orchid like this.
[Music]
When the orchid has withered all the
leaves and only the stem and roots, do
not rush to throw it away.
[Music]
Where are you watching the video from?
Please leave a comment and let me know.
It's amazing that we can chat together
from all around the world.
Uh here the branches are still fresh.
My video features voiceovers in six
languages: English, French, German,
Spanish, Portuguese, and Italian.
Additionally, I have subtitles in
various other languages around the world
for you to choose from.
I will remove all wilted and rotten
leaves.
[Music]
And I remove all the broken roots.
Um, if you haven't subscribed to the
channel yet, please hit the subscribe
button to support me.
[Music]
I keep only the fresh roots that are
left over.
[Music]
I cut off the flower stock so that the
orchid can concentrate nutrients for the
new sprout to grow.
Rinse with water.
[Music]
Apply melted candle solution to the cut
to prevent water from seeping into the
tree.
[Music]
use three cloves of garlic and mince.
Soak garlic in one liter of water at
room temperature.
Incubate for one day.
[Music]
At the same time, spread in a cool place
for one day.
[Music]
One day after
Filter out residue.
[Music]
Soak orchid branches in garlic water for
20 minutes.
[Music]
The rest of the water I will spray on
other orchids to help protect the orchid
from insects and fungi. At the same
time, garlic juice also stimulates the
development of roots and flower sprouts
very well.
[Music]
20 minutes after
After soaking for 30 minutes, plant.
Using pine bark or dry pummus stone to
plant will help absorb moisture in the
roots, making the orchid roots not rot.
[Music]
Put in a cool place for one week without
watering.
[Music]
One week later.
From now on, water the orchid to keep it
moist.
[Music]
Then place it in a place with light
sunlight. The best temperature is 20 to
25° C.
[Music]
Regularly spray moisture to spread life
and revive faster.
2 weeks after
[Music]
Use three emulators of GE ginger water
mixed with one liter of water.
[Music]
Um, GE ginger juice is considered an
organic fertilizer that helps to
stimulate plant growth very well.
[Music]
Water this G ginger every 10 days.
Continue
[Music]
to place the plant in a place with light
sunlight.
Uh cover with a clear vented plastic
container and wait for the plant to
revive.
1 month later,
the root system is very well developed.
When the roots are strong like this, you
can fertilize the orchid with organic
fertilizer like I shared on the channel
uh to help the orchid grow healthier.
Hope this sharing content will help you
in resurrecting weak orchids to grow
again.
Hope this sharing content will help you
in resurrecting weak orchids to grow
again.
[Music]
Um the video I have created many
subtitles. You can you can choose the
appropriate language to understand my
sharing.
[Music]
Welcome to part two of the video.
Today I share with you an amazing
organic fertilizer and anyone can do it
easily.
Just one to two ripe bananas and the
orchid garden will bloom all kinds of
flowers.
Now I will revive this orchid with new
[Music]
Um, you've seen this orchid lose all its
flowers, leaving only withered branches.
And here are the withered orchids that
have been revived with lots of new
flowers.
Step one.
[Music]
Cut off the withers.
Apply toothpaste on the cut.
[Music]
Don't throw away banana peels when
eating bananas.
[Music]
Don't throw away banana peels when
eating bananas.
[Music]
Clip the banana peel to to the place
where the flower buds can grow
[Music]
and note to remove after 6 hours.
This helps to create the right moisture,
provide essential nutrients and
stimulate flower sprouts.
[Music]
Do this once a week.
Step two.
Use a banana peel to wipe the top and
bottom of the leaves. This helps
eliminate insects, fungi, bacteria
hiding on orchid leaves and at the same
time provides a part of nutrients
through the leaves for orchids.
[Music]
This method also helps the orchid plant
to be protected and not be affected by
yellowing or rotten leaves.
[Music]
After wiping you will see green leaves.
Orchids will photosynthesize eyes better
to increase resistance.
[Music]
Step three,
one liter of water.
[Music]
Leave in a cool and dark place for one
day.
[Music]
After one day,
banana juice is darker.
[Music]
Use this absorbent cotton.
Clip a cotton ball where the flower buds
can grow
and note to remove after 6 hours.
Uh this helps to to create the right
moisture, provide essential nutrients
and stimulate flower sprouts.
Do this once a week.
Step four.
[Music]
Normally after 3 to 4 weeks, flower buds
will be formed and develop like this.
Um, with a flower sprout this big,
there's no need to sandwich banana peels
with cotton balls.
[Music]
You will be surprised how amazing this
is.
[Music]
Don't forget to subscribe to see my next
videos.
[Music]
Five.
Add water to make 2 lers. Water this
banana for orchids once every two to
three weeks.
Banana peel is rich in potassium,
phosphorus, and essential vitamins.
Will promote the growth of orchid roots.
In particular, the potassium in banana
peel stimulates flowering very well.
[Music]
In addition, you need to combine using
other organic fertilizers for orchids
like manure made from soybeans, peas,
fish poop as I shared.
[Music]
Hope this sharing content will help you
in taking better care of orchids at
home.
Um, if you find the video interesting,
don't forget to like, share, and
subscribe to support my channel.
Welcome to part three of the video.
In part three, I share a new way to help
spread more roots, branches, and flower
buds.
[Music]
Join me in discovering this wonderful
way to make organic fertilizer.
[Music]
Uh to make this type of fertilizer, you
need one branch of ginger.
[Music]
Where are you watching the video from?
Please leave a comment and let me know.
It's amazing that we can chat together
from all around the world.
[Music]
After slicing, put into a glass jar.
Then add one spoon of yeast.
This is the yeast used to make bread.
And add one teaspoon of honey.
[Music]
and one liter of warm water.
incubate in a dark place for one week.
[Music]
One week later.
Take three tablespoons of fermented
ginger solution.
[Music]
Add one liter of water.
First method,
use cotton balls dipped in organic
fertilizer solution from fermented
ginger.
[Music]
Uh then place it in the places where you
want to take root and sprout.
[Music]
After 6 hours, take the cotton out.
Do it once a week.
[Music]
method two.
If you want this branch to continue
blooming,
[Music]
then add cotton and clip it.
After 6 hours, take the cotton out.
[Music]
Do it once a week.
Method three.
[Music]
Um, if you want this button to continue
growing flower buds,
[Music]
um, if you want this button to continue
growing flower buds,
[Music]
This helps the buds grow faster.
Apply toothpaste to the cut.
[Music]
This helps the cut heal quickly.
Then stuff cotton into the button with
this sleeping bud.
[Music]
After 6 hours, take the cotton out.
Method four.
[Music]
use a fertilizer solution from fermented
ginger after the leaves.
[Music]
helps kelps kill fungi and insects very
well.
[Music]
Cleaning the stamata helps orchids
photosynthesize well.
method five.
Apply this liquid fertilizer to the base
of the orchid.
[Music]
This type of fertilizer helps stimulate
the growth of roots, branches, and buds
very well.
[Music]
Method six,
spray the fertilizer solution from
fermented ginger on the entire orchid.
[Music]
supports nutritional supplementation
through leaves very well.
Let's check the results together.
[Music]
After 2 months, the sprouts and roots
developed very well.
[Music]
The flower buds have also developed and
are ready to bloom.
[Music]
The buds at the tips of the branches
continue to grow and bloom.
[Music]
Sprouts also grow in leaf axles.
Many branches grow on the same tree.
The flowers bloom on the branches for up
to 6 months before falling.
[Music]
The roots are likened to the soul of the
orchid.
Orchids grow healthy thanks to healthy
roots.
Um, if the roots are healthy, the the
orchid will also grow many flower buds.
[Music]
In this video, I will show you how to
make orchids grow roots and flower buds
quickly.
[Music]
You need one fresh ginger, about 50 g.
Put in a jar. Recommended plastic jar.
[Music]
Add 3 tablesp of sugar. Any sugar will
do.
Add in 100 ml of filtered water.
[Music]
Add in 100 milllers of beer. Any beer is
fine.
[Music]
Cover and keep in a dark place for 1
month.
Open the lid once every 3 days to let
the gas out.
[Music]
One month later,
uh, the smell of GE ginger is fermented,
so it's very fragrant.
[Music]
The ratio of mixing is 3 ml of G ginger
for one liter of water.
[Music]
first way.
Soak cotton balls in water mixed with
ginger. GE.
[Music]
Place cotton balls soaked in GE ginger
between the leaves.
helps keep moisture and GE ginger
stimulates rooting and flower sprout
differentiation very quickly.
Change this cotton once every 3 days.
[Music]
On normal days when the cotton is dry,
you just need to mist it with water to
keep it moist.
[Music]
Use this water to wash the top and
bottom of the leaves. Helps provide
nutrients through leaves, clean stamata,
eliminate harmful insects and fungi, and
help orchid photosynthesis the best.
[Music]
Wipe the orchid leaves with GE ginger
once a month so that orchids are best
protected and developed.
[Music]
Way three.
Use GE ginger water to water orchids.
[Music]
Uh, yeast brewed from fresh ginger has
the effect of stimulating sprouting,
strong rooting, repelling insects,
killing fungi, stimulating buds, and
stimulating growth.
GE ginger also helps orchids increase
their ability to absorb nutrients from
the fertilizer you fertilize them.
Only do this one to two times a month.
Do not use too much as it will affect
the growth of orchids.
[Music]
See the results.
After one week of use, new roots grow
very quickly.
[Music]
These roots will help the orchid absorb
nutrients more easily and more.
Orchids grow well or not thanks to the
photosynthesis of roots and leaves.
[Music]
When the orchid is healthy, after the
orchid branch blooms the last flowers,
then there will be new flowers that
flowers that will continue to grow.
[Music]
My video features voiceovers in six
languages: English, French, German,
Spanish, Portuguese, and Italian.
Additionally, I have subtitles in
various other languages around the world
for you to choose from.
[Music]
With this simple way, you can do it
yourself to take care of orchids at home
at very low cost and convenience.
[Music]
I hope the video content will help you
take better care of orchids at home.
Thank you for watching the video.
Wishing everyone good luck and an
abundance of