Hello everyone.
Very happy to see you on my channel.
[Music]
Which country are you watching this
video from?
Please leave a comment to let me know
where you are. It's wonderful. It's
wonderful that we can connect with each
other from all around the world.
Uh, you see here a withered orchid.
Perhaps it's because they haven't been
watered regularly or because direct
sunlight has shown on the orchid.
If if you want the orchid to be
nourished and grow quickly, please watch
this video carefully.
[Music]
Checking the roots, I found that many of
them had rotted.
Cut off all the damaged roots.
[Music]
Only keep the fresh roots like this.
Cut off the yellow leaves.
[Music]
Cut off the old orchid stems that have
fully bloomed.
[Music]
Then rinse it clean with water.
Washing helps remove pathogens, mold, or
bacteria that could harm the plant.
Cleaning helps the plant recover faster
when replanting in a new environment.
When the roots are washed, the plant
will absorb water and nutrients better
from the new environment.
Next, I take an aloe vera leaf.
[Music]
Aloe vera gel has anti-inflammatory
properties, helping to soothe wounds on
the roots or leaves, supporting the
healing process.
Um, apply the gel to the wilted leaves
to help them recover quickly.
Aloe vera contains natural compounds
with antibacterial and antifungal
properties, helping to protect the plant
from common diseases.
[Music]
Aloe vera gel has great moisturizing
properties, helping the orchid maintain
the necessary moisture for its roots and
leaves, especially during the recovery
stage.
Next, cut the aloe vera leaf into small
pieces.
If you haven't subscribed to the channel
yet, please hit the subscribe button to
to support me and not miss any orchid
care tips. It's wonderful to have you as
a companion.
Then place them into a jar.
Add one liter of boiling water.
Add 3 teaspoons of rice.
[Music]
Cover the jar and wait for 30 minutes
for the nutrients to dissolve into the
water.
[Music]
30 minutes later,
stir the flour nutrients into the water.
[Music]
Then strain to get the
Then place the wilted orchid roots into
this glass.
Then soak the orchid roots in this water
for 30 minutes.
30 minutes later,
I plant the orchid in a new pot with
pine bark chips.
The chopped pine bark will help retain
moisture better.
[Music]
Um, add moss on top of the orchid pot to
help retain moisture better.
[Music]
Then water the orchid once every 5 days.
On regular days when the medium is dry,
just water it regularly.
[Music]
Then use a soft cotton pad to soak up
this water and wipe both the top and
bottom sides of the leaves.
Aloe vera contains many vitamins and
minerals providing essential nutrients
for the plant and helping to improve its
overall health.
Then place the orchid pot in a spot with
plenty of indirect light so the orchid
can photosynthesize.
[Music]
The result after 3 weeks.
The new roots are very healthy.
[Music]
The orchid has grown new leaves.
Uh the wilted leaves have become
greener. Continue
[Music]
fertilizing the orchid with aloe vera
leaves and rice water.
Dirt on the leaves can hinder the
photosynthesis process and cleaning them
helps the leaves absorb light better.
[Music]
Cleaning the leaves helps remove mold,
bacteria, and small insects, reducing
the risk of disease for the plant.
[Music]
Then water the orchid with aloe vera
water and rice water once every 5 days.
[Music]
When the medium is dry, just water the
orchid with regular water
[Music]
and place it in a spot with plenty of
indirect light for the plant to
photosynthesize. Well,
[Music]
the result after 2 months.
Healthy roots have developed.
[Music]
The new leaves at the top are growing
healthily.
The wrinkled, wilted condition of this
old leaf has improved and become
fresher.
[Music]
Uh when the root system is this healthy,
it will help the orchid recover quickly
and grow vigorously.
Continue
[Music]
fertilizing the orchid with aloe vera
leaves and rice water.
Wiping the leaves with this water will
help increase humidity around the plant,
especially in a dry environment.
[Music]
When wiping the leaves, you can easily
detect unusual signs such as spots,
discoloration, or pests so that you can
take timely action.
Then water the orchid with aloe vera
water and rice water once every 5 days.
[Music]
When the growing medium is dry, just
water the orchid with regular water.
[Music]
And place it in a spot with plenty of
indirect light so the plant can
photosynthesize. as well.
[Music]
The result after the next 2 months
from a weak orchid, it has now developed
normally and bloomed.
[Music]
Take care of your orchid with all the
love you have for it,
[Music]
and you will enjoy admiring the
beautiful flowers that you've cared for
yourself.
I hope you enjoyed this video. Please
leave a comment to let me know.
If you found the content interesting and
meaningful, don't forget to like, share
it so more people can know, and
subscribe to support me. Thank you for
always being with me.
If you encounter any difficulties in
growing orchids, don't hesitate to leave
a comment for me. I'm always ready to
support you so you can grow healthy
orchids that bloom beautifully.
Thank you for watching the video. I
always pray for blessings to be upon all
of you. Don't look away. The next video
will be very interesting.
Hello friends.
Nice to meet you on my channel.
You see here a withered orchid. Maybe
it's because you didn't water it or due
to direct sunlight shining on the
orchid.
[Music]
Um, if you want orchids to be nourished
and grow quickly, please watch this
video carefully.
[Music]
Now I will share this amazing trick with
you.
You need one aloe vera leaf.
[Music]
Which country are you watching the video
from? Please comment below.
It's wonderful that we can chat together
from all around the world.
This aloe vera gel is great for reviving
orchids.
Now apply aloe vera gel on the top and
bottom of the leaf.
[Music]
Aloe vera gel has a very good
moisturizing effect.
[Music]
In addition, aloe vera also contains
vitamins's A, B, and C and minerals such
as nitrogen, phosphorus, and potassium.
[Music]
Uh, do this every 5 days and leave the
orchid pot in a cool place for 3 weeks.
[Music]
Next, take one liter of warm water and
put it in the bottle.
[Music]
Then take one spoon of rice and soak it
in this water for about 30 minutes. Let
the nutrients in the rice completely
dissolve into the water.
[Music]
Chop the remaining aloe vera leaves into
small pieces.
[Music]
Then puree with 300 mm of water.
filter out residue. Then add 2 L of
water at room temperature.
[Music]
After soaking for 30 minutes, filter
this rice water.
[Music]
mix rice water with aloe vera juice.
So, I ended up with about 3 L of this
wonderful liquid manure solution.
[Music]
Cover the pot with moss to retain
moisture better.
[Music]
Now you use the solution to water the
orchid every 5 days.
[Music]
Soak the orchid pot in this water for 2
hours.
After soaking for 2 hours, remember to
lift the orchid pot and place it in a
cool place to let the orchid recover.
[Music]
Two weeks later,
Fertilize after 2 weeks for fresher
orchid leaves.
[Music]
New roots develop very well.
Many new roots are growing.
[Music]
new roots will help transport water and
nutrients from the roots to the stem.
If the leaves are provided with enough
water and nutrients from the roots, the
leaves will gradually become lush again.
[Music]
One month later,
you see the leaves are very fresh.
[Music]
And the orchid grows a new leaf.
after the next two months,
the orchid has grown two branches, two
buds.
But the leaves at the base have turned
yellow. So I will cut off these yellow
leaves.
[Music]
uh instinctively when an orchid buds, if
the plant lacks nutrients, the the base
leaves will turn yellow and fall off to
provide nutrients for the buds to
develop.
Now I need to supplement the orchid's
nutrition by taking three spoons of
rice.
[Music]
Uh then soak in 2 L of water at room
temperature
[Music]
and wait 30 minutes for the nutrients to
completely dissolve in water before
using.
[Music]
30 minutes later,
add 3 tablesp of milk.
[Music]
Rice water and milk are excellent
sources of nutrients for orchids to
grow.
[Music]
Now you water the orchid with this
solution once a week to help the orchid
recover quickly.
[Music]
after the next one month.
After three to four times of applying
liquid fertilizer from milk and rice
water, the orchid had many roots.
[Music]
Hope the video will help you a lot.
If you like the video, remember to hit
like, share, and subscribe to support
me.
Uh, thank you for watching the video.
Wish you luck and see you in the next
videos.
[Music]