Welcome to the Happiness Garden, where
we explore the beauty of nature together
and find joy in every moment of plant
care. If you love orchids and wish to
propagate and care for your orchids so
they grow strong, lush, and bloom all
year round, then this is the video for
you. If you haven't subscribed yet,
please hit the subscribe button to
support me and never miss any helpful
orchid growing tips. It's truly
wonderful to have you along on this
journey. Let's get
started. This is an orchid that has
finished blooming and I bought it at a
very low price to restore, propagate,
and help it bloom again in future
seasons. After orchids finish blooming,
they usually have been through quite a
long period, so we need to carefully
check their roots and repot them to help
the plant grow healthier.
[Music]
Uh you can see that because the orchid
pot has been used for a long time, mold
has appeared on the growing medium which
negatively affects the plant's
[Music]
growth. If this situation is left
untreated for too long, it will cause
root rot and weaken the orchid, even
risking the plant's death.
[Music]
uh we need to remove all the moldy
growing medium and replace it with fresh
clean medium to provide the best
conditions for root
[Music]
growth. Um next we will cut away all the
damaged roots to prevent disease spread
and help the plant recover faster.
[Music]
The spots where the flower buds have
bloomed cannot bloom again and will not
develop into kiki baby plants.
Uh, these two nodes haven't bloomed yet,
so we can stimulate them to grow into
Kiki baby plants or produce new flower
buds. Um, that's why I cut off the spent
flower nodes so the nutrients won't be
scattered and can focus on supporting
the potential growth of Kiki baby
plants.
Next, I prepare a natural fertilizer to
help restore the orchid and stimulate
the growth of Kiki Kiki baby plants on
the orchid
cutting. Take 3 tablesp of oat flour as
the main ingredient to provide natural
nutrients for the orchid.
Add one liter of water to the oat flour
to dissolve it and create a natural
fertilizer
mixture. Cover the container and wait
for 2 hours to allow the nutrients from
the oat flour to fully dissolve into the
water.
[Music]
Next, sprinkle turmeric powder on the
cut surface of the orchid cutting to
prevent bacteria and promote faster
healing.
[Music]
After 2 hours, strain out the sediment
to collect the clear liquid, which will
be used as a natural fertilizer for the
orchid.
Oat flour contains many natural vitamins
and minerals that provide essential
nutrients, stimulating orchid roots to
grow stronger and
[Music]
healthier. The antioxidants in oat flour
help boost the plant's resistance,
keeping orchid leaves green and
promoting healthy growth.
[Music]
Then add one teaspoon of honey into the
solution to boost nutrients and
stimulate the orchid's
growth. Honey has natural antibacterial
properties that help prevent the growth
of bacteria and fungi on cuts,
protecting the orchid from
infections. Then add three vitamin B1
tablets into the mixture to enhance
nutrient absorption and stimulate
stronger orchid root growth.
[Music]
Then use this mixture to soak the orchid
roots for about 20 minutes, helping to
disinfect and stimulate faster root
growth.
While waiting, I prepare stakes to
secure the orchid after planting,
helping the plant stand firm and grow
more
steadily. Please comment to me which
country you are watching the video from.
It's great that we can chat together
from all over the
world. In addition to English dubbing,
we have now created French, German,
Italian, Spanish, Portuguese, Japanese,
Hindi, and Indonesian dubbing to help
you listen and understand the content
easily.
[Music]
To listen to the language, open the
video and click settings gear icon to
select the appropriate audio language.
[Music]
Next, plant the orchid into a new pot
with fresh, nutrient-rich growing medium
to support better growth.
I choose crushed pine bark as the
growing medium because it provides good
drainage, retains moderate moisture, and
creates a well ventilated environment
for healthy orchid root growth.
Using stakes to secure the orchid after
planting prevents the plant from shaking
uh thus protecting the new roots from
damage or negative impact.
[Music]
Then water the orchid with this natural
fertilizer mixture to provide essential
nutrients and maintain moisture in the
growing medium after planting.
[Music]
From now on, use this mixture to water
or spray the entire orchid about two to
three times a month, helping the plant
stay healthy and grow well.
[Music]
When sprayed, the mixture supplies
nutrients directly through the leaves
and the growing medium, allowing the
orchid to absorb faster and develop more
[Music]
fully. The spraying process also helps
wash away dust and fungal pathogens on
the leaves, keeping the orchid cleaner
and healthier.
[Music]
Uh after spraying, use a soft cloth to
wipe off the water droplets on the
leaves to prevent mold growth and
protect the orchid from damage.
Next, I peel off the protective layer
covering the dormant buds on the stem
cutting, which helps the buds better
access air and nutrients, thereby
promoting faster growth.
[Music]
Then I use aloe vera leaves to stimulate
the growth of kiki baby plants from the
orchid stem cutting. Thanks to the
natural hormones and nutrients in aloe
[Music]
vera. Extract the aloe vera gel because
it provides moisture, nutrients, and
natural hormones that support the rapid
and healthy growth of kiki buds.
[Music]
Then apply or press aloe vera gel onto
the dormant kiki bud for about 30
minutes, allowing the nutrients to
absorb into the plant tissue and
stimulate the bud to awaken and begin
growing.
[Music]
Uh then wait about 30 minutes and take
cotton balls soaked in aloe vera gel out
of the sleeping orchid
buds. After 30 minutes, remove the
cotton. After that, if you place the
orchid pot in a cool and humid area, the
dormant bud will grow into a kiki
plantlet. However, if you place it in a
sunnier spot, the dormant bud will
develop into a flower
[Music]
bud. And here are the results after 5
weeks. Um, you can see that the roots
have grown very strong, indicating that
the orchid is recovering well and
absorbing nutrients effectively.
[Music]
When the roots are healthy, they help
the orchid absorb water and nutrients
more efficiently, leading to strong
growth, new leaves, new shoots, and an
easier blooming in the next
season. The leaves have also become
glossier and plumper, showing that the
plant is in a healthy and vigorous
growth state.
[Music]
And you can clearly see that the dormant
bud has developed into a kiki orchid
plantlet, proving that the stimulation
method is completely effective and safe
for the
orchid. If you find this content helpful
and meaningful, don't forget to like and
share. so more people can discover it
and subscribe to support the channel.
Thank you for always being with me.
[Music]
Uh after that, I continue to care for
the orchid using fertilizer made from
oat solution, honey, and vitamin B1.
Watering or spraying two to three times
a month to keep the plant healthy and
growing well.
[Music]
And here are the results after 10 weeks.
You can see that the kiki baby plant
from the stem cutting has grown very
strong with fresh robust roots proving
the effectiveness of the care method we
applied.
When the kiki baby plant on the stem
cutting is sturdy and has strong roots,
we can completely separate and replant
the baby orchid to help it grow better
and stronger.
[Music]
Now I separate the baby plant to replant
it individually, creating favorable
conditions for strong growth in an
environment with better controlled
light, humidity, and nutrients.
[Music]
I choose pine bark chips as the main
growing medium for the baby orchid
because it provides good arration,
retains moderate moisture, and supports
healthy root development.
[Music]
I spread a thin layer of moss on top to
retain moisture and create a soft
environment, helping protect the young
roots of the baby orchid for better
growth.
When planting in the pot, we only need
to place the orchid cutting from the
stem on top of the moss layer without
burying the roots under the medium,
which helps avoid damaging the young
roots and creates better conditions for
new root
[Music]
growth. Then, water the orchid to keep
it moist. Only when new roots grow and
firmly attach to the medium should you
start fertilizing, allowing the plant to
absorb nutrients more
effectively. If you care for them
patiently, gradually you will have a
beautiful orchid garden filled filled
with lush plants blooming all year
round, bringing joy and relaxation every
day.
I hope this video will be very helpful
to you in caring for orchids at home,
helping the plants grow healthy and
bloom
beautifully. If you find the content
meaningful and helpful, don't forget to
like and share so more people can
discover it and subscribe to support my
channel. Thank you for always being with
me.