Hello friends how are
[Music]
you uh in this video I continue to share
natural fertilizers that are easy to
make from things in the kitchen help
your orchids grow strongly and Bloom
[Music]
continuously if you haven't subscribed
to my channel yet please subscribe
subcribe so you don't miss any Orchid
growing tips on my
[Music]
channel let's get started to make this
fertilizer I need bananas
[Music]
banana peels contain a lot of potassium
phosphorus and nitrogen Essential
Elements for plant
growth uh potassium helps enhance
resistance and flowering
[Music]
ability compounds and banana peels help
plants resist pests and mold
[Music]
cut banana peel into small pieces
banana peel is a natural material easy
to find and environmentally friendly
helps you reduce
[Music]
waste this is aloe vera
leaf aloe vera contains many vitamins
and minerals helping to increase the
plant's resistance
cut aloe vera into small
[Music]
slices then add aloe vera banana peel
into the jar
[Music]
next I need beer
um take 100 ml of beer which is
equivalent to about 7
[Music]
tablespoons beer after fermentation
helps prevent aloe vera and banana peels
from rotting beer contains sugar and
carbohydrates which help provide energy
to plants promoting growth growth and
[Music]
flowering add 2 cups of warm water about
500 ml to help GE ferment
[Music]
better the vitamins and beer can support
metabolism in plants
[Music]
uh use cotton to cover the hole in the
bottle cap this helps prevent bacteria
and mold from entering the GE during
fermentation
[Music]
place in a cool place and incubate for 3
weeks 3 weeks later
[Music]
later this is a GE jar made from banana
peels and aloe vera that I made 3 weeks
ago take 20 M of this ge about more than
1 tablespoon
[Music]
add one liter of water about 1 liter
when the roots are silvery white like
this we need to water the Orchid
[Music]
use this water to water Orchid
Roots GE made from banana peels and aloe
vera helps improve soil structure and
retain moisture for plant
[Music]
roots nutrients help Roots grow
healthily allow the plant to absorb
nutrients
[Music]
better when combining two types of
banana peel and aloe vera to make GE you
will provide a rich source of nutrients
for the Orchid helping the plant develop
comprehensively
[Music]
banana peel adds potassium and
phosphorus while aloe vera adds vitamins
and moisture creating a perfect formula
for plant growth
[Music]
doing this one to two times a month or
combining it with other organic
fertilizers will help orchids develop
comprehensively remember that GE organic
fertilizer made from aloe vera and
banana peels is
[Music]
great but if the Orchid does not absorb
enough light the Orchid will not
[Music]
grow soaking the roots in this water for
20 minutes helps the Orchid absorb
nutrients
[Music]
better when the substrate is still moist
and the roots are still green like this
you do not need to water the Orchid
[Music]
if you water too much The Roots can
easily
[Music]
rot while the Orchid is absorbing
moisture and nutrients we can take
advantage of this time to take care of
the plants
[Music]
leaves do you see any white streaks left
on the leaves from the
[Music]
spray while the Orchid is absorbing
moisture and nutrients we can take
advantage of this time to take care of
the plant's leaves
[Music]
wiping leaves with tea water uh not only
cleanse dirt and dust but also provides
nutrients to the plant through the
leaves
[Music]
be sure to clean the undersides of
leaves as well because that's where
pests like to
[Music]
hide look how green and shiny the leaves
are after cleaning
this method not only cleanse the leaf
surface but also provides nutrients
through the leaves to the
[Music]
Orchid after cleaning the orchid's
photosynthetic organs will function
[Music]
better helps improve orchid's
metabolism do this one to two times a
month to keep the orchids protected
[Music]
now put this water in a spray bottle
banana peel solution is not only great
for watering orchids but can also be
used to miss them
[Music]
this helps provide nutrients freshen the
leaves increase humidity and clean dust
from the
[Music]
leaves you can Mist orchids once a week
with this GE water
[Music]
on week days you only need to spray
water regularly when you see the roots
turn silvery
[Music]
white um treat your plants with love and
they will repay you with lush green
leaves and blooming flowers
[Music]
please let me know in the comments where
you are
[Music]
watching it's wonderful that we can
connect from all over the world United
by our love for plants
thank you for watching the video wish
you luck and success in life