welcome back to the happiness Garden
Channel orchids are special plants that
require proper care to grow and Bloom
beautifully all year
round today I will guide you on how to
make natural fertilizer using simple and
easy to find ingredients that you most
likely already have at
home let's dive in and get started
the orchid has finished blooming proper
care is needed for it to bloom
again please cut off all the old flower
stems to help the Orchid Focus its
energy on recovery and
growth this will allow the plant to
prepare effectively for the next
blooming season and maintain longterm
health
[Music]
if you haven't subscribed to my channel
yet please support me by clicking the
Subscribe button don't forget to like
comment and share if you find this video
[Music]
helpful after that inspect and remove
any dead roots to prevent disease and
allow new new roots to
[Music]
grow healthy roots are usually white or
light
[Music]
green damaged roots are often brown
black or discolored
[Music]
which country are you watching this
video from please comment and let and
let me
[Music]
know it's amazing that we can chat with
each other from all the countries around
the
[Music]
world it's amazing that we can chat with
each other from all the countries around
the world
in addition to the English dub we've now
created dubs in French German Italian
Spanish Portuguese Japanese Hindi and
Indonesian to help you hear and
understand the content videos are
[Music]
easier it's amazing that we can can chat
with each other from all the countries
around the
world uh to make natural fertilizer the
first ingredient I need is
eggshells uh to make natural fertilizer
the first ingredient I need is eggshells
[Music]
the second ingredient I need is about 5
G of ginger
[Music]
Ginger contains many nutrients and
natural compounds that can improve the
health of
[Music]
plants and finally I need oat flour
which is very rich in nutrients to make
natural fertilizer for
orchids add 3 tbsp of oatmeal
[Music]
add 1 liter of boiled water about 4
cups add 1 lit of boiled water about 4
cups
[Music]
2 hours
later stir to dissolve the nutrients
into the water
[Music]
filter out the
residue if you haven't subscribed to the
channel yet please click the Subscribe
button to support me and not miss any
Orchid growing tips it's great to have
company
add another one liter of
[Music]
water step
one water this mixture on the Orchid two
to three times a month
eggshells Supply calcium which helps the
plant grow strong ginger has
antibacterial properties that prevent
diseases oatmeal provides essential
nutrients this mixture provides
essential nutrients to help the plant
recover quickly grow and prepare for the
next blooming
[Music]
season step
two use a soft cotton ball to soak up
the mixture and gently clean the top and
bottom surfaces of the orchid
leaves use a soft cotton ball to soak up
the mixture and gently clean the top and
bottom surfaces of the orchid leaves
the mixture of eggshells Ginger and
oatmeal will be absorbed through the
leaves supplying essential nutrients to
the plant
[Music]
this method helps remove dust and
impurities from the leaves allowing them
to absorb light more effectively
[Music]
helps the leaves maintain moisture and
proper nutrient
[Music]
exchange step
three next we pour the solution into a
spray bottle and spray it onto each
Orchid p
[Music]
pot shake the spray bottle before use to
ensure the solution is well
mixed lightly spray the solution on both
the top and bottom of the leaves
avoiding the flowers to prevent any
damage
[Music]
you can also spray around the roots if
they are
[Music]
accessible spray the fertilizer solution
once a week or as needed
uh be careful not to spray too much to
avoid overwatering the
plant step
four gently use a cloth to absorb excess
water from the surface of the leaves
both the top and
bottom make sure to thoroughly remove
any remaining water on the leaves to
prevent the plant from becoming
overwatered and to ensure it absorbs
nutrients more effectively
[Music]
d
afterward place the Orchid pot in a spot
with gentle sunlight to help it
photosynthesize
properly however ever avoid direct
sunlight especially during the intense
midday Sun as it can cause Leaf burn
heat shock and stress for the
[Music]
plant results after 45
days as you can see the roots have
developed rapidly and are very healthy
[Music]
as you can see on the same plant four
new flower stems can grow at the same
time
[Music]
the leaves have also become vibrant
smooth and very
[Music]
healthy strong new Roots promote faster
plant growth creating a solid foundation
for blooming and further
development new Roots help the Orchid
adapt better to changing environmental
conditions such as light and humidity
and enhance its ability to recover from
harsh conditions
[Music]
what
uh other Orchid plants cared for using
this method will also Thrive and produce
many flower stems on the same orchid
plant produces many new Ro roots and the
leaves stay green shiny and
firm continue taking care of your
Orchids with all the love and dedication
you give to
Nature when you invest your time and
effort the beautiful flowers you receive
will
be a wonderful reward proof of the Pati
and Care you've given to each leaf and
[Music]
root keep nurturing them with love and
you will feel Joy and satisfaction every
time you admire the orchids blooming
bringing Beauty and pride created by
your own
[Music]
hands I hope this video is helpful don't
forget to to like comment share and
subscribe to watch more
[Music]
videos uh thank you for watching and
supporting the channel wishing you
success with your
orchids see you next time