[Music]
I am very happy to welcome everyone to
my little garden, a peaceful space where
we can explore natural beauty and learn
inspiring plant care methods
together. I hope that each vis visit
here brings you joy, relaxation, and a
growing love for
nature. Today, I will show you a simple
yet effective method to grow orchids in
a semihydroponic style right at home.
This method not only helps orchids grow
healthily, but also makes it easier for
you to control moisture and nutrients
for the
roots. This is a great option for those
who who love orchids and want to care
for them in a more modern and convenient
way. If you haven't subscribed to the
channel yet, please hit the subscribe
button to support me and not miss any
orchid care tips. It's wonderful to have
you as a companion.
[Music]
And now, let's explore this amazing
orchid growing method
together. This is an orchid I bought
from a local flower shop. And as you can
see, it has finished
[Music]
blooming. When orchids finish blooming,
the plant usually focuses all its
nutrients on maintaining and developing
the flowers. So, after the blooms fade,
the plant may enter a state of
depletion.
This is why the leaves at the base often
turn yellow and wilt. Don't worry, this
is a natural part of the plant's growth
process. Proper care will help the plant
recover and prepare for new blooms.
[Music]
Um, with the semi-hydroponic method, we
need to remove the entire old growing
medium to allow the root system to grow
strong in a water-based environment.
[Music]
After removing the old growing medium,
you need to cut off any damaged, rotting
or diseased roots.
[Music]
These roots not only reduce the plant's
ability to absorb nutrients but can also
spread diseases to the healthy
roots. Uh use clean sharp scissors to
ensure you don't damage the remaining
healthy roots.
[Music]
The next step is to cut off the old
flower spike. This helps the plant focus
its energy on growing roots and leaves
instead of continuing to sustain the
spent flower spike.
[Music]
Next, you should rinse the orchid under
running water to remove dirt, bacteria,
and any remaining debris.
[Music]
After rinsing the orchid, place the
plant into the container, preparing for
the next
step. Please comment and let me know
which country you're watching the video
from. It's amazing that we can chat
together from all around the world.
[Music]
The next step is to prepare a mild
disinfecting solution and a recovery
nutrient solution for the orchid.
[Music]
To make a recovery nutrient solution for
the orchid, you can mix one liter of
water with one teaspoon of honey and
three tablets of vitamin B1.
[Music]
Stir the solution well until all the
ingredients are completely
[Music]
dissolved. Then soak the entire orchid
in this mixture for about 20 minutes.
Soaking the plant like this allows the
roots to directly absorb the recovery
nutrients and essential vitamins while
also boosting the plant's resistance
after the repotting and root treatment
process. In addition, honey also has
mild disinfectant properties, helping to
prevent bacteria and fungi from
attacking the cuts on the roots and stem
after treatment.
After soaking the orchid in the solution
for about 20 minutes, gently take the
plant ant
out and use a soft cloth to dry off any
excess water on the roots, leaves, and
stem. This drying process helps prevent
prolonged moisture which could create
conditions for mold or bacteria to
develop.
[Music]
Once the plant is dry, you can proceed
with preparing for the next step of
planting in the semihydroponic system.
Be careful during the process to avoid
damaging the roots and any delicate
parts of the plant.
[Music]
The next step is to pour water into the
semihydroponic orchid pot. If you're
using tap water, remember to let it sit
overnight before using it for the
orchid. Uh this helps reduce chlorine
and impurities in the water that could
negatively affect the plant's
growth. Note, in a water-based growing
environment, not all the roots of the
orchid should be submerged in
water. Uh only the tips of the roots
need to be submerged in water. This
allows the orchid to absorb enough water
and nutrients without fully submerging
the roots, keeping them healthy and
preventing root
rot. The roots that are not in contact
with the water will be exposed to air,
ensuring gas exchange and providing the
necessary oxygen for the plant to thrive
in the semihydroponic environment.
After planting the orchid in the
semi-hydroponic system, you should wait
about 3 days for the roots to stabilize
and adapt to the new environment before
fertilizing the
orchid. To make fertilizer for the
orchid, you can mix 3 tesp of oatmeal
powder with one liter of water.
Oatmeal powder will provide nutrients
such as potassium, calcium, and trace
minerals that help the orchid grow
strong, especially the roots and
[Music]
leaves. Stir well and let the mixture
steep for about 30 minutes.
[Music]
After soaking the oatmeal powder in
water for about 30 minutes, you need to
strain out the oatmeal residue to obtain
a clear solution.
[Music]
After straining out the residue, soak
the orchid roots in the oatmeal solution
for about 20
minutes. After straining out the
residue, soak the orchid roots in the
oatmeal solution for about 20 minutes.
This helps remove dust, eliminate mold
and small insects if present, and also
provides additional nutrients through
the leaf
surface. Soaking the roots allows them
to directly absorb the natural nutrients
in the oatmeal, such as vitamins,
minerals, and amino acids, supporting
the recovery process and stimulating the
plant's growth.
We alternate soaking the roots and
wiping the leaves with natural
fertilizers once a
week. Uh we need to top up the water in
the semi-hydroponic orchid pot or change
the water every time we feed the orchid
natural fertilizer.
After wiping the leaves and soaking the
roots in the natural fertilizer solution
for 20 minutes, take the orchid out and
plant it in the semihydroponic pot.
[Music]
After planting, you need to top up the
water in the pot so that the roots have
enough moisture and
nutrients. Check the water level to
ensure that only the tips of the roots
are submerged while the rest of the
roots are exposed to air to prevent root
[Music]
rot. Remember to place the orchid pot in
a spot with gentle sunlight as it will
help the plant uh photosynthesize well
without causing stress to the plant.
[Music]
And now let's take a look at the results
of my orchids grown using the
semihydroponic method.
Uh you can see that this orchid has
multiple flower stems growing from the
same
plant. Um having multiple flower stems
is a wonderful result of using the
semihydroponic method which helps the
plant grow strong and bloom
consistently.
[Music]
The healthy root system with many thick
and strong roots is a great sign that
the orchid is receiving enough nutrients
and being cared for in a good
environment.
The large and strong roots help the
plant absorb water and nutrients
effectively, supporting the vigorous
growth of the leaves and flowers.
[Music]
With the semi-hydroponic method, the
root system is kept in a moist
environment but not water logged,
allowing the plant to grow optimally.
[Music]
With the semi-hydroponic method, the
root system is kept in a moist
environment but not waterlogged,
allowing the plant to grow optimally.
[Music]
The leaves have also become shiny and
green, which shows that the orchid is
receiving the right amount of nutrients
and proper
[Music]
care. The vibrant green and glossy
leaves are signs of a healthy plant that
is photosynthesizing well and growing
vigorously.
[Music]
This orchid is the same with many new
roots growing.
[Music]
The flower buds are large and plump,
which shows that your orchid is in an
excellent stage of development.
I hope this video will be very helpful
for you in taking care of orchids at
home. With these tips and practical
experiences, I hope you will
successfully apply the semihydroponic
method and have healthy orchid pots with
beautiful blooms.
Large flowers and thick petals are not
only beautiful but also indicate that
the plant is receiving the necessary
nutrients to grow
vigorously. If you found this content
helpful and meaning don't forget to
like, share and subscribe to support me.
Thank you for always being with
me. If you have any questions, feel free
to leave them in the comments below the
video. I'm more than happy to share more
of my experiences. Thank you for
watching.