[Music]
It's a pleasure to welcome you to the
happiness garden where we take care of
flowers together and spread joy through
their blooms.
Growing orchids that always display
vibrant colors and produce many blooms
is something every orchid lover wishes
for.
However, to help the plant grow quickly
and develop a truly strong root system,
today I want to share with you a
completely new type of fertilizer.
[Music]
And I will also guide you on simple but
effective care methods that that help
orchids grow quickly and always shine
with many beautiful fresh flowers.
The flowers will last longer on the
stem, helping the orchids remain
vibrant, color fast, and may even bloom
year round, bringing lasting beauty to
your garden.
Let's get started.
[Music]
To start making natural fertilizer,
simply take one liter of warm water and
pour it into a clean bottle.
[Music]
The first ingredient you need to add is
molasses. This is a natural sugar source
rich in minerals that helps nourish
beneficial microorganisms in the
fertilizer.
With just one teaspoon of molasses, you
create the ideal conditions for the
fermentation process to occur naturally.
[Music]
This type of sugar not only activates
beneficial microorganisms but also helps
create a nutrient-rich environment that
supports orchid roots to grow quickly,
strongly, and sustainably.
[Music]
The next ingredient you need to prepare
is oatmeal. It is a natural and healthy
source of starch that when combined with
molasses creates an ideal environment
for beneficial microorganisms to thrive.
[Music]
Just add 3 tsp of oatmeal to the bottle
and that's enough.
Then stir well to dissolve the oatmeal
evenly in the water, making the
fermentation process smoother.
[Music]
Next, simply close the bottle and let it
sit in a warm place for about 1 to 2
days.
During this time, the microorganisms
will begin to work, transforming the
mixture into a nutrient-rich natural
fertilizer for orchids.
[Music]
After about 1 day, strain out the
oatmeal residue to collect the clear
liquid.
[Music]
This is the fermented natural fertilizer
solution, rich in microorganisms and
easily absorbed, making it ideal for
watering orchids at every stage of
growth.
[Music]
Uh, leave a comment and let me know
which country you're watching the video
from.
It's wonderful that we can connect and
chat from all around the world.
[Music]
After straining, add 2 L of clean water
to the fermented solution. This dilution
helps lower the concentration, making it
easier for orchid roots to absorb
without the risk of shock or damage.
[Music]
Um, if you haven't subscribed to the
channel yet, please hit the subscribe
button to support me and never miss any
orchid growing tips. It's truly
wonderful to have you along on this
journey.
The first method is to use a soft cloth
soaked in this solution. Then, gently
wipe the top and bottom surfaces of the
leaves.
[Music]
Wiping orchid leaves with the fermented
solution made from molasses and oatmeal
helps remove dust, salt residues, and
impurities that have accumulated on the
leaf surface.
When the leaves are clean, their ability
to absorb light for photosynthesis
improves, allowing the plant to produce
more energy to grow roots, leaves, and
flowers.
[Music]
Um, the fermented solution contains many
beneficial microorganisms that help
protect the leaf surface from harmful
bacteria and fungal infections.
Uh when you wipe the leaves with this
solution, you're creating a natural
bofilm that boosts the orchid's immune
system, especially in humid conditions
where diseases are more likely to
develop.
[Music]
The fermented mixture of molasses and
oatmeal contains enzymes and mild
organic acids that when applied to the
leaves help activate cellular level
metabolic processes.
This helps the plant absorb nutrients
more efficiently, promotes gas exchange
through the stamata, and supports strong
and steady growth.
[Music]
You can do this about twice a month.
This frequency is enough to provide the
necessary nutrients for orchids while
keeping the leaves clean and healthy.
The second method is to pour the diluted
solution into a spray bottle.
[Music]
Then lightly spray the solution over the
entire plant, including both the top and
bottom surfaces of the leaves. as well
as the roots.
Lightly spraying the solution over the
entire plant helps deliver nutrients
directly not only to the leaves but also
to the roots and stem.
The fermented mixture of molasses and
oatmeal contains many beneficial
microorganisms and natural trace
elements that nourish every part of the
orchid evenly, promoting holistic,
healthy, and sustainable growth.
Liquid fertilizer with small molecular
structure easily penetrates through the
leaf epidermis and the tips of young
roots.
When sprayed evenly on both leaf
surfaces and roots, the solution helps
the plant absorb nutrients more quickly
than simple root watering, which is
especially beneficial when the plant
needs to recover or is in a rapid growth
phase.
The fermented solution contains enzymes
and beneficial bacteria that can inhibit
harmful fungi commonly found on the
unders sides of leaves or in the root
zone.
Spraying the entire plant helps form a
biological protective layer which
enhances disease resistance and reduces
the risk of leaf rot, root rot, or leaf
spots caused by fungi in humid
environments.
You should lightly spray the solution
over the entire orchid about two to
three times a month.
The third method is to water the diluted
mixture directly onto the orchid's base.
For each pot, use only 5 to 10
tablespoons depending on the size and
moisture level of the growing medium.
[Music]
When the diluted mixture is poured at
the base, the trace elements, enzymes,
and natural sugars in the solution
penetrate deeply into the growing medium
and come into direct contact with the
roots. As a result, the orchid absorbs
nutrients quickly and efficiently,
boosting vitality and supporting the
growth of strong new roots.
Regularly watering the orchid base
enriches the microbial community,
promotes the decomposition of organic
matter in the growing medium, and
suppresses the growth of harmful
bacteria and fungi, helping the orchid
grow more sustainably.
[Music]
Uh, orchid roots are the primary site
for nutrient absorption. So, when
nourished with a natural fertilizer rich
in enzymes and easily digestible sugars,
they will grow faster, longer, and
thicker.
A healthy root system is the solid
foundation for vigorous plant growth and
proper preparation for the blooming
stage.
[Music]
With regular watering of the solution,
the growing medium retains just the
right amount of moisture and becomes
more airrated thanks to the gentle
decomposition activity of the
microorganisms.
After watering, you can also soak the
entire orchid pot in the mixture for
about 20 minutes. Soaking allows the
roots to absorb more nutrients.
[Music]
After about 20 minutes, remember to
remove the orchid pot to prevent root
rot.
[Music]
Place the pot in a well ventilated area
to allow water to drain quickly and keep
the roots airy and healthy.
After that, use a soft cloth to absorb
any remaining water on the leaves and
around the base.
[Music]
Standing water in the leaf axles or
orchid crown can easily become a
breeding ground for fungi and bacteria,
leading to leaf or crown rot, especially
in humid weather or during the night.
Timely drying helps the plant avoid
these dangerous diseases, keeping the
leaves and crown dry and healthy.
[Music]
Wiping off standing water also helps
keep the orchid clean, preventing
yellowing or discoloration on the leaves
caused by residue left behind as the
water evaporates.
At the same time, a well- ventilated dry
environment will limit the development
of white mold, black mold, and other
diseases that spread through high
humidity.
Fermented fertilizer should be applied
in the morning. This is when the orchid
begins its most active metabolic
processes of the day, allowing it to
absorb nutrients more effectively.
At the same time, sunlight helps the
leaves and roots dry quickly, reducing
the risk of fungal infections or root
rot.
And finally, remember to place the
orchid pot in a spot with gentle
sunlight so the plant can
photosynthesize well.
When exposed to natural light, orchids
can convert nutrients into energy,
allowing them to absorb fertilizer more
fully and grow stronger day by day.
Now here is the result after 2 weeks of
care.
Uh you can clearly see the orchid has
started to develop many new healthy
roots signaling recovery and good growth
after the care process.
[Music]
New roots help the orchid increase its
ability to absorb water and nutrients
from the soil, creating a strong
foundation for the plant to grow healthy
and produce more beautiful flowers.
[Music]
And here are the orchids that I have
regularly cared for using this natural
fertilizer.
[Music]
You can easily notice their roots
growing very vigorously, creating the
best conditions for the plants to grow
and bloom regularly.
[Music]
If you care for your orchids with all
the love you have for plants, you will
feel the plant's magical response.
Strong, healthy roots, lush green
leaves, and brilliant blooms like a
meaningful gift for your soul.
Blooming orchids help you feel relaxed,
bring gentle joy, and brighten your
living space with their vibrant natural
beauty.
I hope you enjoyed this video. If you
found it helpful, don't forget to hit
the like button and subscribe to the
channel so you won't miss the next tips
on how to care for orchids naturally and
simply.
If you face any difficulties while
growing orchids, don't hesitate to leave
a comment. I'm always here to support
you so you can grow healthy orchids that
bloom beautifully.
[Music]
Thank you for watching the video.
Wishing you lots of joy and beautiful,
healthy orchids all year round.
[Music]
Welcome to my channel.
When growing orchids, everyone wishes
for healthy plants and vibrant blooms.
To help you take care of your orchids at
home in the best way, today I will share
a natural fertilizer recipe using
familiar ingredients from your kitchen.
This is a simple yet highly effective
method that helps orchids grow strong
and bloom beautifully.
Let's get started.
Do you have rice?
[Music]
I took 500 g of rice and washed it
clean.
Uh rice contains many natural vitamins
and minerals such as phosphorus,
potassium, and protein providing
abundant nutrients to help orchids grow
strong and healthy.
[Music]
Therefore, I regularly use rice as
fertilizer for all types of orchids as
well as other plants.
Add one liter of water.
[Music]
Please comment to me which country you
are watching the video from. It's great.
It's great that we can chat together
from all over the world.
[Music]
Stir well so that the nutrients dissolve
into the water.
[Music]
In addition to the English dub, we've
now created dubs in French, German,
Italian, Spanish, Portuguese, Japanese,
H, and Indonesian to help you hear and
understand the content more easily.
[Music]
Then filter this water.
Next, I need one tomato
[Music]
and cut into thin slices.
Tomatoes contain many micronutrients and
nutrients such as potassium, phosphorus,
and vitamins which help promote plant
growth.
[Music]
Put tomatoes in the jar.
Then pour in the rice water to soak with
the tomatoes.
[Music]
Cover tightly and leave in a cool place
for one day to ferment.
[Music]
One day later,
Filter out residue.
[Music]
Then take 200 ml of this liquid
fertilizer solution.
[Music]
and mix with 2 L of water.
Method one,
water the orchid with this liquid
fertilizer at the base.
[Music]
Rice water contains amino acids and
beneficial microorganisms which help
strengthen the soil microbiome thereby
stimulating root growth.
[Music]
Fertilizer from fermented tomatoes also
improves soil irerration and moisture
retention, helping plants absorb water
and nutrients.
Beneficial bacteria in the fermentation
process help orchids increase their
resistance to diseases.
Abundant nutrients and a fresh living
environment help orchids bloom more,
bigger, and more beautifully.
After watering, soaking in this water
for about 20 minutes is best.
Method two,
use soft cotton to absorb this water and
thoroughly wipe the top and bottom of
the leaves.
Wiping leaves helps remove dirt and
impurities, helps plants photosynthesize
better, and increases their ability to
absorb light.
Beneficial bacteria in the solution help
strengthen plant resistance, reducing
the risk of pests and diseases.
[Music]
This solution creates light moisture on
the leaf surface, helping plants
maintain moisture and prevent wilting.
[Music]
In addition, when wiping the leaves, the
organic substances in the solution will
be absorbed through the leaves.
Stimulates the growth of leaves, roots,
and flowers, helping plants grow
healthier.
[Music]
method three.
If you have many orchid pots, put this
water in a spray bottle.
Then spray all over the orchid.
[Music]
This method is like fertilizing plants
through the leaves.
[Music]
Spray both the top and bottom of the
leaves.
[Music]
And spray on orchid roots.
However, you should not spray it on
flowers.
[Music]
Because when flowers get wet, the petals
will quickly fall off.
[Music]
After soaking for about 20 minutes, take
the orchid pot out and place it in a
place with lots of scattered light so
the orchid can photosynthesize well.
[Music]
Do all three methods above one to two
times a month for your orchids.
[Music]
Remaining liquid fertilizer. solution
you freeze and store for next use. This
method can be frozen for 3 months.
[Music]
Results after 3 weeks.
New roots grow many and healthy.
Uh, new roots help the plant absorb
water and nutrients from the
environment, ensuring survival and
growth.
New roots help improve metabolism,
promoting flower formation.
The growth of new roots is often
accompanied by the growth of other parts
such as leaves and flowers.
Take care of your orchids with all the
love you have for plants and you will be
rewarded with beautiful orchids that you
personally care for.
[Music]
Care and love will help the plant grow
strongly, bringing you joy and comfort
when looking at the bright blooming and
fragrant flowers in your living space.
Hope you will like the video. Please
comment for me.
[Music]
Um, if you haven't subscribed to the
channel yet, please subscribe to support
me.
[Music]
Uh, thank you for watching the video.
I pray God always bless you.
[Music]
Goodbye and see you again in the next
videos.