Welcome to the Happiness Garden channel.
In this video, I will continue to share
with you another gentle method that
uh helps the flower spike recover and
continue blooming even after the
first round of flowers has faded.
If you find the content helpful, don't
forget to support me by clicking like,
subscribing to the channel, and sharing so more
people can learn about this orchid growing tip.
These are the flower spikes after
the previous blooming has faded.
Uh let me know in the comments
which country you're watching
from. It's wonderful that we can
connect from all around the world.
But these nodes can still continue to bloom
if you know how to take care of them properly.
I have removed all the wilted
flowers so that the plant so
that the plant can focus its energy
on nourishing the roots and leaves.
If you haven't subscribed yet, please hit
the subscribe button to support me and
never miss any orchid care tips. It's truly
wonderful to have you along on this journey.
I also remove the diseased leaves to
prevent the spread to the rest of the plant.
I continued to remove all the damaged roots so the
plant can focus on growing new, healthier ones.
Damaged roots can become a breeding
ground for bacteria and fungi,
making the plant more susceptible
to disease and harder to recover.
Then sprinkle cinnamon powder on the cuts to
help them dry quickly and prevent
bacteria or fungi from entering.
Then let the plant sit for a day without
watering, allowing the cuts to dry completely.
One day later, now we start
making natural fertilizer
to care for the orchid. Take 2 L of clean water.
Take one spoonful of rice.
Then take three teaspoons of soybeans.
Pour into one liter of boiling water. Wait
for the water to cool before using it.
After 1 hour, stir well to release the nutrients
from the rice. Then gently decant the clear water.
Once the water has cooled, mix the soybean soaking
water with the rice water. This combination
merges nutrients from both ingredients,
making it excellent for orchid growth.
Next, take the remaining grains and sprinkle
about 10 to 20 seeds into each pot. Then,
gently bury them beneath the roots to allow
the orchid to slowly absorb the nutrients.
Now I use this water to water the
orchid roots once every 1 to two weeks.
Rice water contains many essential
nutrients such as potassium,
phosphorus, and other natural minerals
that help promote healthy plant growth.
Meanwhile, soybeans are very rich in
nitrogen, a key element for plant growth,
especially essential during the stages of
sprouting, flowering, and leaf development.
And I continue to spray this water
on the leaves once or twice a week.
When sprayed on the plant, the nutrients
from soybeans and rice also provide proteins
and essential amino acids, compounds
that help the plant grow healthily,
recover quickly, and effectively
stimulate root and flower development.
In addition, you can spray this solution directly
onto the stems and branches. This helps stimulate
the growth of new flower spikes, contributing to
a more vibrant blooming season for your orchid.
And this is the result after 1 month of
consistent care. You can clearly see that
the old flower spikes have begun to sprout new
buds, promising a beautiful blooming season ahead.
This helps the orchid continue to sprout and
bloom from the old flower spikes themselves.
A natural way to extend the blooming
season without cutting the spikes.
What do you think about the way I revived
this little orchid? Feel free to leave a
comment and share your thoughts. I'd love
to hear your feedback and experiences.
After that, I continue watering the orchid
with rice water once or twice a week. A
simple method that helps the roots absorb
nutrients consistently and grow healthily.
You can also spray rice water on your
orchid once or twice a week. This helps
the leaves stay lush and green, retains natural
moisture, and stimulates overall plant growth.
Spraying it on the stems also helps deliver
nutrients directly to the flower buds, supporting
their development and helping the blooms
grow larger, more beautiful, and last longer.
Uh and here is the result after the following
month. You can see the orchid has bloomed with
many magnificent flowers bringing radiant
beauty and vibrant life to your garden.
I hope you enjoy this video. If you find it
helpful, don't forget to hit like and subscribe
to the channel so you won't miss the next tips
on caring for orchids naturally and simply.
Thank you so much for joining me.
Wishing you happiness, good health,
and beautiful, thriving orchids all
year round. See you in the next videos.
Hi everybody. In this video, I share
how to care for orchids to help them
grow quickly and flower many times in the
same year. You see, my orchids new flowers
always grow after old ones fall. So my orchids
bloom all year round from branch to branch.
The flowers bloom for a long time
before dropping their petals and
can stay on the branches for up to 6 months.
Um, please comment to me which country
you are watching the video from. It's
great that we can chat together from all over
the world. Many flowers grow on the same tree.
new roots grow a lot to
help absorb nutrients best.
Chubby flower buds.
Help flowers bloom long on branches.
Brilliant flowers.
How to make fertilizer as follows. Use
one small carrot weighing about 30 g.
Cut into small pieces.
Add one liter of filtered water.
puree.
Filter out residue.
Add one liter of filtered water.
Then use cotton to soak carrot juice and wipe
both the top and bottom sides of the leaves.
This method helps repel insects and
open the stamata. The orchids will
photosynthesize and exchange nutrients better.
At the same time, orchids also absorb
some nutrients through the leaves,
helping keep the leaves green.
If you haven't subscribed to the channel yet,
please subscribe to support me
and not miss any Orchid care tips.
Second way,
water this carrot for orchids. Carrot juice
is a good source of nutrients for orchids,
including vitamins and minerals like beta
carotene, potassium, magnesium, and phosphorus.
Uh when the carrot juice is poured into the
orchid pot, it provides nutrients to the
orchids and helps to promote their health.
In addition, carrot juice is also acidic,
which helps regulate the pH of the potted soil and
enhances the orchid's ability to absorb nutrients.
You can soak the orchid pot in
this carrot juice for 20 minutes.
Do this one two times a month.
Third way.
Mist moisturizing carrot juice for orchids by
spraying both the top and bottom of the leaves.
This helps wash away dirt and eliminate
insects on your orchids. The nutrients
in carrot juice support orchid health,
helping them thrive and bloom beautifully.
However, be careful not to overwater with carrot
juice as it can clog the water channels in the
orchid. Avoid spraying directly on the flowers
as this can cause them to fall off quickly.
I hope this video helps you take
better care of your orchids at home
and encourages them to bloom easily. Um,
if you find it helpful and interesting,
please like, share, and subscribe
to support my channel. Thank you.