welcome to my
channel if you have an orchid did that
has rot causing the leaves to turn
[Music]
yellow so don't rush to throw it away I
will share how to revive it quickly and
easily
[Music]
this Orchid may be suffering from
inorganic fertilizer shock leading to
root Rod causing the leaves to turn
[Music]
yellow so I need to check the roots to
cut off all damaged
[Music]
Roots removing damaged Roots helps
prevent the rot from spreading causing
the entire root of the Orchid to
[Music]
rot and stimulates new root formation
faster
[Music]
then rinse with water
Take 2 L of water and put it in a jar
[Music]
then add 1 teaspoon of baking soda to
help kill bacteria and eliminate
[Music]
pests soak Orchid roots in this water
for 10
[Music]
minutes then use dry moss to grow
orchids
[Music]
after soaking for 10 minutes take the
Orchid out and plant
[Music]
it when planting dry sterilized Moss it
will help absorb moisture from The Roots
this helps the cut heal quickly and the
rot does not spread
[Music]
further then place in a cool place and
do not water for one week
[Music]
after one week start watering the Orchid
once a week
[Music]
soak can water for 10 minutes to keep
the Moss
[Music]
moist then take it out and cover it with
a transparent plastic box
[Music]
and remember to water it every week to
keep it moist
[Music]
one month
later the orchid has revived and grown
healthy roots
[Music]
but it seems like the leaves are a bit
wilted once the root system is strong
you need to add more nutrients to help
the Orchid grow quickly
[Music]
Take 2 L of
water and add 5 teaspoons of rice
[Music]
rice contains a variety of minerals and
amino acids that are important for
orchid growth
[Music]
then use this rice water to water the
orchids once a week
[Music]
in addition to providing necessary
nutrients rice water also creates a
favorable environment for beneficial
microorganisms to grow in Orchid
[Music]
pots soak for 10 minutes then take out
the Orchid pot
[Music]
regularly spray mist to keep the soil
moist when the growing medium is dry
[Music]
2 months
later from an orchid with Leaf rot
causing the leaves to turn completely
yellow it has now grown healthily
[Music]
strong roots fresh green
leaves if you find the video interesting
please like and share so more people
know and subscribe to support my
[Music]
channel my videos have subtitles in many
different languages please choose the
appropriate language to clearly
understand the content I share
I'm very happy that you are
here if you have an orchid I'm sure you
always wanted to bloom for a long time
right
[Music]
right orchids are known for their
ability to keep flowers on their
branches for 3 to 6
[Music]
months for that to happen you need to
nurture water and feed it well
[Music]
now I will show you what is the best
fertilizer for
[Music]
orchids if you follow us till the end of
this video you will learn how to make
orchids bloom like crazy
[Music]
now let's get
started take a bowl and put 5 tbsp of
rice in
[Music]
it if you haven't subscribed to the
channel yet please subscribe to support
me and not miss any orchid care
[Music]
tips pour in 500 M of water at room
temperature mix the rice well and wash
the rice before
[Music]
cooking then filter the water to wash
the
[Music]
rice please comment to me which country
you are watching the video from it's
great that we can chat together from all
over the
[Music]
world use a cotton ball soaked in water
to wash this
[Music]
rice then wipe on the top and bottom of
the leaves
[Music]
will help clean the surface of the
leaves remove disease fungi and insects
on Orchids at the same time it provides
the necessary nutrients for the orchid's
growth
[Music]
repeat after 2 weeks we'll help the
Orchid Stay Green
[Music]
or you can also pour the rice water into
a spray
[Music]
bottle then spray evenly on the top and
bottom of the leaves
[Music]
this method also has the same effect as
the previous method using cotton
[Music]
balls do not spray rice water on flowers
now take a deep Bowl in which you will
place the Orchid ready for watering and
[Music]
soaking rice water is a great natural
fertilizer for orchids as it encourages
the flowering of this beautiful
[Music]
plant you can soak the Orchid in this
rice water for about 1 hour so that the
Orchid Roots can absorb the most
[Music]
nutrients then remove and repeat this
treatment every 14 days
[Music]
you can also freeze rice water to water
your orchids
[Music]
when needed you just need to take a few
cubes wait for them to defrost and reach
room temperature you can feed your
orchids again
[Music]
never Place Frozen blocks directly on
the base of the Orchid because orchids
don't like the
[Music]
cold after only 2 to 3 weeks of use the
leaves will be green
[Music]
um you can see that after fertilizing
the new Roots grow very strongly this
will help the Orchid best absorb
nutrients through its roots
[Music]
if you find the content interesting or
meaningful don't forget to like share so
that more people know and subscribe to
your support Channel thank you for
always accompanying
[Music]
me with enough nutrition your or will
flower all year
[Music]
round and that will be all we have
prepared for you for this video