I am very happy to welcome everyone to
my channel where we explore natural
beauty and inspiring plant care methods
together. Today I want to share with you
an interesting way to grow orchids. No
need to water, yet the flowers can still
bloom brightly all year round. This is a
simple and creative solution, especially
helpful for those who love orchids but
don't have much time to care for them
everyday. Let's get started. This is a
small orchid that I bought from a local
flower shop. Although the plant is
small, it is growing very healthily and
vibrantly. To apply the method of
growing orchids without watering, the
first step is to remove all the old
growing medium, especially the
moss. Moss retains moisture very well,
which will prevent the plant from
growing properly using this method.
The next step is to cut off any damaged
or dry roots. This is important because
unhealthy roots not only reduce the
plant's ability to absorb neut
nutrients, but can also cause
diseases. Removing them will help the
orchid grow stronger, creating a solid
foundation for growing using the no
watering method.
[Music]
To ensure the orchid doesn't rot during
the growing process, I use baking soda
to treat the cuts on the roots.
Baking soda helps kill bacteria and
fungi, preventing the formation of
pathogens while creating a clean
environment for the roots to
grow. Just half a teaspoon of baking
soda is
enough. Then mix it with.5 L of water.
Um, after preparing the baking soda
solution, soak the orchid in it for
about 10 minutes.
Soaking the plant helps disinfect
effectively, ensuring that the roots are
protected from bacteria and mold before
planting. This is an important step that
helps the orchid stay healthy and grow
well throughout the care
[Music]
process. Next, I prepare rice to make a
natural fertilizer that helps stimulate
the rapid growth of the orchid after
planting.
Take one tablespoon of rice and soak it
in 0.5 L of water. This mixture will
provide essential nutrients to help the
orchid grow
healthily. Um, it's best to let the
mixture soak for about 10 to 30 minutes.
This helps the nutrients in the rice
dissolve into the water, creating a
nutrientrich natural fertilizer for the
plant. While waiting, I will recycle
plastic bottle caps to make a no
watering orchid
pot. While waiting, I will recycle
plastic bottle caps to make a no
watering orchid
pot. Uh, this is a great way to combine
plant care and protecting our
planet. Please pay attention and follow
along with me.
Let me know in the comments which
country you're watching this video from.
Um, it's amazing that we can chat
together from all over the
world. And if you haven't subscribed to
the channel yet, click the subscribe
button to support me and never miss any
orchid care tips. It's wonderful to have
you as a companion.
Then we need to wash the plastic bottle
to remove any dirt or impurities left.
This will help ensure a clean growing
environment, allowing the orchid to
thrive without issues related to
bacteria or mold.
In addition to the English voiceover, we
have now created voiceovers in French,
German, Italian, Spanish, Portuguese,
Japanese, Hindi, and Indonesian to help
you listen to and understand the content
more easily.
To listen in your preferred language,
open the video and click on settings,
the gear icon to select the audio
language. Then create a hole in in the
bottle cap just like I did.
[Music]
and make a hole in the body of the
plastic bottle just like I No.
[Music]
After soaking for about 10 minutes, we
stir well to dissolve the rice water
into the liquid.
Then strain out the remaining residue to
keep only the pure rice water solution
ready for watering the
[Music]
orchids. Then take the orchid out and
check it carefully one more time.
[Music]
I noticed a bruise on the leaf, so I
need to cut it off immediately to
prevent it from spreading to the healthy
parts of the
plant. Removing the damaged parts will
help the orchid focus its energy on
growing and keep the entire plant
healthy.
[Music]
Then soak the orchid in the rice water
solution for about 10
[Music]
minutes. This will help the roots absorb
natural nutrients from the rice,
stimulate recovery, and promote growth
after repotting.
This is a simple but very effective step
to boost the plant's
[Music]
vitality. Uh while waiting, I proceed to
make the wick in preparation for the no
water orchid planting method.
Uh, a wick is a string with excellent
water absorption ability, helping to
maintain moisture for the orchid's roots
without the need for direct
watering. Please pay attention and
follow my instructions.
[Music]
When you place the wick in the pot, it
will water from the bottom and provide
it to the plant steadily.
[Music]
Now we will proceed to plant the orchid
in the no water pot.
[Music]
Before planting the orchid, we need to
soak up any excess water on the leaves
and between the leaf
crevices. Use a soft cloth or paper
towel to gently dry these areas,
preventing the orchid from rotting
during the planting process.
[Music]
When planting the orchid, we connect the
wick to the roots to ensure that water
is drawn up from the bottom of the pot
to the roots.
Then insert the growing medium such as
pine bark chips around the roots to
retain moisture and create space for the
roots to develop.
This growing medium helps the orchid
stay stable and grow strong in the no
water planting environment.
After planting, we only need to water
once. to allow the growing medium and
wick to absorb enough
moisture. Then you only need to change
the water when it becomes dirty. This
helps keep the orchid healthy without
the need for frequent watering while
also preventing root
rot. The wick will act as a bridge
allowing water to be drawn up from the
bottom of the pot to the roots. This
way, the orchid will always receive the
necessary moisture naturally without the
need for direct
watering. After planting, we wait for
about a week to allow the orchid roots
to stabilize in the new environment.
Once the roots are settled, you can
start fertilizing the orchid to support
its
[Music]
growth. After a week, I start
fertilizing the orchid with rice water.
Take one tablespoon of rice. Then mix it
with one liter of water and stir well.
[Music]
After the rice has soaked, strain the
rice water to use as fertilizer for the
orchid. Rice water contains many natural
nutrients that help stimulate the growth
of the orchid's roots, leaves, and
flowers. After preparing the rice water,
soak the orchid pot in this solution for
about 20 minutes.
Soaking the plant in rice water allows
the roots to absorb nutrients
gradually. Uh each month you only need
to soak the orchid pot in rice water
twice. Soaking the plant in rice water
allows the roots to absorb nutrients
gradually.
This helps maintain healthy growth for
the orchid without the need for frequent
watering.
After soaking the orchid pot in rice
water for 20 minutes, remove the pot and
wait for the rice water to drain
completely before placing the pot into
the water container.
There. Uh then remove the pot and place
it in a spot with indirect sunlight.
Note that good fertilizer and the right
planting method will only be effective
if the orchid receives enough sunlight.
If there is a lack of sunlight, the
orchid will not grow well and the
fertilizer will not work at its full
potential. And now let's take a look at
the results. After 2
[Music]
months, the orchid has grown strong with
clean white roots and shiny green
[Music]
leaves. What do you think about the way
I revived this little orchid? Don't
hesitate to leave a comment and share
your thoughts. I'd love to hear your
feedback and
experiences. If you face any
difficulties while growing your orchid,
don't hesitate to leave a comment. I'm
always here to support you so you can
grow healthy orchids that bloom
beautifully.
[Music]
The most wonderful part is that the
flowers have bloomed beautifully, full
of vitality.
[Music]
It's hard to believe that with such a
simple and natural method, we can help a
small orchid recover and bloom so
[Music]
beautifully. I hope you enjoy this
video. If you find it helpful, don't
forget to like and subscribe to the
channel so you won't miss the next tips
on how to care for orchids naturally and
simply. I always pray for God's
blessings upon all of you and your loved
ones.
[Music]