Hello everyone. I am very happy to
welcome you to my
channel. Today I will share how to help
orchid plants recover quickly when they
face
rot. With just simple ingredients
available in every family's kitchen, we
can easily revive and help orchid plants
affected by rot to grow back
quickly. And then the flowers will bloom
brilliantly again, continuing to shine
in your beautiful garden.
Let's get
started. For orchid plants that have
rotted like this, don't rush to throw
them
away. You can notice that in this spot,
there are always many harmful molds and
[Music]
bacteria. When signs of rot appear, it
spreads quickly, and if not treated in
time, the orchid can be seriously
damaged or even die.
[Music]
We need to completely remove the damaged
leaves. Uh this helps prevent the spread
of disease uh while also allowing the
orchid to focus on recovering and
developing healthier parts.
Because the orchid is very weak, we need
to cut off the flower stems to reduce
the burden, helping the plant
concentrate nutrients and energy on
faster recovery.
Please comment to let me know which
country you are watching the video
from. It's wonderful that we can chat
together from all over the
[Music]
world. Uh you can see mold on the
growing medium has started to develop
which creates a high risk of root rot
for the orchid.
Since the orchid has been planted in
this pot with the growing medium for a
long time, we need to completely remove
the old medium and replace it with a new
pot.
[Music]
Then proceed to cut off all the damaged
roots. This helps prevent the growth of
fungi and creates conditions for healthy
new roots to develop, contributing to
the orchid's recovery process.
[Music]
Um, when you see this leaf has naturally
dried, we don't need to cut it off, but
should leave it as it
is. Next, we need to wash thoroughly to
completely remove dirt and harmful
bacteria.
If you haven't subscribed to the channel
yet, please hit the subscribe button to
support me and not miss any orchid
growing tips. It's wonderful to have you
along for the journey.
[Applause]
[Music]
To disinfect and stimulate root growth,
I use natural lemon water.
[Music]
I dilute lemon water with one liter of
water to create a mild solution that is
safe for the orchid.
[Music]
Then soak the orchid's roots in the
diluted lemon water solution for about
20 minutes to gently disinfect and
stimulate new root growth.
[Music]
Lemon water contains citric acid and
natural antibacterial agents which help
clean orchid roots, prevent bacteria and
mold, and stimulate healthy new root
growth.
[Music]
The leftover lemon water can be further
diluted with water at a 1:1 ratio to
create a light watering solution, which
both disinfects the growing medium and
supports the recovery process, safely
and naturally, stimulating orchid
growth.
[Music]
Then you can use this solution to spray
on other healthy orchids in the garden,
helping to prevent fungal diseases and
boost the plant's resistance.
[Music]
Uh you can absolutely use this solution
to spray on small orchids, mature
orchids as well as orchids that are
blooming, helping to protect and nourish
the plants comprehensively.
[Music]
For orchids that are blooming, this
fertilizer helps keep the flowers fresh
longer on the stem because it provides
essential nutrients while also enhancing
the plant's health, helping the flowers
maintain color and freshness for a
longer time.
[Music]
Uh besides spraying the upper surface of
the leaves, you also need to pay
attention to spraying thoroughly on the
underside of the leaves as this area is
often damp, creating favorable
conditions for fungi and harmful insects
to gather and develop.
And you should avoid spraying directly
on the flowers because when the flowers
get wet, the petals will quickly wilt
and
[Music]
fade. After soaking in the solution for
about 20 minutes, take the orchid out
and gently blot with a soft cloth to
wipe off the water droplets on the roots
and stem.
[Music]
Then use melted candle wax to drip onto
the cuts. This helps prevent water from
seeping in, protects the wounds from
infection, and prevents rot on the
orchid.
[Music]
Next, plant the orchid into a new pot
with drainage holes at the bottom to
ensure the plant does not become water
logged and helps the roots develop
healthier. After that, I choose to use
dry pine bark as the growing medium for
planting the
[Music]
orchid. After planting with dry pine
bark, we should not water immediately.
This will allow the bark to absorb the
remaining moisture from the roots, keep
the roots dry, and reduce the risk of
[Music]
rot. After planting, place the orchid
pot in a cool, wellventilated area for
about 3 days and do not water.
This helps the plant adjust to the new
environment, allows the cuts to dry
completely, and gives the roots time to
adapt, thereby reducing the risk of
fungal infection and
rot. After 3 days, once the orchid
adjusts, start light watering or use
diluted liquid fertilizer to support
recovery and growth.
[Music]
Take 2 tablespoons of rice and mix with
half liter of water, stirring well to
create a natural, gentle, and
nutrient-rich liquid fertilizer. Perfect
for recovering and nourishing orchids
after
[Music]
treatment.
Before applying the liquid fertilizer,
spread a thin layer of moss on the
orchid pot
[Music]
rim. This helps retain moisture in the
growing medium while creating an ideal
environment for the fertilizer to absorb
evenly and the orchid to absorb
nutrients more effectively.
Then water the orchid with rice water
two to three times a month. This is a
simple but very effective way to provide
natural nutrients and promote healthy
orchid
[Music]
growth. After applying the liquid
fertilizer, soak the orchid pot in this
solution for about 20 minutes.
Uh this helps the growing medium and
roots absorb nutrients more deeply while
cleaning and strengthening the root
system supporting a faster and more
effective
recovery. After soaking for about 20
minutes, take the orchid pot out and
place it in a spot with gentle sunlight
to provide the right temperature that
naturally and effectively promotes
recovery.
[Music]
And here is the amazing result after one
month of caring for and recovering the
rotten orchid using the natural
fertilizer
[Music]
method. You can see the orchid has
revived with a new very healthy chute
growing clearly demonstrating the
effectiveness of care and recovery using
natural fertilizer.
[Music]
And the orchid has also grown many new
healthy roots, helping to strengthen the
nutrient absorbing system and create a
solid foundation for the plant's
long-term
growth. Uh, what do you think about my
method for recovering weak orchids?
Please leave your comments and feedback
to let me know.
I continue to care for the orchids using
liquid fertilizer made from rice
[Music]
water. When the roots are strong, you
can switch to caring with different
natural fertilizers and alternate their
use.
[Music]
This method helps the orchid absorb a
diverse range of essential nutrients
leading to more comprehensive and
sustainable
[Music]
growth. Each time after applying liquid
fertilizer, remember to soak the orchid
pot in the solution for about 20
minutes. Then remember to place the
orchid pot in a spot with gentle
sunlight because without enough light,
the orchid cannot metabolize and absorb
nutrients effectively, slowing down the
recovery and growth process.
And here's the result after 3 months of
caring for and recovering the weak
orchid using natural
[Music]
fertilizer. You can see that the root
system has developed healthily uh
looking fresh and full of
vitality and the leaves have also become
glossy and firm reflecting the plant's
strong vitality after the recovery
period.
Thus, with just a few simple steps and
readily available household ingredients,
we can completely restore orchids at
home effectively, safely, and
economically.
[Music]
If you find the content helpful and
meaningful, don't forget to like, share
so more people can benefit and subscribe
to support me. Thank you for always
being with
[Music]
me. Uh, if you face any difficulties
during the orchid planting process,
don't hesitate to leave a comment. I'm
always here to support you so you can
grow healthy orchids with lots of
beautiful blooms.
Each time you revive an orchid, little
by little over the years, you will build
a vibrant garden full of colorful
orchids, bringing joy, peace, and
natural beauty that inspires your living
space. Thank you all for taking the time
to watch the video. I always pray that
God blesses everyone with many blessings
and peace.