I'm very happy to welcome you to my
little garden where every flower is
cared for with all my love and patience.
Today I will continue to guide you on
how to revive weak orchids, those that
have become exhausted after blooming so
so they can regain their vitality, grow
healthily, and get ready for a vibrant
next blooming season.
[Music]
You can easily notice that this orchid
is wilting. If not revived in time, it
is very likely that the plant will die.
[Music]
When you notice that the orchid is
wilting, the first and most important
step is to immediately check the growing
medium and the root system, as these are
the key factors that will help the plant
recover.
After checking, I found that the orchid
has a lot of rotting roots. So, we need
to cut off all the damaged roots so that
the plant can recover and grow back.
Removing the damaged roots helps stop
the spread of fungi and bacteria while
also creating favorable conditions for
new healthy roots to grow. This in turn
helps the orchid recover quickly and
continue to thrive.
Next, we need to remove the yellowing
and wilting leaves as this will help the
plant focus its energy on recovering and
developing healthier parts.
[Music]
Next, we need to cut off the old flower
stems as this will help the plant focus
its nutrients on developing new parts,
supporting the recovery process, and
preparing for the next blooming season.
[Music]
After cutting off the damaged roots, we
wash the plant under running water to
remove dirt, bacteria, and mold while
also cleaning the growing medium. This
creates a better environment for the
plant to absorb water and nutrients more
easily.
Now we will prepare fertilizer to help
restore the health of the orchid,
providing the necessary nutrients for
the plant to grow strong again.
To make natural fertilizer, I use one
teaspoon of sugar, which provides a
natural energy source for the plant.
Then dilute it with one liter of water
to create a fertilizer solution that is
easy for the plant to absorb.
[Music]
After preparing the solution, pour it
over and soak the orchid leaves for
about 20 minutes. This helps provide
nutrients directly to the plant, aiding
in the recovery of wilted leaves and
stimulating the growth of new leaves.
This process will help revive the wilted
leaves, making them fresher and
healthier by replenishing energy and
essential nutrients.
Next, take one liter of water to prepare
the second natural fertilizer, which
will provide additional nutrients for
the orchid.
Then add one teaspoon of dry yeast,
which helps stimulate the decomposition
process and improve the soil quality,
creating a favorable environment for the
plant's growth.
Next, add 1 teaspoon of flour.
The combination of flour and yeast in
the water will create a nutrient-rich
environment, helping to promote the
growth of beneficial microorganisms,
improve the fertility of the growing
medium, and support the orchid's quick
recovery.
[Music]
Then wait for about 20 minutes to allow
the solution to react, helping the
ingredients in the fertilizer blend
together and work at their best.
After soaking the wilted leaves for
about 20 minutes, be sure to remove them
and avoid leaving them in the solution
for too long as this can cause water
logging, making the leaves prone to
rotting and less effective at absorbing
nutrients.
Then use a soft cloth to gently wipe off
all excess water, helping to prevent
long-term moisture on the leaves. create
conditions for the plant to recover
quickly and reduce the risk of mold.
[Music]
Please let me know which country you're
watching the video from. It's it's
amazing that we can chat together from
all around the world.
Now we will mix the solutions together
to create a perfect blend that will
provide nutrients for the orchid.
When mixing, be sure to filter out any
sediment to ensure the solution is
smooth and easily absorbed by the plant
without hindering the nutrient
absorption process.
[Music]
Then soak the orchid roots in this
mixture for about 20 minutes. This helps
provide nutrients directly to the roots,
promoting the recovery process and
encouraging the strong growth of new
roots.
The remaining mixture can be used to
water the other orchids in the garden,
providing additional nutrients and
supporting healthy growth for all the
plants.
Just water each pot with about 5 to 10
tablespoons of this mixture. Enough to
provide nutrients without causing water
logging.
[Music]
This natural fertilizer helps stimulate
the roots to grow quickly, just like the
strong growth of this orchid.
[Music]
This natural fertilizer not only helps
revive the weakened orchid, but also
supports healthy orchids in the garden,
promoting strong growth, encouraging
root development, and keeping the plants
lush, lush, and thriving.
[Music]
This natural fertilizer not only helps
revive the weakened orchid, but also
supports healthy orchids in the garden,
promoting strong growth, encouraging
root development, and keeping the plants
lush, lush, and thriving.
[Music]
If you haven't subscribed to the channel
yet, don't forget to hit the subscribe
button to support me and never miss any
useful orchid care tips. It's wonderful
to have you with me on this journey.
[Music]
In addition to the English voiceover, we
have now created voiceovers in French,
German, Italian, Spanish, Portuguese,
Japanese, Hindi, and Indonesian to help
you listen and understand the content
more easily.
[Music]
For languages without voiceovers, we
have created subtitles so you can read
and understand the content.
[Music]
For languages without voiceovers, we
have created subtitles so you can read
and understand the content.
Uh at the bottom of the pot, I place a
few pieces of foam to improve drainage,
creating conditions for the orchid roots
to grow easily and preventing water
logging.
[Music]
I insert a plasticcoated metal stake
into the foam. After planting the
orchid, we can secure the plant,
ensuring it stays steady and doesn't
shift during its growth process.
I insert a plasticcoated metal stake
into the foam. After planting the
orchid, we can secure the plant,
ensuring it stays steady and doesn't
shift during its growth process.
[Music]
I spread a layer of moss on top of the
pot to help retain moisture for the
plant, protect the roots from direct
sunlight, and create stable conditions
for the orchid's growth.
[Music]
I spread a layer of moss on top of the
pot to help retain moisture for the
plant, protect the roots from direct
sunlight, and create stable conditions
for the orchid's growth.
[Music]
From now on, water the orchid with this
fertilizer mixture once a week to
provide continuous nutrients. helping
the plant recover quickly and grow
healthily.
On regular days when the growing medium
is dry, simply water the orchid to
maintain moisture, helping the plant
stay hydrated without wilting.
Then place the orchid pot in a spot with
gentle sunlight, ensuring the plant
receives enough light without the risk
of leaf burn, creating the best
conditions for its growth.
Now, let's take a look at the results
after 3 weeks of caring for the orchid
with natural fertilizer.
[Music]
You can see that many new roots have
sprouted, indicating that the orchid is
recovering well and growing strongly.
[Music]
Although the leaves are still wilted, as
new roots develop, the plant will
gradually recover and start growing new
leaves, making it stronger and
healthier.
Continue
watering the orchid with this fertilizer
mixture once a week to maintain strong
growth and help the plant produce new
roots and grow healthily.
And here is the result after 2 months of
recovery with natural fertilizer.
As you can see, although the leaves are
still wilted, they have become much
sturdier compared to before, showing
that the plant is gradually recovering.
The orchid has even grown a new flower
spike, indicating that the recovery
process is progressing very well. This
shows that the plant is gradually coming
back to life. Not only recovering its
leaves, but also starting to show signs
of strong growth, such as the appearance
of a new flower spike.
[Music]
I continue to water the orchid with this
natural fertilizer mixture once a week,
providing regular nutrients to help the
plant grow healthily and produce
beautiful flowers.
Once the orchid has developed enough
roots and is securely anchored in the
medium and pot, we can remove the tying
string to prevent it from constricting
the plant, allowing it to continue
growing naturally.
[Music]
And here is the result after 3 months of
recovery.
[Music]
As you can see, after 3 months of
recovery, the orchid has fully revived.
The leaves are now vibrant and full of
life, showing that the care method has
been incredibly effective, helping the
plant grow strong and healthy once
again.
What do you think about the way I
revived my weak orchid? Feel free to
leave a comment and share your thoughts
with me.
Um, the flower buds are plump and ready
for the next bloom. With the vibrant
flowers about to bloom, the orchid now
shows a remarkable recovery and promises
to bring a colorful season of flowers.
[Music]
If you found the content helpful and
meaningful, don't forget to like, share,
and subscribe to support my channel.
Thank you for always being with me.
Thank you for watching the video. So I
also pray that God blesses you and
everyone.
Hello everyone.
Welcome to my channel. In today's video,
I will continue to share how to make
organic fertilizer that helps weak
orchids with yellowing leaves recover
and leaves and bloom abundantly and
sustainably.
[Music]
Let's get started.
When growing orchids, it is impossible
to avoid the phenomenon of yellowing
leaves and leaf rot, which weakens the
orchid.
[Music]
If you have an orchid with yellow or
rotten leaves like this orchid, this is
the video to help you take better care
of it in the future.
[Music]
First, remove all damaged leaves on the
orchid to prevent the rot from spreading
further.
[Music]
Then remove the damaged roots on the
orchid.
[Music]
Damaged roots can lead to diseases.
Removing them helps prevent the spread
of bacteria and fungi.
By removing damaged roots, the plant can
focus on developing new healthy roots,
improving its ability to absorb water
and nutrients.
[Music]
Then spread a little moss on top of the
orchid pot to help retain moisture
better and stimulate new roots.
[Music]
Moss adds a natural beauty and decorates
the orchid pot, making the planting area
more vibrant.
[Music]
Which country are you watching the video
from? Please comment below.
Uh it's great that we can chat together
from all over the world.
[Music]
If you haven't subscribed yet, please
subscribe to support my channel. Thank
you very much.
[Music]
Um, then I use bananas as fertilizer to
care for this orchid.
Take one banana and cut it into thin
slices.
Bananas are rich in essential nutrients
like potassium, phosphorus, and
magnesium, which are crucial for orchid
growth, especially during flowering.
[Music]
Put the bananas in the jar.
Do you have aloe vera?
[Music]
Take one aloe vera leaf and cut it into
thin slices.
[Music]
Aloe vera contains many vitamins and
minerals providing essential nutrients
for orchid growth.
Put aloe vera in the jar.
Aloe vera gel improves the plant's
ability to absorb water and nutrients,
keeping the soil moist without water
logging.
[Music]
Then add two cups of warm water about
500 ml.
Uh, if you haven't subscribed yet,
please subscribe to support my channel.
Thank you very much.
Now I add beer for fermentation.
[Music]
Beer contains various B vitamins and
minerals providing essential nutrients
for orchid growth.
The sugars and yeast in beer help
stimulate the growth of the root system,
allowing orchids to develop stronger.
Add 100 milllers of beer, about a half
cup.
Beer can enhance the plant's ability to
absorb water and nutrients, making the
orchids healthier.
[Music]
Then cover and leave in a cool place for
3 weeks to create synthetic GE from
banana and aloe vera.
[Music]
And this is the GE banana and aloe vera
product I fermented 3 weeks ago.
Take 50 mills of this synthetic GE.
About 3 tablespoons.
[Music]
Add 2 L of water, about four cups.
Stir well so that the nutrients dissolve
evenly in the water.
[Music]
Stir well so that the nutrients dissolve
evenly in the water.
[Music]
Water and soak the orchid pot in this
liquid fertilizer.
[Music]
The combination of bananas, aloe vera,
and beer creates a natural liquid
fertilizer with many positive effects
for orchids.
The fermented extract from bananas and
aloe vera contains a variety of
vitamins, minerals, and enzymes
providing essential nutrients for the
holistic development of the plants.
[Music]
Uh, the enzymes in aloe vera and
compounds in bananas stimulate root
growth, enabling orchids to absorb water
and nutrients more effectively.
[Music]
Uh, then soak the orchid pot in this
fertilizer solution for about 20 minutes
to help the roots absorb nutrients and
water best.
[Music]
Step two,
use a soft cotton to absorb this liquid
fertilizer and gently wipe the top and
bottom of the leaves.
[Music]
Wiping the leaves provides additional
vitamins and minerals from the extract,
supporting the plant's growth.
This method of cleaning leaves will
remove dust and debris, allowing better
air circulation and enhancing the
plant's ability to photosynthesize.
[Music]
The antibacterial and antifungal
properties of the extract help protect
the leaves from harmful bacteria and
fungi.
The antibacterial and antifungal
properties of the extract help help
protect the leaves from harmful bacteria
and fungi.
[Music]
Wiping the leaves with the extract helps
orchids enhance their resilience against
environmental factors and diseases.
[Music]
Which country are you watching videos
from? Please comment me.
[Music]
It's nice that we can chat with each
other from all over the world.
[Music]
Step three.
And then you put this amount of liquid
fertilizer into a spray bottle.
Then you spray the entire orchid.
[Music]
Spraying the liquid fertilizer helps
strengthen the plant's resistance
against diseases and unfavorable
environmental factors.
Using the liquid fertilizer supports
robust growth of the orchids from roots
to leaves and flowers.
After soaking for 20 minutes, take the
orchid pot out and place it in a place
with lots of sunlight so the orchid can
photosynthesize well.
[Music]
After soaking for 20 minutes, take the
orchid pot out and place it in a place
with lots of sunlight so the orchid can
photosynthesize well.
The orchid has grown many new roots.
[Music]
Uh new roots play a very important role
in the growth and development of
orchids.
Uh new roots help the plant absorb water
and essential nutrients from the
environment uh supporting its growth and
development.
Healthy roots enhance the orchid's
resistance to diseases and unfavorable
environmental conditions.
[Music]
New roots help the plant establish a
strong connection with its habitat,
thereby providing more stability.
[Music]
Roots can also store nutrients, helping
the plant maintain its life and growth
during difficult times.
[Music]
The development of new roots stimulates
the growth of other parts such as stems,
leaves, and flowers.
New roots are a decisive factor in the
healthy growth and development of
orchids, directly affecting the plant's
ability to absorb nutrients and its
resilience.
[Music]
Finally, give your love and care to your
plant companions.
Nurture your orchids with all your heart
and you will be rewarded with their
amazing beauty.
Hope you like the video. Please comment
to let me know how you liked it.
Goodbye and see you again in the next
videos.
Wishing you luck and success in your
plant care journey.