Welcome to my little orchid garden where
each petal is nurtured with love and
passion. Today I will guide you on how
to propagate orchids at home using the
stem cutting method. Simple yet
effective. The ideal time for stem
cutting is when the orchid flowers begin
to fade. When the plant enters its
resting phase and is ready for new
growth. This flower stem is the ideal
time to take a cutting, helping the
plant grow stronger.
[Music]
Keep the unopened buds like this for
stem cutting as they contain dormant
shoots that can sprout into new orchid
plants.
As for the positions where the flowers
have bloomed, you should cut them off as
they no longer contain uh dormant buds
to develop into new orchid plants.
[Music]
I keep these two dormant buds for stem
cutting and later the new orchid plant
will grow from here.
I cut across here to avoid crushing the
cut as crushed areas are prone to
infection and can affect the plant's
growth.
At the base of the cutting, I make a
diagonal cut to create a larger contact
surface, which helps the cutting absorb
water and nutrients more effectively.
Then I sprinkle turmeric powder on the
cut. This helps with antibacterial
protection, uh, prevents rot and
promotes faster healing of the wound.
After that, I leave the cutting for a
few hours without watering to let the
cut dry, reducing the risk of infection
when planting.
After that, you use rice, a material
rich in B vitamins and essential
minerals to support the orchid stem
cutting
process. Take 3 tablesp of rice and
dilute it with.5 L of water to create a
solution for soaking the cutings.
Cover the lid and let it sit for a few
hours to allow the nutrients from the
rice to fully dissolve.
Cover the lid and let it sit for a few
hours to allow the nutrients from the
rice to fully
dissolve. Dilute the turmeric powder
with 0.5 L of water to create a solution
for soaking the stem cutings.
Cover the lid and let the solution sit
for a few hours to allow the nutrients
from the turmeric powder to fully
dissolve into the water.
After 3 hours of soaking, I proceed to
filter the turmeric water to use for the
stem cutings.
Make sure to filter out the residue as
it can cause blockages and affect the
cutting's ability to absorb nutrients.
[Music]
Step one, use a soft cloth to soak up
the turmeric solution and gently wipe it
onto the stem
cutting. This method helps protect the
cut, prevent infection, and stimulate
the rooting process of the stem cutting.
Then use this mixture to wipe both the
top and bottom surfaces of the stem
cutting, helping to enhance nutrient
absorption and protect the plant from
pests and diseases.
If you haven't subscribed to the channel
yet, please hit the subscribe button to
support me and never miss any orchid
growing tips. It's wonderful to have you
along. Let me know in the comments which
country you're watching the video from.
It's amazing that we can chat together
from all around the world.
[Music]
Then mix the rice water with the
turmeric water to create the perfect
nutrient solution, helping the rooting
and growth process of the stem cutting
improve. When mixing, make sure to
filter the rice water thoroughly to
remove any residue, making the solution
cleaner and easier for the stem cutting
to absorb.
After mixing, soak the stem cutting in
this mixture for about 20 minutes to
allow the nutrients to be absorbed into
the
[Music]
cutting. This mixture helps the stem
cutting absorb nutrients more
effectively, stimulating the rooting
process and promoting strong growth.
[Music]
Um, while waiting, I will prepare the
tools to help improve the effectiveness
of the stem cutting
process. Prepare a plastic box or a
transparent glass cup and a piece of
floral foam. then follow the steps I
guide you
through. In addition to the English
voiceover, we have now created
voiceovers in French, German, Italian,
Spanish, Portuguese, Japanese, Hindi,
and Indonesian to help you listen to and
understand the content more easily.
For languages without voiceovers, we
have created subtitles uh so you can
read and understand the content.
[Music]
After soaking for 20 minutes, take the
stem cutting out to proceed with placing
it in the prepared container.
Then add bottled water or cooled boiled
water enough to submerge the floral
foam.
Then add bottled water or cooled boiled
water enough to submerge the floral
foam. Then cover it with a transparent
plastic lid and place it in a spot with
gentle sunlight for the stem cutting to
develop well.
Um, the remaining mixture I used to
water the roots of the orchids in the
garden to provide nutrients to the
plants. Water each plant with about 10
tablespoons as this amount provides
enough nutrients without overwatering
the plant.
[Music]
This mixture helps the orchid strengthen
its rooting ability, promoting strong
growth from the
base. The vitamins and minerals in this
mixture help the orchid resist pests and
harmful factors.
Watering with this mixture helps the
orchid absorb nutrients better, leading
to the production of beautiful and
long-lasting
flowers. You can water each orchid pot
with this mixture one to two times a
month to provide consistent nutrients
for the plants.
Now, let's take a look at the results
after 1 month of stem cutting.
As you can see, the stem cutting has
sprouted two new orchid plants from the
dormant buds, proving that the cutting
process was successful and the plant is
growing well.
The young orchid plant may be small, but
it has already started growing roots,
showing that the plant is developing
healthily and is getting ready to
mature. I will continue to keep the stem
cutting in the container to allow the
orchid to grow larger before planting it
in the outside environment.
Um, when the water becomes cloudy or has
a strange smell, you should change it
immediately to prevent bacteria from
developing and harming the
cutings. Use filtered water or boiled
water that has cooled down when
replacing it to maintain a clean
environment and promote faster root
growth for the cutings.
Then place the cutings in a spot with
gentle sunlight to help the plant absorb
light, stimulate root growth, and
prevent leaf
burn. And here is the result after 2
months of rooting the cutings.
You can see that the roots have grown
strong and healthy, proving that the
correct care method has yielded
excellent results.
[Music]
When the orchid seedlings are healthy
and the roots have developed well, that
is the ideal time to separate them and
plant them into new
pots. Uh this helps the orchids have
more space to grow, which in turn
promotes strong growth in the new
environment.
Plant the orchid in a pot with good
drainage holes to ensure that water
doesn't accumulate, helping the roots
avoid rot and promoting healthier
growth. I choose pine bark chips as the
growing medium because it has good
drainage capacity, helps maintain stable
moisture levels for the orchids without
causing water logging, and also provides
essential nutrients for root
development.
I choose pine bark chips as the growing
medium because it has good drainage
capacity, helps maintain stable moisture
levels for the orchids without causing
water logging and also provides
essential nutrients for root
development.
How do you find my orchid cutting
tutorial video? Please leave a comment
below the video to let me know your
thoughts. Spread a little moss on top of
the pot before placing the orchid
seedling in to help retain moisture
better. create ideal conditions for the
plant's growth and prevent water from
evaporating too
quickly. Thank you for watching the
video. I wish you success with your
orchids. Goodbye and see you in the next
videos.