Hello everyone. Today we will explore
the secrets of caring for orchids so
that they stay healthy and can bloom all
year round. When you understand the
plant's needs from light, water to
nutrients, orchids will not only live
well, but also bring you continuous
beautiful flowers. With patience and
love for the plant, you will see your
home always filled with the colors and
fragrance of radiant orchids.
To make natural fertilizer, I choose a
fresh okra and cut it into very thin
slices.
[Music]
Uh in this way, the nutrients in okra
will dissolve more easily, helping the
orchid absorb them quickly and grow
strong from roots to leaves.
[Music]
Uh, if you haven't subscribed to the
channel yet, click the subscribe button
to support me and not miss any orchid
growing tips. It's wonderful to have you
along for the journey.
After cutting the okra into thin slices,
I put them all into a clean jar.
Uh, the next ingredient is rice. I take
two teaspoons of rice and put it
together with the okra.
Then I put all the ingredients into
about one liter of warm water. Warm
water will help extract the nutrients
from okra and rice faster, creating a
nutrient-rich solution that easily
penetrates the orchid roots and
nourishes the plant to grow vigorously.
[Music]
Then I stir the mixture well, close the
lid tightly, and leave it overnight.
During this time, the nutrients from
okra and rice will be fully released
into the water, creating a natural,
safe, and highly beneficial fertilizer
for orchids.
After buying orchids from industrial
gardens, you will see that the flowers
only bloom beautifully for a short time,
then gradually wither and quickly fall
off. If you don't know how to care for
them properly, the orchid will become
weak, easily die, and will never bloom
again.
[Music]
You can see on this stem many flowers
have already fallen. If we don't take
proper care, the remaining flowers will
also quickly wither and fall off,
leaving the orchid stem bare.
[Music]
To keep the remaining flowers on the
stem blooming longer, the first thing
you should do is remove the old pot and
move the plant into a new one. This way,
the orchid roots will have a clean, airy
environment and can absorb nutrients
more easily.
[Music]
After that, cut off the yellowed or
damaged leaves. This helps the plant
avoid wasting energy on weak parts and
at the same time allows the healthy
roots and leaves to grow better.
[Music]
Next, cut off the rotten or shriveled
roots. By removing the weak roots, the
plant will focus its energy on
nourishing the healthy ones, thereby
providing enough nutrients for the
remaining flowers and helping them stay
fresh longer on the stem.
[Music]
The damaged roots are often a hiding
place for fungi, bacteria, and many
other pathogens. Cutting them off will
help prevent the spread to the healthy
roots and the entire orchid.
[Music]
If the damaged roots are not removed,
rot can easily spread to these new
roots.
New roots will have a better ability to
absorb water and nutrients, thereby
helping the orchid grow stronger.
[Music]
That is my housemmaid. Do you have any
pets?
[Music]
Uh damaged roots will reduce the plant's
ability to absorb water and nutrients.
By removing them, the orchid will more
easily take in the essential nutrients
from the environment, helping it stay
healthy and recover faster.
[Music]
When roots are rotten or damaged, they
can hinder air circulation in the
growing medium. Removing the damaged
roots helps improve irerration for the
roots, creating better conditions for
their growth.
[Music]
After that, cut off all the dried or
damaged stems. This helps the plant
avoid wasting energy on dead parts and
stimulates it to focus on nourishing new
healthy shoots and stems.
Now I plant the orchid into a new pot.
This time adding some crushed pine bark.
Pine bark not only keeps the roots well
airrated but also ensures good drainage
creating an ideal environment for the
plant to grow healthily and bloom
brilliantly.
[Music]
I plant two orchids in the same large
pot after the flowers fade. Orchids
usually need a new environment to
continue growing. Um, transplanting into
a new pot with fresh nutrient-rich
medium provides better conditions for
the roots and the entire plant, helping
them stay healthy and ready for the next
blooming season.
[Music]
For the other plant, I planted into a
smaller pot just the right size for the
plant.
Choosing a suitable pot helps the roots
grow evenly, keeps the plant healthy,
and makes it easier to absorb water and
nutrients.
[Music]
Um, when the plant is replanted, the
roots will have new space and nutrients
to grow. This helps the plant absorb
water and nutrients more efficiently,
promoting its growth.
After being planted in a new pot and
properly cared for, the orchid will grow
more vigorously and have the potential
to continue blooming well or even better
in the following seasons.
After planting, let the plant sit
overnight without watering immediately.
This helps the roots stabilize in the
new environment and prevents them from
rotting due to excess moisture too soon.
After fermenting overnight, we stir well
so that the nutrients from the flowers
fully dissolve in the water.
[Music]
Then strain out the remaining residue in
the solution. This step helps make the
fertilizer solution clear and clean,
allowing it to penetrate the orchid
roots easily and ensure the plant
absorbs nutrients more effectively.
Next, dilute the solution by adding one
more liter of water. Diluting helps make
the solution sufficiently nutritious,
safe for the roots, and easily absorbed
by the plant without causing irritation
or harming the orchid.
Step one, use a cotton pad to soak a
little of the solution. Then gently wipe
both the top and bottom surfaces of the
orchid leaves. This helps the leaves
absorb nutrients directly and keeps the
plant clean and healthy.
Um, this method helps remove dust and
mineral deposits on the leaves, keeping
the leaf surface clean for better
photosynthesis.
Impurities
and dust create conditions for fungi and
bacteria to grow. Wiping the leaves
helps remove hidden pathogens and
reduces the risk of infection.
[Music]
Uh clean leaves help the plant absorb
nutrients and water better from the air
and growing medium promoting strong
growth.
[Music]
When the leaves are healthy and clean,
the plant will have better growth
potential, including blooming and root
development.
[Music]
Clean and shiny leaves not only make the
plant look healthy, but also enhance the
aesthetic value of the orchid.
[Music]
Uh leaf cleaning can be done once a
month or whenever dust accumulates on
the leaves.
[Music]
In addition to English voiceover, we
have now created French, German,
Italian, Spanish, Portuguese, Japanese,
Hindi, Dutch, Polish, Korean, and
Indonesian versions to help you listen
and understand the content easily. To
hear a language, open the video and
click on settings gear icon to select
the appropriate audio language.
Please comment and let me know which
country you are watching the video from.
It's amazing that we can chat together
from all around the world.
[Music]
Step two, evenly water this fertilizer
mixture onto the roots and the growing
medium around the plant.
This method helps the roots absorb
nutrients directly, stimulates healthy
growth, keeps the flowers lasting longer
on the stem, and prepares for upcoming
blooms.
[Music]
Uh when watering this mixture onto the
roots and growing medium, the orchid
will absorb nutrients directly, helping
the roots grow strong. Healthy roots are
an important foundation for lush green
leaves and preparing for vibrant blooms
in the future.
[Music]
Additionally, watering with this mixture
provides the necessary energy for the
remaining flowers on the stem. As a
result, the flowers last longer on the
stem, stay fresher, and maintain their
vibrant beauty, making the orchid more
lively and attractive.
[Music]
You can soak the roots in this solution
for about 20 minutes. This time allows
the roots to absorb the maximum
nutrients, nourishing the plant to grow
strong and be ready for the next
blooming process.
[Music]
Step three, evenly spray the mixture
over the entire orchid, including the
leaves and stem. This helps the plant
absorb nutrients from the leaf surface
while keeping the leaves and flowers
fresh and healthy.
This method works similarly to using
folure fertilizer. It provides the plant
with easily absorbable nutrients,
helping the leaves and flowers take them
up quickly, nourishing the plant and
keeping the flowers fresh for longer.
This lightly fermented mixture will
comprehensively protect and nourish the
orchid, helping the plant grow strong
from roots through the stem to the
leaves.
After soaking for 20 minutes, take the
orchid pot out and place it in a spot
with gentle light. This helps the plant
photosynthesize effectively. Remember,
no matter how good the fertilizer is, if
the plant lacks light, it will be
difficult for it to grow vigorously and
bloom beautifully.
[Music]
And here is the result after 3 weeks.
The leaves are healthier and shinier
than before replanting, showing that the
orchid has absorbed nutrients well and
adapted to the new environment.
[Music]
You can also see many new roots growing.
These new roots have a better ability to
absorb water and nutrients, helping the
orchid grow strong and prepare for the
next blooming season.
[Music]
Clean and shiny orchid leaves help the
plant photosynthesize more effectively,
thereby improving metabolism, keeping
the plant healthy, and promoting vibrant
blooms.
[Music]
You can see the orchid has started to
grow new flower buds while the old
flowers are still on the stem. This
shows that the plant is growing
healthily and the blooming process
continues successfully.
[Music]
The fertilizer made from okra retains
moisture very well, allowing the flowers
on the stem to stay fresh longer before
they start to wilt.
[Music]
Um, what do you think about how I
revived this small orchid? Don't
hesitate to leave a comment and share
your thoughts. I'd love to hear your
feedback and experiences.
If you find the content useful and
meaningful, don't forget to like, share
so more people can see it and subscribe
to support me. Thank you for always
being with me.
[Music]