Welcome to the happiness garden where
every day we care for and admire the
orchids blooming in vibrant colors.
Here every leaf and every root tells a
story of gentle care and love for the
plants.
Today I will share with you how to care
for orchids with wilted and wrinkled
leaves by using natural fertilizer. When
applied correctly, the plant will
quickly regain vitality. The roots will
grow strong and the leaves will become
greener.
Gradually, the orchids will bloom
brilliantly, showing their colors and
bringing joy and excitement to your
garden.
First, gently cut off the dried and
wilted flower stems still attached to
the plant. This not only helps the plant
look tidier but also allows energy to
focus on the roots and leaves thereby
promoting healthy growth.
Next, we will carefully examine the
roots along with the surrounding medium.
This helps you identify which roots are
still healthy, which ones are damaged,
and whether the medium is sufficiently
airy or retaining too much water.
Through the inspection, I noticed that
the plant's roots are still healthy, but
slightly wrinkled, indicating that the
plant needs additional nutrients and
moisture.
The surrounding medium is still good and
airy, so we don't need to repot. We just
focus on caring for the roots to help
them recover.
[Music]
Since both the roots and leaves are
wrinkled, the next step we need to take
is to water and soak the roots before
applying fertilizer.
This helps the roots absorb enough
water, expand, and become more flexible,
creating optimal conditions for the
plant to take in nutrients from the
natural fertilizer.
When the roots are fully hydrated, the
leaves will gradually become plump again
and the orchid will be ready for the
recovery process.
When the roots and medium are
sufficiently moist, fertilizing becomes
much more effective. Nutrients from the
natural fertilizer will easily penetrate
the roots, helping the plant absorb the
essential elements to the fullest. As a
result, the roots will grow strong and
the leaves will gradually recover.
Soak the roots in water for about 20
minutes to ensure they are fully
hydrated.
This time allows the roots to expand,
become flexible, and be ready to absorb
nutrients from the fertilizer.
Uh while waiting for the roots to soak
for 20 minutes, we can take the
opportunity to prepare the natural
fertilizer to care for the orchids.
Aloe vera leaves contain natural gel
which is very good for restoring orchids
with wrinkled leaves. The gel in aloe
vera provides moisture and gentle
nutrients, helping the leaves become
plump again and reducing wilting.
Uh the next ingredient we will use is
rice. Rice is rich in starch and some
minerals and when made into natural
fertilizer, it provides energy and
essential nutrients for the orchid
roots.
Just three teaspoons of rice are enough
to prepare natural fertilizer for the
orchid.
[Music]
The final ingredient we will use is
vitamin B1. Just three tablets, each 2.5
mg. And vitamin B1 will stimulate strong
root growth and enhance the orchid's
ability to absorb nutrients.
[Music]
Mix all the ingredients into one liter
of water. This will create a uniform
natural fertilizer solution that can
easily penetrate the roots and the
medium.
[Music]
After dissolving the ingredients, cover
the container and let the solution rest
for about 2 hours.
[Music]
After soaking the roots for about 20
minutes, gently take the orchid out and
let it drain before applying fertilizer.
Allowing it to drain prevents the roots
from being overly submerged when
receiving the fertilizer, ensuring
nutrients are absor absorbed evenly and
effectively.
[Music]
After letting the fertilizer solution
rest for two hours, stir it well to
ensure the nutrients from the rice, aloe
vera gel, and vitamin B1 are evenly
dissolved, making sure every part of the
solution is rich in nutrients.
[Music]
After stirring well, strain out the
remaining residue in the solution. This
makes the fertilizer smooth and easy to
penetrate the roots, preventing blockage
and keeping the medium airy.
Gently squeeze the aloe vera leaves to
extract the gel and fully dissolve it
into the solution.
Then gently pour this mixture onto your
orchid pot.
Watering evenly over the roots and
medium helps the nutrients penetrate
deeply, stimulating strong root growth.
When you water this mixture onto a
wilting orchid, you will notice many
positive effects from the very first
time.
Aloe vera gel provides moisture and
gentle nutrients, helping wrinkled
leaves become plump again.
The rice in the solution provides starch
and minerals, stimulating strong root
growth while also promoting the
development of new leaves.
[Music]
Vitamin B1 helps the roots absorb
nutrients effectively, enhances
recovery, and enables the orchid to
quickly regain vitality, preparing for
new leaf growth and eventually the
fresh, vibrant flowers about to bloom.
After watering, you can let the orchid
pot soak in this mixture for about 20
minutes. Soaking helps the roots absorb
the maximum nutrients from the aloe
vera, rice, and vitamin B1 while also
increasing the necessary moisture for
the leaves and roots.
Next, use a soft cloth to dab this
mixture and gently wipe both the top and
underside of the leaves. This allows the
nutrients to penetrate directly into the
leaves, providing moisture and helping
restore wrinkled, wilted leaves.
When the leaves are carefully cared for,
they become plump and healthy,
contributing to the orchid's full
recovery and preparing it for the bright
flowers about to bloom.
You can pour the leftover mixture into a
spray bottle and use it to mist the
other orchids in your garden. This helps
make the most of the nutrients while
providing even moisture and nutrition to
all the plants.
When regularly cared for with this
natural solution, the other orchids will
also grow healthy, have lush green
leaves, and be ready to bloom
beautifully.
For orchids that have not yet bloomed,
this fertilizer will help stimulate
strong root growth and healthier,
greener leaves.
When the roots are firm and the leaves
are healthy, the plant will store enough
energy to form buds. As a result, the
blooming process will go smoothly, and
you will soon enjoy the sight of
brilliant flowers blooming all at once
in your garden.
Uh, for orchids that are already
blooming, this fertilizer will help the
flowers stay fresh longer and bloom
evenly with petals that are fuller and
more beautiful.
[Music]
After soaking for about 20 minutes, take
the orchid pot out and place it in a
spot with gentle sunlight. The soft
light will help the plant
photosynthesize better, allowing the
leaves and roots to recover quickly.
[Music]
And here's the result after 2 weeks of
care.
[Music]
uh you can see that many new roots have
grown showing that the plant is
recovering very well. Uh
[Music]
Not only the roots but new leaves have
also alo started to sprout, showing that
the plant is gradually regaining its
vitality. With regular care, in just a
short time, these new leaves will grow
strong, lush green, and full of life.
[Music]
I continue to care for the orchid with
natural fertilizer made from aloe vera,
rice, and vitamin B1. This combination
provides complete nutrients, helping the
roots grow strong and encouraging faster
and more abundant new leaf growth.
[Music]
If you haven't subscribed yet, click the
subscribe button to support me and never
miss any orchid care tips. It's
wonderful to have you along.
Water your orchid with this mixture once
every 2 weeks. A regular watering
schedule will keep the roots healthy,
the leaves green, and the plant
consistently full of vitality.
[Music]
Or you can also pour the mixture into a
spray bottle and mist it evenly over the
leaves. stems, roots, and even the
medium. This method allows the nutrients
to be absorbed directly by each part of
the plant, providing both moisture and
complete nourishment.
When done regularly, the orchid will
recover faster, grow more lush green
leaves, and develop strong, healthy
roots.
[Music]
This method should also be done
regularly, twice a month. Uh regular
spraying helps maintain ideal moisture
levels and provides consistent nutrients
for the plant.
[Music]
And here is the result after the next
month.
You can see that new leaves have grown,
becoming sturdier and healthier.
[Music]
And the root system has also grown
dense, clinging tightly to the medium
and spreading deep into the pot. This
shows that the plant is healthy,
absorbing nutrients to the fullest, and
preparing for vigorous growth in the
coming time.
Uh continue caring for your orchid with
this mixture on the proper schedule and
you will see the plant become greener
with lush leaves, strong roots, and
ready for the next blooming cycle.
[Music]
Uh what do you think about how I revived
this little orchid? Don't hesitate to
leave a comment and share your thoughts.
I'd love to hear your feedback and
experiences so we can take even better
care of orchids together.
[Music]
Continue watering or spraying this
mixture on your orchid twice a month,
alternating with regular watering to
ensure the plant always receives enough
nutrients and maintains ideal moisture.
[Music]
And remember to place the orchid pot in
a spot with gentle sunlight as soft
light helps the leaves photosynthesize
better, strengthens the roots, and
encourages the plant to bloom again more
quickly.
[Music]
And here is the result after 3 months of
recovery.
You can see that the root system has
become denser with many new roots
clinging tightly to the medium. A clear
sign that the orchid is growing very
strong and steadily.
And you can also see new leaves growing
fresh and healthy, a sign that the plant
is full of life.
[Music]
Uh the old wrinkled leaves haven't fully
recovered yet, but they are beginning to
show signs of plumpness again,
indicating that the plant is gradually
regaining vitality and balanced
nutrition.
[Music]
What's special is that the orchid has
even grown a new flower spike, showing
that the plant has not only fully
recovered, but also stored enough energy
to prepare for the bright flowers about
to bloom.
[Music]
Care for your orchid with all your love
and patience because when nurtured with
gentle attention, the plant will grow
strong with lush green leaves and
vibrant flowers bringing complete joy to
your garden.
[Music]
That's the end of today's video. Thank
you for watching and joining me on this
journey of orchid care. Continue to love
and care for your orchid pots so they
stay healthy and bloom beautifully.