hello
[Music]
everyone today we will explore how to
make natural fertilizer to help revive
and promote the growth of orchids after
they
bloom did you know that proper care will
ensure your orchids bloom beautifully in
the next
season let's discover some simple
ingredients and an easy process to keep
your orchids healthy and thriving
[Music]
let's get
started the old Orchid branches have all
[Music]
bloomed after flowering orchids often
become weak because they've spent a lot
of energy to bloom so we need to restore
them so that they can continue to bloom
strongly the next flowering season
cut off all old flower
[Music]
stems when cutting off Old Flower
branches the plant will focus its energy
on growing new branches and leaves
helping the plant become
[Music]
healthier then cut off damaged
leaves damaged leaves can Harbor
bacteria and fungi pruning helps reduce
the risk of spreading disease to the
[Music]
tree removing damaged leaves helps the
plant Focus its energy on healthy Parts
thereby growing better
[Music]
then cut off all damage
Roots damaged Roots can be a breeding
ground for bacteria and fungi causing
harm to the plant excision helps stop
the spread of the
[Music]
disease healthy roots are important for
plants to absorb water and
nutrients removing damaged Roots helps
the plant focus on growing new and
healthier
roots from which country are you
watching my video please comment for me
[Music]
Ginger is not only a familiar Spice in
the kitchen but also a miracle medicine
for your orchids
[Music]
with antibacterial antifungal and growth
stimulating properties Ginger helps
orchids restore Health promotes root and
leaf growth while enhancing resistance
to harmful
factors uh take about 10 G of Ginger and
cut it into small
slices My Maids do you like them
then put it in a
[Music]
jar add four cups of boiling water about
1 liter
close the lid and wait for the water to
[Music]
cool next I need oatmeal
take 3 tablespoons of
[Music]
oatmeal add four cups of boiling water
about 1
liter close the lid and wait for the
water to cool
2 hours
[Music]
later filter out Ginger residue
step one clean the leaves with ginger
juice
by wiping the leaves you help remove
dirt and impurities from the leaf
surface making it easier for the plant
to photosynthesize
[Music]
Ginger water contains compounds that are
beneficial to plant Health helping to
enhance growth and
Recovery ginger has natural
antibacterial properties wiping leaves
with ginger juice helps reduce the risk
of bacterial and fungal infections
[Music]
when leaves are clean plants are better
able to absorb sunlight thereby
promoting photosynthesis
[Music]
uh then you put this water into a spray
bottle
[Music]
step two spray this water on the entire
Orchid spraying Ginger water on the
leaves helps increase humidity
especially in economical conditions
helping the plant not to
[Music]
wither Ginger water helps plants
increase their resistance to harmful
agents such as pests and adverse
environments
then mix the two types of water together
to form Liquid Fertilizer
uh Ginger and oats both contain many
nutrients necessary for plant growth
helping the plant recover quickly after
blooming
[Music]
step three water this mixture into each
Orchid pot to help supplement nutrients
through the roots very
effectively this mixture helps stimulate
the growth of roots and leaves creating
conditions for plants to grow
[Music]
healthier compounds in ginger have
antibacterial and antifungal properties
helping to protect plants from diseases
and increase resistance
[Music]
the remaining liquid fertilizer you use
to water other Orchid pots is also very
[Music]
good this will help the Orchid grow and
bloom faster
Oats help improve soil structure retain
moisture better thereby supporting the
development of the root system
[Music]
after watering soak the Orchid pot in
this water for about 20 minutes so that
the roots can absorb more
nutrients soaking Orchid pots in this
water will kill insects and fungi in the
growing medium
have you found insects crawling out of
orchid pots
[Music]
after soaking for 20 minutes take the
Orchid pot out and place it in a place
with lots of scattered
light scattered light helps plants
photosynthesize effectively without
burning leaves thereby providing energy
for
[Music]
growth on normal days when you see the
growing medium is dry you just need to
water or spray the orch Orchid with
water
[Music]
regularly the oat and ginger fertilizer
I just shared should only be applied
every 10 to 15
[Music]
days results after 16 days
orchids develop many new
Roots new Roots help the plant absorb
water and nutrients needed for growth
especially during the recovery period
after flowering
[Music]
healthy Roots help orchids be more
resistant to harmful agents such as
pests and harsh environmental
[Music]
conditions new root formation often
signals that the plant is in active
growth um which is important for
flowering in The Following season
[Music]
healthy Roots support Leaf growth
thereby helping plants perform
photosynthesis more
[Music]
effectively uh this Orchid I fertilized
with this fertilizer has now taken root
and is very healthy
[Music]
uh the same thing happens in this potted
Orchid the root system develops to the
point where the leaves are very green
and shiny
[Music]
you
uh new Roots also play an important role
in maintaining moisture for the plant
preventing it from drying
out care for your Orchids with passion
and Devotion to Nature and you will
receive brilliant flowers the result of
your own Loving Hands
[Music]
Let each Flower Branch become a symbol
of your care and
dedication thank you for taking the time
to watch this video If you find the
information useful don't forget to press
the Subscribe button and turn on
notifications so you don't miss the next
videos
please support our Channel by sharing
and leaving your comments below the
video your support is the greatest
motivation for us to continue to bring
more interesting knowledge thank you
very much