Welcome to my channel.
If you have an orchid did that has rot
causing the leaves to turn yellow.
[Music]
So don't rush to throw it away. I will
share how to revive it quickly and
easily.
[Music]
This orchid may be suffering from
inorganic fertilizer shock leading to
root rot causing the leaves to turn
yellow.
[Music]
So, I need to check the roots to cut off
all damaged roots.
[Music]
Removing damaged roots helps prevent the
rot from spreading, causing the entire
root of the orchid to rot.
[Music]
And stimulates new root formation.
faster.
[Music]
Then rinse with water.
Take 2 L of water and put it in a jar.
[Music]
Then add one teaspoon of baking soda to
help kill bacteria and eliminate pests.
[Music]
Soak orchid roots in this water for 10
minutes.
[Music]
Then use dry moss to grow orchids.
After soaking for 10 minutes, take the
orchid out and plant it.
[Music]
When planting dry, sterilized moss, it
will help absorb moisture from the
roots. This helps the cut heal quickly
and the rot does not spread further.
[Music]
Then place in a cool place and do not
water for one week.
[Music]
After one week, start watering the
orchid once a week.
[Music]
Soak in water for 10 minutes to keep the
moss moist.
[Music]
Then take it out and cover it with a
transparent plastic box.
[Music]
and remember to water it every week to
keep it moist.
[Music]
One month later,
the orchid has revived and grown healthy
roots.
[Music]
But it seems like the leaves are a bit
wilted.
[Music]
Once the root system is strong, you need
to add more nutrients to help the orchid
grow quickly.
[Music]
Take 2 L of water.
And add 5 teaspoons of rice.
[Music]
Rice contains a variety of minerals and
amino acids that are important for
orchid growth.
[Music]
Then use this rice water to water the
orchids once a week.
[Music]
In addition to providing necessary
nutrients, rice water also creates a
favorable environment for beneficial
microorganisms to grow in orchid pots.
[Music]
Soak for 10 minutes. Then take out the
orchid pot.
[Music]
[Applause]
regularly spray mist to keep the soil
moist when the growing medium is All
right.
[Music]
Two months later,
you can see that after 2 months of
recovery, the orchid has not only come
back to life, but also though grown more
vigorously.
The roots have grown long, the leaves
are lush green, and the whole plant
looks healthy and full of vitality. A
testament to patience and loving care.
[Music]
In fact, orchids are very easy to care
for as long as you truly understand
their needs. Once you know how,
everything becomes simple and the plant
will reward you with its delicate beauty
and enduring vitality.
[Music]
I still continue to care for the orchid
with the natural fertilizer made from
rice, applying it regularly every 2
weeks. Let's wait and see the upcoming
results. You'll be surprised by what
this simple method can bring.
[Music]
And this is the result. After 5 months
of patient recovery, the orchid has
truly transformed, becoming healthier
and more vigorous.
[Music]
And the most remarkable thing is that
the orchid has bloomed again. Not just
one, but two flower spikes have emerged
from the once withered stem. A wonderful
testament to the plant's powerful
vitality when properly cared for.
[Music]
The leaves of the plant have now become
sturdier, thicker, and much healthier
than before. A clear sign that the plant
is reviving from within.
[Music]
Sometimes with just a little proper
care, an orchid that seemed to have lost
all its vitality can miraculously come
back to life. As if with a bit of love,
it is ready to bloom again.
[Music]
With this simple natural method, you'll
see new roots start to grow, the leaves
turn green again, and the whole plant
seems to be revitalized.
Be patient. Be loving and you'll witness
the miracle in what you care for each
day.
Every orchid pot you care for is a small
journey of life where you plant faith,
patience, and love.
Even if the beginning is a weak orchid,
if you don't give up, the plant will
show you its incredible ability to
recover. Believe that as long as you
keep nurturing it, it won't let you
down.
Just start with one plant, then another.
Over time, little by little, you will
build a whole orchid garden bursting
with colorful blooms. Every step of care
you take today is the foundation for
lasting beauty in the future.
I hope you enjoy this video. If you find
it helpful, don't forget to hit like and
subscribe to the channel so you won't
miss the next tips on how to care for
orchids naturally and simply.
Thank you for staying with me and
watching until the end of the video.
Wishing you happiness, good health, and
plenty of orchids blooming beautifully
all year round. See you in the next
video.
[Music]