welcome to my
channel if you have orchids after
[Music]
blooming if all the flowers have fallen
don't rush to throw them
away uh let me tell you how to help
these branches continue to bloom
strongly again
[Music]
these nodes can continue to bloom very
well
[Music]
when you eat bananas don't throw away
the peel
[Music]
thinly sliced banana peels contain many
vitamins and minerals that are very good
for the bud formation
process please comment to me which
country you are watching the video from
it's great that we can chat together
from all over the world
[Music]
[Applause]
soak banana peels in 1 liter of boiled
[Music]
water then take 3 tblsp of coffee
grounds
[Music]
then soak this coffee grounds in 1 liter
of boiled water
then wait for the water to
[Music]
cool after the water cools filter to
remove sediment
[Music]
dip a cotton ball in water extracted
from coffee grounds and wash the
[Music]
leaves helps eliminate pests and
diseases of orchids
[Music]
and leaves will photosynthesize
better um if you haven't subscribed to
the channel yet please subscribe to
support me and not miss any orchid care
tips
[Music]
mix these two types
together dip cotton balls in this water
and clip them to nodes that are likely
to continue blooming
[Music]
do it once a
week will help stimulate rapid Sprout
growth
[Music]
uh keep the cotton pad on the branch
like that for 20 minutes
and then remove
[Music]
it then water The Roots once a week
soak it for 10 minutes then lift it
[Music]
out and spray this water once a week to
help supplement nutrients through the
leaves
[Music]
after 20 minutes remove the cotton pad
and then place the plant in a place with
lots of light so it can bloom easily
1 month
[Music]
later many buds have grown
if you encounter any difficulties during
the Orchid growing process don't
hesitate to comment I am always ready to
support you so you can grow healthy
orchids and Bloom lots of flowers
[Music]
cons
Pon if there in
[Music]
then place the plant in a place with
lots of light so it can bloom
[Music]
easily after the next one month
from the dry branches many beautiful
flowers have sprouted and
[Music]
bloomed the leaves are strong and sturdy
very resistant to pests and diseases
[Music]
the flower color is also more vibrant
than
[Music]
usual hope the video will help you a lot
if you find it interesting please like
share and subscribe to the channel to
help my channel reach 1 million
subscribers soon
[Music]
my videos have subtitles in many
different languages so you can choose
the appropriate
[Music]
language thank you for watching the
video good luck and see you in the next
videos
[Music]