Welcome to this little corner where we
explore the gentle beauty and enduring
vitality of orchids together.
Thank you for stopping by. I hope you
find plenty of inspiration here.
When the orchid is provided with
sufficient nutrients and lives in an
ideal growing medium, it will absorb
better, grow more vigorously, and
produce more radiant blooms than ever
before.
In this video, I will share with you a
natural fertilizer that is easy to make
and can be used by anyone at home.
This simple natural fertilizer recipe
not only helps the orchid grow
healthily, but also stimulates strong
root development and encourages blooms
that exceed expectations.
If you haven't subscribed to the channel
yet, please hit the subscribe button to
support me and never miss any orchid
growing tips. It's wonderful to have you
along.
Leave a comment and let me know which
country you're watching from. It's
amazing that we can connect and chat
from all around the world.
Let's get started.
This is activated charcoal, a natural
material made from dry wood burned at
high temperatures. It's not only clean,
but also very beneficial for plants.
[Music]
You only need about 20 g of activated
charcoal, a small amount that brings
surprising benefits to your orchid.
Add about one liter of water, then blend
thoroughly so the nutrients can easily
dissolve into the water.
[Music]
Then filter out the residue to obtain a
clear solution that is easily absorbed
and safe for orchid roots.
[Music]
Um, add more water to make a total of 2
L of solution.
[Music]
Uh the first method, use a soft cloth to
gently soak the solution. Then slowly
wipe the surface of the leaves.
[Music]
This method not only helps keep the
leaves clean and beautiful, but also
naturally removes fungi and insects from
the leaf surface.
[Music]
At the same time, activated charcoal
provides a rich source of natural
calcium, helping the leaves become
stronger, shinier, and more resilient to
environmental changes.
[Music]
Um, you can apply this method once or
twice a month to maintain the plant's
health and support steady orchid growth.
The second method, pour the filtered
solution into a spray bottle. A
convenient way to gently care for the
entire plant.
[Music]
Lightly spray the entire orchid from
roots to stems and leaves to provide
nutrients and protect the plant
comprehensively.
The activated charcoal mixture offers
many wonderful benefits for orchids.
First, it helps clean the leaves and
naturally remove fungi and insects.
In addition, activated charcoal contains
a good amount of calcium, an essential
nutrient that helps leaves become
stronger, shinier, and more resistant to
stress.
Especially when used regularly, this
mixture also helps stimulate strong root
growth and supports more vibrant
blooming.
The third method, use this mixture to
water each orchid pot directly, helping
the roots absorb nutrients quickly and
nourish the plant from within.
Watering orchids with this mixture
offers many significant benefits. It
helps cleanse the area around the roots
and prevents harmful fungi and bacteria.
[Music]
At the same time, the mixture provides
natural minerals, especially calcium,
which supports sustainable plant growth.
[Music]
The roots will grow stronger, extend
deeper, and spread wider, thereby
helping the plant absorb nutrients more
effectively.
When the root system is healthy, the
plant will have enough energy to produce
lush green leaves and vibrant blooms.
[Music]
You can apply this method once or twice
a month to give the plant time to absorb
and grow steadily.
[Music]
Depending on your conditions and
available time, you can choose one of
the three methods or flexibly combine
all three for the best results. caring
for the leaves and roots while
supporting the plant's overall health.
[Music]
And now let's take a look at the results
after 6 weeks of care using this natural
fertilizer.
[Music]
You can see that the orchid's roots have
grown densely, appearing healthy and
white, firmly attached to the growing
medium, a clear sign of a strongly
recovering orchid.
[Music]
Even in orchid pots that have just
finished blooming, you will see new
roots starting to grow, a sign that the
plant is preparing to enter a new growth
cycle.
[Music]
Um, these new roots play an important
role in absorbing nutrients and keeping
the plant stable. As a result, the
orchid has enough energy to grow new
leaves and prepare for the next blooming
phase.
[Music]
Leave a comment and let me know which
country you're watching this video from.
It's wonderful that we can meet and
share our love for nature from all
around the world.
[Music]
When the flowers begin to bloom, you'll
notice each petal becoming softer,
opening wider, and displaying vibrant,
lively colors.
The flowers also last longer on the stem
before fading as the plant has absorbed
enough nutrients to keep them vibrant
and fresh for many weeks.
[Music]
Orchids in the bud development stage
also show positive signs. The buds are
large, plump, and don't drop early
because the plant has been wellnourished
from within.
You can see up to four new flower spikes
forming on the same orchid. A clear sign
that the plant is thriving and
responding very well to natural care.
[Music]
And the shiny, sturdier green leaves are
also a clear sign that the plant is
healthy, absorbing nutrients well, and
being properly cared for.
You can see that the same orchid has up
to 12 shiny, healthy green leaves and
hasn't lost its older leaves. This
proves the plant is in a stable growth
state and is being very well cared for.
How do you feel about my method of
caring for orchids with this natural
fertilizer? Don't hesitate to leave a
comment and share your thoughts. I'm
eager to hear your valuable feedback and
experiences.
If you encounter any difficulties in
growing orchids, don't hesitate to
comment for me. I'm always ready to
support you so you can grow healthy
orchids that bloom beautifully.
Uh, I hope you enjoy this video. If you
find it helpful, don't forget to like
and subscribe so you won't miss upcoming
tips on how to care for orchids
naturally and simply.
Thank you so much for taking the time to
watch the video. Wishing you lots of
joy, good health, and orchids that bloom
beautifully all year round.
Welcome to part three of the video.
In part three, I share a new way to help
spread more roots, branches, and flower
buds.
[Music]
Join me in discovering this wonderful
way to make organic fertilizer.
[Music]
Uh to make this type of fertilizer, you
need one branch of ginger.
[Music]
Where are you watching the video from?
Please leave a comment and let me know.
[Applause]
[Music]
It's amazing that we can chat together
from all around the world.
[Music]
After slicing, put into a glass jar.
Then add one spoon of yeast.
[Music]
This is the yeast used to make bread.
And add one teaspoon of honey.
[Music]
and one liter of warm water.
Incubate in a dark place for one week.
[Music]
One week later.
Take three tablespoons of fermented
ginger solution.
[Music]
Add one liter of water.
First method,
use cotton balls dipped in organic
fertilizer solution from fermented
ginger.
[Music]
Uh then place it in the places where you
want to take root and sprout.
[Music]
After 6 hours, take the cotton out.
Do it once a week.
[Music]
method two.
If you want this branch to continue
blooming,
[Music]
then add cotton and clip it.
After six hours, take the cotton out.
[Music]
Do it once a week.
Method three.
Um, if you want this button to continue
growing flower buds,
[Music]
um, if you want this button to continue
growing flower buds,
[Music]
This helps the buds grow faster.
Apply toothpaste to the cut.
[Music]
This helps the cut heal quickly.
Then stuff cotton into the button with
this sleeping bud.
After 6 hours, take the cotton out.
[Music]
Method four.
use a fertilizer solution from fermented
ginger after the leaves.
[Music]
helps kelps kill fungi and insects very
well.
[Music]
Cleaning the stamata helps orchids
photosynthesize well.
[Music]
Method five,
apply this liquid fertilizer to the base
of the orchid.
[Music]
This type of fertilizer helps stimulate
the growth of roots, branches, and buds
very well.
[Music]
Method six,
spray the fertilizer solution from
fermented ginger on the entire orchid.
[Music]
supports nutritional supplementation
through leaves. Very well.
Let's check the results together.
[Music]
After 2 months, the sprouts and roots
developed very well.
[Music]
The flower buds have also developed and
are ready to bloom.
[Music]
The buds at the tips of the branches
continue to grow and bloom.
[Music]
Sprouts also grow in leaf axles.
Many branches grow on the same tree.
[Music]
The flowers bloom on the branches for up
to 6 months before falling.
That's all I want to share with you in
this video. Thank you for watching the
video. Wishing you luck and happiness in
life.
[Music]