Welcome to my channel. Uh, in this
video, I'm sharing how to revive a
weakened orchid so it can grow normally
and bloom beautifully. If you haven't
subscribed yet, make sure to hit that
subscribe button so you don't miss any
orchid care tips on my channel.
[Music]
Let's get started.
This is an orchid that has rotted. It
was discarded, but I brought it home to
revive it.
After the orchid blooms, the plant often
becomes a bit weak because it has used a
lot of energy to flower.
Um, if not properly cared for, the
orchid may struggle to recover and it
will be difficult for it to bloom again
next time.
[Music]
You need to remove all the damaged
leaves, roots, and old stems.
[Music]
Removing the infected parts helps
prevent the growth of bacteria and mold.
[Music]
Uh the plant doesn't have to nourish the
weak parts, allowing it to focus on the
healthy sections.
Removing the old parts helps the plant
grow new, stronger shoots and roots.
[Music]
Now I'm cutting through the orchid stem
to check if there's any rot inside.
[Music]
Luckily the inside of the orchid stem
hasn't rotted yet.
[Music]
Cut off all the damaged leaves to
prevent the rot from spreading to other
areas.
[Music]
Then wash it thoroughly with water.
For the orchid stem, we need to make a
clean cut to avoid crushing it, which
will reduce the risk of rot from the
cut.
These rotting leaves should be removed
and kept far from the garden to prevent
spreading the rot to other orchids.
[Music]
Do you have cinnamon powder?
Take one spoonful of cinnamon powder and
put it into a jar.
Then add it to one liter of boiling
water.
[Music]
Stir well to prevent the cinnamon powder
from clumping.
[Music]
Then let it steep and wait for the water
to cool down.
[Music]
Once the water cools down, stir well to
ensure the nutrients are fully dissolved
in the water.
[Music]
That's my helper. Do you have any pets?
Now, strain out the residue.
Cinnamon has natural antibacterial and
antifungal properties, helping to
eliminate bacteria and fungi that cause
rot, especially root and stem rot.
Step one, use a soft cotton ball to soak
up the water and gently wipe the top and
bottom of the leaves.
Wiping the leaves clean helps remove
fungi, bacteria, or mold that may
develop on the surface, reducing the
risk of the plant getting infected.
When the leaves are cleaned, light can
easily reach the surface, helping the
plant photosynthesize more effectively,
especially during the recovery process.
Then place it here
and soak the leaf stem in the cinnamon
water for 10 minutes.
Cinnamon water has antibacterial and
antifungal properties, helping to
prevent infection at the cut. Cinnamon
helps stimulate the growth of new roots,
supporting the orchid's quick recovery.
[Music]
Then water the orchid pot with the
cinnamon water.
It helps prevent diseases caused by
bacteria and fungi in the roots.
It helps the orchid roots grow strong
and healthy.
[Music]
It enhances the plant's ability to
resist harmful factors.
After watering, soak the orchid roots in
this water for about 10 minutes for the
best effect on the roots.
[Music]
Then remove the roots and dry off the
cinnamon water.
[Music]
and take the orchid pot out.
Next, take one aloe vera leaf.
Aloe vera contains oxin, a natural plant
hormone that helps stimulate root
development from the leaf stem.
It helps protect the leaf stem from
bacteria and fungi, preventing infection
and supporting the rooting process.
Then take aloe vera gel and apply it to
the leaf stem.
[Music]
Then apply the aloe vera gel to the cut
on the orchid stem and roots to
stimulate root growth and protect
Protect against rot from the cut.
[Music]
Aloe vera gel contains natural hormones
that stimulate the growth of new roots
and shoots.
[Music]
I use moss to plant orchids as it helps
retain moisture. well and stimulates
fast root growth.
[Music]
Soak the moss in cinnamon water for
about 5 minutes to eliminate bacteria
and fungi that may be present in the
moss.
[Music]
Then take the moss out and ring out any
excess water.
[Music]
Place the moss in here as I
place the orchid leaf in here.
Then you should spray water to maintain
moisture once every 3 days.
Use plastic wrap to cover the mouth of
the bottle.
Create
ventilation holes at the top like this.
Then place it in a location with enough
light, but avoid direct sunlight on the
orchid.
Now I'm adding more moss to the surface
of this orchid pot to help retain
moisture better.
[Music]
This method also helps stimulate the
rapid growth of new roots.
Then spray water to maintain moisture
for the orchid pot whenever you notice
the growing medium is dry.
Then spray water to maintain moisture
for the orchid pot whenever you notice
the growing medium is dry.
The results after 50 days.
[Music]
Wow. As you can see, many new roots have
grown from the leaf stem
and and the new leaves have also grown
bigger than before the recovery.
[Music]
the new roots help the plant absorb
water and nutrients more effectively.
Healthy roots help the plant resist
diseases and adverse environmental
factors.
This in turn helps the plant grow
stronger and healthier.
[Music]
You can see that the base of the orchid
has also revived very well.
[Music]
The orchid stem has grown a new very
healthy chute.
Many new roots are growing under the
layer of moss.
[Music]
These new roots help the plant grow
strong, recover quickly, and prepare to
bloom.
[Music]
Now I'm planting the orchid leaf in a
new pot so it can grow better in the
outside.
[Music]
Um I'm planting it with pine bark chips
uh which maintain uh moderate moisture
and provide good drainage for the roots
to grow.
[Music]
With this simple method, you can quickly
and effectively revive a weakened orchid
on your own.
I hope you enjoyed the video. Don't
forget to support the channel and leave
a comment.
now. You just need to care for it like
any other regular orchid plant.
Uh take care of your orchids with all
the love for plants and you'll get to
enjoy beautiful, vibrant blooms. Uh
thank you for watching. I wish you
success in caring for your orchids and
many wonderful moments with your plants.
Goodbye and see you again soon.
Welcome back to the Happiness Garden
channel.
[Music]
Orchids are special plants that require
proper care to grow and bloom
beautifully all year round.
[Music]
Today, I will guide you on how to make
natural fertilizer using simple and easy
to find ingredients that you most likely
already have at home.
Let's dive in and get started.
[Music]
The orchid has finished blooming. Proper
care is needed for it to bloom again.
Please cut off all the old flower stems
to help the orchid focus its energy on
recovery and growth.
[Music]
This will allow the plant to prepare
effectively for the next blooming season
and maintain long-term health.
[Music]
If you haven't subscribed to my channel
yet, please support me by clicking the
subscribe button. Don't forget to like,
comment, and share if you find this
video helpful.
[Music]
After that, inspect and remove any dead
roots to prevent disease and allow new
roots to grow.
[Music]
Healthy roots are usually white or light
green.
[Music]
Damaged roots are often brown, black, or
discolored.
[Music]
which country are you watching this
video from? Please comment and let and
let me know.
[Music]
It's amazing that we can chat with each
other from all the countries around the
world.
[Music]
It's amazing that we can chat with each
other from all the countries around the
world.
In addition to the English dub, we've
now created dubs in French, German,
Italian, Spanish, Portuguese, Japanese,
Hindi, and Indonesian to help you hear
and understand the content. Videos are
easier.
[Music]
It's amazing that we can chat with each
other from all the countries around the
world.
[Music]
Uh to make natural fertilizer, the first
ingredient I need is eggshells.
[Music]
Uh to make natural fertilizer, the first
ingredient I need is eggshells.
[Music]
The second ingredient I need is about 5
g of ginger.
[Music]
Ginger contains many nutrients and
natural compounds that can improve the
health of plants.
[Music]
And finally, I need oat flour, which is
very rich in nutrients to make natural
fertilizer for orchids.
[Music]
Add 3 tablespoons of oatmeal.
Add one liter of boiled water, about
four cups.
[Music]
Add one liter of boiled water, about
four cups.
[Music]
2 hours later.
Stir to dissolve the nutrients into the
water.
[Music]
Filter out the residue.
If you haven't subscribed to the channel
yet, please click the subscribe button
to support me and not miss any orchid
growing tips. It's great to have
company.
[Music]
Add another one liter of water.
Step one,
water this mixture on the orchid two to
three times a month.
Eggshells supply calcium, which helps
the plant grow strong. Ginger has
antibacterial properties that prevent
diseases. Oatmeal provides essential
nutrients.
[Music]
This mixture provides essential
nutrients to help the plant recover
quickly, grow, and prepare for the next
blooming season.
[Music]
Step two,
use a soft cotton ball to soak up the
mixture and gently clean the top and
bottom surfaces of the orchid leaves.
[Music]
Use a soft cotton ball to soak up the
mixture and gently clean the top and
bottom surfaces of the orchid leaves.
[Music]
The mixture of eggshells, ginger, and
oatmeal will be absorbed through the
leaves, supplying essential nutrients to
the plant.
[Music]
This method helps remove dust and
impurities from the leaves, allowing
them to absorb light more effectively.
[Music]
Helps
the leaves maintain moisture and proper
nutrient exchange.
[Music]
Step three.
Next, we pour the solution into a spray
bottle and spray it onto each orchid
pot.
[Music]
Shake the spray bottle before use to
ensure the solution is well mixed.
[Music]
Lightly spray the solution on both the
top and bottom of the leaves, avoiding
the flowers to prevent any damage.
[Music]
You can also spray around the roots if
they are accessible.
[Music]
Spray the fertilizer solution once a
week or as needed.
Uh, be careful not to spray too much to
avoid overwatering the plant.
Step four,
gently use a cloth to absorb excess
water from the surface of the leaves,
both the top and bottom.
Make sure to thoroughly remove any
remaining water on the leaves to prevent
the plant from becoming overwatered and
to ensure it absorbs nutrients more
effectively.
[Music]
Afterward, place the orchid pot in a
spot with gentle sunlight to help it
photosynthesize properly.
[Music]
However, avoid direct sunlight,
especially during the intense midday
sun, as it can cause leaf burn, heat
shock, and stress for the plant.
[Music]
results after 45 days.
As you can see, the roots have developed
rapidly and are very healthy.
[Music]
As you can see, on the same plant, four
new flower stems can grow at the same
time.
[Music]
The leaves have also become vibrant,
smooth and very healthy.
[Music]
Strong new roots promote faster plant
growth, creating a solid foundation for
blooming and further development.
[Music]
New roots help the orchid adapt better
to changing environmental conditions
such as light and humidity and enhance
its ability to recover from from harsh
conditions.
[Music]
Uh other orchid plants cared for using
this method will also thrive and produce
many flower stems on the same orchid
plant.
[Music]
produces many new roots and the leaves
stay green, shiny, and firm.
[Music]
Continue taking care of your orchids
with all the love and dedication you
give to nature.
[Music]
When you invest your time and effort,
the beautiful flowers you receive will
be
a wonderful reward, proof of the
patience and care you've given to each
leaf and root.
[Music]
Keep nurturing them with love, and you
will feel joy and satisfaction every
time you admire the orchids blooming,
bringing beauty and pride created by
your own hands.
[Music]
I hope this video is helpful. Don't
forget to like, comment, share, and
subscribe to watch more videos.
[Music]
Uh, thank you for watching and
supporting the channel. Wishing you
success with your orchids.
[Music]
See you next time.