Hello
friends, I am an expert in organic
fertilizers and orchid care
techniques. In this video, I show you
how to rejuvenate an old orchid and the
secret to reviving the orchid to take
root and produce young
leaves. Uh if you haven't subscribed to
the channel yet, please click the
subscribe button to support me and not
miss any orchid growing tips. It's great
to have company.
[Music]
Now remove all damaged leaves to help
the orchid concentrate nutrients on
healthy parts, stimulating the growth of
new roots and leaves.
[Music]
Then cut off damaged roots to create
conditions for healthy roots to grow
better.
[Music]
Rinse with
water. Uh, this helps eliminate fungal
and bacterial diseases that cause root
rot.
Use one clove of
garlic. Garlic has antiseptic properties
that help prevent rot and stimulate root
growth and development for
[Music]
orchids. Use one sprig of fresh
ginger. Add 300 mls of filtered water,
about 1 cup.
[Music]
Garlic and ginger have a very good
effect on stimulating germination and
root
growth. Puree the garlic and ginger to
extract their beneficial compounds for
the orchids.
[Music]
Filter out the residue to obtain a clear
solution for easy absorption by the
orchid roots.
[Music]
Soak orchid branches in garlic and
ginger juice for 20 minutes to
disinfect, stimulate root growth, and
enhance resistance to
[Music]
diseases. After soaking for 20 minutes,
take out the orchid stem and let it dry
naturally before planting.
[Music]
Wipe the orchid stem gently and wait for
the cut to dry completely before
planting to prevent infection.
[Music]
Then drop melted wax onto the cut to
help it heal quickly and prevent
infection.
[Music]
Recycle plastic boxes into mini green
houses to help weak orchids grow faster
by maintaining humidity and warmth.
[Music]
Place the orchid branches inside the
miniature greenhouse to create a warm,
humid environment that promotes faster
root growth and
recovery. Add water to the miniature
greenhouse, ensuring that it creates
humidity but does not touch the orchid
branches. This helps maintain moisture
while preventing rot.
Place the orchid in a cool area with a
temperature between 20 to 30° C,
ensuring it gets light but avoiding
direct sunlight. This creates the ideal
environment for healthy
growth. Now I will rejuvenate this old
orchid to help it grow strong and bloom
beautifully again.
[Music]
Water once every 2 weeks and keep it in
a cool place as mentioned earlier to
support healthy growth.
[Music]
results. After 5
weeks, the old orchid stem has been
rejuvenated, grown new healthy roots,
and grown two healthy baby orchids.
[Music]
The orchid branch has grown many roots
and is very healthy.
[Music]
and developed one more young leaf.
Now I plant in pots to grow orchids in
the outside
[Music]
environment. After planting, you take
care of them like any other normal
plant.
[Music]
If you find the video meaningful, please
subscribe to help the channel reach 10
million subscribers soon.
[Music]
And don't rush to leave the video
because in part two I share how to grow
orchids. Hello
everyone. Welcome to my channel. In
today's video, I will continue to share
how to make organic fertilizer that
helps weak orchids with yellowing leaves
recover and leaves and bloom abundantly
and
[Music]
sustainably. Let's get started.
When growing orchids, it is impossible
to avoid the phenomenon of yellowing
leaves and leaf rot, which weakens the
[Music]
orchid. If you have an orchid with
yellow or rotten leaves, like this
orchid, this is the video to help you
take better care of it in the future.
[Music]
First, remove all damaged leaves on the
orchid to prevent the rot from spreading
[Music]
further. Then remove the damaged roots
on the orchid.
[Music]
Damaged roots can lead to diseases.
Removing them helps prevent the spread
of bacteria and
fungi. By removing damaged roots, the
plant can focus on developing new
healthy roots, improving its ability to
absorb water and nutrients.
[Music]
Then spread a little moss on top of the
orchid pot to help uh retain moisture
better and stimulates new roots
[Music]
There. Moss adds a natural beauty and
decorates the orchid pot, making the
planting area more vibrant.
[Music]
Which country are you watching the video
from? Please comment
below. Um, it's great that we can chat
together from all over the world.
[Music]
Um, if you haven't subscribed yet,
please subscribe to support my channel.
Thank you very
[Music]
much. Then I use bananas as fertilizer
to care for this orchid.
Take one banana and cut it into thin
slices. Bananas are rich in essential
nutrients like potassium, phosphorus,
and magnesium, which are crucial for
orchid growth, especially during
flowering.
[Music]
Put the bananas in the jar.
Do you have aloe
[Music]
vera? Take one aloe vera leaf and cut it
into thin slices.
[Music]
Aloe vera contains many vitamins and
minerals providing us essential
nutrients for orchid
growth. Put aloe vera in the jar.
Aloe vera gel improves the plant's
ability to absorb water and nutrients,
keeping the soil moist without water
logging.
[Music]
Then add 600 ml of warm water.
Um, if you haven't subscribed yet,
please subscribe to support my channel.
Thank you very
much. Now I add beer for fermentation.
[Music]
Beer contains various B vitamins and
minerals providing essential nutrients
for orchid
growth. The sugars and yeast in beer
help stimulate the growth of the root
system, allowing orchids to develop
stronger.
Add 100 mm of
[Music]
beer. Beer can enhance the plant's
ability to absorb water and nutrients,
making the orchids healthier.
[Music]
Then cover and leave in a cool place for
3 weeks to create synthetic GE from
banana and aloe
[Music]
vera. And this is the GE banana and aloe
vera product I fermented three weeks
ago. Take 50 mls of this synthetic GE.
[Music]
Add 2 L of water.
Stir well so that the nutrients dissolve
evenly in the water.
[Music]
Step
one, water and soak the orchid pot in
this liquid fertilizer.
[Music]
The combination of bananas, aloe vera,
and beer creates a natural liquid
fertilizer with many positive effects
for
[Music]
orchids. The fermented extract from
bananas and aloe vera contains a variety
of vitamins, minerals, and
enzymes providing essential nutrients
for the holistic development of the
plants.
[Music]
The enzymes in aloe vera and compounds
in bananas stimulate root growth,
enabling orchids to absorb water and
nutrients more effectively.
[Music]
Then soak the orchid pot in this
fertilizer solution for about 20 minutes
to help the roots absorb nutrients and
water best.
[Music]
Step
two, use a soft cotton to absorb this
liquid fertilizer and gently wipe the
top and bottom of the
[Music]
leaves. Wiping the leaves provides
additional vitamins and minerals from
the extract, supporting the plant's
growth.
This method of cleaning leaves will
remove dust and debris, allowing better
air circulation and enhancing the
plant's ability to
[Music]
photosynthesize. The antibacterial and
antifungal properties of the extract
help protect the leaves from harmful
bacteria and fungi.
The antibacterial and antifungal
properties of the extract help protect
the leaves from harmful bacteria and
[Music]
fungi. Uh wiping the leaves with the
extract helps orchids enhance their
resilience against environmental factors
and diseases.
[Music]
Which country are you watching videos
from? Please comment
[Music]
below. Um, it's nice that we can chat
with each other from all over the world.
[Music]
Step
three, then you put this amount of
liquid fertilizer into a spray
bottle. Then you spray the entire
orchid.
[Music]
Spraying the liquid fertilizer helps
strengthen the plant's resistance
against diseases and unfavorable
environmental
factors. Using the liquid fertilizer
supports robust growth of the orchids
from roots to leaves and flowers.
[Music]
Uh after soaking for 20 minutes, take
the orchid pot out and place it in a
place with lots of sunlight so the
orchid can photosynthesize.
[Music]
Well, results after 3 weeks.
The orchid has grown many new
[Music]
roots. New roots play a very important
role in the growth and development of
orchids. New roots help the plant absorb
water and essential nutrients from the
environment supporting its growth and
development.
Healthy roots enhance the orchid's
resistance to diseases and unfavorable
environmental
[Music]
conditions. New roots help the plant
establish a strong connection with its
habitat. thereby providing more
[Music]
stability. Uh roots can also store
nutrients helping the plant maintain its
life and growth during difficult
[Music]
times. The development of new roots
stimulates the growth of other parts
such as stems, leaves, and flowers.
Um, new roots are a decisive factor in
the healthy growth and development of
orchids, directly affecting the plant's
ability to absorb nutrients and its
resilience.
[Music]
And this is the result after the next 45
days.
As you can see, the orchid has come back
to life and is growing three new flower
spikes. With these three new flower
spikes, the orchid promises to bring an
even more vibrant and colorful blooming
season ahead.
The leaves have become lush, glossy, and
stronger than ever.
even the old wilted leaves have
completely recovered and now look
vibrant green and
healthy. The strong, thriving root
system reaches deep into the soil to
absorb water and nutrients, nurturing
the plant to produce the largest, most
beautiful and vibrant blooms.
Uh, this is an orchid that was once
weak, but thanks to this method, I've
been able to restore it completely. And
as you can see, it is now thriving and
healthy.
[Music]
In addition to its strong, thriving root
system, this orchid has produced three
new flower spikes, promising an upcoming
blooming season that will be vibrant and
full of color.
[Music]
Finally, give your love and care to your
plant companions.
[Music]
Nurture your orchids with all your heart
and you will be rewarded with their
amazing
[Music]
beauty. Hope you like the video. Please
comment to let me know how you liked
[Music]
it. Goodbye and see you again in the
next videos.
Um wishing you luck and success in your
plant care journey.