Welcome to the happiness garden, where
we gently and lovingly care for each
little green sprout.
In today's video, I want to tell you
about a very simple natural formula that
brings surprising results. Uh, a bud
stimulating solution for orchids and
roses made from eggshells and honey.
Uh when these two familiar ingredients
are combined, they create a pure source
of nutrients that helps the plant
recover quickly, nourish the buds, and
prepare for a more vibrant blooming
season.
Eggshells contain a large amount of
calcium, an essential nutrient that
helps the roots stay strong and supports
the plant in forming buds more
vigorously. Meanwhile, honey contains
natural enzymes that stimulate growth,
helping the plant sprout quickly and
develop with full vitality.
First, prepare a clean bottle and pour
one liter of water into it.
Next, add 1 teasp of honey into the
bottle.
This small amount of honey plays a very
important role as it provides natural
enzymes that help stimulate the
development of roots and buds right from
the very first steps.
[Music]
Next, take three clean eggshells and
crush them finely. When the eggshells
are broken down this small, the calcium
dissolves more easily in the water,
allowing the plant to absorb it more
quickly and effectively throughout the
bud nurturing process.
Let me know in the comments which
country you're watching from. It's
amazing that we can connect and chat
with each other from all over the world.
[Music]
After preparing everything, add the
crushed eggshells into the bottle. Then
stir well so the nutrients can begin to
blend together.
[Music]
Finally, simply close the lid and let
the mixture rest overnight.
This time allows the eggshells and honey
to release their nutrients completely,
uh, creating a powerful natural bud
stimulating solution for your plants.
[Music]
Um, after the mixture has been left to
sit overnight, you just need to stir it
once more so the nutrients can fully
blend together.
[Music]
Next, strain out the residue to obtain a
clean, clear solution. Removing the
residue helps the solution absorb
quickly into the roots and leaves and
also prevents clogging the surface of
the growing medium when watering.
[Music]
[Applause]
For orchids, you just need to apply this
fertilizer solution directly to the
roots and growing medium or alternate it
with other natural fertilizers. By using
it regularly two to three times a month,
the plant will gradually absorb the
nutrients, recover strongly, and prepare
for healthier new buds.
[Music]
The mixture made from eggshells and
honey provides a natural source of
calcium that helps the orchids orchids
roots grow stronger. When the roots are
healthy, the plant has enough energy to
nourish its buds, which in turn
stimulates the formation and development
of new flower spikes more quickly.
[Music]
The natural enzymes in honey act as
growth catalysts, helping the plant
enhance its metabolism and restore
vitality. Thanks to this, orchids can
produce buds more easily, especially
during the period when they are
preparing for a new blooming season.
[Music]
The solution after being left to sit
overnight also helps balance the
nutrients in the growing medium,
allowing the plant to absorb them more
effectively. When the living environment
is stable and rich in minerals, orchids
will develop strong, plump, and evenly
formed buds, promising vibrant clusters
of blooms in a short time.
[Music]
[Applause]
Next, for roses, you can use this
mixture to water the plant every 3 days,
helping it steadily absorb the essential
nutrients needed for bud development.
[Music]
Uh on the alternating days, remember to
water the soil to keep it moist because
roses always need more water and more
nutrients compared to orchids. When they
receive enough of both, the plants grow
vigorously, their buds form strongly,
and the flowers become larger and more
defined.
Calcium from the eggshells helps the
stems and branches become stronger,
creating a solid foundation for the
plant to support healthy buds.
Meanwhile, honey provides growth enzymes
that help the plant speed up its
metabolism, thereby promoting the
formation of flower buds. When these two
factors combine, roses will soon enter
the pre-blooming stage with vibrant,
healthy buds.
[Music]
Step two, you can also pour the mixture
into a clean spray bottle to mist it
directly onto your orchids.
Then gently mist the solution over the
entire orchid on the leaf surfaces, the
aerial roots, the base, and the growing
medium. The fine mist will naturally
coat the plant, allowing the nutrients
to absorb evenly and helping the orchid
push out new buds more quickly and more
strongly.
[Music]
When you mist the solution over the
entire plant, the fine droplets cling
directly to the leaf surfaces and aerial
roots, allowing the plant to absorb
nutrients faster than with regular
watering. Thanks to this folure
absorption, your orchid receives an
instant boost of energy, creating ideal
conditions to activate bud formation.
[Music]
Misting evenly over the leaves also
helps remove dust and increases the
plant's ability to photosynthesize. When
the leaves breathe better and receive
enough light, the plant becomes
stronger, making it easier for it to
enter the stage of forming new buds.
Misting the fertilizer in a fine spray
also helps maintain light moisture
across the entire plant, creating an
ideal environment for orchids to
activate their natural growth hormones.
The combination of stable humidity and
the nutrients from the solution will
encourage the plant to produce buds
early, resulting in plump and healthy
flower spikes.
[Music]
After misting, remember to gently wipe
off any excess water on the orchid
leaves with a soft cloth. This helps
prevent water from sitting on the leaf
surface for too long, reduces the risk
of leaf rot, and keeps the plant well
ventilated.
When the leaves are clean and dry, the
nutrient absorption process also becomes
more effective, helping the plant
prepare for the budding stage in a
healthy way.
[Music]
After that, place the orchid pot in a
spot with gentle airy light. Soft
morning light or late afternoon light
will help the plant process nutrients
better and naturally activate the bud
forming process.
[Music]
After applying the fertilizer, you
should place the rose pot in a spot with
gentle morning sunlight and good air
flow so the plant can absorb the
nutrients optimally.
Roses love sunlight. So when they
receive gentle light for 4 to 6 hours a
day, the plant photosynthesizes more
strongly. Its stems become sturdier and
bud formation is stimulated more
quickly. At the same time, a
wellventilated environment helps reduce
fungal diseases and allows new buds to
develop strongly from within.
[Music]
and here are the results after 1 month
of care.
You can also notice that the orchid has
grown two new flower spikes looking very
healthy and full of vitality. These buds
are clear evidence of the effectiveness
of the natural bud stimulating solution,
helping the plant prepare for the
upcoming vibrant blooming season.
[Music]
Additionally, you can also see that the
plant's roots have grown strongly,
firmly anchoring into the medium and
extending outward into the surrounding
space. Healthy roots provide a solid
foundation for the plant to fully absorb
nutrients, thereby supporting better bud
and flower development.
[Music]
Um, this orchid, although its buds are
developing slightly slower than the
previous plant, still shows two new
flower spikes clearly emerging. This
demonstrates that despite the different
pace, the bud stimulating solution is
still effective, gradually helping the
plant form healthy and vibrant flower
buds.
[Music]
And here are the results for the rose
plant after a period of care. You can
see many buds have grown, looking
healthy and full of vitality, promising
vibrant clusters of flowers soon to
bloom. Uh the natural solution has truly
helped the plant recover and strongly
stimulate new bud development.
[Music]
The newly emerging buds show that the
rose is gradually entering the blooming
stage with stronger stems and lusher
green leaves. When the plant is
regularly supplied with nutrients and
water, the buds will grow bigger,
sturdier, and bloom evenly, bringing a
vibrant and colorful flowering season.
[Music]
As long as you diligently and patiently
follow each step as instructed, the
plant will gradually recover, grow
strongly, and form healthy flower buds.
Consistency and patience are the key to
keeping your garden always vibrant and
full of life.
[Music]
Let me know in the comments which
country you're watching from. It's
wonderful that we can connect and chat
with each other from all around the
world.
[Music]
I hope you enjoy this video. If you find
it helpful, don't forget to hit like and
sub subscribe so you won't miss future
tips on caring for orchids naturally and
easily.
[Music]
Thank you so much for watching. I truly
appreciate your time and support. Don't
forget to like, subscribe, and share if
you enjoyed this video. Wishing you a
wonderful day full of joy and blooming
orchids. See you in the next video.