Hello everyone. When your orchid has
just finished its blooming cycle or even
has never bloomed, don't worry. Each
orchid pot has its own growth rhythm.
And with a little patience along with
the right care steps, you can completely
help your orchid become healthy and
bloom brilliantly in the future.
First, you should cut off all the wilted
flower stems, leaves, and roots. This
not only helps eliminate potential
diseases, but also stimulates the orchid
to grow new healthy leaves, roots, and
flower buds.
Uh please comment and let me know which
country you are watching the video from.
It's wonderful that we can chat together
from all around the world.
And if you haven't subscribed to the
channel yet, please hit the subscribe
button to support me and not miss any
orchid care tips. It's wonderful to have
you along on this journey.
[Music]
Next, I use eggshells as a natural
fertilizer to stimulate the orchid to
bloom. Eggshells are rich in calcium and
minerals, helping the orchid not only
stay healthy, but also develop new
flower buds quickly and steadily.
Crush about five eggshells. Grinding
them very finely will help the minerals
dissolve easily into the water and soil,
providing nutrients effectively for the
orchid's roots and leaves.
[Music]
After crushing, put the eggshells into a
clean jar to prepare for soaking. This
step helps the eggshells blend with
other nutrients during the soaking
process, creating a nutrient-rich
natural fertilizer for the orchid.
[Music]
Then add about 50 ml of vinegar into the
jar. Vinegar helps the eggshells ferment
slightly and dissolve the organic
calcium, turning it into a fertilizer
that is easily absorbed by the orchid's
roots and leaves.
You can see immediately after pouring
the vinegar in, a lively reaction occurs
between the vinegar and the eggshells.
This process produces quickly soluble
organic calcium ready to provide
nutrients effectively to the orchid's
roots and leaves.
[Music]
Then let the mixture sit for 1 day. This
process allows the calcium and minerals
from the eggshells to fully dissolve,
creating a nutrient-rich solution ready
to nourish the orchid's roots, leaves,
and flower buds.
After one day, strain out the remaining
residue. This step makes the solution
clear and smooth, ready to be diluted
and used directly for your orchid pot.
[Music]
After straining, dilute the solution
with about 3 L of water. Diluting helps
the nutrients from the eggshells spread
evenly, is safe for the roots and
leaves, and also stimulates the new
flower buds to grow strongly.
[Music]
Step one, water this fertilizer mixture
directly onto the orchid's roots and
growing medium about once every 2 weeks.
Regular watering provides continuous
nutrients, helping the orchid stay
healthy, stimulating root growth and
preparing for new flower buds.
Eggshells contain a lot of calcium,
helping the orchid stay healthy and
increasing its resistance to pests and
diseases. Not only that, eggshells are
also rich in potassium, an important
nutrient that helps stimulate flower
development, bringing more vibrant and
consistent blooms.
[Music]
In addition, the nitrogen and phosphorus
in eggshells also help the leaves and
roots grow strongly. When the roots are
healthy and the leaves are green, the
orchid can absorb nutrients more
effectively, ready to nurture new flower
buds in a healthy and sustainable way.
[Music]
Step two, spray this solution directly
onto the orchid's leaves about once
every 2 weeks. Regular spraying helps
the leaves absorb more nutrients,
maintain a lush green color, and
increase the vitality of the entire
plant while also supporting more
efficient photosynthesis.
The vinegar in the solution helps remove
dirt, insects, and fungal diseases on
the orchid's leaves and flowers.
Meanwhile, the calcium from the
eggshells helps the leaves become
stronger, increases resistance to pests,
and maintains the plant's long-term
vitality.
[Music]
After watering, remember to place the
orchid pot in a spot with gentle
sunlight. Gentle light helps the orchid
photosynthesize effectively, increases
nutrient absorption, and stimulates bud
development, preparing for the vibrant
flowers about to bloom.
And here is the result after 2 months of
care and recovery. You can see the
orchid continues to produce many new
buds, promising vibrant flowers soon to
bloom.
What do you think about how I revived
this small orchid? Don't hesitate to
leave a comment and share your thoughts.
I'm very eager to hear your feedback and
experiences.
[Music]
You can see that each orchid has up to
six to seven flower stems at the same
time. This shows that with the right
care and patience, orchids can grow
strongly, bloom many flowers
simultaneously, and bring vibrant beauty
to the entire garden.
When the orchid receives sufficient
nutrients, the flowers bloom larger,
more uniform, and more vibrant than
ever. They not only display stunning
beauty, but also reflect the plant's
strong vitality thanks to your
meticulous and patient care.
[Music]
Don't rush to leave the screen. Part two
of the video will bring more amazing
tips to help your orchid grow healthy
and bloom more brilliantly than ever.
Next, I will share how to quickly revive
a rotting orchid, helping it recover
healthily and continue to bloom as
usual.
And if you haven't subscribed to the
channel yet, please hit the subscribe
button to support me and not miss any
orchid care tips. Um, it's wonderful to
have you along on this journey.
If you have an orchid that is rotting
and has lost all its leaves like this
one, don't rush to throw it away. With
proper care, the plant can still
recover, grow new roots, and continue to
bloom beautifully.
[Music]
This orchid is infected by bacteria
causing its stem and roots to gradually
rot.
[Music]
First, cut off and clean the rotting
parts on the orchid stem and roots. This
step helps remove harmful bacteria,
prevent the disease from spreading, and
prepare the plant to begin a healthy
recovery process.
Then completely cut off the damaged
roots. Removing the rotting roots not
only prevents bacteria from spreading
but also helps the plant focus on
nourishing the healthy roots, laying the
foundation for recovery and the
development of new flower buds.
[Music]
And here's hydrogen peroxide. We will
use it to disinfect the recently cut
stem and roots of the orchid, helping
eliminate any remaining bacteria and
creating conditions for the plant to
recover quickly.
[Music]
Apply pure hydrogen peroxide directly
onto the rotting areas and also on the
freshly cut wounds. This helps disinfect
effectively, eliminate any remaining
bacteria, and prevent the disease from
spreading, creating conditions for the
plant to recover healthily.
[Music]
Then leave the plant undisturbed for one
day without watering to allow the cuts
to heal completely.
[Music]
Next, prepare 3 L of water in a clean
container to mix the growing medium
treatment solution.
[Music]
Then add one spoon of baking soda and
stir well until completely dissolved.
Baking soda helps balance the pH in the
growing medium while also preventing
bacteria and fungal growth, creating an
ideal environment for the orchid's roots
to recover.
[Music]
Soak the entire orchid in this solution
for about 10 to 20 minutes. This process
helps remove any remaining pathogens and
balances the pH in the growing
environment, creating ideal conditions
for the orchid's roots to regrow.
[Music]
Then gently take the orchid out and
place it on a plate.
[Music]
Next, pour water into the plate so the
growing medium can absorb it naturally,
helping maintain the proper moisture and
creating an ideal environment for the
orchid's roots to recover and grow
strongly.
[Music]
Place the orchid pot in a spot with
gentle sunlight, good ventilation, and
not too much wind. This location helps
the plant photosynthesize adequately,
maintain moisture, and reduce stress,
allowing the roots and new flower buds
to grow healthier.
And regularly mist with water whenever
the surface of the growing medium is
dry. This helps maintain stable
moisture, supports even root growth, and
provides the best conditions for the
plant to recover quickly.
[Music]
Next, we prepare fertilizer for the
orchid. Take two teaspoons of rice into
a cup to mix.
[Music]
Then add about one liter of water into
the cup. Rice water helps dissolve the
nutrients from the rice, creating a
solution rich in vitamins and minerals,
naturally nourishing the orchid's roots,
leaves, and flower buds.
[Music]
After mixing, pour the rice water over
the roots and growing medium and soak
for about 20 minutes. This process helps
the nutrients penetrate deeply into the
roots and growing medium, nourishing the
orchid and stimulating the growth of new
leaves and roots.
[Music]
Do this about once every 1 to 2 weeks.
Regular repetition provides continuous
nutrients, helping the orchid recover
more quickly.
After soaking for about 20 minutes,
gently take the orchid out and place it
in a spot with gentle sunlight. Gentle
light helps the roots and leaves
photosynthesize effectively while also
supporting nutrient absorption from the
solution, creating conditions for
healthy bud development.
[Music]
The result after one month of recovery
is truly amazing. You can see that from
an almost dead rotting orchid, it has
now recovered and grown a healthy new
plant from the side of the stem.
[Music]
It's wonderful to see an orchid recover
so strongly. This moment not only brings
joy but also inspires, reminding us that
with patience and proper care, any
orchid can be revived.
[Music]
Keep watering the orchid with rice water
every 1 to two weeks. Maintaining this
regularly provides continuous nutrients,
helping the roots, leaves, and buds grow
strongly, resulting in fresh and healthy
flowers.
[Music]
After watering, let the plant soak for
about 20 minutes. This process helps the
nutrients from the solution penetrate
deeply into the roots and growing
medium, nourishing the orchid and
stimulating even bud development.
[Music]
And here is the result after the next
month. You can see the orchid has grown
bigger with roots, leaves, and buds
developing noticeably, promising vibrant
flowers in the near future.
[Music]
It's wonderful to see the orchid growing
day by day. Every green leaf, every
healthy root, and every new bud is the
result of meticulous and patient care,
bringing joy and inspiration to the
grower.
[Music]
Uh please comment and let me know which
country you are watching the video from.
It's wonderful that we can chat together
from all around the world.
[Music]
And if you haven't subscribed to the
channel yet, please click the subscribe
button to support me and not miss any
orchid care tips. It's wonderful to have
you as a companion.
I continue to care for the orchid with
natural fertilizer, watering it twice a
month. Watch until the end of the video
to admire the amazing results this care
method brings to your orchid.
And here is the result after the next 5
months. You can see the orchid has fully
recovered, grown strong, and blooms
brilliantly, demonstrating its vigorous
vitality when properly cared for.
Keep caring for your orchid with all
patience and love. Every leaf and every
bud you nurture is a testament to your
effort. And seeing the orchid bloom
brilliantly will inspire you to continue
cultivating and cherishing each of your
orchid pots.
I hope you enjoyed this video. If you
find it helpful, don't forget to like
and subscribe to the channel so you
won't miss any future tips on caring for
orchids naturally and simply.
Thank you for watching until the end of
the video. Apply these natural orchid
care tips and patiently tend to each of
your orchid pots. You will surely see
them recover strongly, bloom
brilliantly, and bring complete joy.
[Music]