Welcome to my
channel. When you grow orchids, it is
unavoidable that the leaves may
rot. If your orchid's leaves are rotting
like this, don't worry because in this
video, I'm sharing a new method to help
you quickly treat leaf rot in
time. First, you need to cut off the
rotting part of the leaf from the
orchid. This helps prevent the rot from
spreading to the stem and other healthy
leaves. Then we check the roots and
remove any rotten ones from the orchid.
This helps prevent the rot from
spreading throughout the entire plant
from the roots to the stem and
leaves. Please comment to me which
country you're watching the video from.
It's great that we can chat together
from all over the
[Music]
world. If you haven't subscribed to the
channel yet, please hit the subscribe
button to support me and not miss any
orchid care tips. It's wonderful to have
you along.
[Music]
If you encounter any difficulties while
growing orchids, don't hesitate to
comment to me. I'm always ready to help
you so you can grow healthy orchids that
bloom beautifully.
[Music]
In addition to the English voiceover, we
have now created voiceovers in French,
German, Italian, Spanish, Portuguese,
Japanese, Hindi, and Indonesian to help
you listen and understand the content
more
easily. Please go to the settings in the
video to choose the audio version in the
language that suits you.
Uh, it's best to check the orchid once a
week to remove yellow or rotting
leaves. For orchids with rotting leaves
caused by bacteria, we need to isolate
them from the garden to treat the rot.
This helps prevent the rot from
spreading to other
plants. Now I am using turmeric powder
because it has excellent natural
antibacterial and anti-inflammatory
properties which are great for treating
orchid leaf rot.
[Music]
Apply turmeric powder to the cut as it
helps the wound heal
quickly. This helps reduce the risk of
infection and aids the plant in
recovering quickly.
[Music]
Moreover, turmeric helps stimulate the
process of cell regeneration, allowing
the cut to heal quickly and the plant to
return to a healthy state.
Then place it in a well ventilated area
and avoid watering to help the cut heal
quickly. Then add one teaspoon of
turmeric powder into a bottle and mix it
with four cups of hot water, about one
liter.
Cover the bottle and wait for the water
to cool
down. This is oatmeal which can be used
as a very good natural fertilizer for
orchids.
Take 1 tbsp of oatmeal powder and mix it
with four cups of room temperature
water, about one
liter. Wait for about 2 hours to allow
the nutrients to fully dissolve into the
water.
[Music]
after the water cools down, strain the
residue to obtain the turmeric
water. You can use a sieve or a thin
cloth to filter, ensuring that only
clean liquid turmeric remains, which
will easily absorb into the plant's cut.
If you haven't subscribed to the channel
yet, please click the subscribe button
to support me and never miss any orchid
growing tips. It's wonderful to have you
as a companion.
[Music]
The first step is to soak a cotton ball
in the turmeric water mixture and gently
wipe both the top and bottom of the
orchid leaves.
Wiping the leaves with turmeric water
not only helps clean the leaves but also
provides nutrients that keep the leaves
healthy. Additionally, it has
anti-inflammatory and antibacterial
properties helping the leaves avoid
diseases.
You should wipe evenly and gently to
avoid damaging the
leaves. Turmeric contains curcumin which
helps reduce inflammation and prevent
the growth of harmful bacteria and fungi
on the leaves. This helps the plant
fight against diseases such as leaf rot
and
mold. Curcumin and turmeric also has
antioxidant properties, protecting the
leaves from the harmful effects of the
environment and strong sunlight, helping
the orchid leaves maintain their
freshness. To care for orchids
effectively, you can wipe the leaves
with turmeric water about one to two
times a
month. Step two, pour the turmeric water
into a spray bottle. Then spray it onto
the entire orchid plant.
Um, this helps the turmeric water cover
the leaves, roots, and stem evenly,
providing nutrients and protecting the
plant from harmful agents.
Regularly spraying turmeric water helps
the orchid maintain its health, reduce
inflammation, and prevent mold
growth. You should spray turmeric water
on the orchid about one to two times a
month. This is enough to provide the
plant with nutrients from turmeric while
also protecting the leaves from bacteria
and fungi without causing excess
moisture to linger too
long. Um, if the plant has health issues
or is infected, you can do it more
frequently, but for healthy plants, a
frequency of one two times a month is
ideal.
Now, mixing turmeric water with oatmeal
water is a great way to create a
natural, nutrient-rich mixture for
orchids. Oatmeal water is rich in
vitamins and minerals, providing
essential nutrients for the plant's
healthy growth. While turmeric water
adds antibacterial and anti-inflammatory
[Music]
properties, you need to strain the
oatmeal residue and use only the clear
liquid for application.
[Music]
And then use a watering can or a small
cup to pour the turmeric and oatmeal
water mixture onto the plant's roots.
[Music]
Um, you can water slowly and evenly,
ensuring the mixture soaks into the soil
or the plant's roots. Be sure to water
both the main roots and the secondary
roots
evenly. Um, you can water slowly and
evenly, ensuring the mixture soaks into
the soil or the plant's roots. Be sure
to water both the main roots and the
secondary roots evenly.
[Music]
Moss has excellent moisture retention,
so you only need to water with this
mixture once every 2
weeks. With moss as the growing medium,
you don't need to water too frequently
because it retains water longer, helping
to maintain a stable moisture level for
the plant's roots.
[Music]
However, if your orchid's growing medium
is bark chips, it drains water faster.
So, you will need to water with this
mixture once a week to ensure the plant
receives enough nutrients.
Bark chips don't retain moisture as well
as moss, so more frequent watering is
needed to ensure the plant doesn't lack
water and nutrients.
[Music]
Step four. After watering the plant with
the turmeric and oatmeal mixture, you
should wipe off any remaining mixture on
the leaves and leaf
axles. Uh this is an important step to
prevent the mixture from remaining on on
the plant which could create prolonged
moisture and provide favorable
conditions for mold or bacterial growth.
Um, you can use a soft cloth or cotton
ball to gently wipe away any excess,
ensuring that areas like the top and
bottom of the leaves and the leaf axles
are dry and not left wet for too
long. This helps the orchid maintain its
health, prevents mold, and keeps the
leaves clean.
After wiping off the excess mixture, you
should place the orchid pot in a spot
with gentle sunlight as light is a
crucial factor that helps the orchid
perform photosynthesis and grow
well. However, you should avoid direct
and intense sunlight as it can cause
leaf burn or stress the plant.
[Music]
Now, let's take a look at the results
after 2 months of caring for the orchid.
The with it with the natural fertilizer
mixture made from turmeric powder and
[Music]
oatmeal. You can see that my orchid pot
has grown three new flower spikes, all
thick and healthy. This shows that the
natural fertilizer made from turmeric
powder and oatmeal has truly had an
amazing
effect. Not only has it produced many
new flower spikes, but it's also
developed many new
roots. This proves that the plant is
very healthy and receiving enough
nutrients from the natural fertilizer.
[Music]
New roots help the orchid absorb water
and nutrients more efficiently, which in
turn helps the plant grow better and
maintain its
health. The strong growth of the flower
spikes is a sign that the plant is
receiving all the necessary nutrients
and the care environment is perfect for
its growth.
This orchid, although smaller, has grown
two flower spikes after 2 months of
careful care, which is a very positive
sign.
This proves that although the plant
doesn't grow as vigorously as the
others, with the right care and natural
fertilizer, it can still bloom and
recover its health.
Uh this is a clear example that patience
and careful care will help the plant
recover and produce beautiful
blooms. Here's another regular orchid.
And when cared for using this method,
you can clearly see the difference. The
leaves are vibrant, firm, and healthy.
The flower spikes are not only large but
also thick and full of vitality.
[Music]
This care method has helped the plant
grow vigorously and bloom brilliantly,
proving its exceptional effectiveness in
nurturing and caring for
orchids. With this simple method, you
can easily care for and revive orchids
right at home, helping them grow
healthily and bloom beautifully.
If you found the content helpful and
meaningful, don't forget to like, share
so more people can know and subscribe to
support me. Thank you for always being
with me.