Welcome to my little garden where orchid
branches begin a new journey.
Today I will show you how to propagate
orchids from cutings. Simple and
effective right at home.
This is my orchid. It it has finished
blooming and is ready for propagation.
When the petals fade, it's the perfect
time to start propagating orchids from
cutings.
Cut off any damaged leaves so the plant
can grow stronger.
Cutting off damaged leaves helps
eliminate fungi, prevents the spread of
disease, and keeps the plant healthy.
[Music]
Next, trim off any damaged roots to
ensure the plant grows well.
[Music]
Uh, trimming off damaged roots helps
prevent mold growth and creates
conditions for new healthy roots to
grow.
[Music]
Uh, identifying damaged roots is simple.
If the roots are soft, they are
completely damaged. If the roots are
still firm but have a dark brown color,
it is also a sign of damage.
Please comment and let me know which
country you're watching the video from.
It's amazing that we can chat together
from all over the world.
Um, if you haven't subscribed to the
channel yet, please hit the subscribe
button to support me and not miss any
orchid growing tips. It's wonderful to
have you as a companion.
Next, trim off the faded petals. This
helps the plant conserve energy and get
ready for the next blooming cycle or for
producing baby plants on the stem if
properly stimulated.
[Music]
The nodes that have already bloomed will
not bloom again. and cannot produce baby
plants for baby from there.
Young nodes like this should not be used
for propagation as the dormant buds are
prone to rotting and damage.
Old nodes like this should also not be
used for propagation as the dormant buds
are very hard to develop.
This node is neither too old nor too
young, making it the ideal choice for
propagation from cutings.
Um, peeling off the protective layer of
the dormant bud helps nutrients absorb
better when stimulated, allowing the
baby plant to sprout quickly.
In addition to the English voiceover, uh
we have now created voiceovers in
French, German, Italian, Spanish,
Portuguese, Japanese, Hindi, and
Indonesian to help you listen to and
understand the content more easily. To
listen to the language, open the video
and click settings gear icon to select
the appropriate audio language.
[Music]
For languages without voice over, we
have created subtitles to help you
easily read and understand the content.
Bananas when made into GE gel enzyme are
very effective in orchid propagation
from cutings helping to stimulate rapid
growth.
Bananas when made into GE gel enzyme are
very effective in orchid propagation
from cutings helping to stimulate rapid
growth.
Uh next take a pieces of gin to make GE
which helps enhance growth and fight
diseases during the propagation process.
Then place the sliced banana and ginger
into a glass or plastic jar to prepare
for making GE.
Make sure the jar is clean so that when
the GE fermentss, uh, the mixture
doesn't spoil and maintains its quality.
Next, add.5 L of water to make it easier
for the mixture to dissolve and ferment
effectively.
[Music]
Uh, leave some space in the jar so that
when it ferments, the GE will produce
gas and allow the fermentation process
to proceed smoothly.
Finally, add about 2 tesp of honey to
boost nutrients and stimulate the
fermentation process.
Stir the mixture well so that the
ingredients blend together and ferment
easily. Close
the lid and place it in a cool, airy
spot for 3 weeks. The mixture will
ferment and turn into a highly effective
GE for orchid propagation from cutings.
This is the GE product I made earlier.
Now all you need to do is take it out
and apply it for orchid propagation from
cutings.
Just take about 20 mil of this GE and
apply it to the orchid cutting.
Dilute the GE with one liter of water to
create an effective orchid propagation
solution.
Next, I add vitamin B1 to the mixture to
help stimulate root growth and enhance
the plant's health.
Add three vitamin B1 tablets to the
mixture to enrich it with nutrients,
helping the orchid grow stronger.
[Music]
Step one, use a soft cloth to soak up
the mixture. Then firmly attach it to
the node with the peeled dormant bud to
help the nutrients absorb effectively.
This helps stimulate the dormant bud to
sprout quickly and develop into a baby
orchid plant.
Step two, use a soft cloth to soak up
the mixture and gently wipe both the top
and bottom of the leaves to allow better
nutrient absorption.
[Music]
This mixture helps enhance nutrients and
stimulates strong root development.
Vitamin B1 and the components in the
mixture help the plant resist diseases
and stress.
[Music]
Wiping the leaves helps remove dirt,
creating a shiny surface that easily
absorbs light.
When the leaves are clean and healthy,
the plant will photosynthesize more
efficiently, helping the orchid grow
well.
Wiping the leaves with the mixture helps
the plant absorb nutrients through the
leaves more easily, especially when the
plant is young or weak after blooming.
[Music]
Then transfer the mixture into a spray
bottle for easy application on the
leaves and dormant buds.
Step three, spray this mixture on the
leaves, stem, and roots of the orchid to
provide the plant with complete
nutrients.
Spraying the mixture helps the orchid
recover after pruning or during the
propagation process, promoting quick
recovery and rapid growth.
Spraying helps maintain the ideal
humidity for the orchid, especially in
dry environments.
The mixture, when sprayed, helps
stimulate rapid root growth, especially
when the plant is in the propagation
stage.
Step four, spray the mixture onto this
cotton pad to boost nutrients and
support strong growth of the dormant
bud.
Wait about 20 minutes for the nutrients
to absorb into the dormant bud before
removing the cotton.
The leftover mixture in the bottle can
be used to spray on other orchids in the
garden. It will be very beneficial for
their growth.
For healthy orchids, apply once or twice
a month. For orchids being stimulated to
sprout keis, apply three to four times a
month for best results.
Step five, water the orchid pot with
this mixture to stimulate the growth of
keis on the spike.
Um, water each pot with about 10
tablespoons to provide enough nutrients
for the plant.
When watering with this mixture, it will
provide nutrients that help the dormant
buds on the flower spike grow quickly
and sprout into keakis.
Watering with this mixture helps the
orchid become healthier, increasing its
ability to endure and thrive during the
propagation process.
Apply this to the orchid three to four
times a month to effectively stimulate
the dormant buds to sprout into keis.
Step six, use a soft cloth to wipe off
any excess mixture on the leaves and
between the leaf crevices to prevent the
plant from staying too moist for too
long, which can lead to mold.
Step six, use a soft cloth to wipe off
any excess mixture on the leaves and
between the leaf crevices to prevent the
plant from staying too moist for too
long, which can lead to mold.
After about 20 minutes, remove the cloth
from the dormant bud to allow the
nutrients to have fully absorbed into
the plant.
Now let's take a look at the results
after 30 days of care.
You can see that the kei has sprouted
and is quite healthy. Uh proving that
this method is very effective.
Although small, the kei already has
roots showing strong development right
from the early stages.
The mother orchid has also grown many
new roots, proving that this care method
helps the plant grow healthy.
You can also see that the orchid's
leaves have become glossy green, showing
good health and growth after applying
this care method.
[Music]
Uh, I continue to care for the orchid
with the natural fertilizer mix from the
GE product to maintain strong and
sustainable growth.
Now, let's take a look at the results
after 45 days of care with the natural
GE fertilizer.
You can see that the kei on the stem has
grown bigger and healthier, proving that
the care method is very effective.
However, the orchid is still small and
not yet ready to be separated and
replanted into a new pot.
Uh, I continue to care for the orchid
with a natural fertilizer mixture from
GE products to maintain strong and
sustainable growth.
[Music]
Uh, I continue to care for the orchid
with a natural fertilizer mixture from
GE products to maintain strong and
sustainable growth.
You can see that the orchid plant
growing on the stem now has leaves and
roots that are developing very
healthily.
[Music]
Uh, the mother orchid has even grown a
new flower spike, showing that the care
method has really helped the plant grow
strong and healthy.
[Music]
This is the perfect time to cut the
orchid pups from the stem and transplant
them into a new pot, allowing the plants
to thrive even more.
[Music]
Before
planting, you should disinfect the cut
area or apply candle wax to the wound to
prevent rotting.
[Music]
I hope this video will be helpful to you
in caring for and propagating orchids at
home.
What do you think about my method of
propagating orchids from stems? Please
leave your feedback and suggestions in
the comments.
[Music]
If you encounter any difficulties during
the orchid growing process, don't
hesitate to comment and let me know. I'm
always here to support you so you can
grow healthy orchids and enjoy many
beautiful blooms.
[Music]
If you find the content helpful and
meaningful, don't forget to like, share
so more people can benefit and subscribe
to support my channel. Thank you for
always being with me.
[Music]
Thank you for watching the video. I
always pray that God blesses all of you.
Goodbye and see you in the next videos.
Hello friends.
[Music]
In my hand is a withered Dendrobium
orchid. And in this video I will share
how you can propagate any Dendrobium
orchid.
We cut off the spots that have bloomed.
[Music]
Only keep these three parts for
propagation because they still have
dormant buds at the nodes.
Drip melted wax onto the cut to protect
it from absorbing water, preventing the
cut from rotting.
Which country are you watching this
video from? Please leave a comment for
me.
It's amazing that we can chat with each
other from all around the world.
[Music]
Peel off the protective film of the
sleeping sprout.
[Music]
Use one sprig of chopped fresh ginger.
If you haven't subscribe to the channel
yet, click the subscribe button to
support me.
[Music]
500 ml of boiled water.
Wait one day.
[Music]
Soak orchids in ginger water for 30
minutes.
[Music]
Soak moss in ginger water for 30
minutes.
[Music]
I use recycled plastic boxes to make
miniature green houses to help propagate
orchids faster.
[Music]
There's a vent here.
Put the orchid in a miniature greenhouse
and spray it with moisture once a week.
Uh place in a bright place and avoid
direct sunlight.
21 days after
[Music]
Continue
misting to keep moisture and keep in a
light place. Avoid direct sunlight.
After
[Music]
10 next day,
Continue
[Music]
misting to keep moisture and keep in a
light place. Avoid direct sunlight.
after two next weeks.
[Music]
I hope this video will be very helpful
for you in taking care of orchids at
home.
[Music]
Plant in pots to let the orchid adapt
and grow in the Outside environment.
[Music]
If you find it interesting, please
subscribe to the channel, like, share to
let more people know.
[Music]
My videos have subtitles in different
languages. Please select the appropriate
language to understand the video content
clearly.
[Music]
Remember to plant the root higher than
the pot so that the orchid does not have
root rot.
That's all I want to share with you in
this video.
Now, goodbye and see you in the next
videos.