Hello everyone. Nice to see you
again. If you want more orchids, flowers
bloom for a long time on the branch
before the bright color of the flower
fades. If you haven't subscribed to the
channel yet, please hit the subscribe
button to support me and not miss any
orchid growing tips. It's great to have
you
along. Like my orchids, flowers can last
up to 6 months.
[Music]
Flowers bloom all year round, one flower
after another. There are always many
flowers growing on the same
[Music]
branch. If you want that, do the
following. One, place the orchid pot in
a place with mild sunlight.
[Music]
or on a window
sill. Avoid the sun and strong
[Music]
wind. Two, before fertilizing, water the
orchid. This will make it easier for the
roots to absorb nutrients from the
fertilizer.
[Music]
Uh after each watering, soak the orchid
roots in water for 20 minutes so that
the plant can absorb enough
[Music]
water. For leaves, you use a spray.
Spray to wet the leaves with water to
help open
[Music]
stamata. After soaking for 20 minutes,
the roots absorb enough water and will
turn green like this.
[Music]
Then I take it out and wait 30 minutes
before
[Music]
fertilizing. Three, use lemon as an
organic fertilizer for orchids.
[Music]
Use the remaining juice of half a
lemon. Mix lemon juice into 0.5 US
gallon, about 2 L of water.
[Music]
Please comment to me which country you
are you are watching the video from.
It's great that we can chat together
from all over the
[Music]
world. Pour the lemon juice mixture into
a spray bottle.
Then spray evenly on the top and bottom
of the
leaves. Lemon juice is packed with
nutrients like vitamin C, citric acid,
potassium, and magnesium.
[Music]
These substances are quickly absorbed
through the leaves of the orchid,
helping to provide the nutrients needed
to promote the health and growth of the
[Music]
plant. After spraying, use cotton to dry
the leaves.
[Music]
If you haven't subscribed to the channel
yet, please hit the subscribe button to
support me and not miss any orchid
growing tips. It's great to have you
[Music]
along. If you haven't subscribed to the
channel yet, please subscribe to support
me and not miss any orchid care tips.
[Music]
Pay attention to drying the upper leaf
crevices. Regular fertilization of
orchid leaves will keep them green like
this and the leaves will not be infected
with fungus.
[Music]
four. Add one teaspoon of honey to the
lemon juice solution earlier.
[Music]
water this solution for orchid roots one
to two times
[Music]
month. Honey has the ability to
stimulate growth and cell division in
[Music]
plants. Uh when using honey mixed with
lemon juice as a fertilizer, it it will
help the plant thrive, produce many new
shoots, and have beautiful petals.
[Music]
Honey has antibacterial and antifungal
properties, helping orchids better
resist
[Music]
diseases. When using honey mixed with
lemon juice as fertilizer, uh, it'll
help it also helps orchids have bright
colors, a sweet fragrance, and prolongs
the life of
[Music]
flowers. You can also soak in this water
for 20 minutes, letting the roots absorb
the most nutrients.
Care for your orchids with love and
patience, and they will reward you with
radiant beauty and miraculous
[Music]
vitality. These delicate petals not only
bring joy, but also brighten up the
living space, bring a sense of peace,
relaxation, and connect you closer to
nature right in your own
[Music]
home. Thanks for watching. Have fun, and
have a beautiful orchid garden.
Welcome to my channel
uh to help you have many choices when
caring for orchids at home with organic
fertilizer. In this video, I continue to
share new
[Music]
methods. Please subscribe to the video
so you don't miss any tips on my
channel.
Now, let's get
started. To make this organic
fertilizer, you need coffee or coffee
[Music]
grounds. I use three teaspoons.
Add one liter of boiled water.
[Music]
Incubate until cool.
after the water cools. filter to remove
[Music]
residue. Add water to make 5 L of coffee
solution.
[Music]
Next, add 1 teaspoon of baking soda.
first method.
[Music]
Water this fertilizer solution on the
orchid roots.
[Music]
Coffee contains many minerals and
organic matter helps provide orchid
nutrition.
[Music]
It contains nitrogen, potassium, and
phosphorus, important nutritional
elements for orchid growth.
[Music]
Uh, baking soda bicarbonate soda has the
ability to increase the pH level in
orchid pots. This is helpful in reducing
acidity if you use too much chemical
fertilizer.
[Music]
Baking soda has the ability to kill
insects and fungi that damage plants.
[Music]
Second
method. Spray this fertilizer on the
entire orchid.
[Music]
This method is similar to using folure
fertilizer.
[Music]
[Applause]
You can use it as a natural pesticide to
protect orchids from insects and
diseases.
[Music]
third
method. Clean the leaf surface with this
fertilizer solution.
[Music]
The leaf surface will always be clean
and an airy with stomata. Orchids will
photosynthesize better.
[Music]
Please see the
results. Please see the results.
[Music]
Uh because of enough nutrition, the
flowers bloom more brilliantly.
[Music]
Many flowers bloom on the same branch.
The flowers stay on the branches for a
long time before
[Music]
fading. Thank you for watching the
video. Wish you luck and success in
life. Thank you for watching the video.
Wish you luck and success in life.