hello
everyone to give you more options for
taking care of orchids at home with
natural fertilizers in this video I will
share how to use fertilizer to help
orchids recover after blooming and
provide nutrients to encourage more
flower spikes and continuous
blooming let's get
started this is a phenopsis orchid after
it has finished blooming I bought it
from an orchid nursery for $3
today I will guide you on how to repot
and care for this Orchid to help it
recover and Bloom
again after blooming orchids often
become exhausted because the nutrients
were focused on flowering leaving the
plant weak with poor resistance making
it susceptible to diseases like Leaf rot
and root rot
[Music]
after cutting off the old flower Spike I
proceed to remove the old plastic pot to
check the root
system this Orchid is beginning to show
signs of root rot and fungal
[Music]
growth orchids planted in Moss retain
moisture very well however if the
environment is too moist and not
properly controlled it can easily lead
to fungal infections and root
rot I will remove all the old moss and
replace it with fresh potting
[Music]
medium repotting and replacing the
growing medium not only provides the
plant with a fresh healthy environment
but also allows me to check and treat
the roots creating the best conditions
for the plants growth
uh Moss is an excellent moisture
retaining medium but over time it can
decompose become compacted and restrict
air flow to the roots potentially
harboring bacteria and
fungi removing the old Moss will help
improve the air flow to the roots
if there are any soft rotting damaged or
shriveled Roots I will cut them off
immediately this helps prevent the rot
from spreading to the healthy
Roots this is an important step for
quick recovery after repotting
uh by cutting off the damaged Roots the
plant will have space for new healthy
roots to grow helping it absorb water
and nutrients more
effectively damaged Roots can reduce the
air flow in the pot leading to water
logging removing them helps the root
system breathe more easily
cutting off the damaged Roots allows the
plant to focus on growing new healthy
Roots which helps the Orchid Thrive
better cutting off the damaged Roots
should be done gently and carefully to
avoid harming the remaining healthy
roots
after cutting off the damaged Roots it
is also important to remove wilted
damaged and rotting
leaves wilted damaged or rotting leaves
can be a breeding ground for bacteria
and fungi removing them helps reduce the
risk of disease spreading to other parts
of the
plant removing weak rotting or damaged
leaves allows the plant to focus its
energy and nutrients on healthier Parts
especially new leaves and growing
Roots removing unhealthy leaves also
helps the plant look tidier and more
[Music]
attractive when weak leaves are removed
the plant can receive better light and
air flow creating favorable conditions
for the growth of new healthy leaves
[Music]
after removing the damaged roots and
unhealthy leaves washing the Orchid
under running water is a very important
step water helps remove dirt debris and
any remaining impurities on the roots
and leaves after trimming keeping the
plant clean and
healthier if the plant has been exposed
to fertilizers or chemicals in its
previous environment washing it helps
remove these substances preventing harm
to the
plant washing the plant helps remove any
bacteria or fungi that may be present on
the surface reducing the risk of
infection
then I temporarily plant it in this
glass cup to allow the plant to dry
off next take two cloves of garlic and
slice them thinly you can use either
fresh or dried
garlic garlic has antibacterial and
antifungal properties helping the plant
stay healthier
please comment and let me know which
country you are watching the video from
it's wonderful that we can chat together
from all around the
world if you haven't subscribed to the
channel yet please hit the Subscribe
button to support me and never miss any
orchid care tips it's great to have you
as a companion
after slicing place the garlic into a
jar and pour in.3 Gall about 1.2 L of
room temperature
[Music]
water next I take five vitamin B1
tablets thiamine which are great for
orchid root recovery Y and growth it
helps stimulate the growth of new roots
and boosts the plant's
Health add the vitamin B1 to the mixture
and wait for 1 hour to allow the
nutrients from the garlic and vitamin B1
to fully dissolve in the water before
using
then we strain the garlic and vitamin B1
water mixture to use for orchid Recovery
Care
in addition to the English dub we've now
created dubs in French German Italian
Spanish Portuguese Japanese Hindi and
Indonesian to help you hear and
understand the content videos are now
easier
after preparing the garlic and vitamin
B1 mixture pour it into a cup to soak
the entire root system of the Orchid
[Music]
make sure the roots are evenly and fully
submerged in the solution so the plant
can absorb the nutrients from the garlic
and vitamin
[Music]
B1 then take a cotton pad soak it in the
mixture and gently wipe both the top and
bottom surfaces of the orchid
leaves garlic has antibacterial and
anti-fungal properties helping to
eliminate bacteria mold or harmful
agents that may be present on the
surface of the leaves this helps prevent
diseases for the
Orchid vitamin B1 supports the plant in
growing healthily especially during the
recovery process when applied to the
leaves vitamin B1 absorbs through the
epidermis making the leaves stronger and
promoting
[Music]
photosynthesis after soaking for about
20 minutes in the garlic GC and vitamin
B1 mixture gently remove the Orchid from
the
solution let the plant drain off any
excess water to prevent water logging
when
[Music]
repotting pine bark chips are an
excellent choice for orchid growing
medium because they offer many benefits
for the plant's growth
[Music]
pine bark chips have a porous structure
providing excellent irration in the
growing medium which allows the roots to
grow healthily without the risk of water
logging this Orchid growing medium has
moderate moisture retention helping to
maintain the necessary humidity for the
orchid's roots without letting water
stay stagnant for too
long Pine bark chips don't compact like
some other types of soil allowing the
root system to grow freely without
restriction pine bark has natural
properties that help prevent the growth
of bacteria and fungi which is crucial
for keeping the Orchid healthy
then use some dry moss that has been
sterilized to eliminate fungi and spread
it on top of the Orchid pot this helps
maintain moisture for the plant and
supports the orchid's
growth although Moss retains moisture
well it also has a porous structure that
enhances aeration for the plants root
system
preventing root water logging or oxygen
deficiency dry moss also helps make the
Orchid poic more attractive and tidy
adding a natural touch to the plant's
growing
space next take about 50 g which is
approximately 1.76 o odds and slice it
thinly to make a natural fertilizer that
is great for orchids
bananas are an excellent source of
minerals like potassium phosphorus and
magnesium which are very beneficial for
the growth of
orchids then place the banana slices
into a jar
[Music]
next take and add three packets of lipin
yellow label tea into the
jar tea contains components like tannins
and minerals that help enhance the
growth and health of the
plant tannins and tea have antibacterial
and antifungal properties helping to
protect the plant from diseases
minerals tea provides essential minerals
that help orchids grow strong and Bloom
beautifully pour hot water into the jar
about 0.5 L which is equivalent to 17 us
o close the lid and let it steep until
the water cools down allowing the
nutrients from the tea and banana to
dissolve into the
water after the water cools proceed to
strain out the residue
[Music]
pour .5 L of water into the filtered tea
and banana solution and stir well to
ensure the mixture is evenly
diluted after diluting the tea solution
you can directly water the Orchid roots
with this mixture it's a great way to
provide nutrients and support the
Healthy Growth of the
plant you can use a watering can with a
small nozzle to control the amount of
water avoiding overwatering the plant
gently water the diluted tea solution
onto the Orchid Roots making sure to
distribute it evenly around the root
area so the plant can absorb the
nutrients
gradually the tea water contains many
minerals especially potassium and
phosphorus which help the plant grow
strong particularly during root
development and
flowering banana water is a rich source
of potassium phosphorus and magnesium
which improves root development promotes
Leaf growth and enhances the orchid's
flowering
ability it's best to soak the Orchid pot
in this mixture for about 20 minutes so
that the roots can absorb the maximum
nutrients from the
solution next you can pour the tea and
banana water mixture into a spray bottle
and spray it onto the entire orchid
plant
[Music]
spray evenly on all parts of the plant
including both the top and bottom of the
leaves the stem and especially the root
area if
possible spray gently avoiding excessive
water on the growing medium just enough
to cover the surface of the plant and
leaves
evenly you can spray this solution one
to two times a week especially when your
orchid shows signs of weakness or needs
recovery next use a soft cloth to wipe
off any excess mixture from the leaves
and crevices to prevent damage to the
plant help it breathe better and avoid
water
logging wiping off the excess ex mixture
from the leaves and crevices helps
prevent mold bacteria growth and avoids
leaves from rotting or turning yellow
due to the accumulation of
substances this also helps the plant
breathe more easily while keeping the
leaves clean and
[Music]
healthy when water accumulates on the
leaves for too long the moist
environment can promote the growth of
bacteria and fungi wiping off the water
helps reduce the risk of disease and
keeps the plant
healthy water on the leaves can block
light reducing the efficiency of
photosynthesis wiping the water off
helps the leaves absorb light better uh
thereby enhancing the photosynthesis
process and promoting the plants
[Music]
growth after wiping off the water on the
leaves placing the Orchid pot in a spot
with gentle sunlight will help the plant
absorb light efficiently without causing
heat shock or Leaf
[Music]
burn let's take a look at the results
after 3 months of care with natural
fertilizer
[Music]
as a result you can see that the orchid
has grown four new flower spikes this is
a sign that the plant is absorbing
nutrients well growing healthily and
preparing for a brilliant blooming
[Music]
period the appearance of four new flower
spikes proves that the plant is in a
strong growth phase with its roots and
leaves functioning well
the plant is provided with enough
nutrients and suitable conditions to
produce more flowers that last
longer if properly cared for the plant
can continue to bloom regularly in the
future
I hope this video helps you take care of
your orchids at
home if you find it helpful please like
and share so more people can discover my
channel if you encounter any
difficulties during the Orchid planting
process don't hesitate to comment I'm
always here to help you grow healthy
orchids that bloom
beautifully thank you for watching I
always pray that God blesses you