hello
everyone today I'm going to share with
you how to care for orchids after they
bloom so that they recover quickly and
continue to flower in the
future one of the key factors is using
natural
fertilizers in this video I will
introduce you to a fantastic natural
fertilizer that works wonders for
orchids if you haven't subscribed to the
channel yet please click the Subscribe
button to support me and not miss any
Orchid growing tips it's great to have
company let's get
started my orchid has finished
blooming Old Flower branches have been
cut
off then cut off damaged
leaves if you haven't subscribed to the
channel yet please click the Subscribe
button to support me and not miss any
Orchid growing tips it's great to have
[Music]
company which country are you watching
videos from please comment and let me
know um it's nice that we can chat with
each other from all over the world
[Music]
this is a sprouted
potato I use these potato Sprouts as
fertilizer to stimulate Orchid
[Music]
growth potato Sprouts contain many
vitamins and minerals like vitamin C
potassium and iron helping the plant
grow strong
[Music]
place these potatoes in a dark place so
they continue to sprout and can be used
next time
in addition to the English dub we've now
created dubs in French German Italian
Spanish Portuguese Japanese Hindi and
Indonesian to help you hear and
understand the content more
easily then cut these potato Sprouts
into small pieces
that's my maid how do you like
it the nutrients in potato Sprouts
stimulate root development improving the
plant's ability to absorb water and
nutrients
compounds in potato Sprouts boost the
orchid's resistance helping the plant
combat diseases and unfavorable
environmental
conditions then I took five cloves of
garlic
minced garlic Into Thin slices
garlic contains Allison a compound with
antibacterial and antifungal properties
which helps protect orchids from common
diseases
put potato sprouts and chopped garlic in
a
jar add 1 liter of hot water
incubate
overnight after one night
stir well so the nutrients dissolve into
the
water filter residue
mix 1 liter of water at room temperature
[Music]
step
one water this water into each Orchid
pot combining potato sprouts and garlic
soaked in water to create a liquid
fertilizer has many wonderful effects on
caring for orchids especially after they
bloom
this solution contains a variety of
vitamins and minerals from both uh
potato sprouts and garlic providing
essential nutrition for orchids
the compounds in garlic and nutrients
from potato Sprouts help the plants
recover quickly after blooming improving
overall health then you let the Orchid
pot soak in this water for about 20
minutes this helps the roots absorb
water and nutrients in the best
way step two
you have this water in a spray
bottle garlic boosts the orchid's
resistance while potato Sprouts support
strong root development helping the
plants combat diseases and unfavorable
environmental conditions
then spray the entire
Orchid spray thoroughly on both the top
and bottom of the leaves
spraying the solution on the leaves
enhances moisture retention reducing
stress on the plants especially in dry
and hot weather conditions
this combination not only AIDS recovery
but also stimulates the next flowering
cycle resulting in more beautiful
blooms garlic has antibacterial and
antifungal properties helping orchids
resist diseases and harmful
environmental
factors after spraying you should not
leave the leaves wet like
this you need to dry the leaves
immediately after spraying this Liquid
Fertilizer
when leave stay wet for too long it
creates a favorable environment for
fungi and bacteria to thrive wiping the
leaves dry helps reduce the risk of
disease dry leaves can absorb light more
effectively enhancing the photosynthesis
process and providing energy for the
[Music]
plant when the leaves are dry the the
stamata can open more efficiently
allowing the plant to better absorb
nutrients from the air
wiping the leaves dry helps prevent
excess water accumulation thereby
reducing stress caused by high humidity
[Music]
dry leaves improve the absorption of
nutrients from the liquid fertilizer uh
increasing the effectiveness of
[Music]
fertilization then place the Orchid in a
place with enough light for better
photosynthesis
[Music]
results after 2 months of care using
liquid fertilizer formula every 2
[Music]
weeks the green leaves are shiny and
stronger than before
many new Roots grow
[Music]
strongly new Roots help the plant absorb
water from the environment providing the
necessary moisture for growth
new Roots also take in nutrients from
the soil or growing medium ensuring the
plant has enough nutrition to
[Music]
develop the orchid has also grown many
new flower branches
[Music]
es uh with this care the Orchid will
Bloom continuously from old to new and
the plant will not be stunted
take care of your Orchids with all the
love you have for plants and you will
enjoy the stunning flowers that bloom
beautifully under your care at
home each flower that blossoms is not
only a result of your nurturing but also
a testament to your love and patience
for
nature wishing you success in caring for
your plants and wonderful moments with
your favorite
flowers thank you for watching and see
you in the next videos