welcome to the happiness Garden
Channel if you have an orchid that is
rotting like this don't rush to throw it
away in this video I'll guide you on how
to treat rot and restore it so it can
can quickly bloom
again prune off the dry stems damaged
roots and withered leaves to give your
plant a fresh burst of energy helping it
grow healthier and more
vibrant which country are you watching
this video from please leave a comment
and let me
[Music]
know it's amazing that we can chat
together from all around the world
[Music]
damaged Roots leaves and stems if not
removed can create conditions for rot to
spread worsening the plant's condition
remove these parts immediately to
protect the plant's health health
[Music]
only leave the fresh Roots like
this then wash the plant thoroughly with
water to remove dirt mold and bacteria
helping to keep the plant clean and
prevent disease more effectively
[Music]
then place the plant in a dry area
overnight to allow the cuts to heal
helping the plant recover better and
prevent
infection then I take a teaspoon of
cinnamon as cinnamon has excellent
properties in helping orchids recover
from rot while also preventing bacteria
and mold from
entering add it to 1 ler of boiling
water to allow the cinnamon Essence to
dissolve into the
water and I cut an aloe vera leaf as it
contains many valuable nutrients that
help weak orchids recover quickly and
grow stronger aloe vera also has
anti-inflammatory properties helping to
protect the plant from infection
uh cover the lid and leave it overnight
allowing the nutrients from aloe vera
and cinnamon powder to fully dissolve
into the water creating a nutrient-rich
solution that helps the Orchid recover
effectively after one night strain the
mixture to remove the residue leaving
only the pure nutrient solution ready to
be used for the Orchid
[Music]
then soak the Orchid roots in this
mixture for 20 minutes to disinfect them
while also stimulating the roots to grow
quickly and
healthily next I use a cotton pad to
soak up the mixture and gently wipe the
top and bottom of the leaves helping the
plant absorb nutrients better and
preventing diseases caused by bacteria
and mold
[Music]
after soaking for 20 minutes remove the
Orchid and plant it in a new pot to help
it recover
better I plant the Orchid using pine
bark mulch because it helps with good
drainage maintains stable moisture and
provides an ideal environment for the
Orchid roots to grow healthy
healthy if you haven't subscribed to the
channel yet don't forget to hit the
Subscribe button so you won't miss any
helpful videos on orchid care join the
happiness Garden family
today spread a little moss on top of the
Orchid pot to help retain moisture for
the roots create a cool environment and
protect the plant from drying out it
also helps prevent weeds and keeps the
Orchid pot
clean after planting water the Orchid
with this mixture every 10 days to
provide continuous nutrients and support
the plant in growing strong and healthy
this mixture works wonderfully in
helping the Orchid recover and grow
strong cinnamon powder has antibacterial
properties helping to prevent mold and
bacteria from entering the cut while
also aiding the healing
process aloe vera provides essential
nutrients such as vitamins minerals and
amino acids stimulating the growth of
roots and leaves and boosting the
plant's immune system
remember to place the Orchid pot under
gentle sunlight avoiding direct and
strong sunlight as this helps the Orchid
grow healthily without the risk of leaf
burn after one month of recovery you can
see that the orchid has become
fresher the new leaves have grown taller
indicating that the plant is growing
strong strong and healthy the the
appearance of new leaves shows that the
plant is absorbing nutrients and energy
well ready for its next phase of growth
[Music]
wow the new Roots have grown a lot
showing that the Orchid is recovering
quickly and healthily strong root growth
helps the plant absorb water and
nutrients better ensuring sustainable
growth for the plant in the
[Music]
future for
when replanting the Orchid in into the
pot be sure to handle it gently to avoid
damaging the new roots
[Music]
after planting continue to care for the
Orchid with this nutrient mixture every
10 days this will provide continuous
nutrients to the plant promote strong
root and leaf growth protect the plant
from diseases and enhance its
[Music]
resistance for
on regular days if you notice the
growing medium is dry or the roots turn
silvery white simply water or Mist
gently to keep the Orchid
hydrated remember to always place the
Orchid pot in a location with gentle
sunlight allowing the plant to absorb
enough light for photosynthesis without
stressing the plant
[Music]
after the next 2 weeks you'll notice
that the new leaves have grown larger uh
indicating that this fertilizer is
helping the Orchid recover
effectively the growth of new leaves
shows that the plant is absorbing
nutrients well and gradually becoming
healthier ready for the next stages of
development
continue to care for the Orchid with
this nutrient mixture every 10 days
helping to maintain steady growth and
provide the necessary nutrients to keep
the Orchid healthy and thriving
if you encounter any difficulties in
caring for and restoring your orchid
don't hesitate to leave a comment for me
I'll be happy to assist
you for
after the next 2 months you'll see that
the orchid has grown very healthily with
vibrant green leaves and strong roots
just like other healthy orchids the
plant has fully recovered and is ready
for the next growth cycle prepared to
bloom if cared for properly
[Music]
y
with this simple method you can easily
care for and restore weak orchids at
home this approach helps the Orchid
continue to grow strong produce new
leaves and eventually Bloom beautifully
bringing a fresh and vibrant Beauty to
your living space
I hope you enjoyed this video don't
forget to like share the video so more
people can learn how to care for orchids
and if you haven't subscribed to the
channel yet make sure to subscribe so
you won't miss the next videos thank you
for watching and see you in the next
video