Hello
everyone. Very happy to see you on my
channel. Which country are you watching
this video
[Music]
from? Please leave a comment to let me
know where you are. It's wonderful. It's
wonderful that we can connect with each
other from all around the world.
Uh, you see here a withered
orchid. Perhaps it's because they
haven't been watered regularly or
because direct sunlight has shown on the
orchid. If if you want the orchid to be
nourished and grow quickly, please watch
this video carefully.
[Music]
Checking the roots, I found that many of
them had
rotted. Cut off all the damaged roots.
[Music]
Only keep the fresh roots like
this. Cut off the yellow
leaves. Cut off the old orchid stems
that have fully bloomed.
[Music]
Then rinse it clean with
water. Washing helps remove pathogens,
mold, or bacteria that could harm the
plant.
Cleaning helps the plant recover faster
when replanting in a new environment.
When the roots are washed, the plant
will absorb water and nutrients better
from the new
environment. Next, I take an aloe vera
leaf.
[Music]
Aloe vera gel has anti-inflammatory
properties, helping to soothe wounds on
the roots or leaves, supporting the
healing
process. Um, apply the gel to the wilted
leaves to help them recover quickly.
Aloe vera contains natural compounds
with antibacterial and antifungal
properties, helping to protect the plant
from common diseases.
[Music]
Aloe vera gel has great moisturizing
properties, helping the orchid maintain
the necessary moisture for its roots and
leaves, especially during the recovery
stage. Next, cut the aloe vera leaf into
small pieces.
If you haven't subscribed to the channel
yet, please hit the subscribe button to
to support me and not miss any orchid
care tips. It's wonderful to have you as
a
companion. Then place them into a jar.
Add one liter of boiling
water. Add 3 teaspoons of rice.
[Music]
Cover the jar and wait for 30 minutes
for the nutrients to dissolve into the
[Music]
water. 30 minutes
later, stir the flour nutrients into the
water.
[Music]
Then strain to get the
Then place the wilted orchid roots into
this
glass. Then soak the orchid roots in
this water for 30 minutes.
30 minutes
later, I plant the orchid in a new pot
with pine bark chips.
The chopped pine bark will help retain
moisture better.
[Music]
Um, add moss on top of the orchid pot to
help retain moisture
[Music]
better. Then water the orchid once every
5 days.
On regular days when the medium is dry,
just water it regularly.
[Music]
Then use a soft cotton pad to soak up
this water and wipe both the top and
bottom sides of the
leaves. Aloe vera contains many vitamins
and minerals providing essential
nutrients for the plant and helping to
improve its overall health.
Then place the orchid pot in a spot with
plenty of indirect light so the orchid
can
[Music]
photosynthesize. The result after 3
weeks.
[Music]
The new roots are very
healthy. The orchid has grown new
leaves. Uh the wilted leaves have become
greener.
[Music]
Continue fertilizing the orchid with
aloe vera leaves and rice water.
Dirt on the leaves can hinder the
photosynthesis process and cleaning them
helps the leaves absorb light better.
[Music]
Cleaning the leaves helps remove mold,
bacteria, and small insects, reducing
the risk of disease for the
[Music]
plant. Then water the orchid with aloe
vera water and rice water once every 5
days.
[Music]
When the medium is dry, just water the
orchid with regular
[Music]
water and place it in a spot with plenty
of indirect light for the plant to
photosynthesize.
[Music]
Well, the result after 2 months.
Healthy roots have
[Music]
developed. The new leaves at the top are
growing
healthily. The wrinkled, wilted
condition of this old leaf has improved
and become fresher.
[Music]
Uh when the root system is this healthy,
it will help the orchid recover quickly
and grow
vigorously.
[Music]
Continue fertilizing the orchid with
aloe vera leaves and rice water.
Wiping the leaves with this water will
help increase humidity around the plant,
especially in a dry
[Music]
environment. When wiping the leaves, you
can easily detect unusual signs such as
spots, discoloration, or pests so that
you can take timely action.
Then water the orchid with aloe vera
water and rice water once every 5 days.
[Music]
When the growing medium is dry, just
water the orchid with regular
[Music]
water. And place it in a spot with
plenty of indirect light so the plant
can photosynthesize. as
[Music]
well. The result after the next 2
months from a weak orchid, it has now
developed normally and bloomed.
[Music]
Take care of your orchid with all the
love you have for
[Music]
it, and you will enjoy admiring the
beautiful flowers that you've cared for
yourself.
I hope you enjoyed this video. Please
leave a comment to let me
know. If you found the content
interesting and meaningful, don't forget
to like, share it so more people can
know, and subscribe to support me. Thank
you for always being with
me. If you encounter any difficulties in
growing orchids, don't hesitate to leave
a comment for me. I'm always ready to
support you so you can grow healthy
orchids that bloom beautifully.
Thank you for watching the video. I
always pray for blessings to be upon all
of you.