Welcome to the garden of happiness.
Orchids are a tropical plant with a very
strong vitality.
[Music]
When you see this orchid, don't rush to
throw it away.
[Music]
Today, I will show you how to restore a
wilted orchid like this in the fastest
way.
[Music]
First, you need to cut off all damaged
roots.
[Music]
If you haven't subscribe to the channel
yet, please hit the subscribe button to
support me and not miss any orchid
growing tips. It's great to have you
along.
[Music]
Rinse with water.
Dry the cut.
Drop the molten candle solution on the
freshly cut wound. It will help orchids
not lose water and also work against
fungal diseases.
[Music]
Um, please comment to me which country
you are watching the video from. It's
great that we can chat together from all
over the world.
[Music]
Use one teaspoon of cinnamon powder.
Add four cups of boiling water, about
one liter.
[Music]
Close the lid and wait for the water to
cool.
[Music]
Now the water has cooled.
Filter out the residue.
[Music]
Uh, soak orchids in cinnamon water for
30 minutes.
[Music]
Spray this mixture evenly on the top and
bottom of the orchid leaves. Um,
cinnamon has antiseptic properties, so
it helps to eliminate fungi and insects
that are harmful to orchids very well.
Cinnamon also contains many minerals,
vitamins, and amino acids that are very
beneficial for the revival of orchids.
[Music]
Do this once a month to keep your orchid
protected and healthy.
[Music]
After soaking for 30 minutes, take out
the orchid cutings and plant them.
I plant in shredded pine bark to help
with drainage, but also provide the
right amount of moisture for the orchid
to thrive.
[Music]
Spread one turn of dry moss on top of
the pot.
[Music]
Leave in a cool place and do not water
for one week so that the fungus does not
grow harmful.
[Music]
One week later, start watering to keep
the orchid moist.
[Music]
Pour water into the dish at the bottom
of the pot to create the right humidity
for the orchid to to revive quickly.
Recycling plastic bottles into miniature
green houses makes it easier for orchids
to revive.
[Music]
One month later.
Since the tree has grown roots, I use
organic fertilizer made from fish waste
to fertilize the orchid.
The baby orchid is still very small, so
I only apply it on the outside edge of
the pot to avoid causing the baby orchid
to be shocked with feces.
[Music]
Watering and moisturizing once a week.
2 months later,
you can see that the orchid has revived
and is growing very vigorously with
healthy roots and strong leaves.
This shows that natural fertilizer is
truly effective, helping the plant
recover after blooming and continue to
grow sustainably.
Uh, what do you think about the way I
revived this little orchid? Feel free to
leave a comment and share your thoughts.
I'd love to hear your feedback and
experiences.
If you encounter any difficulties during
the orchid growing process, don't
hesitate to leave a comment for me. I'm
always ready to support you so that you
can grow healthy orchids that bloom
abundantly.
I hope you will enjoy this video. If you
find it useful, don't forget to hit like
and subscribe to the channel so you
won't miss the upcoming shares on how to
care for orchids naturally and simply.
Welcome to my channel.
If you want orchids to bloom a lot,
orchids always grow healthily.
Uh then join me in discovering organic
fertilizers in this video.
[Music]
Take 50 g of coffee grounds, about 2 oz.
Soak in 2 L of hot water.
Wait for the water to cool.
[Music]
After the water cools, filter to remove
sediment.
[Music]
Add water to make 5 L of solution. About
1.3 US gallons.
[Music]
Method one, fertilize orchid roots.
Coffee grounds contain many important
nutrients such as nitrogen, potassium,
phosphorus, and minerals.
[Music]
Um, when used as fertilizer, it helps
promote their growth and flowering.
[Music]
Coffee grounds also have the ability to
hold water, helping to maintain the
necessary humidity for orchids.
[Music]
Method two, spray the entire orchid.
You can also spray this fertilizer on
the entire orchid.
[Music]
Like folure fertilization for orchids.
Coffee grounds often have a slightly
acidic pH which reduces the alkalinity
of the soil.
This is beneficial for orchids because
many orchids prefer a soil environment
with a slightly acidic pH.
[Music]
The second type of fertilizer I want to
share with you is also made from coffee
grounds.
[Music]
I took 3 tablespoons of coffee grounds.
Add two quarts of warm water about 0.53
US gallons.
[Music]
Leave space.
Add 1 teaspoon of sugar.
Add 1 tbsp yeast.
[Music]
Cover with vented lid.
1 month later,
take 50 ml of fermented coffee water,
about 3 tablespoons.
[Music]
Add water to make 5 L of solution about
1.3 US gallons.
Method one, water the roots.
You water the roots with fertilizer from
fermented coffee one to two times a
month.
[Music]
Coffee grounds when fermented will
become nutrient-rich organic fertilizer.
[Music]
Fermented coffee grounds contain many
important nutrients for plant growth
such as nitrogen, potassium, phosphorus,
calcium, and minerals.
[Music]
This is a natural source of nutrients
that helps orchids grow healthily.
[Music]
Method two, clean the leaves.
Clean the top and bottom of the leaves
with this water.
[Music]
Helps
kill fungi, insects, and harmful
bacteria very effectively.
If you fertilize one to two times twice
a month, the leaves will always be green
and disease-free.
[Music]
Let's see the results.
After 3 weeks, new roots begin to grow.
[Music]
after 5 weeks. The roots grow a lot.
Uh this helps the plant rts absorb the
most nutrients through the roots.
[Music]
Flower buds also develop faster.
Many flower stems grow on the same
orchid.
[Music]
Flowers bloom with more vibrant colors.
flowers bloom with more vibrant colors.
[Music]
Hope the video will help you a lot.
If you find it interesting, please share
and like so more people know about this
video.
Thank you for watching the video. Good
luck and see you in the next videos.