Hello everyone. Welcome to the Happiness
Garden
channel. Today I'll share an amazing tip
for taking care of orchids after their
flowers have faded. This method is
especially effective for helping wilted
or weak orchids recover and grow
[Music]
quickly. This is an orchid that has
already bloomed but became wilted and
stunted, so it was discarded.
I picked it up with the hope of reviving
it and helping it grow strong again.
Let's see how I do
it. First, trim off the old flower spike
that has long
withered. This helps the plant redirect
nutrients to root and leaf growth
instead of sustaining the dried flower
stem.
[Music]
Next, upon checking the roots, I found
many inorganic fertilizer pellets in
green and
[Music]
gray. Uh, this orchid may have wilted
because the inorganic fertilizer damaged
its roots, preventing it from absorbing
water and nutrients, which caused the
leaves to wilt. Therefore, we need to
remove these fertilizer pellets and
treat the roots to help the plant
[Music]
recover. The roots are severely damaged
and dry. Uh this prevents the plant from
absorbing water and nutrients.
[Music]
Uh, the next step is to trim off the
damaged roots so the plant can focus on
growing new, healthier ones.
Next, rinse the roots thoroughly with
water.
This removes any remaining dirt, old
fertilizer, and damaged parts, preparing
the plant for
recovery. Which country are you watching
this video from? Leave a comment below
and let me
know. I'd love to connect and chat with
all of you from around the world.
[Music]
To make natural fertilizer, I first take
one teaspoon of honey. Honey provides
natural nutrients and supports the
plant's growth in a safe and effective
way.
Dilute the honey in one liter of
water. This makes the solution lighter,
allowing it to easily penetrate the
leaves and roots without causing harm
while effectively providing nutrients.
[Music]
Next, I take one aloe vera leaf as it is
excellent for helping wilted or stunted
orchids recover. Aloe vera provides
moisture and natural nutrients to help
the plant recover quickly and grow
strong. Add the aloe vera leaf to about
300 ml of water.
[Music]
Then blend the aloe vera with a blender
until smooth. This ensures the aloe vera
is fully mixed into the water, creating
a fine, smooth solution that can easily
absorb into the roots and leaves of the
orchid.
Strain out any pulp or residue from the
aloe vera
mixture. This makes the solution smooth,
ensuring it can easily penetrate the
plant without clogging or causing damage
to the roots and leaves.
[Music]
Place the aloe vera leaf in a cup and
pour the aloe vera water over it,
letting it soak for about 20
minutes. This method helps provide
moisture and essential nutrients,
speeding up the recovery process for
wilted orchids.
[Music]
After soaking for 20 minutes, remove the
orchid and wipe off any excess mixture
on the
leaves. This helps prevent overwatering
or excess mixture, reducing the risk of
leaf or root rot.
Place the orchid roots into the cup.
This makes it easier to observe and
proceed with the next steps in the
recovery
process. Now mix the honey with the aloe
vera mixture.
And here is vitamin B1, which is great
for recovering wilted leaves and
encouraging new root
growth. Vitamin B1 helps strengthen the
plant's resistance and supports its
quick recovery after stress or weakness.
Then pour this mixture and soak the
orchid roots for about 20
minutes. This helps provide all the
necessary nutrients and vitamins,
accelerating the plant's recovery
process.
[Music]
After soaking for 20 minutes, we take
the orchid out and plant it into a new
pot. Planting it into a new pot provides
the plant with the best conditions to
grow and absorb nutrients from fresh
soil.
I plant the orchid using moss to help
retain
moisture. Moss is a fantastic natural
material that maintains humidity and
supports the plant's quick recovery.
[Music]
From now on, water the orchid with the
honey, aloe vera, and vitamin B1 mixture
once every 10 days. This will provide
essential nutrients and moisture,
promoting quick recovery and healthy
growth.
[Music]
On regular days, if you notice the
growing medium is dry, simply water or
mist the orchid to maintain
moisture. This helps the plant maintain
proper hydration and grow steadily
without needing a special mixture.
[Music]
Then place the orchid pot in a spot with
gentle
sunlight. Gentle sunlight allows the
plant to absorb enough energy for growth
without burning its leaves or causing
damage from excessive sun.
[Music]
You can use any leftover mixture to
water other regular
orchids. This will help stimulate root
growth and promote the development of
new shoots, improving the overall health
and growth of the plants.
[Music]
Uh you can see this orchid of mine which
was cared for using this method has
developed many new shoots and roots and
is now healthy. The natural method using
honey, aloe vera and vitamin B1 is truly
effective and helps the plant recover
quickly.
[Music]
The result after 3 weeks is that the
orchid has developed many new emerging
roots. This is a clear sign that the
plant has recovered strongly and is now
in a healthy growth phase.
[Music]
If you haven't subscribed yet, please
hit the subscribe button and support my
channel. Your support is a great
motivation for me to keep creating more
interesting and helpful videos.
[Music]
The orchid has sprouted a new leaf
bud. This is a great sign that the plant
is recovering well and ready to continue
growing in the future.
[Music]
The wilted leaves are much fresher
compared to before the recovery
process. This is a clear sign that the
plant has absorbed sufficient nutrients
and is on the path to healthy growth.
[Music]
I will continue to water this orchid
with the natural fertilizer mixture of
honey, aloe vera, and vitamin B1 once
every 10
days. This will help the plant maintain
its health and continue to develop
strong roots and leaves in the future.
[Music]
Next, use a soft cotton pad to soak up
the mixture and gently wipe both the top
and bottom sides of the
leaves. This helps provide nutrients
directly to the leaves and remove dirt,
promoting better plant health and
growth.
[Music]
Then place the orchid pot in a spot with
gentle
sunlight. Remember, while fertilizer is
beneficial, without sufficient sunlight,
the orchid won't synthesize nutrients
properly, leading to stunted growth.
[Music]
The result after the next 2 months is
that the orchid has grown very well with
many new roots and healthy
leaves. The natural care method with
honey, aloe vera, and vitamin B1 has
proven to be highly effective.
[Music]
You can see the orchid has grown many
new healthy
leaves. And it has also sprouted a new
flower shoot which proves that the
orchid has fully recovered.
This is a wonderful sign that the plant
is thriving and ready to bloom
soon. Care for your orchids with all the
love and tenderness in your heart, and
nature will always reward your efforts.
Every drop of water, every moment of
care is a gift that brings life, vibrant
blooms, and endless
joy. Thank you for watching. Wishing you
a joyful and energetic day. Goodbye and
see you next time.