Welcome to my
channel. When you buy an orchid or
someone gives it to
[Music]
you. You need to do the
following. First, you need to remove the
packaging from the
[Music]
orchid. Next, leave the orchid in a cool
place for a few hours to allow it to
adjust to the new climate.
[Music]
Uh if the growing medium is moss or
small wood chips, it is only suitable
for industrial orchid gardens.
[Music]
[Applause]
Because moss retains a lot of moisture,
many plant roots rot due to water
logging.
If you haven't subscribed to the channel
yet, please hit the subscribe button to
support me and not miss any orchid
growing tips. It's great to have you
[Music]
along. Uh the humidity was too high, so
the leaves were also infected with black
mold.
In addition to the English dub, we've
now created dubs in French, German,
Italian, Spanish, Portuguese, Japanese,
Hindi, and Indonesian to help you hear
and understand the content more
[Music]
easily. Therefore, you need to remove
all moss or old growing medium.
Um because this type of substrate is
only suitable for industrial orchid
gardens that can control special
[Music]
humidity. Please comment to me which
country you are watching the video from.
It's It's great that we can chat
together from all over the
[Music]
world. Then you cut off all damaged
roots.
[Music]
and cut off all wilted flowers.
Then you take one aloe vera leaf.
[Music]
and take a clove of garlic.
Put all the aloe vera and garlic in a
jar and soak it with 2 L of water.
[Music]
Wait 30 minutes for the nutrients from
the garlic and aloe vera to dissolve
into the
[Music]
water. 30 minutes later.
Soak the roots in this solution for 30
minutes.
Garlic and aloe vera help stimulate root
growth and effectively fight harmful
insects and fungi.
[Music]
Um, spraying this solution on the entire
orchid will help repel insects,
eliminate fungal diseases, and keep the
leaves green.
[Music]
Then clean the black mold stains with
this
[Music]
solution. This helps prevent orchids
from recurring mold.
[Music]
Now I recycle used plastic containers to
make orchid pots.
[Music]
Hey, hey, hey.
I put a layer of pummus on the bottom of
the orchid pot.
[Music]
This helps keep the bottom of the orchid
pot clear so the roots don't get water
[Music]
logged. For the top, I use dried pine
bark as a growing
[Music]
medium and mix in some dry moss.
When planting, cushion the substrate
tightly so that the roots do not move.
[Music]
Insert the flower branch into the right
position to help prevent the orchid from
shaking.
[Music]
After planting, let it dry for 5 days
before
[Music]
watering. Take care of your orchids with
all the love you have for plants, and
they will bloom all over the garden this
way.
[Music]
Thank you for watching the video. Good
luck and see you in the next videos.