Welcome to the happiness garden where we
explore the gentle beauty of nature
together and learn how to care for
flowers with all our
love. Uh all of us when we start growing
orchids hope to have beautiful orchid
pots with many flower buds and blossoms
always in full bloom showing off their
vibrant colors throughout the season.
[Music]
Today I want to share with you a new
type of fertilizer that is not only easy
to make but also very effective for
orchids. Anyone can prepare it by
themselves right at
home. This type of fertilizer will help
orchid plants develop healthy, greener
roots. And thanks to that, your orchids
will always bloom beautifully, stay
fresh and long lasting on the branch,
bringing bright colors all year
[Music]
round. Let's get
started. To start making the fertilizer,
first prepare one liter of warm water in
a clean bottle.
If you haven't subscribed yet, please
hit the subscribe button to support me
and never miss any orchid care tips.
It's wonderful to have you along on this
journey. Then add one teaspoon of bread
[Music]
yeast. Please comment below and tell me
which country you're watching this video
from.
It's amazing that we can connect and
chat together from all around the
[Music]
world. Add one teaspoon of sugar to help
activate the yeast more effectively.
[Music]
Add 50 ml of beer to boost the
microorganisms and make the mixture more
nutritious for orchids.
[Music]
Then stir the mixture well. Close the
lid tightly and let it sit for about 2
hours to allow the yeast to ferment
naturally.
[Music]
Um, these are the orchid pots that have
entered the post blooming stage. When an
orchid has finished blooming, it's not
the end, but a new beginning. This is a
perfect time to care for the roots,
nourish the leaves, and prepare for the
next blooming season. With just a little
patience and love, your orchid will come
back stronger than you expect.
[Music]
Uh, you should cut off all the withered
petals as well as the buds that are
beginning to fade to help the nutrients
focus on nurturing stronger new
flowers. The nutrients will focus on the
orchid producing new buds while also
helping the developing buds become
bigger and healthier.
[Music]
You should also pinch off the flowers
that are beginning to fade so the orchid
can focus on producing fresher,
healthier, new flower stems.
[Music]
Thanks to that, the nutrients will focus
on nurturing new flower stems while also
stimulating the plant to grow many more
flower stems.
[Music]
After removing the withered petals. The
flowers that bloom afterward will have
petals that are much more vibrant and
beautiful.
[Music]
For the wilted flower stems, you should
also cut them off to help the nutrients
focus on nurturing the remaining flowers
to be healthier.
[Music]
You can see that after removing the old
stems and wilted and flower stems. The
flowers that bloom afterward will have
petals that are much more vibrant and
[Music]
beautiful. Then you need to remove the
old, weak, wilted, or yellow leaves to
help the orchid become healthier and
absorb nutrients better.
[Music]
Old and wilted leaves have weak
resistance, so they are very prone to
fungal infections and other diseases.
[Music]
Next, you should Cut off the damaged
roots,
[Music]
Ned. Cutting off the damaged roots helps
the orchid avoid the risk of root rot
while focusing nutrients on nurturing
healthier roots.
[Music]
To identify damaged roots, gently hold
the orchid root. If the root feels soft
and breaks easily, it is damaged. While
the hard green roots are healthy and
normal.
[Music]
After the mixture has fermented for 2
hours, add three vitamin B1 tablets into
the bottle to create a super nutritious
solution for orchids.
[Music]
Then dilute the mixture with one liter
of water to ensure safety and
effectiveness when using it for orchids.
[Music]
Then water each orchid pot with this
mixture twice a month for the best
growth. This mixture helps stimulate the
growth of orchid roots, making the root
system healthier and
greener. When the roots are healthy, the
plant can absorb nutrients more
effectively, thereby enhancing its
overall growth and development.
[Music]
Watering with this mixture helps helps
strengthen the orchid's resistance,
enabling the plant to fight against
diseases caused by fungi and
[Music]
bacteria. Uh, thanks to that, the orchid
will have fewer pests and diseases and
grow more steadily in all environmental
conditions.
[Music]
Watering with homemade nutrient mixture
also helps improve the soil environment
and increase the activity of beneficial
microorganisms in the orchid pot. This
keeps the soil loose, retains moisture
well, and creates ideal conditions for
healthy plant growth.
[Music]
Next, put the nutrient mixture into a
spray bottle.
[Music]
Then spray thoroughly on both the top
and underside of the leaves so the
nutrient mixture can absorb evenly and
work at its
[Music]
best. Uh, spraying the nutrient mixture
helps the leaves absorb nutrients
quickly, making the orchid leaves
greener and healthier.
[Music]
Spraying this mixture also helps clean
dust off the leaves, allowing the leaves
to breathe and absorb light more
effectively, thereby enhancing the
overall health of the
[Music]
plant, providing nutrients through the
leaves. also promotes the photosynthesis
process, helping the orchid grow faster
and bloom regularly, making your garden
more vibrant.
If there is any leftover mixture, you
can use it to spray on orchids that are
currently blooming. It is very good for
keeping the flowers fresh and
long-lasting. This fertilizer mixture
helps orchids stay fresh longer. keeping
the petals bright and vibrant for a long
time. When nutrients are provided
through the leaves, it helps improve the
overall health of the plant, resulting
in more even and longerlasting blooms.
[Music]
After watering, remember to use a soft
cloth to wipe off any water droplets on
the leaves and between the
[Music]
leaves. This helps prevent fungal
diseases from developing and keeps the
leaves dry and healthy.
[Music]
In addition, wiping the leaves also
helps remove any remaining dust after
spraying, keeping the leaves clean and
allowing them to absorb light better.
[Music]
Thanks to this, the leaves will always
be shiny green, firm, and full of
vitality.
[Music]
Wiping off the water on the leaves also
helps remove insect larae hiding in the
crevices and unders sides of the leaves,
keeping the orchid clean and
[Music]
healthy. You should water, spray, and
wipe off any remaining moisture with
this liquid fertilizer mixture two to
three times a month to keep your orchid
healthy and blooming beautifully.
You should do this in the morning so
that when the sun rises, the remaining
moisture will evaporate completely,
keeping the orchid dry and preventing
fungal
diseases. And finally, uh remember to
place the orchid pot in a spot with
gentle sunlight and good
ventilation.
Remember that no matter how good the
fertilizer is, if the orchid lacks
sunlight, its metabolism will be
affected and the plant will not be able
to absorb nutrients
properly. As long as you are persistent
and care for it regularly, the orchid
will always have shiny green and healthy
leaves.
In addition, the roots will grow
exceptionally well and be protected by
the beneficial microorganisms present in
the fermented
mixture. Uh, everyday care for your
orchid with all the love you have for
plants and you will be rewarded with
stunningly beautiful
blooms. These petals not only decorate
your living space but also bring a
feeling of relaxation and peace.
They help you and your family members
relax and enjoy a living space full of
vitality. I hope you will like this
video. If you find it useful, don't
forget to like and subscribe to the
channel so you won't miss the upcoming
shares about natural and simple orchid
care
methods. Thank you for watching the
video. I always pray that God's
blessings will be with all of you.