Hello everyone, welcome to the happiness
garden channel. Today I will share a
great tip for taking care of orchids
after the flowers have faded.
This method is especially effective in
helping wilted or weak orchids recover
and grow quickly.
[Music]
This is an orchid that has been attacked
by insects, causing its leaves to become
torn and no longer intact as they were
originally.
These marks are evidence that the plant
once had to fight against pests in
nature.
And this orchid has also finished its
previous blooming cycle. The once
vibrant flowers have now faded, making
way for the plant's period of rest and
energy regeneration.
[Music]
At this time, we need to cut off the
withered flower spike to prevent the
plant from wasting energy on a part that
is no longer necessary.
This will allow the plant to focus on
developing new roots and leaves.
[Music]
Leaves that are severely damaged or
starting to turn yellow should also be
gently removed.
Removing damaged leaves helps the orchid
become more ventilated, reduces the risk
of fungal diseases, and allows it to
focus on nourishing the healthy parts.
[Music]
Moss growing medium is only truly
suitable in a professional farming
environment where humidity is strictly
controlled.
[Music]
Um, when humidity is not well
controlled, you may easily notice signs
of mold appearing around the roots.
This is a warning sign that the plant is
having problems and needs to be treated
promptly to prevent spreading and root
rot.
Therefore, when growing orchids at home,
we should remove the moss and replace it
with a more breathable medium to avoid
water retention that can cause root rot.
Let me know in the comments which
country you're watching from. Uh it's
wonderful that we can connect and chat
from all around the world.
[Music]
In addition to the English voiceover, we
have now created versions in French,
German, Italian, Spanish, Portuguese,
Hippie Hindi, Dutch, Polish, Korean, and
Indonesian to help you listen and
understand the content more easily.
To hear your language, open the video
and click on settings, the gear icon to
select your preferred audio language.
This is the foam plug used for
propagating seedlings from a very young
stage.
However, at this point, the foam plug is
no longer necessary and may hinder root
development. So, we need to gently
remove it.
[Music]
Next, we will trim off the damaged
roots. However, before cutting, it's
important to sterilize the pruning tools
with 90% alcohol to prevent spreading
pathogens to the plant.
Trimming off damaged and old roots helps
remove part parts that no longer absorb
nutrients while also creating favorable
conditions for the plant to grow
stronger, healthier new roots.
[Music]
After pruning, we need to thoroughly
rinse all the roots under running water.
This helps remove old soil, debris, and
any remaining pathogens before moving on
to the next treatment step.
[Music]
After rinsing, place the roots into a
clean jar. This helps keep the plant
hygienic and properly prepared for the
next steps of treatment or root care.
[Music]
To treat the orchid before planting, I
use lemon. You can use either green or
yellow lemons as both contain natural
acids that gently disinfect the roots.
[Music]
squeeze the lemon juice into a clean
cup.
[Music]
This juice will be used to soak or rinse
the roots, helping to disinfect and
support the plant's recovery process.
Next, we need to prepare the necessary
tools to dilute the lemon juice.
First, pour 3 L of clean water into a
container. This will serve as the base
to dilute the lemon juice, creating a
safe solution for treating the orchid
roots.
Next, add 3 tsp of lemon juice into the
container. This amount is just enough to
create a mild disinfecting solution that
cleans the roots without causing damage.
[Music]
Then stir the solution thoroughly to
ensure the lemon juice is fully
dissolved in the water, maximizing its
effectiveness when soaking the roots.
Step one, use a soft cloth soaked in
this solution. Then gently wipe both the
upper and lower surfaces of the leaves.
Wiping the leaves helps remove dust
buildup on their surface, thereby
improving their ability to absorb light.
When the leaves are clean,
photosynthesis B becomes more efficient,
allowing the plant to grow healthier and
recover more quickly.
[Music]
Regularly wiping the leaves also helps
detect and remove mold or small insects
like meie bugs early on. Meie bugs
attached to the stem, leaves, roots, and
base of the orchid to suck sap, causing
the plant to weaken, become stunted, and
grow slowly.
This method also helps eliminate scale
insects at an early stage. Scale insects
cling tightly to both the upper and
lower surfaces of the leaves, sucking
sap and causing the plant to weaken,
leaves to yellow and drop easily.
When the leaves are clean, the stamata
on their surface are not blocked,
allowing the gas exchange process to
take place more smoothly.
You should wipe orchid leaves one to two
times a month to keep them clean and
breathable while still protecting the
natural layer on the leaf surface.
[Music]
Step two, pour the diluted lemon juice
mixture in and soak the orchid roots in
the solution for about 20 minutes.
[Music]
Soaking the roots in the diluted lemon
juice solution gently disinfects them,
removing harmful bacteria and mold still
clinging to the roots, thereby reducing
the risk of root rot after planting.
In addition, the diluted lemon juice
solution also helps stimulate the
formation of new roots thanks to its
mild acidity that supports metabolism
and root tissue regeneration.
[Music]
To ensure healthy plant growth, we need
to treat the growing medium before
planting. This step helps eliminate
mold, bacteria, and insects that may
still exist in the medium.
[Music]
I pour the diluted lemon juice mixture
in to soak the pine bark for about 20
minutes. This helps clean, disinfect,
and remove any mold remaining on the
surface of the growing medium.
[Music]
after that. Add a small amount of dried
moss to soak in the same solution. This
helps clean the moss and improves its
moisture retention when replanted, while
also reducing the risk of fungal
diseases.
[Music]
Uh after soaking for about 20 minutes,
take out the dried moss and pine bark
and let them drain.
This is the final preparation step
before replanting the orchid into the
new growing medium.
[Music]
Prepare a new pot with drainage holes at
the bottom. This design prevents water
from accumulating and creates a well
ventilated environment for healthy root
development.
[Music]
Then add the growing medium into the pot
and place the orchid in it, making sure
the roots are nestled within the medium,
but the base of the plant is not buried
too deeply.
[Music]
When adding the growing medium, gently
shake the pot so that the pine bark and
moss fill in the gaps around the roots,
helping the plant stay stable and
allowing the roots to have even contact
with moisture.
[Music]
Spread a small amount of moss on the
surface of the growing medium after
planting. This moss layer helps retain
light moisture around the base of the
plant while also giving the orchid pot a
fresh and more visually appealing look.
Uh, if you've made it this far and found
the content helpful, don't forget to
like, share, and subscribe to support
me. Your support is the motivation for
me to keep sharing more meaningful
videos.
[Music]
You can see dark spots appearing on the
underside of the leaves. This is an
early warning sign, so it needs to be
treated promptly to prevent the spots
from spreading and causing leaf rot.
[Music]
Before treating the dark spots, you need
to sterilize the pruning tools with 90%
alcohol. This helps prevent the spread
of pathogens to other parts of the
plant.
Then use the sterilized tool to gently
cut off the darkened part of the leaf.
Timely removal will help prevent the
disease from spreading and protect the
remaining healthy leaf tissue.
[Music]
Yes, squeeze.
space.
[Music]
Hey
After removing the damaged part of the
leaf, sprinkle a little cinnamon powder
on the cut.
[Music]
Cinnamon powder has natural
antibacterial properties that help the
wound dry quickly and effectively
prevent fungal infections.
[Music]
I also sprinkle cinnamon powder on the
cut of the flower spike after pruning.
This provides natural disinfection,
helps the cut dry quickly, and prevents
rot from spreading down to the base.
[Music]
After that, place the orchid pot in a
spot with gentle sunlight and good
airflow and avoid watering for 1 week.
This allows the cuts to dry completely
and helps prevent root rot or fungal
infections.
After about 1 to two weeks, once the
roots have stabilized, in addition to
watering, you can gently apply a natural
fertilizer to the orchid uh every 2
weeks to support its recovery and
healthy growth.
And here is the result. After 5 weeks,
the orchid has begun to recover with
clear signs from the roots to the
leaves. A gentle care process yet full
of hope.
You can see that the orchid has grown a
new leaf at the top. This is a sign that
the plant is reviving and coming back to
strong growth.
[Music]
Uh the leaves have also become much
greener and glossier than before,
indicating that the plant is absorbing
nutrients well and recovering
positively.
[Music]
Um, when the leaves are healthy, the
plant photosynthesizes more efficiently,
generating more energy to nourish the
roots, develop new shoots, and prepare
for the next blooming cycle.
[Music]
In addition, the orchid has also grown
many new healthy roots, helping the
plant absorb nutrients better and grow
stronger daybyday.
[Music]
These healthy new roots will help the
plant absorb water and nutrients more
effectively, thereby enhancing its
vitality and long-term growth potential.
[Music]
If you've made it this far and found the
content helpful, don't forget to like,
share, and subscribe to support me. Your
support is the motivation for me to keep
sharing more meaningful videos.
As long as you know this knowledge and
persistently apply it, your orchid will
surely recover and grow healthy over
time. Patience is the secret to success
in orchid care.
And you will be rewarded with radiant
flowers spreading fragrant scents and
vibrant colors that brighten up your
space.
Be patient in caring for and applying
this knowledge every day. Your orchid
will not only recover, but also grow
strong, bringing radiant flowers and
complete joy.
If you face any difficulties in growing
orchids, don't hesitate to leave a
comment. I'm always ready to support you
so that you can grow healthy orchids
that bloom abundantly.
Thank you for joining me on this
journey. See you in the next videos.