welcome to my
channel in this video I continue to
share how to make orchids bloom at the
same time with many flower
branches orchids after flowers fade
[Music]
we cut off all the spent flower
stems if the plant has never bloomed it
must have three or more pairs of
leaves and healthy roots
which country are you watching this
video from please leave a comment and
let me
know it's amazing that we can chat
together from all around the
world sprinkle cinnamon powder on the
wound to help it heal quickly
[Music]
then wait one day for the cut to
dry then take half small onion and cut
it into thin slices
[Music]
add 1 liter of water and bring to a boil
wait a day then
[Music]
use next take three spoons of
rice then soak in 1 liter of water and
leave for 1 day before
[Music]
using after a day filter out the residue
mix the two types together
[Music]
clean the leaves with this
water helps eliminate fungi and bacteria
to help orchids grow
[Music]
better do it once a week
then use this water to water the Orchid
[Music]
Roots this will help stimulate root and
flower stem
[Music]
growth do it once a
week Place cotton balls between two
leaves
[Music]
then spray this water on the Cotton
pad this stimulates flower stems to
[Music]
grow and spray on the top and bottom of
the leaves to help supplement nutrients
through the leaves for the orchids
[Music]
this should be done early in the morning
so that by noon the leaves will dry
before the sun
[Music]
shines after 30 minutes remove the
cotton and repeat once a
[Music]
week and take out the Orchid pot
2 months
[Music]
later many flower stems grow at the same
time
[Music]
orchids also grow many new
roots with this simple method you can
easily care for Blooming orchids at home
[Music]
tips for recovering rot infected orchids
uh when orchids are old and have poor
resistance we need to rejuvenate
[Music]
them first you need to cut off all
damaged leaves and
[Music]
Roots keep only fresh roots
is
[Music]
onions have very good antiseptic and
growth stimulating effects
[Music]
take about 20 G of thinly sliced onion
take one teaspoon of baking soda helps
balance pH levels and eliminate fungal
diseases harmful to
[Music]
orchids add 2 L of water at room
temperature
[Music]
wait 30 minutes before
using after 30 minutes filter to remove
residue
[Music]
then water the Orchid with onion water
and baking soda
[Music]
soak in this water for 30 minutes
cover the pot with a layer of dry moss
[Music]
place the dried moss in this transparent
plastic box
[Music]
leave in a cool place for one day
without watering
[Music]
one day
later from now on water your orchids
once a
[Music]
week or water when the Moss is dry
be careful to keep the Moss moist if the
Moss is water loged the Orchid will
easily
[Music]
rot then place it in a cool place with
enough light for the Orchid to grow
[Music]
3 weeks later
many baby orchids have spread
[Music]
Ed Take 2 lers of water at room
temperature
[Music]
then add five spoons of rice
water the Orchid with rice water once a
[Music]
week helps stimulate baby orchids to
grow and take root quickly
[Music]
continue to place in a cool well-lit
place for the Orchid to
[Music]
grow after the next one month
the baby orchids grow very
[Music]
healthy hopefully the video will help
you a lot in taking care of orchids at
home
[Music]
if you find it interesting please click
like and share so more people
[Music]
know and um don't forget to subscribe to
the channel so your channel can soon
reach 1 million subscriptions
[Music]
next to help you have many options when
caring for orchids at home with organic
fertilizer helps orchids grow and Bloom
with many long- lasting flowers in this
video I continue to share new methods
[Music]
when eating oranges don't rush to throw
away the
[Music]
peel right now I will share this tip for
making organic fertilizer from orange
[Music]
peels if you haven't subscribed yet
please uh subscribe to support me and to
not miss any orchid care tips and don't
forget to share so more people can learn
these great tips
[Music]
I cut the peel of an orange and put it
in a
jar add 2 L of warm water
then add one spoon of sugar and one
spoon of yeast
[Music]
punch holes in the lid close the lid and
leave in a cool place for 1
[Music]
month 1 month later
I already have GE orange peel
[Music]
fertilizer I took 4 tablespoons of GE
orange peel
[Music]
mix 2 L of
water first
method use a GE Orange Peel to
thoroughly wipe the top and bottom of
the leaf
[Music]
orange peels contain essential oils that
after incubation will help repel insects
very
[Music]
effectively helps leaves photosynthesize
and create chlorophyll
[Music]
better do this one to two times a month
to protect orchids and keep the leaves
green
[Music]
second
method applying this fertilizer to the
roots one to two times per month helps
provide organic substances such as humic
acid fulvic acid and enhance water
retention in Orchid growing media
[Music]
Orange Peel also contains many important
minerals such as potassium magnesium
calcium and Trace
[Music]
elements GE fertilizer helps orchids
grow strongly and increase FL
[Music]
production GE fertilizer helps improve
the ability of plants to absorb
[Music]
nutrients helping orchids make better
use of available nutrients in the
environment
[Music]
let's see the
results the flower color is more vibrant
than usual
[Music]
orchids bloom many flowers on the same
tree but do not
[Music]
fall flowers bloom continuously from
season to season all year round
[Music]
the flowers stay on the branches for a
long time before
[Music]
fading thank you for watching the video
good luck and see you in the next
videos welcome to my
channel in this video I share the method
of recovering weak orchids helping them
quickly take root and grow
[Music]
strongly if you haven't subscribed to
the channel yet please subscribe to
support me and not miss miss any orchid
care
[Music]
tips let's get
started I picked up a rotten Orchid that
someone had thrown
[Music]
away please comment to me which country
you are watching the video
from it's great that we can chat
together from all over the
[Music]
world all the roots have
rotted which country are you watching
this video from please comment and let
me know
uh it's wonderful that we can connect
and chat with each other from all around
the
[Music]
world this original part has completely
rotted so it can no longer be used
[Music]
wash Orchid branches with
water then take one clove of garlic and
mince it
[Music]
garlic has antibacterial and antifungal
properties helping to prevent common
diseases in orchids such as mold and
harmful
[Music]
bacteria uh garlic contains allisin um a
compound that stimulates plant root
growth which is especially helpful when
orchids are recovering from a period of
flower loss or a weakened plant
[Music]
antioxidants in garlic help strengthen
the orchid's resistance helping the
plant stay healthy and and grow better
in a caring
[Music]
environment add 500 mL of water and soak
for 30 minutes letting the flour
nutrition completely dissolve in
[Music]
water after 30
minutes wiping Orchid branches with
garlic water helps disinfect and
eliminate fungal
[Music]
diseases if you encounter any
difficulties during the Orchid growing
process don't hesitate to comment I am
always ready to support you so you can
grow healthy orchids and Bloom lots of
flowers
[Music]
then soak the Orchid branches in garlic
water for 10 minutes this helps
stimulate root and Chute growth
[Music]
10 minutes
later because this orchid has many scars
from previous insect bites so I waited a
day for the Orchid to dry completely
before planting it
[Music]
one day
later I recycle sponges as orchid
nursery tools
[Music]
f
soaking the sponge in garlic water for
20 minutes helps disinfect and kill
[Music]
fungus 20 minutes later
insert the Orchid stem into the sponge
and place it in the
[Music]
vase pour some water into the J
and change it every time it gets
[Music]
dirty Spray moisturizer every 3 days and
place it in a cool well-lit place
[Music]
5 Weeks
Later The Roots have grown very
[Music]
healthy The Roots have grown very
healthy
[Music]
how do you see how to restore your weak
orchids please write a comment to let me
know your opinion
[Music]
I planted it in a pot so the Orchid
could grow
[Music]
better if you find the video interesting
please like and share so more people
know this tip
[Music]
water orchids regularly to keep them
moist thank you for watching the video
good luck and see you in the next
[Music]
videos hi
everybody in this video I share how to
care for orchids to help them grow
quickly and flower many times in the
same
year you see my orchid's new flowers
always grow after old ones fall so my
orchids bloom all year round from Branch
to branch
[Music]
the flowers bloom for a long time before
dropping their petals and can stay on
the branches for up to 6 months
um please comment to me which country
you are watching the video
from it's great that we can chat
together from all over the
world many flowers grow on the same tree
[Music]
new Roots grow a lot to help absorb
nutrients
[Music]
best chubby flower
buds help flowers bloom long on branches
[Music]
brilliant
flowers how to make fertilizer as
follows use one small carrot weighing
about 30 G
[Music]
cut into small
pieces add 1 liter of filtered water
[Music]
puree filter out residue
add 1 ler of filtered
[Music]
water then use cotton to soak carrot
juice and wipe both the top and bottom
sides of the
[Music]
leaves this method helps repel insects
and open the stamata the orchids will
photosynthesize and exchange nutrients
better
[Music]
at the same time orchids also absorb
some nutrients through the leaves
helping keep the leaves green
[Music]
if you haven't subscribed to the channel
yet please subscribe to support me and
not miss any orchid care tips
[Music]
second
way water this car for
orchids carrot juice is a good source of
nutrients for orchids including vitamins
and minerals like beta carotene
potassium magnesium and
[Music]
phosphorus uh when the carrot juice is
poured into the Orchid pot it provides
nutrients to the orchids and helps to
promote their
[Music]
health in addition carrot juice is also
acidic which helps regulate the pH of
the Potted soil and enhances the
orchid's ability to absorb
nutrients you can soak the Orchid pot in
this carrot juice for 20
[Music]
minutes do this one two times a
month Third Way
[Music]
Mist moisturizing carrot juice for
orchids by spraying both the top and
bottom of the leaves this helps wash
away dirt and eliminate insects on your
orchids the nutrients in carrot juice
support Orchid Health helping them
Thrive and Bloom beautifully
[Music]
however be careful not to overwater with
carrot juice as it can clog the water
channels in the
Orchid avoid spraying directly on the
flowers as this can cause them to fall
off
quickly I hope this video helps you take
better care of your orchids at home and
encourages them to bloom
easily um if you find it helpful and
interesting please like share and
subscribe to support my channel thank
you hi
everybody to give you more options for
taking care of your orchids at home
using organic fertilizer in this video I
continue to share methods for making
natural fertilizer from everyday kitchen
ingredients you can find in your home
subscribe to the video so you don't miss
any tips on my
[Music]
channel number
one to make this fertilizer you need
apples
[Music]
apples contain potassium an important
mineral for orchid
[Music]
growth potassium helps orchids develop
stronger leaves roots and flowers
[Music]
uh I took the apple peel and put it in a
bottle soak in boiled water and leave
overnight please comment to me which
country you're watching the video
from it's great that we can chat
together from all over the
[Music]
world number
two to make this type of fertilizer you
need more eggshells
[Music]
if you haven't subscribed to the channel
yet please subscribe to support me and
not miss any orchid care
[Music]
tips soak the eggshells in boiled water
and leave overnight
[Music]
leave overnight
after one night filter the water
[Music]
so we have fertilizer from apples and
eggshell
[Music]
first
method water this fertilizer Solution on
the Orchid roots
[Music]
eggshells provide natural calcium which
is very good for orchids they help
orchids stay healthy and increase
resistance
[Music]
apple peels contain a lot of phosphorus
which is also an important nutrient for
orchid
[Music]
growth especially during the flowering
and flower development stage
[Music]
do this one to two times a month to
supplement nutrition and increase the
orchid's resistance
[Music]
second
method spray this fertilizer on the
entire orchid
[Music]
this method is similar to using foler
fertilizer calcium and eggshells helps
orchids stay healthy and increases their
resistance to pests
[Music]
apples contain nitrogen an essential
nutrient that helps orchids develop
healthy green growth and enhances their
ability to photosynthesize
[Music]
do not spray on flowers because wet
flowers will easily fall off
[Music]
third
method clean the leaf surface with this
liquid
[Music]
fertilizer the leaf surface will always
be clean and Airy
[Music]
orchids will photosynthesize
better fertilizing regularly one to two
times a month will help keep the leaves
healthy
[Music]
number
three you can reuse eggshells and apple
peels to make fertilizer again
[Music]
let's check out the results
together this type of fertilizer
stimulates rooting very quickly
[Music]
after 1 month of use you will see great
results many flower buds develop and do
not fall
[Music]
blooming flowers stay on the branches
for a long time before fading
[Music]
flowers can remain on branches for up to
6 months before
[Music]
falling thank you for watching the video
good
welcome to my
channel if you have orchids after
[Music]
blooming if all the flowers have fallen
don't rush to throw them
away uh let me tell you how to help
these branches continue to bloom
strongly
[Music]
again these nodes can continue to bloom
very well
[Music]
when you eat bananas don't throw away
the peel
[Music]
thinly sliced banana peels contain many
vitamins and minerals that are very good
for the bud formation process
[Music]
please comment to me which country you
are watching the video from it's great
that we can chat together from all over
the
[Music]
[Applause]
world soak banana peels in 1 liter of
boiled water
[Music]
then take 3 tblspoon of coffee grounds
then soak this coffee grounds in 1 liter
of boiled
[Music]
water then wait for the water to cool
after the water cools filter to remove
[Music]
sediment dip a cotton ball and water
extracted from coffee grounds and wash
the leaves
[Music]
helps eliminate pests and diseases of
orchids and leaves will photosynthesize
better
[Music]
um if you haven't subscribed to the
channel yet please subscribe to support
me and not miss any orchid care
[Music]
tips mix these two types together
dip cotton balls in this water and clip
them to nodes that are likely to
continue
[Music]
blooming do it once a week
will help stimulate rapid Sprout growth
[Music]
uh keep the cotton pad on the branch
like that for 20 minutes and then remove
[Music]
it then water The Roots once a week
soak it for 10 minutes then lift it out
[Music]
and spray this water once a week to help
supplement nutrients through the leaves
[Music]
after 20 minutes remove the cotton pad
and then place the plant in a place with
lots of light so it can bloom
[Music]
easily 1 month later
many buds have
[Music]
grown if you encounter any difficulties
during the Orchid growing process don't
hesitate to comment I am always ready to
support you so you can grow healthy
orchids and Bloom lots of
[Music]
flowers cons Contin Pony Aon if therex
in
[Music]
there then place the plant in a place
with lots of light so it can bloom
[Music]
easily after the next 1
month from the dry branches many
beautiful flowers have sprouted and
bloomed
[Music]
the leaves are strong and sturdy very
resistant to pests and
[Music]
diseases the flower color is also more
vibrant than usual
[Music]
hope the video will help you a
lot if you find it interesting please
like share and subscribe to the channel
to help my channel reach 1 million
subscri criers
[Music]
soon my videos have subtitles in many
different languages so you can choose
the appropriate language
[Music]
thank you for watching the video good
luck and see you in the next
[Music]
videos Hello
friends nice to meet you on my
channel you see here a withered Orchid
maybe it's because you didn't water it
or due to direct sunlight shining on the
Orchid
[Music]
um if you want orchids to be nourished
and grow quickly please watch this video
carefully
[Music]
now I will share this amazing trick with
you you need one aloe vera
leaf which country are you watching the
video from please comment
below it's wonderful that we can chat
together from all around the
world this this aloe vera gel is great
for Reviving
[Music]
orchids now apply aloe vera gel on the
top and bottom of the
[Music]
leaf aloe vera gel has a very good
moisturizing
[Music]
effect in addition aloe vera also
contains vitamins a b and c and minerals
such as nitrogen phosphorus and
potassium
[Music]
uh do this every 5 days and leave the
Orchid pot in a cool place for 3
[Music]
weeks next take 1 lit of warm water and
put it in the
[Music]
bottle then take one of rice and soak it
in this water for about 30 minutes let
the nutrients in the rice completely
dissolve into the
[Music]
water chop the remaining aloe vera
leaves into small pieces
[Music]
then puree with 300 mm of water
filter out residue then add 2 L of water
at room temperature
[Music]
after soaking for 30 minutes filter this
rice
[Music]
water mix rice water with aloe vera
juice
[Music]
so I ended up with about three lers of
this wonderful liquid manure solution
[Music]
cover the pot with moss to retain
moisture better
[Music]
now you use the solution to water the
Orchid every 5 days
[Music]
soak the Orchid pot in this water for 2
hours after soaking for 2 hours remember
to lift the Orchid pot and place it in a
cool place to let the Orchid recover
[Music]
2 weeks
later fertilize after 2 weeks for
fresher orchid
[Music]
leaves new Roots develop very well
many new roots are
[Music]
growing new Roots will help transport
water and nutrients from the roots to
the stem
if the leaves are provided with enough
water and nutrients from the roots the
leaves will gradually become Lush
[Music]
again 1 month later
you see the leaves are very fresh
[Music]
and the Orchid grows a new
Leaf after the next 2
[Music]
months the orchid has grown two branches
two buds
[Music]
but the leaves at the base have turned
yellow so I will cut off these yellow
[Music]
leaves uh instinctively when an orchid
buds if the plant lacks nutrients that
the base leaves will turn yellow and
fall off to provide nutrients for the
buds to
[Music]
develop now I need to supplement the
orchid's nutrition by taking three
spoons of rice
[Music]
uh then soak in 2 L of water at room
temperature and wait 30 minutes for the
nutrients to completely dissolve in
water before
[Music]
using 30 minutes
later add 3 tbsp of
[Music]
milk rice water and milk are excellent
sources of nutrients for orchids to grow
[Music]
now you water the Orchid with this
solution once a week to help the Orchid
recover quickly
[Music]
after the next 1
month after 3 to four times of applying
liquid fertilizer from milk and rice
water the Orchid had many
[Music]
roots hope the video will help you a lot
if you like the video remember to hit
like share and subscribe to support
[Music]
me uh thank you for watching the video
wish you luck and see you in the next
videos
[Music]
welcome to my
Channel today I share with you an
amazing organic fertilizer and anyone
can do it
easily just one to two ripe bananas and
the Orchid Garden will bloom all kinds
of flowers
now I will revive this Orchid with new
[Music]
flowers um you've seen this Orchid lose
all its flowers leaving only withered
branches and here are the withered
orchids that have been revived with lots
of new flowers
step
[Music]
one cut off the withers
apply toothpaste on the cut
apply toothpaste on the
[Music]
cut don't throw away banana peels when
eating
[Music]
bananas don't throw away banana peels
when eating bananas
[Music]
clip the banana peel to to the place
where the flower buds can
[Music]
grow and note to remove after 6 hours
this helps to create the right moisture
provide essential nutrients and
stimulate Flower
[Music]
sprouts do this once a
week step two
use a banana peel to wipe the top and
bottom of the leaves this helps
eliminate insects fungi bacteria hiding
on orchid leaves and at the same time
provides a part of nutrients through the
leaves for
[Music]
orchids this method also helps the
orchid plant to be protected and not be
affected by yellowing or rotten
[Music]
leaves after wiping you will see green
leaves orchids will photosynthesize eyes
better to increase resistance
[Music]
step
three 1 liter of water
[Music]
leave in a cool and dark place for one
day
[Music]
after one
day banana juice is darker
[Music]
use this absorbent
cotton clip a cotton ball where the
flower buds can grow
and note to remove after 6
hours uh this helps to to create the
right moisture provide essential
nutrients and stimulate flour
Sprouts do this once a
[Music]
week step
four normally after 3 to 4 weeks flower
buds will be formed and develop like
this
[Music]
um with a flower Sprout this big there's
no need to sandwich banana peels with
cotton
[Music]
balls you will be surprised how amazing
this is
[Music]
don't forget to subscribe to see my next
videos St
add water to make 2 lers water this
banana for orchids once every 2 to 3
weeks banana peel is rich in potassium
phosphorus and essential
vitamins will promote the growth of
orchid
roots in particular the potassium and
banana peel stimulates flowering very
[Music]
well in addition you need to combine
using other organic fertilizers for
orchids like manure made from soybeans
peas fish poop as I
[Music]
shared hope this sharing content will
help you in taking better care of
orchids at home
um if you find the video interesting
don't forget to like share and subscribe
to support my
channel welcome to my
channel uh to help you have many choices
when caring for orchids at home with
organic fertilizer in this video I
continue to share new
methods in addition to the English
voiceover we have now created voiceovers
in French German Italian Spanish
Portuguese Hindi Japanese and Indonesian
to help you listen to and understand the
video content more easily open the video
and click on settings the gear icon to
select the appropriate audio
language now let's get
started to make this type of organic
fertilizer you need black tea or tea
grounds
[Music]
I use three teaspoons of black
tea add 1 ler of boiled water
[Music]
incubate until the water
cools after the water cools filter to
remove sediment
if you haven't subscribed to the channel
yet please click the Subscribe button to
support me and never miss any Orchid
growing tips it's wonderful to have you
along for the
[Music]
[Applause]
journey add water to make 5 L of black
tea
[Music]
solution next add 1 teaspoon of baking
soda
[Music]
first
method water this fertilizer solution on
the Orchid
[Music]
roots black tea contains many minerals
and organic substances that help provide
nutrition for orchids
[Music]
it contains nitrogen potassium and
phosphorus important nutritional factors
for orchid
[Music]
growth please comment to me which
country you are watching the video from
it's great that we can chat together
from all over the world
[Music]
baking soda bicarbonate soda has the
ability to increase the pH level in
Orchid
[Music]
pots um this is helpful in reducing
acidity if you use too much chemical
fertilizer
[Music]
baking soda has the ability to kill
insects and fungi that are harmful to
plants
[Music]
second
method spray this fertilizer on the
entire orchid
[Music]
this method is similar to using foler
fertilizer
[Music]
you can use it as a natural pesticide to
protect orchids from insects and
diseases
[Music]
third
method clean the leaf surface with this
fertilizer solution
[Music]
the leaf surface will always be clean
and the stomata will not be clogged
[Music]
orchids will photosynthesize
better join us to see the results when
caring for orchids with this natural
[Music]
fertilizer a plant roots are protected
and supplemented with nutrients so they
grow very
[Music]
healthily will help orchids absorb the
most nutrients
[Music]
because they are provided with enough
nutrition the flowers bloom more
[Music]
brilliantly many flowers bloom on the
same branch
[Music]
if you find the video helpful please hit
like share it to reach more people and
don't forget to subscribe to the channel
to support me
[Music]
the flowers stay on the branches for a
long time before
fading thank you for watching the video
wishing you luck and success in
life I'm very happy that you are
here if you have an orchid I'm sure you
always want it to bloom for a long time
right
[Music]
right orchids are known for their
ability to keep flowers on their
branches for 3 to 6 months
[Music]
for that to happen you need to nurture
water and feed it
[Music]
well now I will show you what is the
best fertilizer for
[Music]
orchids if you follow us till the end of
this video you will learn how to make
orchids bloom like
[Music]
crazy now let's get
started take a bowl and put 5 tbsp of
rice in
[Music]
it if you haven't subscribed to the
channel yet please subscribe be to
support me and not miss any orchid care
[Music]
tips pour in 500 M of water at room
temperature mix the rice well and wash
the rice before cooking
[Music]
then filter the water to wash the
rice please comment to me which country
you are watching the video from it's
great that we can chat together from all
over the
[Music]
world use a cotton ball soaked in water
to wash this
[Music]
rice then wipe on the top and bottom of
the leaves
[Music]
we'll help clean the surface of the
leaves remove disease fungi and insects
on Orchids at the same time it provides
the necessary nutrients for the orchid's
growth
[Music]
repeat after 2 weeks will help the
Orchid Stay Green
[Music]
or you can also pour the rice water into
a spray
[Music]
bottle then spray evenly on the top and
bottom of the leaves
[Music]
this method also has the same effect as
the previous method using cotton balls
[Music]
do not spray rice water on
flowers now take a deep Bowl in which
you will place the Orchid ready for
watering and
[Music]
soaking rice water is a great natural
fertilizer for orchids as it encourages
the flowering of this beautiful plant
[Music]
you can soak the Orchid in this rice
water for about 1 hour so that the
Orchid Roots can absorb the most
[Music]
nutrients then remove and repeat this
treatment every 14 days
[Music]
you can also freeze rice water to water
your orchids
[Music]
when needed you just need to take a few
cubes wait for the to defrost and reach
room temperature you can feed your
orchids
[Music]
again never Place Frozen blocks directly
on the base of the Orchid because
orchids don't like the cold
[Music]
after only two to 3 weeks of use the
leaves will be
[Music]
green um you can see that after
fertilizing the new Roots grow very
strongly this will help the orchan could
best absorb nutrients through its
[Music]
roots if you find the content
interesting or meaningful don't forget
to like share so that more people know
and subscribe to your support Channel
thank you for always accompanying
[Music]
me with enough nutrition your or will
flower all year round
[Music]
and that will be all we have prepared
for you for this video
[Music]
welcome to my
channel um there are different ways to
propagate orchids for you to have more
options in Orchid breeding today I share
how to make a new guide to propagate
orchids from ginger root it will be very
simple but extremely
[Music]
effective please watch to the end of the
video to understand my
[Music]
comments first first peel off this film
so that small orchids can grow
[Music]
easily please comment to me which
country you are watching the video from
it's great that we can chat together
from all over the
[Music]
world use 10 G of fresh
ginger add 1 cup of water
Ginger is a very good plant growth
stimulant at the same time Ginger also
has antiseptic properties that will help
eliminate fungus for
[Music]
orchids Ginger prevents rot disease on
Orchids very
[Music]
well soak Orchid branches in ginger
water for 10 minutes
[Music]
use 1 teaspoon of turmeric
powder add 2 cups of water
turmeric contains many minerals such as
magnesium calcium zinc protein
phosphorus and natural potassium very
good for the growth of
orchids and turmeric also has very high
antibacterial
properties take take it out and wait for
it to
[Music]
dry mix ginger juice with turmeric
water soak moss in this water for 20
minutes helps kill mold and bacteria in
Orchid growing media
[Music]
apply melted candle solution to the cut
to prevent the Orchid from losing water
this will prevent water from seeping
inside the Orchid and protect it from
[Music]
rotting if you haven't subscribed to the
channel yet please subscribe to support
me and not miss any orchid care tips
[Music]
reuse plastic boxes to make Orchid
propagation
[Music]
tools I made many drainage holes
here and this is this the vent that
helps to circulate the air inside with
the outside of the box
[Music]
put the Orchid branch in pay attention
to the Sprouts facing
up then spray moisturizing Mist every 5
[Music]
days place in a cool
place after 2
months uh from a small Sprout that has
grown into a
[Music]
Seedling Roots grow healthy
but the Orchid is small and weak so I
continue to grow orchids in this mini
Greenhouse for a while longer
[Music]
continue misting to moisturize every 5
days continue to keep in a cool
[Music]
place after the next 20 days
Orchid is bigger and
[Music]
healthier the roots are also much
healthier in order for the Orchid to not
rot later I will plant it with a more
ventilated medium
[Music]
I grow with a medium that includes Pine
bark pmus and Terra
Cotta this medium will help the orchid's
roots to always be ventilated and have
the right humidity for the Orchid
helping orchids not root
rot uh add some moss on your face for
for better moisturizing
[Music]
now take care of it like any other
Orchid apply organic fertilizer once
every 2 weeks for good
growth and thank you for watching the
video good luck and see you in the next
video for