hello
everyone uh in today's video we will
explore how to create an amazing organic
fertilizer that helps sick orchids
recover quickly and grow
[Music]
vigorously with easily accessible
ingredients you will learn how to create
a nutrient-rich solution that promotes
lush green leaves and faster blooming
stay tuned to take care of your orchids
effectively
[Music]
let's get
started pythium or risea Tonia fungi
often cause soft rot especially in wet
conditions when you see a rotten Orchid
like this cut off the rotten part as
quickly as
[Music]
possible lemon is an easily accessible
ingredient and very useful for caring
for orchids especially when they are
rotting
[Music]
which country are you watching this
video from please leave a comment for
me it's wonderful that we can chat with
each other from all around the world
[Music]
if you haven't subscribed to the channel
yet please subscribe to support me and
not miss any tips on my
channel in addition to the English dub
we have now created dubs in French
German Italian Spanish Portuguese
Japanese Hindi and Indonesian to help
you listen and understand the content
more easily videos are now more
accessible
[Music]
I take the peels of four lemons and cut
them into small
pieces lemon peels contain many
micronutrients such as Vitamin C calcium
magnesium and potassium which help
provide nutrients for the
[Music]
plant add 300 M of water about 1 Cup
then blend until smooth
[Music]
then strain out the residue
step
one use a soft cotton pad to soak up
this liquid and gently wipe both the
upper and lower surfaces of the leaves
lemon peels contain antibacterial
compounds that help eliminate harmful
bacteria and fungi preventing diseases
in
Plants lemon peel smoothie contains many
beneficial micronutrients for plants
helping the leaves stay vibrant and
healthy
the underside of the leaves has many
stamata where photosynthesis takes
place cleaning off dust and impurities
helps the plant photosynthesize more
efficiently
uh wiping the leaves also helps remove
dust and impurities reducing the risk of
pests attacking the plant
uh wiping the leaves also helps remove
dust and impurities reducing the risk of
pests attacking the
plant lemon is acidic which helps
dissolve dirt mineral salts and
chemicals on the leaves making them
easier to
remove the natural compounds in lemon
peels act as a gentle cleanser helping
to clean without harming the
leaves carefully tending to both sides
of the leaves will help orchids grow
healthier and produce more beautiful
flowers
[Music]
mix 3 L of water about 0.8 us Gall into
this lemon peel
smoothie step
two lemon peel smoothie contains many
vitamins and minerals providing
essential nutrients for plants
the acidity in lemons helps regulate the
soil's pH creating an ideal environment
for root growth
the compounds and lemon peels have
antibacterial properties helping to
prevent harmful fungi and bacteria
[Music]
uh watering with lemon infused water can
stimulate root growth and help the plant
thrive
after each watering soak the Orchid pot
in this lemon peel smoothie for about 20
[Music]
minutes 5 minutes
later do you see snails and insects
crawling on the surface of the
[Music]
pot the compounds and lemon peels have a
bitter taste that makes insects
uncomfortable forcing them to move
upward in search of a safer place
[Music]
the lemon peel smoothie creates an
environment unsuitable for snails and
insects forcing them to move out of the
growing medium in search of another
place
[Music]
step
three now pour this liquid into a spray
bottle
[Music]
then spray this liquid over the entire
Orchid lemon peel smoothie contains
antibacterial and antifungal
compounds the compounds and lemon peels
contain many micronutrients that help
boost plant health and growth
helping to prevent and treat plant
[Music]
diseases after soaking for 20 minutes
take the Orchid pot out and place it in
a spot with plenty of diffused light so
the Orchid can absorb more light for
photosynthesis
photosynthesis is the process by which
plants convert sunlight into chemical
energy plants use this energy to grow
develop and sustain their vital
functions results after 10
[Music]
days the leaves become greener shinier
and
[Music]
stronger during photosynthesis plants
produce glucose which is the primary
nutrient that helps them grow vigorously
and
[Music]
Bloom after 10 days new Roots also begin
to grow vigorously
[Music]
new Roots help the plant absorb water
and nutrients from the growing medium
providing the necessary energy for
growth
healthy new Roots help the plant grow
faster produce more flowers and develop
shiny green
leaves if you encounter any difficulties
while growing orchids don't hesitate to
leave a comment I'm always ready to
support you so you can grow healthy
orchids that bloom beautifully
[Music]
take care of your Orchids with all the
love you have for plants and they will
reward you with blooming flowers vibrant
colors and a sweet
fragrance dedicated care not only brings
Beauty to your living space but also
makes life more
wonderful let orchids be a source of
inspiration bringing joy and peace to
your soul
[Music]
I hope this video brings you Great Value
in taking care of your orchids at home
in the best way
possible if you find the content helpful
please like and share or leave a comment
to support me
[Music]
I always wish you goodness and
blessings wishing you lots of luck and
success in life