Welcome to my little garden where I
share how to care for orchids using
natural and easy to find ingredients.
Today I'm sharing a natural fertilizer
that helps keep orchid leaves shiny and
healthy.
[Music]
This fertilizer will help the orchid
roots grow stronger and more abundantly.
[Music]
the flower buds will appear earlier and
they will also become plump and healthy.
[Music]
This fertilizer also helps multiple
branches grow on the same flower stem,
creating a beautiful and dense flower
cluster.
[Music]
In addition, this fertilizer helps the
petals grow larger and stay on the stem
for a long time before wilting.
Let's get started.
To make this amazing natural fertilizer
today, I'm using onions, something that
every household has in their kitchen.
[Music]
Onions contain many natural
antibacterial compounds that help
protect orchid roots from fungal
diseases and stimulate strong new root
growth.
[Music]
Um, when you eat onions, save the peels
to use as natural fertilizer. It's very
beneficial for orchids.
[Music]
Take the peel of one onion and put it
into a clean jar. are.
[Music]
Then add one liter of boiling water to
extract the nutrients from the onion
peel.
[Music]
Cover the jar and wait until the water
cools down completely.
Please comment and let me know which
country you're watching this video from.
It's wonderful that we can chat together
from all over the world.
[Music]
Once the water has cooled completely,
stir it well to extract the nutrients
from the onion peel into the water.
Then strain out the solids to keep only
the liquid.
Next, add about 10 milllers of fresh
milk to the mixture.
Fresh milk provides calcium and protein,
helping the orchid grow stronger with
vibrant green leaves and long-lasting
flowers.
In addition, fresh milk has
antibacterial and disinfectant
properties, helping protect the plant
from fungal diseases.
[Music]
Step one, use a soft cloth to soak up
the mixture and gently wipe both the top
and bottom of the leaves.
Wiping the leaves helps remove dust and
impurities, allowing the plant to absorb
light better.
Fresh milk has antibacterial properties
that help prevent fungi and harmful
bacteria from affecting the plant.
Wiping the leaves also helps the stamata
on the leaves to open wider enhancing
the photosynthesis process.
Wiping with this mixture also provides
calcium and protein from the milk,
helping the leaves stay healthy and grow
well.
Uh, cleaning the leaves helps the plant
absorb light more efficiently, promoting
growth.
This mixture helps reduce the growth of
pests that harm the plant.
Wiping the leaves helps create a natural
protective layer, making the leaves
glossy and giving the plant a fresh,
vibrant look.
Once a month, you should wipe the leaves
with this mixture one to two times to
help your orchid stay healthy and grow
well.
If you haven't subscribed yet, please
hit the subscribe button to support me
and not miss any orchid growing tips.
It's amazing to have you as a companion.
Step two, spray this mixture on the
leaves, especially the underside where
fungi and pests are more likely to
thrive.
Spraying this mixture is like washing
away dust, mold, and fungi on the leaves
and leaf joints, making the leaves
glossy and keeping the plant fresh.
This mixture has antibacterial and
disinfectant properties, helping prevent
fungal and bacterial diseases on the
orchid.
Fresh milk and onion peels help prevent
pest attacks, protecting the leaves from
harmful factors.
Fresh milk provides calcium and protein,
improving the plant's health and
supporting the growth of leaves and
roots.
Once a month, you should spray this
mixture one to two times. The best time
to do this is in the early morning or
late afternoon when the plant is not
exposed to harsh sunlight.
Step three, water the roots and the
orchid growing medium with this mixture.
Fresh milk contains calcium and protein,
helping the roots grow stronger and
absorb nutrients more effectively.
This mixture helps stimulate root
growth, making the roots healthier and
more resilient.
[Music]
Onion peel and fresh milk contain
potassium and calcium, two essential
nutrients that help orchids develop
strong, healthy flowers.
Uh you should apply this care method
twice a month, preferably in the early
morning or late afternoon when the
weather is not too hot. At this time,
the plant can easily absorb nutrients
without experiencing heat shock or leaf
burn.
Step four, use a soft cloth to wipe off
any excess water on the leaf surfaces
and in the leaf joints.
Wiping off excess water helps reduce the
risk of leaf rot and soft rot caused by
prolonged moisture.
[Music]
This helps prevent the growth of fungi
and bacteria, protecting the plant from
diseases.
[Music]
When the leaves are dry and well
ventilated, it helps the plant absorb
light better, improving the
photosynthesis process.
Wiping off excess water helps remove
dust and residue, making the plant look
cleaner and more beautiful.
Well ventilated leaves help the plant
absorb nutrients better when you spray
fertilizer or apply it.
Wiping off excess moisture helps reduce
the risk of insects hiding in the moist
leaf joints.
[Music]
Any leftover fertilizer mixture can be
placed in a spray bottle to spray on
other blooming orchids in your garden.
[Music]
When spraying the fertilizer mixture on
a blooming orchid, it helps stimulate
flower growth, making the flowers bloom
larger and last longer. This allows the
orchid to produce beautiful and
impressive flowers.
The fertilizer mixture also helps
strengthen the flowers, keeping them on
the stem longer without easily falling
off. Uh, this ensures the flowers stay
fresh and last throughout the blooming
process.
Adding nutrients from the fertilizer
helps the flowers have brighter, more
vibrant colors, enhancing the beauty of
the orchid and making the garden more
lively.
[Music]
The fertilizer mixture also supports the
orchid in maintaining its health
throughout the blooming process, helping
the plant withstand stress and grow
strong, ensuring that it continues to
bloom in the following seasons.
[Music]
You should spray the fertilizer mixture
on blooming orchids about 1 to two times
a month. The best time to do this is in
the early morning or late afternoon when
the temperature is not too high,
allowing the plant to absorb nutrients
easily without experiencing heat shock.
[Music]
Now, let's take a look at the results
after 1 month of using this fertilizer
care routine.
You can clearly see the changes in your
orchid with glossy, healthy leaves,
large, longlasting flowers, and
especially the strong growth of new
roots.
[Music]
The orchid will become healthier, better
able to fight off diseases, and produce
even more beautiful flowers in the
following seasons.
[Music]
The abundant growth of new roots shows
that the orchid has absorbed enough
nutrients from the natural fertilizer.
When the roots are healthy and strong,
the plant will have a solid foundation
to continue growing, allowing the orchid
to absorb enough water and nutrients to
nourish its flowers and leaves.
The strong growth of the roots is also a
sign of a healthy plant system ready for
the next blooming cycle.
Uh the orchids that were previously
cared for with the natural fertilizer
made from milk and onion skins have
produced more buds which are healthier,
plumper, and stronger.
[Music]
The combination of nutrients from onion
skins and milk helps the orchid develop
strong buds, ensuring they will bloom
evenly and last longer.
The buds are not only plentiful uh but
also plump, showing that the orchid is
healthy and wellnourished, ready to
develop into beautiful flowers.
Multiple branches growing on the same
flower stem is a fantastic result of
using the natural fertilizer made from
milk and onion skins.
This fertilizer provides essential
nutrients that help the orchid grow
vigorously, stimulating a uniform bloom.
And when the plant receives enough
nutrients, it will develop multiple
flower branches on the same stem,
creating a beautiful and dense bouquet
that adds more charm to your garden.
I hope this video will be very helpful
for you in taking care of orchids at
home.
With these simple yet effective tips and
tricks, you'll be able to create the
best conditions for your orchid to grow
healthy and bloom beautifully.
I wish you success in caring for and
nurturing your beloved orchids.
Welcome to the happiness garden, where
every green leaf and every flower tells
its own story. This is not just a
garden, but also a space that brings
peace, joy, and inspiration to those who
love nature.
In this video, I will guide you on how
to revive weak orchids with yellowing or
wilting leaves using aloe vera. Because
inside the aloe vera leaf, there is a
natural gel rich in nutrients that helps
stimulate strong root growth and makes
the wrinkled leaves quickly become firm
and smooth again.
[Music]
You just need to take a small aloe vera
leaf then then cut it into pieces to
prepare a wonderful natural fertilizer
for your orchids.
Next, take two eggshells because
eggshells contain a lot of organic
calcium. When combined with aloe vera
leaves, they will create a natural
source of nutrients that helps orchids
grow healthier from roots to leaves.
[Music]
Eggshells need to be dried, then cleaned
to remove dirt, and only then added
together with the aloe vera leaves,
preparing for the step of grinding the
mixture.
Eggshells
need to be dried, then cleaned to remove
dirt and only then added together with
the aloe vera leaves. Preparing for the
step of grinding the mixture.
[Music]
Please comment and let me know which
country you are watching this video
from. It's wonderful that we can chat
together from all around the world.
[Music]
after blending. Strain out the residue,
keeping only the clear solution so that
the orchids can absorb it more easily.
[Music]
Add more water to make about 3 L of
solution. And this is the natural
fertilizer mixture from aloe vera and
eggshells.
[Music]
On my channel, there are currently
narrations available in 20 different
languages. Please go to the settings to
choose the language that suits you.
If you haven't subscribed yet, please
click the subscribe button to support me
and not miss any orchid care tips. It's
wonderful to have you along on this
journey.
[Music]
After mixing, use a soft cloth soaked in
the aloe vera and eggshell mixture. Then
gently wipe both the upper and lower
sides of the leaves. This method is
especially effective for leaves that are
wrinkled from lack of water or wilting.
[Music]
Aloe vera gel contains many essential
vitamins and minerals for the plant. At
the same time, it also has good moisture
retention, helping wilted leaves quickly
regain their vitality.
You can do this every 2 days. If
maintained regularly, the orchid leaves
will always stay green and healthy while
also reducing the attack of fungi and
insects.
[Music]
The second method is to use this aloe
vera and eggshell mixture to water
directly onto the roots and growing
medium, helping the plant absorb
nutrients naturally and effectively.
For orchids with wrinkled leaves due to
wilting, you just need to water the
plant with the aloe vera solution about
once a week. This method will provide
sufficient vitamins and minerals through
the roots while also acting as a natural
fertilizer that helps the root system
recover quickly.
For orchids that are growing normally,
you only need to water them with aloe
vera about once every 2 weeks. That is
enough for the plant to absorb nutrients
without the risk of excess.
[Music]
The third method is to put the mixture
into a spray bottle and mist it onto
wilted orchids about every 2 to 3 days.
This method works like folure feeding,
helping the plant absorb nutrients
directly and recover faster.
[Music]
For healthy orchids, you only need to
spray this mixture about once every two
weeks. This simple method will help
orchids grow better and keep the flowers
fresh longer with stronger stems.
[Music]
Now let's take a look at the results
after 2 weeks.
You can see a little caterpillar on this
leaf, which shows that the new leaf has
become tender and soft, making it a
favorite spot for the caterpillar to
stay.
I gently guided the caterpillar to
another spot so it would not continue
damaging my orchid.
[Music]
You can see that my wilted orchid has
started to grow many new roots. These
new roots will help the plant absorb
more nutrients and water, allowing the
wilted leaves to quickly regain their
vitality.
[Music]
These new roots will help the orchid
absorb nutrients and water more
effectively, thereby restoring vitality
to the leaves and the entire plant.
[Music]
Therefore, roots are often referred to
as the heart of the orchid because they
play an important role in nourishing and
sustaining the vitality of the entire
plant.
[Music]
Therefore, to help orchids grow well, we
need to focus on caring for the roots
first, ensuring they are healthy to
nourish the entire plant.
[Music]
When the roots are healthy, they will
absorb nutrients efficiently, thereby
nourishing the plant and giving us
vibrant flowers.
And when the flowers bloom, they are not
only beautiful, but also fragrant,
bringing joy and relaxation to everyone
around.
I hope this video will be very useful
for you, helping you care for and revive
orchids at home effectively and easily.
If you find this video meaningful, don't
forget to hit like and share so that
more people can learn how to care for
orchids.