[Music]
welcome to my channel
rice is a popular and very effective
source of organic fertilizer for plants
so today I will show you two ways to
make orchid fertilizer from
[Music]
Rice first
way use three spoons to eat rice
[Music]
grind rice into
powder please comment to me which
country you're watching the video from
it's great that we can chat together
from all over the
[Music]
world uh if you haven't subscribed to
the channel yet please click the subs
the Subscribe button to support me and
not miss any Orchid growing
[Music]
tips add 1 liter of boiled water
close the lid and wait for it to cool
[Music]
filter out
residue add 2 L of water
[Music]
now use this water to water the
Orchid rice contains many nutrients such
as potassium phosphor and protein uh
which are essential nutrients for the
growth of
[Music]
orchids using rice as fertilizer helps
provide these nutrients for your orchid
garden helps plants grow healthy
enhances resistance to pests and
diseases
[Music]
rice is a food source for beneficial
bacteria and microorganisms in Orchid
growing
media using rice as fertilizer enhances
the activity of this microflora in the
Orchid growing medium thereby helping
the Orchid absorb nutrients
better do this once a month will help
orchids grow healthy
[Music]
and of course it also blooms a
lot the microflora in the Orchid growing
medium helps to protect the roots from
rot when Roots grow they will absorb
nutrients to make flowers more beautiful
so flowers bloom long
[Music]
regular care in this way the leaves are
also provided with enough nutrients so
they grow very green
[Music]
second
way when we cook we usually wash the
rice
and every time you cook rice don't rush
to throw away this rice
water please filter this rice
[Music]
water wait for it to settle
down after settling we filter 100 mm of
clear water
[Music]
above add 200 mm plain
water put this rice water in a spray
bottle
[Music]
uh use this water to spray evenly on the
surface of the orchid
leaves vitamin B1 in rice water helps
stimulate the conversion of nutrients
especially harmful substances such as
manganese iron and copper into a more
easily absorbed
form vitamin B1 helps strengthen the
immune system of orchids helps plants
resist attack by pests and other
environmental
[Music]
agents for the rice water that settles
below I filter out the scum then add 2 L
of water
[Music]
and I use this water to water my orchids
to help stimulate rooting and provide
good nutrition for all types of
plants do this once a month for your
orchid in addition you need to combine
the use of other organic fertilizers to
help the Orchid receive full nutrients
[Music]
with this care method you can see that
my orchid has a very strong and healthy
root
[Music]
system this helps the Orchid absorb
nutrients and water more efficiently
from promoting vigorous growth and
beautiful blooms in the next flowering
cycle the flowers will bloom more
vibrantly with larger petals and richer
colors lasting longer and displaying
their full
[Music]
Beauty thank you for watching the video
goodbye and see you in the next ones
[Music]
welcome to my
Channel today I share with you an
amazing organic fertilizer and and
anyone can do it
easily just one to two ripe bananas and
the Orchid Garden will bloom all kinds
of
[Music]
flowers now I will revive this Orchid
with new
[Music]
flowers um you've seen this Orchid lose
all its flowers leaving only withered
branches
and here are the withered orchids that
have been revived with lots of new
flowers step one
[Music]
cut off the
withers apply toothpaste on the cut
apply toothpaste on the cut
[Music]
don't throw away banana peels when
eating bananas
[Music]
don't throw away banana peels when
eating
[Music]
bananas clip the banana peel to to the
place where the flower buds can
[Music]
grow and note to remove after 6
hours this helps to create the right
moisture provide essential nutrients and
stimulate flour sprouts
[Music]
do this once a
week step
two use a banana peel to wipe the top
and bottom of the leaves this helps
eliminate insects fungi bacteria hiding
on orchid leaves and at the same time
provides a part of nutrients through the
leaves for orchids
[Music]
this method also helps the orchid plant
to be protected and not be affected by
yellowing or rotten
[Music]
leaves after wiping you will see green
leaves orchids will photo synthesize
eyes better to increase
[Music]
resistance step
three 1 liter of water
[Music]
leave in a cool and dark place for one
[Applause]
[Music]
day after one
day banana juice is darker
[Music]
use this absorbent
cotton clip a cotton ball where the
flower buds can
grow and note to remove after 6
hours uh this helps to to create the
right moisture provide essential
nutrients and stimulate flour
Sprouts do this once a week
[Music]
step
four normally after 3 to 4 weeks flower
buds will be formed and develop like
this um with a flower Sprout this big
there's no need to sandwich banana peels
with cotton balls
[Music]
you will be surprised how amazing this
is
[Music]
don't forget to subscribe to see my next
videos
[Music]
sty add water to make 2 lers water this
banana for orchids once every 2 to 3
weeks banana peel is rich in potassium
phosphorus and essential
vitamins we'll promote the growth of
orchid
roots in particular the potassium and
banana peel stimulates flowering very
[Music]
well in addition you need to combine
using other organic fertilizers for
orchids like manure made from soybeans
peas fish poop as I shared
[Music]
hope this sharing content will help you
in taking better care of orchids at
[Music]
home um if you find the video
interesting don't forget to like share
and subscribe to support my channel