Welcome to a peaceful little corner
where we grow love together and explore
the gentle beauty of nature. This is the
happiness garden. In this video, I will
continue to share a simple method that
helps even busy people care for orchids
easily. So, the plant stays healthy and
blooms all four seasons of the year.
If you also love orchids, don't forget
to hit the subscribe button to support
me. Let's explore helpful tips together
to make growing orchids fun and easy.
It's truly wonderful to have you along
on this journey.
[Music]
Uh, this is an orchid with a mushy
rotten leaf that I bought as a clearance
item from a small local flower shop.
The price was only $2, but I believe
that with a little love and proper care,
the plant still has a chance to recover
and bloom beautifully.
First, we need to remove the rotten part
of the leaf to prevent the disease from
spreading.
But before pruning, don't forget to
sterilize your tools with 90% alcohol to
ensure the plant's safety and prevent
the infection from spreading to other
parts.
The rotten part of the leaf often
harbors many fungal pathogens. If not
treated promptly, they will quickly
spread to other parts, especially in hot
and humid weather conditions, the ideal
environment for pathogens to thrive.
[Music]
After treating the leaf, the next step
is to check the roots and the growing
medium.
[Music]
Moss growing medium is often chosen by
orchid farms because of its good
moisture retention and lightweight,
which helps the plant grow easily during
the early stages.
However, if used for a long time without
being replaced, moss can easily become
infected with fungi or retain too much
water, which may lead to root rot.
And as you can see, the growing medium
has been infected with white mold, a
sign that the environment is no longer
clean and safe for the plant. If left as
is, the orchid roots will be easily
damaged and weaken quickly.
[Music]
In addition to the English voiceover, we
have now created versions in French,
German, Italian, Spanish, Portuguese,
Japanese, Hindi, Dutch, Polish, Korean,
and Indonesian to help you listen and
understand the content more easily.
To listen in your preferred language,
open the video and click on settings,
the gear icon, to select the appropriate
audio language.
Leave a comment and let me know which
country you're watching the video from.
It's wonderful that we can connect and
chat from all around the world.
Next, gently trim away any roots that
are hollow or damaged.
Damaged roots are often breeding grounds
for mold and bacteria. If not removed,
they can easily spread to healthy roots
and cause the plant to weaken quickly.
By removing the damaged roots, the plant
no longer has to carry the burden of
nonfunctional parts, allowing it to
focus its energy on nourishing healthy
roots, and stimulating new root growth.
Cleaning the roots helps improve air
flow in the pot, reduces water logging,
and creates ideal conditions for the
plant to recover after repotting.
[Music]
After trimming the damaged roots, rinse
the entire plant thoroughly under
running water.
This helps remove any remaining residue,
dirt, and pathogens from the roots and
stem.
After rinsing, place the plant in a well
ventilated area overnight to let the
cuts dry and prevent fungal infection
when repotting.
To make a fertilizer that helps
stimulate orchid recovery and growth, I
use a simple and easy to find
ingredient, ginger.
Take about 10 grams of ginger,
preferably the part with sprouts, as it
contains a high amount of oxin, a
natural substance that stimulates
growth, especially effective in
promoting fast and healthy development
of young roots.
After slicing it thinly, place the
prepared ginger into a clean bottle.
Using a clean bottle helps ensure that
the solution remains free from
contamination during fermentation and
future use.
Next, add about 500 ml of warm water
into the bottle.
Warm water will help speed up the
fermentation process, allowing the
nutrients in the ginger to be released
more effectively, making it easier for
the plant to absorb when used.
[Music]
The next ingredient is molasses.
This natural ingredient supports the
fermentation process by promoting the
growth of beneficial microorganisms
while also providing additional
nutrients to the orchid during its
recovery phase.
Just one teaspoon of molasses is enough.
It's a small amount, but sufficient to
stimulate fermentation and nourish the
beneficial microorganisms in the
solution.
Then stir the mixture well to fully
dissolve the ginger and molasses in the
larm water, helping the fermentation
process occur more evenly and
effectively.
Close
the bottle tightly, then place it in a
cool, wellventilated area away from
direct sunlight. After about 3 weeks,
you'll have a natural fertilizer made
from ginger, commonly known as GE, which
is excellent for helping orchids recover
and grow healthily.
And this is the bottle of ginger GE I
prepared 3 weeks ago. After the
fermentation period, the solution has
fully fermented with a mild distinctive
ginger aroma and is now ready to use for
the orchids.
Take 30 ml of ginger GE to dilute and
use as fertilizer for the orchids.
[Music]
Dilute 30 mm of ginger GE with one liter
of clean water. This is a safe and
effective ratio providing enough
nutrients for the plant without harming
the young roots.
After being left overnight, the cuts on
the roots have dried. At this point,
gently place the orchid roots into a
clean cup to prepare for soaking in the
diluted ginger GE solution.
[Music]
Pour the diluted ginger GE solution into
the cup, covering the roots, and soak
for about 20 minutes.
[Music]
This is an important step to disinfect,
stimulate root recovery, and prepare the
plant for repotting.
While waiting for the roots to soak, you
can use a soft cloth dipped in the
solution to gently wipe both the upper
and lower surfaces of the leaves.
Wiping the leaves helps remove dust and
bacteria from the surface, allowing the
leaves to breathe better and absorb
light more efficiently, an important
factor in helping the plant grow strong
and healthy.
Ginger has natural antibacterial
properties. So, wiping the leaves with
the ginger GE solution helps prevent the
invasion of fungi and bacteria,
protecting the orchid leaves from
harmful environmental agents.
Besides cleaning, the solution also
provides nutrients that help the leaves
maintain their fresh green color and
natural shine, thereby enhancing
photosynthesis and aiding the plant's
faster recovery.
[Music]
While waiting for the roots to soak, I
make use of an empty plastic bottle to
recycle it into a semihydroponic orchid
pot.
This method not only makes it easier for
busy people to care for their plants,
but also helps protect the environment
by reducing plastic waste.
[Music]
I make small holes in the body of the
bottle to serve as drainage holes. This
helps keep the roots well ventilated and
reduces the risk of water logging and
rot.
[Music]
I use a piece of floral foam to cover
the bottom of the pot. This helps
prevent the growing medium from falling
out, keeps the roots stable, and allows
water to drain more evenly during care.
Watch carefully and follow each step
with me. Everything is simple and easy
to do at home.
[Music]
The growing medium I chose is finely
chopped pine bark that has been
carefully treated and sterilized.
This type of medium is airy, drains
well, and is very safe for orchid roots,
making it especially suitable for the
semi-hydroponic method.
I use a plasticcoated steel rod as a
support stake to secure the orchid after
planting.
Keeping the plant upright helps the
roots attach more quickly to the growing
medium and promotes more stable
development.
[Music]
After soaking for about 20 minutes,
gently take the orchid out and place it
into the prepared pot.
At this point, the roots have been
disinfected and are ready to adapt to
the new growing medium.
[Music]
When adding the growing medium to the
pot, do it gently and distribute it
evenly around the roots. Avoid packing
it too tightly to maintain air flow,
allowing the roots to breathe easily and
grow healthily.
[Music]
Um, after planting, place the orchid pot
in a cool, well ventilated area away
from direct sunlight and avoid watering
for the next 3 days.
Don't worry about the orchid drying out,
as orchids are naturally drought
tolerant, but can be easily damaged if
overwatered.
Temporarily stopping watering for a few
days after repotting allows the cut huts
on the roots to dry completely, reducing
the risk of fungal infection and root
rot.
After 3 days, you can start watering the
orchid.
Water gently around the base so the
roots can gradually adjust to the
moisture. Avoid overwatering as it may
cause water shock or rot the young
roots.
[Music]
Um you can see that the water level
reaches just this point uh enough to
provide moisture to the lower roots
without soaking the upper ones. This is
an important principle in the
semihydroponic method of growing
orchids.
With this growing method, we don't need
to water frequently, yet the plant still
maintains stable moisture. This helps
the roots develop well, reduces the risk
of root rot, and is especially suitable
for busy people.
After that, place the orchid pot in a
spot with gentle sunlight and good air
circulation.
About 1 to two weeks later, once the
roots have settled into the medium, you
can start fertilizing to nourish the
orchid grown using the semihydroponic
method.
[Music]
About 10 days after planting, once the
roots have stabilized and started
attaching to the growing medium, we can
begin fertilizing the orchid. This is
the right time to provide nutrients to
help the plant recover quickly and grow
more vigorously.
Uh each time you fertilize, you can also
change the water in the orchid pot. This
helps remove any residue, keeps the
growing environment clean, and provides
the best conditions for the roots to
absorb nutrients effectively.
[Music]
Method one, I use diluted natural ginger
GE fertilizer and put it into a spray
bottle. This method is very convenient
for spraying directly onto the leaves
and roots, helping the plant absorb
nutrients gently and effectively.
[Music]
Then gently spray the solution over the
entire orchid from the leaves, stem, and
roots to the growing medium. This allows
the plant to absorb nutrients through
multiple parts while also naturally
boosting its disease resistance.
[Music]
Method two, use the diluted ginger GE
solution to water directly onto the
roots and growing medium.
This method delivers nutrients more
deeply, nourishing the roots from within
and supporting the plant's overall
recovery.
Fertilizing the orchid once or twice a
month is enough. Using the right amount
at the right time will help the plant
grow strong and healthy without the risk
of nutrient overload.
After fertilizing, let the excess
solution drain into the tray below.
Once the excess water has fully drained,
place the orchid pot back into the
semihydroponic setup to prevent root rot
and help the plant absorb nutrients more
effectively.
While waiting, use a soft cloth to
gently absorb any water trapped on the
leaf surfaces and in the leaf crevices.
This helps prevent fungal growth and
keeps the leaves dry and clean.
[Music]
After the excess fertilizer solution has
drained, place the orchid pot into the
semihydroponic tray and put it in a spot
with gentle sunlight. This helps the
plant receive enough light without harsh
exposure, supporting healthy growth.
[Music]
And here is the result. After 6 weeks of
caring for and restoring the orchid with
the rotten leaf,
you can see that the plant has recovered
well with fresh green leaves and healthy
root growth. A testament to the love and
patience in every step of care.
Many new roots have sprouted, signaling
that the orchid is recovering strongly
and growing healthily day by day.
[Music]
When the roots are healthy, the orchid
absorbs water and nutrients more
efficiently, leading to vigorous growth.
In the coming time, the plant will
produce lush green leaves and bloom
brilliantly, bringing new life to your
garden.
That's why roots are often compared to
the heart of the orchid. Roots not only
transport water and nutrients, but also
play a crucial role in maintaining the
plant's vitality and sustainable growth.
Uh, what do you think about how I
restored this orchid with a rotten leaf?
Don't hesitate to leave a comment and
share your thoughts. I'm eager to hear
your feedback and experiences.
And here is the orchid I planted using
the semihydroponic method. You can see
the plant has fully recovered and is
blooming brilliantly, bringing joy and
satisfaction after the patient care
process.
Though the orchid is small, its roots
have grown very strong.
The petals are soft, fully open, and
vibrant in color, creating an elegant
and lively beauty for the entire pot.
[Music]
This simple growing method is perfect
for busy people or beginners caring for
orchids, helping you easily keep the
plant healthy and blooming regularly.
[Music]
Remember, every orchid you care for is
not just a plant, but a result of love,
patience, and passion.
No matter the difficulties or setbacks,
don't give up because it's the small
daily efforts that create great
miracles, turning your garden into a
place full of life and happiness.
[Music]
I hope you'll enjoy this video. If you
find it helpful, don't forget to like
and subscribe to the channel so you
won't miss upcoming tips on caring for
orchids naturally and easily.
Thank you for watching today's video.
Wishing you many enjoyable experiences
and success in caring for your orchids.
See you in the next videos.
[Music]