hello
everyone to give you more options for
making natural fertilizers to care for
orchids at home helping your plants grow
healthy and Bloom beautifully today I'll
continue sharing a new fertilizer making
method that's super simple and
[Music]
effective let's explore
together this this is the Orchid I
bought which was grown in an industrial
orchid garden and it has now finished
[Music]
blooming if you don't know how to care
for it the Orchid after blooming may
become weak its leaves could turn yellow
Roots May dry out or rot and it will be
very difficult for the plant to bloom
[Music]
again remove all the damaged
leaves because damaged orchid leaves can
Harbor pests mold and bacteria
negatively affecting the plant's health
and hindering its new
growth and remove all the damaged roots
[Music]
um because damaged Orchid Roots can
cause rot to spread to healthy Roots
making it difficult for the plant to
absorb water and nutrients which weakens
the plant and hinders its
growth if you haven't subscribed to the
channel yet please click the Subscribe
button to support me and not miss any
Orchid growing tips
[Music]
um in this spot there's still a dorant
flower Bud that hasn't grown into a
bloom yet so I'll keep it so it can
continue to develop and flower
[Music]
uh at the spots where the flower Spikes
have finished blooming they won't bloom
again so they should be discarded
[Music]
this is cinnamon powder which has
antibacterial and antiseptic
effects then take cinnamon powder and
sprinkle it on the cut to help it heal
faster
please comment to me which country you
are watching the video
from it's great that we can chat
together from all over the
[Music]
world then leave it overnight without
watering to let the cut heal
completely then I use potatoes as
natural ferti izer for
[Music]
orchids take about 10
G then add about five dry
eggshells eggshells when used as natural
fertilizer for orchids provide calcium
improve soil structure enhance root
health and help the Orchid grow strong
and resist
diseases add 300 mm of water and puree
the whole
thing which country are you watching
videos from please comment for me
um it's nice that we can chat together
from all over the
[Music]
world then leave overnight
after one
night stir to dissolve the nutrients in
the water
then strain to get this water
[Music]
add 1 liter of
water add 1 liter of water step one use
a soft cloth to soak up this liquid
ferti solution and gently wipe the
leaves clean both the top and bottom
sides of the leaves
thoroughly wiping orchid leaves with a
liquid fertilizer solution made from
potatoes and eggshells helps provide
direct nutrients to the leaves
strengthen the orchid's health stimulate
photosynthesis and make the leaves
Greener and
[Music]
healthier and it also helps remove dirt
mold and impurities on the surface of
the leaves allowing the plant to easily
absorb light and perform photosynthesis
in addition to the English voiceover we
have now created voiceovers in French
German Italian Spanish and Portuguese to
help you listen to and understand the
video content more
easily how to select the audio language
on YouTube one uh open the video and
click on settings the gear icon two
select subtitles CC three click on audio
and choose the language you want English
France Deutch Italiano espanol or
Portuguese then use a soft cloth to wrap
the dormant flower bud
[Music]
step two put the solution into a spray
bottle and spray it on the
[Music]
Orchid you spray skills above and below
the leaves
this provides additional nutrients to
the plant enhances Leaf growth
stimulates flowering and helps the
Orchid grow healthy resist pests and
improve its overall
resistance then spray this water here to
awaken the dormant flower Bud helping it
bloom faster
[Music]
step three water the solution onto the
roots and the Orchid growing
[Music]
medium watering with a liquid fertilizer
made from potatoes and eggshells can
help stimulate plant growth including
both root and flower development
[Music]
soaking in this solution for about 20
minutes helps plant roots absorb water
and nutrients best
[Music]
after 20 minutes take the Orchid pot
out step four use a clean soft cloth to
gently wipe off the water droplets from
the leaf
axles avoid using rough cloths or
materials with stiff fibers that might
damage the
leaves wiping off excess water from the
leaf axles of orchids is an important
step in orchid care because stagnant
water on the leaves can lead to issues
like rot or
[Music]
mold remove the wrapper from the
sleeping
Bud do all four steps once a week with
this liquid fertilizer for your
orchids place it in a well- lit area so
the Orchid can photosynthesize and
metabolize
properly results after 1 month
the leaves will be greener and
[Music]
healthier The Roots grow very quickly
and many new root tips grow
in
[Music]
new Roots help the plant absorb water
and essential nutrients from the soil or
growing medium which is vital for
healthy plant development and
[Music]
blooming if the new roots are not strong
and healthy the plant will struggle to
supply nutrition and moisture to the
flower ing
[Music]
tissues when new roots are welldeveloped
the plant can adequately Supply the
necessary nutrients and moisture to
trigger the blooming process resulting
in larger more beautiful and
longer-lasting flowers
you can see that the sleeping bud has
awakened and grown into a new flower
Spike and
if now I'm planting it into a larger pot
so so the Orchid can Thrive better in
the outdoor
environment planting with pine bark
chips helps retain moisture well while
also draining quickly preventing the
orchid's roots from rotting
[Music]
then you take care of the Orchid like
other normal
orchids I hope you enjoy this video
don't forget to like share and subscribe
to the channel so you don't miss out on
helpful videos about orchid care
take care of your Orchids with all the
love and attention you have for nature
and you will be rewarded with stunning
vibrant flowers that light up your world
dispelling all worries and stress bring
you peace and endless
Joy thank you for supporting the channel
and I wish you peaceful moments and joy
with your beautiful orchids