Welcome to the garden of happiness where
every leaf and every flower tells a
story of life and joy. Here we explore
together the little wonders that nature
gives us and learn how to nurture
happiness with our own hands.
The topic of today's video is do this
once your orchid will never stop
growing.
And when you see the new roots
stretching out strongly, you'll feel the
true happiness that comes from caring
for orchids. With just a little love, a
little patience, and today's simple
secret, your orchid will become
healthier than ever.
And now, let's get started together to
make a special natural fertilizer that
helps orchids grow endlessly.
[Music]
To start making this natural fertilizer,
the first ingredient we need is onion.
You just need about 10 g of onion. This
is an important component that helps
stimulate root growth and strengthen
your orchid's resistance.
[Music]
Onion contains natural sulfur, a
valuable mineral that helps stimulate
strong root growth and protects the
plant from fungal diseases. That's why
when you use onion in your natural
fertilizer formula, you're giving your
orchid a source of energy that
strengthens its roots, keeps its leaves
green, and supports sustainable growth.
[Music]
After cutting the onion into small
pieces, put them all into a clean jar.
[Music]
The next ingredient is rice. You just
need to add about 3 teaspoons of rice. A
small amount, but incredibly effective.
Rice contains natural starch and vitamin
B, which help nourish the roots,
stimulate new shoots to grow, and boost
the overall vitality of your orchid.
[Music]
Then pour in about 500 ml of clean
water.
[Music]
Next, blend it thoroughly. This step
helps release all the nutrients from the
onion and rice, creating a smooth
mixture that's easy for your orchids to
absorb when you use it for their care.
Let me know in the comments which
country you're watching from. It's
wonderful that we can connect and chat
with each other from all around the
world.
[Music]
After blending, close the lid tightly
and let it sit overnight. The resting
time allows the natural nutrients from
the onion and rice to blend together,
creating a gentle yet highly energizing
organic fertilizer for your orchid.
The next morning, after the mixture has
been fermented overnight, gently stir it
so that all the nutrients are completely
dissolved in the water.
If you haven't subscribed yet, click the
subscribe button to support me and make
sure you don't miss any orchid growing
tips. It's wonderful to have you along
on this journey.
[Music]
Next, strain out the residue to obtain
the clear liquid. This step helps make
the solution smoother and purer,
preventing root blockage or residue
buildup in the growing medium when
watering your orchids.
[Music]
After straining, add another 500 ml of
clean water to the solution you've
obtained. This dilution makes the
mixture gentler and perfectly safe to
use directly on orchids while still
retaining all the essential nutrients.
[Music]
After straining, add another 500 ml of
clean water to the solution you've
obtained. This dilution makes the
mixture gentler and perfectly safe to
use directly on orchids while still
retaining all the essential nutrients.
[Music]
Wiping the leaves with the onion and
rice mixture naturally cleans the leaf
surface, removing dust, tiny insects,
and mold that may have accumulated over
time. When the leaves are clean, the
stamata open more easily, allowing the
plant to breathe better and maintain
daily freshness and health.
When the leaves are clean, the orchid
can absorb light more effectively,
allowing photosynthesis to occur more
vigorously. This helps the plant
synthesize energy better, promoting
balanced and vibrant growth of roots,
leaves, and flowers.
The solution made from onion and rice
also provides a direct source of
nutrients for the leaves. Natural
nutrients like vitamin B and minerals
are absorbed through the leaf epidermis,
nourishing the cells and helping the
leaves become darker green, thicker, and
shinier each day.
[Music]
This mixture also helps boost the
plant's natural resistance thanks to the
sulfur content in onions, which has
strong antifungal and antibacterial
properties. Regularly wiping the leaves
with this solution helps the orchid
avoid leaf diseases, especially in humid
environments.
[Music]
When the leaves are healthy and absorb
enough nutrients, the orchid will grow
more comprehensively. Roots grow strong,
new shoots develop quickly, and flowers
bloom more regularly. This is a simple
yet effective way to maintain freshness
and vitality for your orchid all year
round.
The second method, you can directly pour
this mixture onto the roots and growing
medium of your orchid.
In this way, the nutrients from onion
and rice penetrate deeply into the
roots, nourishing a strong root system
and enhancing the absorption of water
and minerals. Uh at the same time, the
growing medium becomes more
nutrient-rich, creating an ideal
environment for new roots to grow and
the orchid to thrive day by day.
[Music]
The mixture provides vitamin B,
minerals, and natural nutrients that are
absorbed directly by the roots, helping
them grow strong and healthy while
enhancing their ability to absorb water
and nutrients.
When watered, the growing medium becomes
more nutrient-rich, creating an ideal
environment for new roots to grow and
helping the orchid develop
comprehensively with healthy roots,
leaves, and flowers.
The third method, you can pour the
mixture into a spray bottle and gently
mist it onto the leaves, roots, or
growing medium.
[Music]
Uh, this method helps the solution
disperse evenly and absorb more quickly
into the plant parts while also
providing light humidity around the
leaves and roots. When using a spray
bottle, the orchid consistently absorbs
nutrients, resulting in glossy leaves,
strong roots, and effective stimulation
of new shoots.
When misted, the nutrients in the
mixture are absorbed directly by the
leaves, roots, and growing medium,
allowing the plant to quickly take in
vitamins, minerals, and starch. As a
result, the leaves the leaves become
glossy, the roots grow strong, and the
orchid develops more comprehensively.
Misting helps increase light humidity
around the plant, while the thin layer
of solution also helps prevent dust and
some fungal diseases, keeping the orchid
healthy and reducing stress caused by
dry conditions.
After watering, you can leave the pot
and soak it in this mixture for about 20
minutes, allowing the nutrients to
penetrate deeply into the roots and
growing medium, helping the plant absorb
the maximum nutrition.
[Music]
After soaking for about 20 minutes,
remember to take the orchid pot out of
the mixture. This helps prevent the
growing medium from staying too wet for
too long. while still retaining enough
nutrients absorbed by the roots.
If there is still water on the leaves
after watering or soaking, you should
use a dry cloth to absorb it. This small
but important step helps prevent fungal
diseases and leaf rot while keeping the
leaf surface dry, allowing the orchid to
absorb nutrients more effectively and
grow healthily.
[Music]
Then you should place the orchid pot in
a spot with gentle sunlight. The soft
light helps the leaves and roots dry
gradually while supporting efficient
photosynthesis.
This also helps the plant boost its
resistance, nurture new shoots and
roots, and ensure the orchid grows
healthy and sustainably.
[Music]
And here are the results after 3 weeks
of applying this method. You can see
that the leaves have become glossy,
plump, and firm, reflecting good health
and effective nourishment from the
fermented onion and rice mixture.
Healthy leaves not only bring a fresh
beauty, but also serve as a clear sign
that the orchid is being properly cared
for. They become thicker, shinier, and
full of vitality, ready to support new
root growth and flower buds in the
coming weeks.
[Music]
Not only the leaves but the roots of the
plant have also become dense and strong.
[Music]
The new roots are bright white and grow
evenly throughout the growing medium,
showing that the orchid is absorbing
nutrients fully and is ready for
vigorous growth in the coming period.
[Music]
These healthy roots not only help the
plant absorb water and nutrients more
efficiently, but also increase its grip
on the growing medium, keeping the
orchid stable and secure.
Um, when the roots grow vigorously, they
also help the orchid regulate moisture
and metabolize more efficiently,
creating favorable conditions for the
entire plant's growth. A strong root
system also means the plant can recover
better after repotting or or
environmental stress, ensuring the
orchid remains lush and full of
vitality.
[Music]
Healthy roots are also an important
energy reserve for the orchid, helping
sustain life during periods of drought
or low nutrients. They also support the
development of new shoots and flower
buds, ensuring the plant is always ready
for the next vibrant blooming season.
With a dense and healthy root system,
the orchid is ready for comprehensive
and sustainable growth. This solid
foundation helps the plant bloom
beautifully, maintain glossy green
leaves, and grow vigorously all year
round, clearly demonstrating the
effectiveness of the natural care method
we just applied.
[Music]
Uh apart from healthy leaves and roots,
after about 1 month, you will see small
delicate flower buds beginning to
appear. They are a clear sign that the
orchid is preparing for a new flowering
season, showcasing its vibrant vitality
and the excellent nourishment from the
natural fertilizer method we just
applied.
When the flower buds become large and
plump like this, they signal that the
orchid is about enter full bloom. At
this stage, careful care, maintaining
gentle light and appropriate humidity
will help the flowers open evenly,
retain their color, and stay vibrant for
a long time, bringing a brilliant beauty
to the entire plant.
[Music]
When the flower buds open, you will see
vibrant and fresh blossoms adorning the
orchid. The flowers not only bring
stunning beauty but also serve as clear
evidence of the plant's health and
comprehensive growth resulting from the
care with natural fertilizer made from
fermented onion and rice.
[Music]
The newly bloomed flowers not only shine
brightly but also emit a gentle
fragrance brightening the surrounding
space. They are also a sign that the
orchid is at its most vigorous stage,
ready to continue producing new roots
and shoots and preparing for the next
flowering seasons, creating a
sustainable growth cycle.
[Music]
I hope you enjoy this video. If you find
it helpful, don't forget to like and
subscribe so you won't miss future tips
on caring for orchids naturally and
easily, keeping your plants healthy and
blooming beautifully all year round.
[Music]