Welcome to my
channel. If you have an orchid after
flowering like this, uh don't rush to
throw it
[Music]
away. Please pay attention and follow me
to recover and help the orchids bloom
again.
[Music]
Remove old growing medium.
Uh, when the moss is green like this, it
proves that the humidity in the orchid
pot is very suitable. Uh, so I only
removed part of the old substrate so the
roots could grow faster.
[Music]
If the growing medium is dark green or
viscous, it means the humidity is too
high, easily rotting the orchid roots.
[Music]
If you haven't subscribed to the channel
yet, please click the subscribe button
to support me and don't miss any orchid
growing tips. Truly great
[Music]
company. Please comment to me which
country you are watching the video from.
It's great that we can chat together
from all over the world.
[Music]
Cut off all damaged
roots. In addition to the English dub,
we've now created dubs in French,
German, Italian, Spanish, Portuguese,
Japanese, Hindi, and Indonesian to help
you hear and understand the content more
easily.
[Music]
Cutting off wilted flower branches will
help the orchid quickly recover and
quickly produce new flower
[Music]
branches. These black spots are caused
by fungal growth that rots the roots.
[Music]
When there is too much moisture, fungi
will grow and cause root rot.
[Music]
Upon closer inspection, I saw fungal
disease thriving inside the substrate.
[Music]
Um therefore it is necessary to remove
all old planting material so that the
fungus does not spread further.
[Music]
If you encounter any difficulties during
the orchid growing process, don't
hesitate to comment. I am always ready
to support you so you can grow healthy
orchids and bloom lots of flowers.
[Music]
Then rinse with water helps eliminate
some fungal diseases.
[Music]
Then leave in a cool place for 2 hours
to drain.
Next, make fertilizer for
orchids. Take one spoon of
[Music]
oatmeal. Add 500 ml boiled water, about
2 cups.
Uh, wait until it cools before using it
as
[Music]
fertilizer. Take one spoon of dry yeast.
Adding two cups of warm water, about 500
milliliters of warm water, helps the
yeast grow
[Music]
better. Be careful not to use hot water
because it will kill the microorganisms
in the
[Music]
yeast. Wait 1 hour for the yeast to
develop before using it as fertilizer.
One hour later.
[Music]
Filter the oatmeal solution.
Uh, mix the yeast solution with the
oatmeal
[Music]
solution. Add one liter of room
temperature water, about four cups.
[Music]
Then soak the orchid roots in this
solution for 30 minutes.
[Music]
[Applause]
Beneficial microorganisms in the yeast
will protect the roots from
rot. And vitamins and minerals in oats
help stimulate rapid
[Music]
rooting. The remaining solution is used
to fertilize other orchids in the
garden.
This fertilizer helps stimulate root
growth. A strong root system will help
orchids absorb nutrients best.
[Music]
Um, you can see that my orchid pots have
developed very healthy roots.
[Music]
This fertilizer also contains a large
amount of natural potassium to help
bloom more and flowers last
longer. Apply this liquid fertilizer to
orchids every 2 weeks for healthy
growth.
[Music]
Uh after soaking for 30 minutes, take
the orchid out and plant it in a new
pot.
[Music]
Um, I plant with pine bark, which helps
drain water quickly and has appropriate
moisture so it doesn't cause root rot.
[Music]
After planting, apply this liquid
fertilizer to the orchids every 2 weeks.
[Music]
Place the orchid pot in a place with
light sunlight so that the orchid can
photosynthesize and the orchid It will
grow faster.
[Music]
On weekdays when the foundation is dry,
you just need to spray mist to keep it
moist or watering to keep the substrate
moist will help the roots take root
[Music]
quickly. When growing orchids, always
follow the principle of the substrate is
moist but not wet, which will be good
for your
[Music]
orchids. Results after 1
month. After only one month, orchid
roots have grown many and healthy.
[Music]
leaves become
stronger. These new roots will help the
orchid absorb nutrients and water best.
[Music]
Um, when the leaves and roots grow
healthy like this, the orchid will
quickly produce new flower branches.
[Music]
Uh, hope the video will help you a lot.
If you find it interesting, please like,
share, and subscribe to support my
[Music]
channel. Thank you for watching the
video. Wish you luck and see you in the
next videos.
[Music]
Hello
everyone. Today we will discover how to
create a natural fertilizer that will
revitalize and promote the growth of all
[Music]
orchids. Uh comprehensive development
from roots, stems, leaves, and orchids.
[Music]
Let's get
started. Do you have chamomile and
lemongrass
tea? Chrysanthemums contain many
vitamins and minerals providing a rich
source of nutrition for orchids.
[Music]
The ingredients in chrosanthemum help
strengthen the plant's resistance and
prevent
diseases. Nutrition from chrosanthemums
also promotes orchids to flower more and
more
[Music]
beautifully. Take three packs of
chrysanthemum and lemongrass tea and put
them in a jar.
Then add one liter of boiled
[Music]
water. Then close the lid and wait for
the water to cool.
[Music]
Next, I need garlic to make fertilizer
for orchids.
[Music]
Take three cloves of garlic and cut them
into small
[Music]
slices. Garlic contains allisonin, a
compound with antibacterial and
antifungal properties that helps protect
orchids from common diseases.
Nutrition from garlic helps improve
plants resistance, helping them better
cope with environmental conditions and
pests.
[Music]
Then put it in the
jar and add one liter of
water. Which country are you watching
videos from? Please comment
me. It's great that we can chat together
from all over the world.
Wait 2 hours for nutrients to dissolve
in water before using as
[Music]
fertilizer. After two
hours, filter the garlic water.
[Music]
method
one. Use a soft cotton to soak the
garlic water and thoroughly wipe the top
and bottom of the
leaves. Garlic juice contains allisonin
which helps kill harmful bacteria and
fungi protecting leaves from disease.
Wiping leaves helps remove dirt,
creating conditions for leaves to
photosynthesize more
effectively. Um, the smell of garlic
helps repel insects and pests,
protecting plants from attack.
Using garlic water helps improve the
plant's natural resistance, making
orchids healthier.
Therefore, wiping orchid leaves with
garlic water is a natural and effective
way to care for and protect the
plant. Which country are you watching
videos from? Please comment and let me
know.
Um, it's nice that we can chat together
from all over the
world. Um, do this one to two times a
month to protect your orchids.
[Music]
after the water cools. Mix the two types
of water
together. Method
two, water the orchid roots with this
liquid fertilizer.
Allisonin in garlic helps kill fungi and
bacteria harmful to
roots. Garlic strengthens plants
resistance, helping roots grow
healthily.
Compounds in garlic promote root growth,
helping plants absorb nutrients
better. Chrysanthemum and lemongrass tea
contain many vitamins and minerals
necessary for root
growth.
[Music]
Essential oils from lemongrass and
compounds in chrysanthemum help protect
plants from
diseases. The scent from lemongrass
creates a pleasant environment for the
plant.
[Music]
After watering, soak the orchid pot in
this water for about 20 minutes to let
the roots absorb nutrients.
[Music]
method
three. Or you can also put this water in
a spray bottle.
Then spray the entire orchid.
Allisonin and garlic and compounds in
chrosanthemum help protect plants from
diseases. Nutritious ingredients help
plants grow healthily and resist stress.
[Music]
The essential oil in lemongrass has the
effect of repelling insects and
protecting plants from
pests. Spraying both leaves and orchid
roots is good.
Spraying both leaves and orchid roots is
good. But you should not spray this
water on flowers.
[Music]
Water wets flower petals, creating
conditions for fungi and bacteria to
grow, leading to flower
[Music]
rot. After soaking for 20 minutes, take
the orchid pot out and place it in a
place with lots of scattered
light. Scattered light provides enough
energy for photosynthesis without
causing leaf burn, helping plants absorb
nutrients better.
[Music]
results after 3 weeks of caring for
orchids with this liquid
fertilizer. Green leaves are shiny and
sturdy.
[Music]
This green color is due to the orchid
photosynthesizing a lot of light. So
it's very
[Music]
hard. Many new roots grow.
Uh, new roots also play an important
role in maintaining moisture for the
plant, preventing it from drying out.
[Music]
The the new roots help the orchid firmly
adhere to the substrate or surface,
keeping the plant from falling over.
New roots also create relationships with
microorganisms in the soil, helping the
plant absorb nutrients better.
[Music]
Uh, new root growth is often a sign that
the plant is growing healthily and is
ready for
flowering. Uh, new roots help the plant
adapt to its living environment,
searching for moisture and nutrients in
different areas.
[Music]
Care for your orchids with passion and
devotion to
nature. You will receive brilliant
flowers that are the result of your own
loving hands.
[Music]
Let each flower become a symbol of your
care and dedication.
Thank you for taking the time to watch
this video. If you find the information
useful, then don't forget to click the
subscribe button and turn on
notifications so you don't miss the next
[Music]
videos. Please support our channel by
sharing and leaving your comments below
the video.
Your support is the greatest motivation
for us to continue to bring more
interesting knowledge. Thanks a lot.