Hello everyone, welcome to the happiness
garden
channel. In today's video, we will
explore how to take care of orchids from
the small stage all the way to full
bloom using only natural
fertilizers. If you love plants and want
to grow healthy, beautiful orchids,
don't miss the simple yet effective tips
and techniques in this video.
Let's get
started. This is a baby orchid that I
previously propagated from a Phelinopsis
orchid
branch. Cut off damaged roots and
leaves.
[Music]
Cutting off damaged roots helps remove
rotting, non-developing roots, prevents
the spread of diseases, and stimulates
the growth of new healthy
[Music]
roots. Cutting off damaged leaves helps
prevent the spread of diseases, reduces
the risk of infection, and allows the
plant to focus its energy on healthy
parts.
[Music]
Then plant the orchid in a new pot so
the orchid grows
faster. The bottom of the pot is planted
with chopped pine bark to help drain
water easily.
Uh this prevents the roots from becoming
water
logged. Please comment to me which
country you're watching the video from.
It's great that we can chat together
from all over the world.
[Music]
Then spread a layer of moss on the
surface of the pot to help retain
moisture better.
[Music]
Moss helps beneficial microorganisms
grow to protect roots from
[Music]
rot. Then we make natural fertilizer for
this orchid.
[Music]
To make this fertilizer, I need ripe
bananas.
[Music]
Take ripe banana peel and cut it into
small
pieces. Uh banana peels are a source of
potassium, phosphorus, and essential
minerals helping to stimulate root
growth and enhance the orchid's
flowering ability.
Then put the banana peel into the
jar. Next, I need
coffee. Take three teaspoons.
[Music]
Then add one liter of boiling
water.
Close the lid and wait for the water to
[Music]
cool. After the water cools, stir well
so that the nutrients are completely
dissolved in the water.
[Music]
Then filter out the residue.
Step
one, use this water to thoroughly wipe
the top and bottom of the leaves.
leaves. Wiping orchid leaves with banana
peel water provides nutrients,
stimulates photosynthesis, and keeps the
leaves vibrant.
[Music]
Put this water in a spray bottle and
spray the entire
[Music]
orchid. Spraying banana peel water
provides potassium, phosphorus, and
minerals, stimulating root growth and
flowering in orchids.
Step
three, water this water into the orchid
pot. Watering with banana peel water
provides potassium, phosphorus, and
minerals, helping orchids develop strong
roots and bloom well.
Coffee soaked water improves soil
acidity, enhances nutrient absorption
and promotes overall plant
[Music]
growth. Then soak in water for 20
minutes.
[Music]
Soak for about 20 minutes. Then take it
out and put it in a place with lots of
[Music]
light. Do the above three steps every 10
days.
results. After 3
[Music]
weeks, uh, the baby orchids have grown
healthier and have greener leaves.
[Music]
Continue to care for orchids with
natural fertilizer every 10
[Music]
days. Continue wiping the top and bottom
of leaves. helps remove dirt, plaque,
and small insects, helping the plant
photosynthesize better and grow
[Music]
healthily. Uh, and if you haven't
subscribed to the channel yet, please
click the subscribe button to support me
and don't miss any orchid growing tips.
Truly great company.
[Music]
After cleaning the leaves, you can spray
the natural fertilizer mixture on the
entire orchid, including the leaves,
stem, and
roots. Don't forget to spray the
underside of the leaves, as this is
where insects or fungi can easily grow.
[Music]
When applying the mixture to the roots
and growing medium, make sure to apply
enough to saturate the roots without
letting the water sit too long, as this
can cause root
[Music]
rot. Make sure that the growing medium
still drains well to prevent the plant
from water logging. This will help the
orchid grow healthy with strong roots
and support the next blooming
cycle. After watering, soak in this
water for 20 minutes.
[Music]
Then take it out and place it in a place
with plenty of
light to spread the light more properly.
[Music]
Results after 5
months. The orchid has matured and has
flower buds.
[Music]
Leaves are strong and
sturdy. The orchid has grown three new
flower branches.
[Music]
Then you continue to care for the orchid
with this natural fertilizer.
[Music]
Do all three steps every 10
days. If you encounter any difficulties
in growing orchids, don't hesitate to
comment for me. I'm always ready to
support you so you can grow healthy
orchids that bloom beautifully.
[Music]
When spraying the mixture, you should
spray it in the early morning or late
afternoon so that the mixture does not
evaporate too quickly under the sun.
[Music]
Watering in the early morning or late
afternoon will help the fertilizer
mixture be absorbed better. Avoid
watering during intense sunlight hours
because it can easily cause leaf burns.
[Music]
After watering with the fertilizer
mixture, you should gently wipe off any
water remaining on the leaves,
especially the underside to prevent mold
or leaf rot.
[Music]
You should place the orchid pot in a
spot with gentle indirect light so the
plant can photosynthesize
better. Take care of your orchids with
all the love you have for plants and
you'll be rewarded with beautiful
flowers that you've nurtured yourself.
Don't forget to subscribe to the
Happiness Garden channel so you don't
miss out on more helpful
[Music]
videos. Thank you for watching and I
wish you success and joy with your
orchid garden.
[Music]
See you in the next video.