hello
[Music]
everyone um to give you more options for
taking care of orchids at home with
natural fertilizers in this video I will
share a type of fertilizer that helps
orchids bloom continuously with multiple
flower
[Music]
stems um if you haven't subscribed to
the channel yet please subscribe to
support me and not miss any orchid care
tips let's get started
this is the Orchid after
blooming first you need to cut off
damaged leaves and
Roots first you need to cut off damaged
leaves and Roots after the flowers fade
the orchid needs time to recover and
store energy for the next blooming cycle
without proper care the plant may not
have enough energy to develop new flower
[Music]
buds orchids are delicate plants that
require specific conditions to
thrive proper post Bloom care helps
maintain the plant's Health preventing
pests and diseases and ensuring it grows
well for the next
Bloom now we make natural fertilizers
for
[Music]
orchids take two banana peels and cut
them into small
[Music]
pieces banana peels are rich in
nutrients such as potassium phosphorus
magnesium and Trace elements like
calcium and manganese which promote
Healthy
Growth potassium in particular helps
stimulate flowering and improves plant
Health encouraging orchids to bloom
regularly and last longer
put banana peels in the
jar next I use crysanthemum tea to care
for the Orchid after
blooming chamomile tea contains
essential nutrients like potassium
phosphorus and magnesium which promote
healthy growth in orchids potassium
enhances plant Health especially in root
development and flowering while
phosphorus and magnesium support the
growth of tissues and flower
buds I put in four chamomile tea bags
add 1 liter of boiled
water then wait until the water
[Music]
cools 2 hours later
stir well so that the nutrients are
completely dissolved in the
water then filter out the residue
add 1 liter of
water step one
using a liquid fertilizer made from
banana peels and chamomile tea helps
orchids recover quickly after blooming
by providing essential nutrients like
potassium phosphorus and magnesium from
the banana peels as well as the
antibacterial and antifungal properties
of chamomile tea
[Music]
both stimulate root growth boost plant
immunity and improve flower quality
promoting Healthy Growth and continuous
blooming
then you soak the Orchid pot in this
water for about 20
minutes soaking the Orchid pot in the
liquid fertilizer allows the roots more
time to absorb nutrients like potassium
phosphorus magnesium and other minerals
aiding in quicker
recovery step
two you put this liquid fertilizer
solution into a spray bottle
then spray the entire
Orchid spray thoroughly on both the top
and bottom of the leaves
spraying a liquid fertilizer made from
banana peels and chamomile tea helps
orchids recover quickly after blooming
by providing nutrients for the leaves
and stems stimulating
photosynthesis chamomile's antibacterial
and antifungal properties also remove
dirt tests and prevent diseases on the
leaves promoting Healthy Growth and
continuous
blooming step
three wiping the orchid leaves after
spraying a liquid fertilizer made from
banana peels and chamomile tea removes
dirt pests fungal infection
and water droplets reducing the risk of
disease this enhances photosynthesis
improves nutrient absorption and helps
the plant recover quickly leading to
continuous blooming
which country are you watching videos
from please comment for
me it's nice that we can chat together
from all over the world
do these three methods one to two times
a month for your orchids
after soaking for 20 minutes take the
Orchid pot out and place it in a place
with plenty of
light as a result after 2 months of
taking care of my orchid my orchid has
grown strongly and especially you have
seen the appearance of five new flower
branches
this shows that the tree is recovering
and growing very
well the tree grows many new Roots the
leaves become Greener and glossier than
before
uh if you encounter any difficulties
during the Orchid growing process don't
hesitate to comment I am always ready to
support you so you can grow healthy
orchids and Bloom lots of flowers
[Music]
this shows that the tree is recovering
and growing very
[Music]
well hopefully the video will help you
you a lot in taking care of orchids at
home if you find it interesting please
click like and share so more people know
about my
[Music]
channel and if you haven't subscrib to
the channel yet please subscribe to
support my channel
[Music]
take care of your Orchids with all the
love you have for them and you will be
rewarded with orchids blooming all year
round in your home space
[Music]