Hello friends
Today I will show you how when we need to water the orchid
When the orchid's roots are green like this, the orchid has enough water
The leaves will be green and sturdy
But if the roots turn white, the plant is lacking water
check the potting medium you will find it very dry
Leaves will wilt very quickly if we don't water them in time
In this case, we need to quickly water the orchid
HOW TO WATER AS FOLLOWING:
Place the orchid pot in a deep dish and water the substrate completely
If the roots are still fresh but the leaves are wilted, we can soak the orchid in water for 20-30 minutes
With pots using moss growing medium, the ability to retain moisture is very good,
so we only need to water enough moisture.
and no need to soak.
Eat bananas, don't throw away the peels
Banana peel contains a lot of vitamins and minerals:
vitamins A, B, C, E and protein, phosphorus, especially rich in potassium.
Potassium resists drought very well, helps the orchid to transport water from the root to the top, so the orchid does not wilt
At the same time, potassium helps to stimulate flower growth and keep flowers fresh for a long time
We cut banana peels
Put all banana peels in a jar and pour 500ml of boiled water
Then incubate for 1 day for the nutrients to dissolve into the water
5 vitamin b1 tablets mixed with 500ml of filtered water
B1 helps plants to better absorb nutrients
and growth regulator
It also stimulates root growth very well
After 1 day of incubation, we mix banana juice with vitamin B1 water to get 1 liter of synthetic organic fertilizer solution.
Divide into a spray bottle
Spray the top and bottom of the leaves evenly
Orchid plants are provided with a part of nutrients that are supplemented through the leaves
At the same time, it also eliminates insects to help the orchid stay green
You can also use a cotton ball soaked in this synthetic organic fertilizer solution to wipe the leaves
Do this 1-2 times a month, the orchid will always be protected and green
Next, you use this liquid synthetic organic fertilizer solution to irrigate the orchid
do 1-2 times a month and combine with other organic fertilizers that I have shared on the channel
It will help orchids easily absorb nutrients
Vitamin B1 helps stimulate root growth
Potassium in banana juice will stimulate flower growth and help flowers stay fresh for a long time
It is truly the perfect formula for the full development of roots, leaves and flowers
It's very good, but you should not overdo it, it will harm the orchid
You should only fertilize according to my instructions so that your orchid garden always blooms without affecting the growth of orchids.
Please comment below about your results
Please comment in the video so that I can help you further if your lan has problems
In addition to the English dub, we've now created dubs in French, German, Italian, Spanish, Portuguese,
Japanese, Hindi and Indonesian to help you hear and understand the content. Videos are easier.
If you find it interesting, don't forget to like, share and subscribe to support me
Don't rush to leave this video and continue watching part 2/2 to support me
Hello friends!
When you plant a lot of orchids, you will not be able to avoid rotten orchids.
You see my orchid has been infected with a fungus.
If not treated promptly, the orchid may die.
Even though it's rotten, it's still fresh when cut across.
It is also a favorable condition for the spread to respawn faster.
We need to cut off the branches and remove all the rot.
This will prevent rot from spreading.
Then rinse with water.
Take 1 cup of room temperature water (about 3000ml).
Mix 1 tablespoon of unsweetened fresh milk into the water.
add 1 vitamin B1 tablet.
Use a cotton ball to absorb the mixture of B1 water and milk.
Then wipe the top and bottom of the leaves.
This water mixture has a disinfecting effect.
Helps get rid of fungal diseases.
Then use this mixture of water B1 and milk to soak the orchid root for 20 minutes.
The rest is used to spray other normal orchids.
Helps get rid of fungal diseases.
and supplement necessary nutrients for orchids.
After soaking for about 20 minutes, take out the orchid leaves and dry the cut.
use toothpaste Applying it on a cut will help it heal faster will protect orchids from rot.
While waiting for it to dry, I recycle old plastic containers to make tools to revive orchids.
Use industrial cotton to put it in the pot.
then let the orchid in.
Next, every 3 days, spray moisturizing mist with normal water.
Then put the orchid pot in a cool place.
The most suitable temperature for reviving orchids is from 20-30 degrees Celsius.
1 MONTH LATER.
The orchid has rooted very well.
and grow 1 more young leaf.
B1 stimulates rooting very well.
Milk contains natural calcium to help orchids stay strong and increase resistance.
Now I grow orchids in pots with moss so that it adapts to the outside environment.
If you find it interesting, please like, share and subscribe to support my channel.
Wish you all success and happiness in life.
See you in the next videos.