Welcome to Happiness Garden, where the
simplest things become magical moments
that nurture the beauty of nature.
Today, I'm sharing another simple yet
highly effective way to grow and care
for orchids. With this easy toake
natural fertilizer at home, even weak
orchids can recover, grow well, and
bloom beautifully.
When growing orchids at home, everyone
hopes their orchid spikes will produce
lots of buds and bloom with vibrant,
healthy flowers, just like the orchids I
take care of every day.
Please comment and let me know which
country you're watching the video from.
Uh it's wonderful that we can chat
together from all around the world.
When orchids begin to bloom, each flower
stays on the spike for a long time
before fading, as if trying to prolong
its gentle and pure beauty over time.
And right now, I'll guide you through
the steps in a simple and detailed way
so you can start applying it to your
beloved orchid pots right away.
Each month, you only need to water each
orchid pot one to two times, just like
the way I always do. Simple, yet
surprisingly effective.
[Music]
Regular watering helps orchids maintain
the necessary moisture, allowing them to
absorb nutrients more effectively. When
provided with enough moisture, the
flowers will bloom fully and stay on the
spike for a long time before fading.
Like a lasting gift from nature,
[Music]
you can keep the orchid in its pot and
soak it in water for about 10 to 20
minutes. This method allows the roots to
absorb enough moisture without causing
the plant to become water logged.
After that, don't forget to take the
orchid pot out and let it drain,
allowing the roots to breathe and
preventing rot.
If you haven't subscribed to the channel
yet, please hit the subscribe button to
support me and never miss any orchid
growing tips. It's wonderful to have you
along.
To start making natural fertilizer for
orchids, you only need one very familiar
ingredient from the kitchen. Garlic.
[Music]
Take two cloves of garlic and slice them
very thinly so the nutrients can easily
dissolve into the water.
[Music]
After slicing, place the garlic into a
clean bottle to prepare the watering
solution for your orchids.
Next, pour about one liter of room
temperature water into the bottle to
help the garlic release its natural
compounds effectively.
[Music]
The next ingredient is honey. a natural
component rich in nutrients that help
stimulate root growth and boost the
plant's resistance.
[Music]
Just add one teaspoon of honey to the
mixture and stir gently until the honey
is completely dissolved in the water.
Garlic and honey combined create a
mixture with natural antibacterial and
antiseptic properties, helping eliminate
harmful fungi in the orchid growing
medium, while also providing nutrients
that support healthy growth from root to
tip.
After finishing, you just need to wait
about 1 hour for the nutrients from the
garlic and honey to fully infuse into
the water, creating a nutrientrich
solution ready for your orchids.
[Music]
If you have a weak orchid that hasn't
been able to bloom, start by checking
its roots. Remove any damaged roots and
leaves. Then replant the orchid in a
clean growing medium. This is the first
step to help it recover and prepare for
the next blooming cycle.
[Music]
This helps prevent the spread of fungal
diseases while allowing the plant to
focus on nourishing its healthy parts.
As a result, new roots will grow
vigorously, helping the plant recover
quickly and get ready for the next
blooming cycle.
[Music]
After soaking for about 1 hour, strain
out the residue to get a clear solution,
which helps the orchid absorb nutrients
more effectively and prevents clogging
in the growing medium.
[Music]
Step one, use a soft cloth soaked in the
solution. Then gently wipe both the top
and underside of the leaves.
[Music]
This method not only helps clean dust
and effectively kill bacteria uh but
also delivers nutrients directly through
the leaves allowing the plant to absorb
them quickly and recover better.
You can also apply this method to
healthy orchids to boost their
resistance, keep the leaves glossy
green, and help the flowers last longer.
[Music]
Apply this method regularly, one to two
times a month, for the orchid pots in
your garden to maintain their health and
vibrant beauty all year round.
[Music]
Step two, soak the orchid roots in the
garlic and honey solution for about 10
to 20 minutes.
This method not only helps naturally
disinfect, but also stimulates new root
growth to be stronger and healthier,
creating a solid foundation for the
orchid to recover and thrive.
The remaining solution can be used to
water each orchid pot in your garden.
This is a simple way to provide extra
nutrients and boost the plant's
resistance.
Regularly watering with the garlic and
honey mixture helps orchids strengthen
their resistance against fungi and
harmful bacteria in the growing medium.
As a result, the plant stays healthy and
is less affected by its surrounding
environment.
Uh, this nutrient-rich solution helps
the roots grow strong and absorb water
and minerals more efficiently. When the
roots are healthy, the orchid has enough
energy to produce more blooms that are
vibrant and long-lasting.
You can also pour the remaining solution
into a spray bottle and lightly mist the
leaves of the orchid pots in your
garden. This method helps clean the
leaves, kill bacteria, and provide
nutrients directly through the leaf
surface.
You can apply this fertilizer every 2
weeks or flexibly alternate it with
other natural fertilizers such as
banana, aloe vera, fish emulsion,
soybean or molasses to provide a diverse
range of nutrients for your orchid's
overall growth.
Spraying the garlic and honey mixture on
the leaves helps clean the leaf surface,
eliminate harmful bacteria and fungi,
and at the same time provide a natural
layer of nutrients that keeps the leaves
glossy, healthy, and enhances their
photosynthesis capacity.
[Music]
After soaking, gently take the orchid
out and replant it in a new pot with
clean, well-arrated growing medium. This
is an important step to help the plant
start fresh in a better environment.
[Music]
And here is another weak orchid that I
treated with this care method 3 weeks
ago. As you can see, it has started to
grow many new roots. A very positive
sign of recovery.
When the root system becomes healthy
again, the plant will start to absorb
water and nutrients more effectively,
and gradually the once wilted leaves
will come back to life.
When the roots absorb enough water and
nutrients, the orchid can sustain its
flowers more effectively. As a result,
the petals on the spike stay fresh,
vibrant, and retain their beauty for a
long time before fading.
After soaking for about 10 to 20
minutes, once the roots have absorbed
enough nutrients, take the orchid pot
out and place it in a spot with gentle
sunlight. Uh this helps the plant
photosynthesize better, recover quickly
and grow healthily.
When provided with good fertilizer and
enough light for photosynthesis, the
orchid will grow healthily and its
leaves will always be lush green and
glossy, a clear sign of a happy plant.
[Music]
Thanks to proper care, orchids will
bloom more brilliantly than usual,
shining dazzlingly and brightening up
the surrounding space.
[Music]
Many petals can bloom simultaneously on
the same spike, and those flowers will
stay fresh for a long time before
fading, creating a truly vibrant and
impressive scene.
[Music]
What do you think about how I care for
these small orchids? Don't hesitate to
leave a comment and share your thoughts.
I'm really eager to hear your feedback
and experiences.
I hope you will enjoy this video. If you
find it helpful, uh don't forget to hit
like and subscribe to the channel so you
won't miss upcoming tips on how to care
for orchids naturally and simply.
Thank you for taking the time to watch.
Wishing you happiness, joy, and
wonderful experiences with your beloved
orchid pots. See you in the next video.
Welcome to my channel.
When orchids have enough nutrients and
good soil environment, the plant will
grow stronger and flower more.
[Music]
To help create the best conditions for
flower development, at the same time
make orchids bloom more beautiful, both
roots and flowers grow beyond
imagination. In this video, I share a
new fertilizer that few people know
about.
[Music]
Let's explore with me
When when you plant a lot of orchids,
the orchid rot is inevitable.
[Music]
If it accidentally rots, you need to cut
off the rotten part right away.
[Music]
Then isolate the rotten orchid pot from
other normal orchid pots.
[Music]
This helps prevent rot from spreading to
normal orchids.
[Music]
After cutting off the rotten part, you
need to dry the rot solution.
[Music]
Uh if you haven't subscribe to the
channel yet, please hit the subscribe
button to support me and not miss any
orchid growing tips. It's amazing to
have you as a companion.
[Music]
Please comment to me which country you
are watching the video from. It's great
that we can chat together from all over
the world.
[Music]
Um, waste from rotten orchids should be
isolated from the garden as far as
possible.
[Music]
This is activated carbon. It is made
from natural dry firewood.
[Music]
I took a piece of activated carbon like
this and ground it into powder.
[Music]
Then sprinkle activated charcoal powder
on the newly cut wound. Helps cuts heal
faster and eliminates fungal diseases
because activated carbon has a very good
sterilization function.
[Music]
Then you sprinkle more in between the
two leaves and on the base.
Then put the orchid pot in a cool place
and do not water for one week. The
orchid will recover from the disease.
Next way,
mix one teaspoon of activated carbon
with one liter of water.
[Music]
Then use this water to water the base of
the orchid.
[Music]
Perform periodically once every 2 weeks
for normal orchids. Helps prevent
disease and improve pH in growing media.
[Music]
in activated carbon. There is also a
high content of calcium and natural
minerals that are very good for orchids.
Help stimulate rooting.
[Music]
Soak in this water for 30 minutes is
better.
[Music]
The next way you filter this water to
get clear water.
[Music]
Then use this water to wash the leaves.
orchid will be protected from fungi and
insects.
[Music]
The calcium content in activated carbon
helps to strengthen the leaves.
[Music]
Do it regularly once every 2 weeks and
you will be healthy like this.
[Music]
You can also use this water to spray the
entire orchid. It helps to eliminate
fungi and insects on leaves very well
and it also provides some nutrients
through the leaves.
[Music]
Now, let's see the results.
Lots of new roots growing. This helps
orchids absorb nutrients best.
[Music]
The potassium and phosphorus content in
activated carbon stimulates extremely
fast rooting.
[Music]
The flowers are brighter and stronger.
many flower buds growing on the same
tree.
[Music]
Surely you will be surprised with this
fertilizer.
If you find it interesting, please like
and share it with many people and don't
forget to subscribe to my channel.
[Music]
Thank you for watching the video.
Goodbye and see you again in the next
videos.
[Music]