Welcome to the little garden where
wonders begin from a leaf, a flower, or
a moment of listening to nature.
Today, I want to share with you a
special way to grow orchids. No need for
frequent watering, yet the plant stays
healthy and blooms brilliantly to your
amazement.
These are two orchid plants that
probably haven't bloomed for a long time
and were thrown away. I picked them up
hoping to revive the beauty they once
had.
The first thing I need to do is gently
take the plant out of the pot and remove
all the old growing medium to begin the
recovery process.
Next, I gently trim off the damaged
leaves and the old dried flower spike to
purify the plant, making it lighter and
ready for a fresh new start.
I continue trimming off the rotten roots
to keep only the healthy parts, helping
the plant recover more easily and grow
better.
[Music]
After that, I rinse the entire orchid
under running water to completely remove
the old growing medium and clean the
plant before repotting.
[Music]
After rinsing, I let the plant rest for
a while to dry completely before
repotting.
To help the plant recover during
repotting, I use rice as a natural
fertilizer. Simple yet effective.
I put 5 tablesp of rice into a clean
bottle.
[Music]
Then I add about one liter of room
temperature water and stir well.
I let the mixture soak for about 1 hour
so the nutrients from the rice can begin
to dissolve into the water.
[Music]
After about 1 hour of soaking, I stir
well to help the nutrients from the rice
deeply infuse into the water, preparing
for the next step in orchid care.
[Music]
Uh, I place the orchid roots into a
clean cup, then pour in the prepared
rice water and soak for about 20 minutes
to nourish the roots.
[Music]
Rice water contains vitamin B1 and
natural amino acids which help stimulate
new root growth and nourish the plant
from within.
[Music]
While waiting for the roots to soak, I
make use of a used plastic bottle to
create an orchid pot. a method that
helps retain moisture without the need
for frequent watering.
[Music]
Recycling used plastic bottles not only
saves costs but also helps reduce
plastic waste and protect the
environment.
[Music]
In addition to the English voiceover, we
have now created versions in French,
German, Italian, Spanish, Portuguese,
Japanese, Hindi, Dutch, Polish, Korean,
and Indonesian to help you listen and
understand the content more easily.
To listen in your language, open the
video and click on settings, the gear
icon, to select your preferred audio
language.
Leave a comment and let me know which
country you're watching from. It's truly
wonderful that we can connect and chat
with each other from all around the
world.
[Music]
And if you haven't subscribed yet,
please hit the subscribe button to
support me and never miss any orchid
growing tips. It's truly wonderful to
have you along on this journey.
[Music]
Um, I make a few small holes at the
bottom of the two orchid pots to allow
good drainage and keep the roots well
ventilated.
[Music]
After soaking for about 20 minutes, I
gently take the orchid out and begin
planting it into the new pot I've
prepared.
[Music]
I choose crushed pine bark as the
growing medium for orchids because it's
airy, retains moisture well, and is very
root friendly, creating ideal conditions
for healthy growth.
[Music]
The growing medium needs to be
sterilized before planting to eliminate
harmful fungi and bacteria, protecting
the roots and creating a clean
environment for the orchid to grow.
[Music]
After planting, you only need to water
once. With this method, you only need to
add more water when it runs low.
[Music]
Uh the water level should just barely
touch the bottom of the pot. This allows
the orchid roots to absorb moisture
without becoming water logged.
You can also mist the plant to maintain
humidity when the weather is too dry,
creating an ideal environment for
healthy orchid growth.
Place the orchid pot in a spot with
gentle sunlight and add slowrelease
fertilizer to the growing medium to
provide long-term nutrients for the
plant.
And here is the result. After 2 months,
the orchid has grown strong and produced
a new flower spike.
Many new flower spikes have grown on the
same plant. This shows that the orchid
is thriving with strong roots, vibrant
leaves, and a good supply of nutrients.
What do you think about the way I
revived this little orchid? Don't
hesitate to leave a comment and share
your thoughts. I'd love to hear your
feedback and experiences.
During the care process, if you notice
the water in the container becomes
dirty, you should replace it with clean
water to maintain a healthy environment
for the orchid roots to grow.
[Music]
And here is the result after 3 months.
You can see the orchid has bloomed
beautifully and vibrantly.
[Music]
The leaves are greener, stronger, and
much firmer than before. This helps the
plant increase its resistance to pests
and grow more sustainably.
[Music]
With this growing method, the roots
develop very well and don't rot, helping
the plant absorb nutrients efficiently
and grow vigorously.
The flowers always bloom brightly, stay
fresh, and last long, like a
well-deserved reward for your loving
care.
Thanks to consistent moisture, the
flowers don't wilt and stay fresh.
As a result, they can remain on the
spike for a very long time, even up to a
year before fading.
[Music]
Thank you for watching the video.
Wishing you joy and happy orchid care
every day. Goodbye and see you in the
next video.
[Music]
The roots are likened to the soul of the
orchid.
Orchids grow healthy thanks to healthy
roots.
Um, if the roots are healthy, the the
orchid will also grow many flower buds.
[Music]
In this video, I will show you how to
make orchids grow roots and flower buds
quickly.
[Music]
You need one fresh ginger, about 50 g.
Cut ginger into small pieces.
[Music]
Please comment to me which country you
are watching the video from. It's great
that we can chat together from all over
the world.
[Music]
Put in a jar. Recommended plastic jar.
Add 3 tablesp of sugar. Any sugar will
do.
Add in 100 ml of filtered water.
[Music]
Add in 100 milllers of beer. Any beer is
fine.
[Music]
Cover and keep in a dark place for 1
month.
Open the lid once every 3 days to let
the gas out.
[Music]
One month later,
uh, the smell of GE ginger is fermented,
so it's very fragrant.
[Music]
The ratio of mixing is 3 ml of G ginger
for one liter of water.
[Music]
If you haven't subscribed to the channel
yet, please click the subscribe button
to support me and not miss any orchid
growing tips. It's great to have
company.
[Music]
First way,
soak cotton balls in water mixed with
ginger. GE.
[Music]
Place cotton balls soaked in GE ginger
between the leaves.
helps keep moisture and GE ginger
stimulates rooting and flower sprout
differentiation very quickly.
Change this cotton once every 3 days.
[Music]
On normal days when the cotton is dry,
you just need to mist it with water to
keep it moist.
[Music]
Use this water to wash the top and
bottom of the leaves. helps provide
nutrients through leaves, clean stamata,
eliminate harmful insects and fungi, and
help orchid photosynthesis the best.
[Music]
Wipe the orchid leaves with GE ginger
once a month. So that orchids are best
protected and developed.
[Music]
Way three.
Use GE ginger water to water orchids.
[Music]
Uh, yeast brewed from fresh ginger has
the effect of stimulating sprouting,
strong rooting, repelling insects,
killing fungi, stimulating buds, and
stimulating growth.
GE ginger also helps orchids increase
their ability to absorb nutrients from
the fertilizer you fertilize them.
Only do this one to two times a month.
Do not use too much as it will affect
the growth of orchids.
[Music]
See the results
after one week of use. New roots grow
very quickly.
[Music]
These roots will help the orchid absorb
nutrients more easily and more.
Orchids grow well or not thanks to the
photosynthesis of roots and leaves.
[Music]
When the orchid is healthy, after the
orchid branch blooms the last flowers,
then there will be new flowers that
flowers that will continue to grow.
[Music]
My video features voiceovers in six
languages: English, French, German,
Spanish, Portuguese, and Italian.
Additionally, I have subtitles in
various other languages around the world
for you to choose from.
[Music]
With this simple way, you can do it
yourself to take care of orchids at home
at very low cost and convenience.
[Music]
I hope the video content will help you
take better care of orchids at home.
Thank you for watching the video.
Wishing everyone good luck and an
abundance of