Welcome to the channel. Today I will
share how to care for orchids after the
flowers have faded so the plant can
continue to grow and bloom again soon.
In my hand is an orchid spike that has
lost all its petals, leaving only the
bare stem. To help the plant produce new
flowers, we need to cut off the old
flower nodes that have already bloomed.
[Music]
We only keep the note of never bloomed
because it is from from these nodes that
a new flower spike may emerge.
Uh at the same time, we should also
gently peel off the thin outer layer to
to create better conditions for the new
flower bud to develop easily.
After cutting, the wound on the stem
should be left to dry naturally.
During this time, you should avoid
watering to prevent the cut from
becoming moist and susceptible to fungal
infection.
Uh, this is a sprouted potato. These
sprouts contain a high amount of oxin, a
plant hormone that helps stimulate
growth.
[Music]
I will add 20 g of fresh ginger, a
natural ingredient that helps with
antibacterial action and supports
healthy plant growth.
Next, I add 6 L of room temperature
water to easily blend the ingredients.
Blend all the ingredients until you get
a smooth mixture.
Strain out the pulp to obtain the liquid
solution.
[Music]
Next, I add another 0.6 6 L of room
temperature water to dilute the
solution, making it easier for the plant
to absorb.
The first method is to dip cotton into
the mixture, then wrap it around the
nodes on the stem that contain dormant
buds.
[Music]
This will help stimulate those buds to
grow and develop into new flower spikes.
[Music]
Let me know in the comments which
country you're watching from. It's
amazing that we can connect and chat
from all around the world.
[Music]
If you haven't subscribed to the channel
yet, please hit the subscribe button to
support me and not miss any orchid
growing tips. It's truly wonderful to
have you along on this journey.
[Music]
Uh every 7 days you should apply this
mixture once to the nodes to promote the
flowering process.
[Music]
The second method, pour the mixture into
a spray bottle and mist it evenly on the
leaves, stem, and roots to nourish the
entire plant.
[Music]
However, you should not spray it on the
flowers as it may cause them to wilt and
fall off quickly.
[Music]
Potato sprouts contain many essential
nutrients for plants such as oxin,
vitamins, and minerals, which help
stimulate root growth, promote
development, and enhance the plant's
resistance.
Potato sprouts also contain natural
nitrogen, phosphorus, and potassium,
essential nutrients that help plants
develop strong roots, green leaves, and
stimulate flowering.
[Music]
The third method, pour the mixture
directly onto the roots to nourish the
plant from the base.
[Music]
Evenly pour the mixture over the base,
roots, and surface of the growing medium
to help the plant absorb it better.
[Music]
Potato sprouts also contain phosphorus,
an important nutrient that promotes root
development and plays an essential role
in the plant's overall growth process.
[Music]
Potato sprouts are also rich in calcium,
an essential nutrient for plant cell
development, helping to form strong and
stable cell structures.
At the same time, calcium also improves
soil pH and increases the plant's
ability to absorb other nutrients.
[Music]
Potato sprouts also contain magnesium,
an important nutrient that helps balance
pH levels and enhances the plant's
ability to absorb nutrients.
[Music]
Um, you can apply the misting method on
the leaves or water directly at the base
once a month to provide the plant with a
steady supply of nutrients.
After more than a month, the orchid
spikes that had once faded have started
uh blooming again.
As you can see, the nodes with dormant
eyes have now developed into new flower
spikes, preparing for the next blooming
cycle.
[Music]
Uh, what do you think about the way I
stimulated the orchid to grow new flower
spikes from a faded stem?
Don't hesitate to leave a comment and
share your thoughts. I'd love to hear
your feedback and suggestions.
[Music]
Um, if you face any difficulties during
the orchid growing process, don't
hesitate to leave a comment. I'm always
here to support you so you can grow
healthy orchids that bloom beautifully.
Uh, I hope you enjoy this video. If you
find it helpful, don't forget to hit
like and subscribe to the channel so you
won't miss upcoming tips on caring for
orchids in a natural and simple way.
[Music]
The orchids treated with potato juice
have bloomed profusely with many flowers
blooming together on a single spike.
Not only do they bloom abundantly, but
the flowers also stay fresh on the spike
for a long time. Sometimes lasting up to
6 months.
The leaves have also become thicker and
sturdier, clearly showing the vitality
and health of the orchid.
The root system has grown large and
strong, firmly attaching to the growing
medium. Um, a sign that the plant is
absorbing nutrients very well.
[Music]
Thank you for watching. See you in the
next video.
[Music]
Welcome to my channel.
When you buy an orchid or someone gives
it to you,
you need to do the following.
[Music]
First, you need to remove the packaging
from the orchid.
[Music]
Next, leave the orchid in a cool place
for a few hours to allow it to adjust to
the new climate.
[Music]
Uh if the growing medium is moss or
small wood chips, it is only suitable
for industrial orchid gardens.
[Music]
[Applause]
Because moss retains a lot of moisture,
many plant roots rot due to water
logging.
If you haven't subscribed to the channel
yet, please hit the subscribe button to
support me and not miss any orchid
growing tips. It's great to have you
along.
[Music]
Uh the humidity was too high, so the
leaves were also infected with black
mold.
In addition to the English dub, we've
now created dubs in French, German,
Italian, Spanish, Portuguese, Japanese,
Hindi, and Indonesian to help you hear
and understand the content more easily.
[Music]
Therefore, you need to remove all moss
or old growing medium.
Um because this type of substrate is
only suitable for industrial orchid
gardens that can control special
humidity.
[Music]
Please comment to me which country you
are watching the video from. It's It's
great that we can chat together from all
over the world.
[Music]
Then you cut off all damaged roots.
and cut off all wilted flowers.
[Music]
Then you take one aloe vera leaf.
and take a clove of garlic.
[Music]
Put all the aloe vera and garlic in a
jar and soak it with 2 L of water.
[Music]
Wait 30 minutes for the nutrients from
the garlic and aloe vera to dissolve
into the water.
[Music]
30 minutes later
Soak the roots in this solution for 30
minutes.
[Music]
Garlic and aloe vera help stimulate root
growth and effectively fight harmful
insects and fungi.
[Music]
Um, spraying this solution on the entire
orchid will help repel insects,
eliminate fungal diseases, and keep the
leaves green.
[Music]
Then clean the black mold stains with
this solution.
[Music]
This helps prevent orchids from
recurring mold.
[Music]
Now I recycle used plastic containers to
make orchid pots.
[Music]
I put a layer of pummus on the bottom of
the orchid pot.
[Music]
This helps keep the bottom of the orchid
pot clear so the roots don't get water
logged.
[Music]
For the top, I use dried pine bark as a
growing medium
[Music]
and mix in some dry moss.
When planting, cushion the substrate
tightly so that the roots do not move.
[Music]
Insert the flower branch into the right
position to help prevent the orchid from
shaking.
[Music]
After planting, let it dry for 5 days
before watering.
[Music]
Take care of your orchids with all the
love you have for plants, and they will
bloom all over the garden this way.
[Music]
Thank you for watching the video. Good
luck and see you in the next videos.