welcome everyone to my
garden um I'm really happy to see you
again in this
video today we'll continue exploring a
wonderful organic fertilizer for
orchids this fertilizer not only helps
the orchids grow strong but also
encourages them to bloom all year
round let's dive into the details
together to make this fertilizer I need
onions onions contain essential
nutrients such as nitrogen phosphorus
and pottassium which help the plant grow
strong the sulfur compounds in onions
have antibacterial and antifungal
properties helping protect orchids from
common diseases
[Music]
onion extract helps stimulate the growth
of new Roots allowing orchids to
thrive put the onion into a jar
[Music]
please comment to me which country you
are watching the video from it's great
that we can chat together from all over
the
world add one liter of boiled water
[Music]
then incubate and wait
overnight after one night
[Music]
the onion peel juice I leave overnight
will look like
this now I open this and filter it I
will just use the onion juice we do not
use the onions
[Music]
add 1 liter of
water step
one in the first method I put onion
juice in a spray bottle
and spray on orchid leaves as fertilizer
we will fertilize orchids from the
leaves and Roots by spraying both the
top and bottom
Parts spray the top and bottom of the
leaves thoroughly
and spray onto aerial roots to help
deliver nutrients directly to the aerial
roots
when the substrate is dry and the roots
are silvery white spray
immediately uh onion soak water contains
many vitamins and minerals providing
nutrition for the plant from leaves to
roots
spraying on leaves enhances
photosynthesis keeping the leaves green
and
healthy after spraying water on the
orchid leaves if it's sunny you need to
wipe off any water droplets left on the
leaves
uh because the water droplets on the
leaves can create a magnifying effect
under the sunlight leading to Leaf
burn water accumulation on leaves can
foster the growth of fungi and bacteria
increasing the likelihood of disease
water on leaves can obstruct
photosynthesis wiping it off allows
leaves to transpire and absorb light
more effectively
cleaning off water helps the leaves dry
faster keeping the plant healthy and
avoiding issues related to excessive
[Music]
humidity if you haven't subscribed to
the channel yet please please hit the
Subscribe button to support me and not
miss any Orchid growing tips it's
wonderful to have you as a companion
[Music]
step
two water each Orchid pot with this
liquid
fertilizer this natural fertilizer
contains essential vitamins and minerals
that help orchids grow healthily
[Music]
the compounds and onions have
antibacterial and antifungal properties
protecting orchids from
[Music]
diseases onion soak water can stimulate
root growth helping the plant absorb
water and nutrients more
[Music]
effectively watering with onion liquid
helps keep leaves Greener and enhances
photosynthesis it helps the plant combat
environmental stress such as high
temperatures or low humidity
it helps retain moisture in the soil and
improves fertility creating favorable
conditions for root
development uh it enhances the activity
of beneficial microorganisms in the soil
improving the overall health of the
plant
it is best to soak the Orchid pot in
this water for about 20 minutes
[Music]
after soaking for 20 minutes take the
Orchid pot out and place it in a place
with enough
light then place the pot in a spot with
gentle sunlight so plant can
photosynthesize allowing the natural
fertilizer to work at its
best orchids typically need about 50 to
70% natural light as too much direct
sunlight can Scorch the
leaves a good place to place the Orchid
pot is a spot with moderate wind flow
which will help reduce excessive
humidity and prevent fungal diseases
very
well you can place the Pot near a window
or a place with a light
Breeze now let's take a look at the
results after caring for The Orchids
with the natural
fertilizer the leaves will grow vibrant
thick and healthy they will have bright
colors and and will not turn yellow or
Scorch due to appropriate light and
humidity
[Music]
The Roots will develop robustly and
evenly with adequate moisture and
nutrients The Roots will have a shiny
appearance and will not rot or
deteriorate if you encounter any
difficulties during the Orchid growing
process don't hesitate to comment and
let me know I'm always always ready to
support you so that you can grow healthy
orchids and have them bloom
[Music]
abundantly proper care and ideal
environmental conditions will stimulate
bud
formation the buds will be strong and
capable of developing into
flowers how do you find the way to
revive weak orchids and care for your
orchids please leave your comments and
suggestions to let me know
[Music]
if you find the content useful and
meaningful don't forget to like share it
so more people can see and subscribe to
the channel to support me thank you for
always being with me
[Music]
the flowers will Bloom evenly last
longer and display vibrant
colors when placed correctly orchid
flowers will be less likely to drop and
will have a longer blooming period
[Music]
take care of your Orchids with all the
love you have for plants and you will be
rewarded orchids are sensitive beings
that respond positively to Dedicated
care
[Music]
when you invest your time and effort in
nurturing them um you not only help the
plants grow strong but also get to enjoy
beautiful blooms symbolizing the love
and patience you have put in Let Your
Love Shine through every Orchid pot
[Music]
thank you for watching today's
video I hope the information about how
to care for and water orchids with
liquid fertilizer helps you have healthy
and vibrant Orchid
[Music]
Pots if you found the video helpful
don't forget to like And subscribe to
the channel for more gardening tips
see you in the next video