[Music]
Welcome to my channel. I share helpful
tips for growing and caring for orchids.
Today I will share the simplest way to
help your orchids grow strong roots and
bloom beautifully at home.
Uh if you haven't subscribed yet, please
click the subscribe button to support me
and never miss any orchid tips. It's
great to have you with me.
If your orchid has wilted soft leaves
like this, don't throw it away. This
video will show you how to revive it
quickly.
First, we need to check the roots and
the growing medium to find the cause of
the orchid's wilting.
[Music]
We remove all the damaged roots.
Removing all the damaged roots helps the
orchid get rid of dead parts, prevents
harmful bacteria and fungi, allowing the
plant to recover faster and grow
healthier and stronger.
[Music]
Next, rinse the orchid with water to
remove dirt and impurities.
[Music]
Uh, please comment to me which country
you are watching the video from. It's
great that we can chat together from all
over the world.
[Music]
Next, take one spoon of cinnamon powder.
Mix with 0.5 L of boiling water.
[Music]
Cover and let it steep until the water
cools, allowing the nutrients and
minerals from the cinnamon powder to
dissolve into the water.
[Music]
Um once the water has fully cooled,
strain out all the residue to get a
clear, clean solution.
[Music]
Next, dilute the mixture with half a
liter of clean water to ensure
effectiveness and safety for your
orchid.
[Music]
Next, soak your orchid in the cinnamon
water solution for about 20 minutes to
allow nutrients penetrate deeply and uh
provide effective antibacterial
benefits.
[Music]
While waiting, I repurpose an old
plastic cup to create a nursery pot for
the orchid.
[Music]
We need to make drainage holes at the
bottom of the pot to prevent water
logging.
[Music]
Uh after soaking the orchid in the
cinnamon water mixture for about 20
minutes, gently take the plant out.
Then use a soft cloth to wipe off all
the remaining water, helping to prevent
the orchid from rotting.
[Music]
These are the pebbles.
[Applause]
[Music]
Next, soak the pebbles in cinnamon water
for about 15 minutes to disinfect them,
ensuring the orchid growing medium stays
clean and safe.
[Music]
The next growing medium is construction
sand.
[Music]
Sand is an ideal orchid growing medium
that provides excellent drainage,
prevents water logging, and keeps the
roots healthy.
[Music]
Then soak the sand in cinnamon water for
about 15 minutes. This helps sterilize
the orchid growing medium, reducing
harmful molds and bacteria.
[Music]
Cinnamon water also stimulates orchid
roots to grow stronger, creating a
favorable environment for the plant to
absorb nutrients effectively.
[Music]
After soaking for about 15 minutes, we
take out the stones and sand to plant
the orchids. This ensures the medium is
clean and ready to provide a solid
foundation for the orchid roots to grow.
[Music]
Then we place the stones at the bottom
of the orchid pot to improve drainage,
helping the orchid roots avoid water
logging and grow healthier.
[Music]
for construction sand as the growing
medium. After soaking in cinnamon water,
we need to rinse it several times with
water to remove any remaining mud and
soil, making the medium cleaner and more
airrated for the orchid roots.
[Music]
Then we plant the orchid into the pot,
carefully placing it to avoid damaging
the roots and ensuring the plant stands
firmly on the prepared medium.
When planting with construction sand,
the medium consistently maintains
appropriate moisture levels, helping
weak orchids quickly develop new roots
and grow healthier.
[Music]
After planting, place the orchid pot in
a well ventilated area, avoiding strong
winds and allowing only gentle sunlight,
helping the plant adapt well and grow
steadily.
[Music]
And now here are the results after 3
weeks of recovering the orchid with
wilted leaves.
Uh you can see the orchid has grown a
new leaf which indicates that the plant
is recovering well and beginning to grow
again after the care period.
[Music]
Now let's check the roots together to
see how they are developing.
We just need to gently pour water and
the sand will naturally flow down
through the drainage holes at the bottom
of the pot.
[Music]
Wow. You can see many new roots growing
from the stem buried in the moist sand.
This shows that the growing medium
provides an ideal environment for the
orchid to develop new roots and recover
quickly.
[Music]
How do you feel about my method of
reviving weak orchids? Please leave a
comment and share your feedback with me.
I'm eager to learn from you.
[Music]
The new roots will help the wilted
orchid recover quickly, regain vitality,
and grow back after a week period.
[Music]
As new roots grow, the orchid can absorb
water and nutrients more effectively,
contributing to a complete recovery
process.
The growth of new roots also creates a
strong foundation for the orchid to
develop longterm and bloom regularly in
the future.
Rooting weak orchids in sand stimulates
quick new root growth, but we should
avoid keeping them in sand for too long
as it can cause root rot and damage due
to poor air circulation.
[Music]
Therefore, you need to plant the orchid
into a new pot using mediums like pine
bark chips, pummus, or moss to ensure
better irerration and healthy root
growth.
[Music]
Yummy. Yummy.
After planting, you need to secure the
orchid stem to a steak to keep the plant
stable, reduce movement from wind or
handling, which helps the roots firmly
attach to the medium and grow stronger.
[Music]
If you are busy, you can use slowrelease
fertilizer designed for orchids.
[Music]
Um, this type of fertilizer gradually
supplies nutrients over a long period,
saving you care time while ensuring
healthy orchid growth.
[Music]
However, if you're not too busy, I
recommend using natural fertilizers.
These are environmentally friendly and
help orchids grow well and sustainably
over time.
After planting, you need to water and
maintain moisture for the orchid.
[Music]
Depending on the weather conditions, I
usually water the orchid once every one
to two weeks to ensure the plant is
neither too dry nor water logged.
[Music]
After watering, place the orchid pot in
a spot with gentle sunlight to allow the
orchid to photosynthesize,
helping the plant produce energy and
grow healthier.
[Music]
After watering, place the orchid pot in
a spot with gentle sunlight to allow the
orchid to photosynthesize,
helping the plant produce energy and
grow healthier.
Uh the leaves have fully recovered and
become glossy green, showing that the
orchid is healthy and thriving after
careful care.
[Music]
The roots have developed strongly,
enabling the orchid to absorb nutrients
and water efficiently, providing a solid
foundation for long-term growth.
The petals are large and vividly
colored, highlighting the orchid's
elegant beauty and vibrant vitality
after the recovery process.
[Music]
Uh with this simple planting method,
anyone can easily revive and care for
orchids at home, keeping them healthy
and blooming beautifully.
[Music]
I hope you enjoy this video. If you find
it helpful, please like and subscribe to
the channel so you don't miss upcoming
tips on caring for orchids naturally and
easily.
If you face any difficulties during the
orchid growing process, don't hesitate
to leave a comment. I'm always ready to
support you so you can grow healthy
orchids that bloom beautifully.
Thank you so much for watching. Wishing
you a wonderful day filled with joy and
blooming orchids.
[Music]
Welcome to Happiness Garden, where every
leaf and every petal tells us a gentle
story of love for nature and care from
the heart.
Let's discover together the wonders that
come from the smallest things in this
garden.
After buying an orchid and enjoying its
blooms, the plant often starts to
decline. Yellowing leaves, weak roots,
and a tired look.
Sadly, many people throw it away too
soon, not knowing there's still a strong
life force inside, waiting to be
revived.
[Music]
Many orchids here have been discarded
wastefully.
[Music]
This orchid, although weakened, still
has fresh green leaves, a sign that it's
alive. So, I decided to take it home to
care for and revive it, hoping to bring
it back to full strength.
[Music]
We need to gently remove the old growing
medium, which may hold dust and
bacteria, and repot the orchid into a
new container to give it a better
environment to grow.
This helps the roots breathe and absorb
nutrients and water more effectively,
supporting the recovery process.
[Music]
After removing all the old growing
medium, we trim away all the damaged
roots, those that are rotten or no
longer able to absorb water and
nutrients.
This helps the plant focus its energy on
growing new healthy roots, increasing
its chances of recovery and healthy
growth.
[Music]
Next, we cut off the dry flower spikes
and old weak stems.
[Music]
This helps the plant save energy and
focus nutrients on its healthy leaves
and roots, promoting new growth and
preparing for more vibrant blooms in the
future.
Next, we remove the wilted and yellow
leaves as they no longer perform
photosynthesis well and may harbor
harmful bacteria.
This keeps the plant clean and allows it
to focus nutrients on healthy leaves,
supporting recovery and growth.
Next, we rinse the entire orchid
thoroughly with clean water to remove
dust, bacteria, and impurities from the
leaves, roots, and stem.
This step creates a clean environment,
reduces the risk of infection, and helps
the plant absorb nutrients more
effectively during recovery.
[Music]
Next, I sterilize the moss used as the
orchid growing medium.
This step is crucial to eliminate
bacteria, mold, and harmful agents that
might exist in the moss, creating a
clean and safe environment for the
orchid roots to grow strong.
I soak the moss in hot water to
sterilize it, effectively removing
bacteria, mold, and insects that may be
hidden inside.
[Music]
I soak the moss in hot water to
sterilize it, effectively removing
bacteria, mold, and insects that may be
hidden inside.
Next, we prepare a natural fertilizer to
restore the orchid's health.
Take one liter of clean water as the
base to dissolve the fertilizer
ingredients.
[Music]
Here
is the banana extract, GE banana, that I
made 3 weeks ago.
It is a natural fertilizer rich in
nutrients, helping stimulate strong
growth from roots to leaves while also
promoting recovery after the plant has
weakened.
[Music]
Take 50 ml of banana extract and mix it
into one liter of clean water. This
ratio creates a balanced fertilizer
solution, providing enough nutrients for
the orchid to absorb effectively without
causing irritation or damage during
recovery.
[Music]
You can refer to the video tutorial on
how to make banana extract GE banana via
the link in the description of this
video.
[Music]
Next, soak the entire orchid in the
banana extract fertilizer solution for
about 20 minutes.
[Music]
This allows the plant to absorb
nutrients directly and deeply,
supporting faster recovery and boosting
its resilience.
While waiting, I recycle old plastic
cups to make recovery pots for the
orchids.
This is an economical and eco-friendly
way also providing good erration and
drainage for the roots to grow strong.
[Music]
After soaking the orchid for about 20
minutes, remember to gently remove the
plant.
Use a soft cloth to gently pat dry the
water droplets on the leaves and between
the leaf folds.
This helps prevent prolonged moisture,
reducing the risk of mold and leaf
diseases while keeping the plant clean
and healthy.
[Music]
Once the water has fully cooled, take
out the moss and prepare it for
repotting the orchid.
[Music]
The clean sterilized moss provides an
ideal environment helping the orchid
roots grow strong and the plant recover
faster.
[Music]
Next, plant the orchid in the pot using
the sterilized moss as the growing
medium.
[Music]
Gently place the roots into the moss,
making sure they have good contact with
the medium without being too tightly
packed to allow proper air flow and
encourage healthy root growth.
[Music]
after planting. From now on, water the
orchid once every 10 days with the
diluted banana GE solution.
This regular watering helps provide
nutrients to the plant regularly,
supporting healthy root growth and green
leaves during recovery.
Just about 5 tablespoons of the diluted
banana GE solution is enough for each
watering.
This moderate amount allows the plant to
absorb nutrients effectively without
causing overwatering or wasting
fertilizer.
Then place the orchid pot in a spot with
gentle sunlight, good air circulation,
and protection from heavy rain.
Soft morning or late afternoon light
helps the plant photosynthesize better,
supporting recovery and growth without
burning the leaves.
[Music]
Um, put put the remaining fertilizer
mixture into a spray bottle and mist it
onto the orchids that are currently
blooming.
[Music]
This method delivers nutrients directly
to the leaves and flowers, promoting
healthy growth and enhancing the
longevity and vibrancy of the blooms.
[Music]
The natural potassium content in the
banana extract, GE, helps the orchid
petals last longer, potentially keeping
the flowers fresh for up to 6 months.
Now, I invite you to join me in seeing
the results after 3 weeks of orchid
recovery.
Oh, can you see the new white root
growing inside the orchid pot?
Let's check the roots inside the orchid
pot together.
[Music]
Wow. You can see the orchid has grown
many new roots which shows the plant is
recovering very well and ready for the
next strong growth phase.
These new roots increase its ability to
absorb water and nutrients, bringing
vibrant life to the plant.
[Music]
How do you find the way to restore your
weak orchid? Please write a comment to
let me know your opinion.
If you find the content interesting and
meaningful, don't forget to like, share
so that many people know and subscribe
to the channel to support me. Thank you
for always accompanying me.
[Music]
Once the orchid has developed many new
roots, I transplanted into a new pot
filled with pine bark as the growing
medium.
Pine bark improves irerration and
drainage, creating an ideal environment
for the roots to grow stronger, helping
the plant become healthier and ready for
vibrant blooming cycles ahead.
[Music]
If you haven't subscribed to the channel
yet, please hit the subscribe button to
support me and not miss any orchid
growing tips. Um, it's great to have you
along.
After planting, we prepare natural
fertilizer to care for the orchid.
To make natural fertilizer, I take I
take one tablespoon of wheat flour
diluted in one liter of water.
This mixture provides gentle nutrients
and helps stimulate beneficial
microorganisms in the growing medium,
contributing to the orchid's health
naturally and effectively.
[Music]
After mixing, strain out the sediment so
the solution becomes clear and can
penetrate the growing medium and roots
more easily.
This helps the natural fertilizer work
most effectively without clogging or
harming the orchid.
Then apply this fertilizer twice a month
to provide consistent nut nutrients for
the orchid.
Regular feeding helps the plant grow
steadily, boosts its resistance, and
prepares it well for future blooming
cycles.
[Music]
Then place the orchid pot in a spot with
gentle sunlight so the plant can
photosynthesize. Only with good
photosynthesis can the orchid absorb
nutrients effectively.
[Music]
And here is the result after 5 months of
recovery. Like
you can see that the orchid has grown
vigorously with many new roots growing
and the leaves are greener and shinier
than before.
[Music]
Especially the orchid has bloomed with
new flowers. A wonderful achievement
after a journey of patient and loving
care.
[Music]
This moment brings not only joy but also
motivation to keep nurturing our love
for orchids.
[Music]
Uh, thank you for joining me on this
orchid recovery journey.
I hope these tips help you care for and
cherish your orchids even more.
[Music]
Don't forget to like, share, and
subscribe so you won't miss upcoming
helpful videos. See you next time.
Welcome to Happiness Garden, where we
together explore the gentle beauty of
nature and the love for orchid petals.
Today I want to share with you how to
care for orchids using natural
fertilizer. A simple yet effective
method that helps orchids bloom multiple
times a year. As a result, your home
will always be filled with the colors
and gentle fragrance of nature.
Uh the orchid petals after falling leave
a quiet emptiness on the branch, marking
the time when the orchid begins to
weaken. During the blooming period, the
plant puts all its strength into
nurturing each petal, gradually
depleting the energy stored in its stem,
roots, and leaves.
We need to cut off the entire old orchid
branch. This helps the plant focus its
nutrients on nurturing healthy new
shoots while also stimulating the growth
of new roots, preparing for a more
brilliant next blooming season.
[Music]
If you haven't subscribed to the channel
yet, please press the subscribe button
to support me and not miss any orchid
growing tips. It's wonderful to have you
along.
[Music]
Leave a comment and let me know which
country you're watching from. It's
amazing that we can chat with each other
from all around the world.
[Music]
To make natural fertilizer, the first
ingredient I use is eggshells. Eggshells
are rich in calcium, which helps orchid
roots grow strong and also improves soil
quality, creating favorable conditions
for the plant to absorb nutrients more
effectively.
[Music]
Take two cleaned eggshells, then crush
them by hand and put them into a small
jar.
[Music]
The next ingredient I use is rice
because rice contains vitamins,
minerals, and a small amount of starch,
all of which are beneficial for orchid
root development.
Take 3 tablespoons of rice and add them
to the prepared eggshells. Then pour in
about.5 L of boiling water.
[Music]
Um the high temperature will help
release nutrients from the rice and
eggshells, creating a nutrient-rich brew
for the orchid.
Close the jar and let the solution cool
naturally. This process helps the
nutrients fully dissolve, ready to
nourish your orchid.
[Music]
After the water cools, stir the solution
well so that the nutrients blend
completely, ensuring the natural
fertilizer works at its best when used
for the orchid.
[Music]
Then we proceed to filter out the
sediment. This helps make the fertilizer
solution clear and easier to absorb into
the soil when watering the plant.
[Music]
Next, dilute the solution with water at
a ratio of one part solution to one part
water. This helps make the fertilizer
not too concentrated, safe, and easier
for the orchid to absorb.
[Music]
Step one, use a soft cloth to soak up
the fertilizer mixture. Then, gently
wipe both the top and bottom surfaces of
the orchid leaves thoroughly.
[Music]
This method helps remove dust stuck on
the leaves while also supporting the
leaves in absorbing nutrients better,
contributing to keeping the plant
healthy.
[Music]
Additionally, this method helps remove
insects and fungal diseases attached to
the leaves, keeping the orchid clean and
healthy.
[Music]
This is a way to help the leaves
directly absorb nutrients, thereby
nourishing the orchid to be healthy and
develop better every day.
[Music]
Note to wipe thoroughly the underside of
the leaves because this is where many
stamata concentrate, helping the leaves
exchange gases and absorb nutrients most
effectively.
Um the underside of the leaves does not
directly receive sunlight. So it is
often where insects and fungal diseases
tend to gather. Therefore thoroughly
wiping this part is very important to
keep the plant healthy.
[Music]
You should perform this method one to
two times a month to keep the orchid
leaves clean and help the plant absorb
nutrients most effectively.
[Music]
Step two, use the diluted fertilizer
mixture to water each orchid pot
directly, helping the plant absorb
nutrients from the soil effectively.
Doing this once every 2 weeks is enough.
[Music]
We water the roots and growing medium,
helping supply nutrients directly to
where the plant absorbs best, promoting
healthy growth from within.
When you water this mixture onto the
roots and growing medium, it helps
loosen the soil, creating conditions for
the roots to exchange gases well and
absorb nutrients more effectively.
[Music]
This mixture provides plenty of calcium
and minerals that help orchid roots grow
strong, enabling the plant to absorb
water and nutrients better.
[Music]
Uh, the nutrients in the mixture help
the plant produce new shoots faster,
creating a foundation for future
blooming seasons that are more beautiful
and longlasting.
Step three, put the diluted fertilizer
mixture into a spray bottle. Then spray
evenly onto the orchid leaves,
especially the underside of the leaves,
so the nutrients penetrate deeply and
help the plant become healthier.
Um, when spraying the fertilizer mixture
onto the leaves, the minerals and
vitamins from the eggshells and rice are
absorbed directly through the leaf
surface.
This helps the orchid leaves become
greener and healthier while also
supporting the photosynthesis process
effectively, contributing to enhancing
the plant's vitality.
[Music]
Spraying the mixture onto the leaves not
only provides nutrients but also helps
clean the layer of dust remaining on the
leaves after we wipe them.
[Music]
Additionally, the solution helps reduce
the presence of harmful insects, keeping
the orchid leaves clean and well
ventilated, creating a good environment
for the plant to thrive.
[Music]
Step four. After spraying, use a soft
cloth to gently wipe off any remaining
water on the leaf surface and between
the leaf folds to prevent mold and keep
the leaves well ventilated.
[Music]
When water remains on the leaves under
sunlight, the droplets can act like
lenses, increasing the risk of leaf
burn.
Wiping off the remaining water helps
prevent this issue, keeping the leaf
surface green and protected from damage
caused by strong light.
[Music]
Wiping the leaves with a soft cloth
after spraying not only helps clean
them, but also gently massages the leaf
surface, supporting deeper absorption of
nutrients. As a result, the orchid can
fully benefit from the natural
fertilizer mixture.
After finishing the care routine,
remember to place the orchid pot in a
spot with gentle sunlight and good
ventilation.
Light is an essential factor for
photosynthesis, which allows the orchid
to absorb and fully convert nutrients
from the fertilizer, helping the plant
recover quickly and grow stronger each
day.
And here is the result after 6 weeks.
You can see the orchid has recovered
strongly with roots developing well.
that
uh the orchid continues to develop new
flower spikes, promising a brilliant
blooming season ahead.
These new roots will help the orchid
absorb more nutrients, enhancing
stability and vitality throughout its
growth process.
[Music]
You can also see orchid leaves become
greener and sturdier, proving the
plant's improving health.
[Music]
Uh, this orchid pot is the same. Many
new roots have grown and new flower buds
are developing strongly, signaling a
beautiful blooming season is
approaching.
[Music]
Um, the calcium in the eggshells along
with the minerals in the rice water help
stimulate the growth of many new roots,
proving that the natural fertilizer
mixture is very effective.
[Music]
Uh, rice water also helps improve the
plant's health by providing natural
vitamins and enzymes, supporting growth
and fighting pests.
[Music]
With just a few simple steps, we can
care for orchids at home, helping them
stay healthy and bloom brilliantly all
year round.
[Music]
Uh, how do you find my method of
restoring the orchid after the petals
fall? Please leave your comments and
share your thoughts with me.
[Music]
If you encounter any difficulties during
the orchid growing process, don't
hesitate to comment. I'm always ready to
support you so you can grow healthy
orchids that bloom abundantly.
Um, as long as you persist in daily
care, gradually you will have a happy
garden like mine filled with brilliant
flowers.
I hope you will like this video. If you
find it helpful, don't forget to hit the
like button on the video
and subscribe to the channel so you
don't miss the next shares about how to
care for orchids naturally and simply.
[Music]
Thank you for watching the video.
Wishing you joy and success in caring
for your beloved orchid plants.