Welcome to the Happiness Garden channel.
In my hands is an orchid pot whose last
petals have just closed.
When the radiant beauty of the flowers
fades, the plant enters its resting and
recovery phase. This is the perfect time
for us to repot it, giving the roots a
new airy space to grow strong and
healthy. From this point on, the plant
will gradually store energy for fresh
blooms in the coming season.
Now we will cut off the faded flower
spike to help the plant focus its
nutrients on the resting phase. By
removing the old spike, all the plant's
energy will be redirected to the roots
and leaves instead of maintaining the
dried stems.
Next, we gently remove the plant from
the pot and observe the roots.
The roots that are dry, mushy, or dark
brown are signs of rot, and you should
cut them off. Removing the damaged roots
will help prevent disease and stimulate
the healthy roots to grow stronger.
Since the growing medium is still quite
new and loose, I will remove only half
of the old medium.
Keeping part of the familiar growing
medium helps the plant avoid shock when
moving to a new environment while still
ensuring ventilation and cleanliness for
the roots. This method helps the plant
adapt faster, maintain stable moisture,
and continue to grow naturally and
gently.
Uh, leave me a comment and let me know
which country you're watching from. It's
wonderful that we can connect and chat
together from all around the world.
And if you haven't subscribed yet,
please hit the subscribe button to
support me and never miss any orchid
care tips. It's wonderful to have you
with me.
Next, I use coffee to prepare a special
care solution for the plant. Coffee not
only gently disinfects the roots and
growing medium, but also provides
natural nutrients that help stimulate
stronger root growth.
Just one teaspoon of pure coffee powder
is enough to create a highly effective
root care solution.
Pour 500 ml of hot water into the coffee
powder and stir well until the water
turns a rich dark brown color.
uh after mixing, cover the container and
let it steep until the water cools
completely. Steeping helps the nutrients
in the coffee blend evenly into the
water while keeping a safe temperature
for the roots when watering.
Once the water has completely cooled,
stir the solution again to ensure the
nutrients are evenly dissolved in the
water.
Next, strain out the coffee grounds,
keeping only the clear solution. This
makes the watering gentle, prevents
clogging of the growing medium or young
roots, and ensures the nutrients are
absorbed to the fullest.
After straining out the grounds, add one
liter of water to dilute the solution.
This step makes the solution gentle,
just enough for the roots to absorb
without being too strong, while evenly
distributing nutrients throughout the
growing media.
Next, pour the diluted solution over the
roots and growing medium, letting them
soak for about 20 minutes.
This time is enough for the roots to
absorb nutrients from the coffee while
gently disinfecting and removing any
remaining bacteria or mold in the
growing medium.
While waiting for the roots and old
growing medium to soak, we take the
opportunity to prepare the new growing
medium.
Um, pour the diluted coffee solution
over the new growing medium and let it
soak for about 20 minutes. This time not
only helps disinfect the medium,
removing bacteria and mold, but also
allows the nutrients from the coffee to
permeate each particle. When planting
the orchid, the roots will come into
direct contact with the nutrient-rich
medium, supporting strong growth and
preparing for the next growth and
blooming cycle.
Any leftover diluted coffee solution can
be applied with a soft cloth to gently
wipe both the top and underside of the
leaves.
This method helps remove dust while
allowing the nutrients to gently adhere
to the leaf surface. supporting partial
nutrient absorption and enhancing the
plant's overall health.
After wiping, the leaves will become
clean and vibrant, and the orchid will
be ready to grow strongly during its
resting phase.
After soaking for about 20 minutes, we
gently remove the orchid from the
solution.
Next, let the plant rest and the growing
medium dry naturally for one day. This
process helps stabilize the roots,
prevent root rot when replanting, and
prepares the plant to absorb nutrients
better when transferred to the new
medium.
Then scoop out the new growing medium
and let it drain for about a day before
replanting the orchid. This ensures the
medium is moderately dry, preventing the
roots from being water logged or rotting
when planted.
When planted into the drained medium,
the roots will come into contact with an
ideal environment, absorb nutrients
efficiently, and grow strong, preparing
for the next growth and blooming cycle.
After one day, when the growing medium
has completely drained, we can proceed
to replant the orchid.
You should choose a pot with drainage
holes to plant the orchid. The drainage
holes allow excess water in the medium
to escape, preventing the roots from
becoming water logged or rotting.
Place a few pieces of foam at the bottom
of the pot to support drainage and keep
the roots from touching the bottom
directly.
Then gently position the orchid in the
pot and cover it with the growing
medium, taking care not to break or
damage the roots.
Next, slowly pack the growing medium
around the roots, filling any gaps in
the pot.
Make sure the medium surrounds the roots
evenly but is not packed too tightly,
allowing the roots space to breathe and
grow. When finished, the plant will
stand firmly in the pot with roots in
good contact with the nutrient-rich
medium ready for recovery and strong
growth.
Both the new and old growing medium have
reached the appropriate moisture level.
So after planting, you should let the
plant rest for about 3 days without
additional watering.
After 3 days, when the roots have
stabilized and the plant is no longer in
shock, we proceed to prepare the natural
fertilizer to water the plant.
Take three teaspoons of rice to prepare
the natural fertilizer. The rice will
provide a slowrelease source of
nutrients, gently supplementing energy
for the roots and leaves, helping the
plant recover after the resting phase.
Next, pour 500 ml of water over the rice
to soak it.
This is the banana mixture I have
prepared. Bananas provide many minerals
and natural sugars helping the orchid
absorb energy easily.
Next, take 50 ml of the banana mixture
to dilute.
After mixing, let the mixture rest for
about 2 hours for light fermentation.
The fermentation process helps the
nutrients in the rice, banana, and
ginger blend and transform into a form
that is easily absorbed by the roots.
After soaking for about 2 hours, stir
the mixture again to ensure the
nutrients are evenly dissolved.
Next, strain out any remaining solids,
keeping only the clear solution. This
makes the watering gentle, prevents
clogging of the medium or young roots,
and ensures the roots fully absorb the
natural nutrients, recovering healthily,
and preparing for the new blooming
season.
Step one, water this natural fertilizer
mixture directly onto the roots and
growing medium about two to three times
per month.
Regular watering helps the roots gently
absorb nutrients, stimulating healthy
growth of both roots and leaves.
This is an important step for the plant
to recover quickly, maintain vitality,
and prepare for new flower buds to bloom
in the coming seasons.
The fermented banana and rice water
mixture provides the plant with a full
range of natural nutrients. It not only
supplies minerals and sugars for the
roots to easily absorb energy, but also
stimulates root and leaf growth,
enhancing the plant's resistance.
Uh, step two, pour the natural
fertilizer mixture into a spray bottle.
Using a spray bottle helps distribute
the solution evenly over the leaves and
young stems while easily reaching the
nooks and crannies of the plant that
direct watering might miss.
This spraying not only supplies
nutrients but also allows the plant to
absorb them directly through the leaves,
enhancing overall health. As a result,
the leaves become lush and vibrant and
the plant is ready to nurture new flower
buds, preparing for a brilliant blooming
season ahead.
Step three, after spraying, use a soft
cloth to blot any water remaining on the
leaves.
This prevents the leaves from holding
water for too long, reducing the risk of
mold or disease on the leaf surface. At
the same time, it helps the nutrients
from the fertilizer solution absorb
evenly into the leaves, nourishing the
orchid and preparing new flower buds to
grow strong.
After completing all the care steps,
place the plant in a spot with gentle
sunlight.
And here are the results after 3 weeks
of dedicated care. You can see the roots
growing strong and healthy, beginning to
spread evenly throughout the growing
medium.
Not only are the roots growing
vigorously, but the plant has also
started producing new vibrant green
leaves. This is a clear sign that the
plant is recovering well, absorbing
nutrients efficiently, and storing
energy for the next flower buds.
Uh, I continue to water the plant with a
natural fertilizer made from rice and
fermented banana every month about two
to three times.
Maintaining this care routine allows the
roots and leaves to absorb nutrients
consistently, sustaining vitality and
stimulating strong growth. As a result,
the orchid will fully recover with lush
green leaves and be well prepared for
new flower buds to bloom in the next
season.
And here are the results after 3 months
of consistent care.
You can see the orchid growing
vigorously in both roots and leaves.
Lush and healthy.
And the special thing is the orchid has
sprouted a new flower spike. This is
clear evidence of the plant's strong
vitality and the effectiveness of caring
with natural fertilizer. The new spike
signals that the orchid is ready for a
brilliant blooming season ahead with
fresh, vibrant, and lively flowers.
And here are the results after four
months of consistent care. You can see
the orchid not only avoided exhaustion
after the flowering season, but also
grew vigorously with strong roots and
healthy leaves.
It's wonderful to see the plant
continuing to bloom with vibrant
flowers, showing that care with natural
fertilizer made from rice and fermented
banana truly helps the orchid recover,
maintain vitality, and prepare for many
more beautiful blooming seasons ahead.
Seeing the orchid recover and bloom
consistently, you will truly feel the
joy that comes from caring for every
small detail.
Believe that with love and patience, any
orchid can be revived strongly, grow
healthy and beautiful, and bloom
brilliantly.
Every care step you give the plant is
not only nourishment for its roots,
leaves, and flowers, but also a way to
sew joy and happiness in your own
garden.
If you find this content helpful and
meaningful, don't forget to like, share,
and subscribe so more people can see it
and support me.
Thank you for always being with me.