Hello everyone. Welcome to the Happiness
Garden
channel. Today I will share a great tip
for taking care of orchids after the
flowers have
faded. This method is especially
effective in helping wilted or weak
orchids recover and grow
quickly. This Phelinopsis orchid has
finished blooming but became wilted and
stunted, so it was
removed. I picked it up with the hope of
reviving it and helping it grow strong
again.
And now I will show you how to revive
[Music]
it. Uh if you're interested and haven't
subscribed yet, please hit the subscribe
button to support me and not miss any
orchid care tips. It's wonderful to have
you as a companion on this orchid care
journey. Thank you so much for watching
and sharing this passion with me.
First, we need to remove the yellowing
and damaged leaves from the orchid. Um,
this helps the plant focus its energy on
healthier parts and prevents diseases
from spreading through the damaged
[Music]
leaves. Then, we need to check the roots
and the orchid's growing medium as after
the flowers fade, the plant often goes
through a resting phase or prepares for
a new growth cycle.
[Music]
Due to the growing medium too wet, many
of the orchids roots were damaged,
resulting in the plant being unable to
absorb enough water and
nutrients. This caused the orchid's
leaves to start wilting, and the plant
became weak.
To fix this issue, we need to remove the
old growing medium and replace it with a
new one, ensuring that the orchid's
environment is well ventilated and not
water logged, allowing the roots to grow
healthily and the plant to recover
quickly.
[Music]
Next, cut off the damaged roots to stop
the growth of fungi and bacteria while
also creating space for new healthy
roots to
grow. Uh, this step not only helps the
orchid recover faster, but also allows
the plant to absorb nutrients better
from the new growing medium.
Next, cut off the wilted flower stalks
to help the plant focus its energy on
developing new leaves and roots rather
than nourishing the spent flower stems.
Next, we wash the orchid with water to
remove dust, fungus residues, bacteria,
or any impurities that could harm the
plant. Um, in addition to the English
voiceover, we have now created
voiceovers in French, German, Italian,
Spanish, Portuguese, Japanese, Hindi,
and Indonesian to help you listen and
understand the content more easily.
Uh to listen in your preferred language,
open the video and click on click on
settings, the gear icon to select the
appropriate audio
language. After washing, wait for the
orchid to dry before moving on to the
next
step. Next, take one aloe vera leaf to
make a natural fertilizer to revive the
orchid.
Aloe vera has antibacterial properties,
helping the orchid recover quickly and
grow
healthily. Put the aloe vera leaf into
300 ml of water and blend it to create a
natural fertilizer solution.
[Music]
After blending, strain it through a
sieve to remove the coarse fibers. ers
leaving only the aloe vera gel mixed
with
water. After straining, dilute it with
an additional 0.7 lers of water to get
one liter of aloe vera
solution. Next, I add three vitamin B1
tablets to the aloe vera solution to
enhance the recovery effect for the
orchid.
[Music]
Step one, use a soft cloth to soak up
this mixture and gently wipe both the
top and bottom surfaces of the orchid
leaves.
Step one, use a soft cloth to soak up
this mixture and gently wipe both the
top and bottom surfaces of the orchid
leaves.
[Music]
Clean and healthy leaves will
photosynthesize better, supporting the
plant's recovery and growth process.
[Music]
After wiping the leaves, soak the entire
orchid in this mixture for about 20
minutes.
Soaking helps the roots absorb the
maximum nutrients from the aloe vera and
vitamin B1, supporting the stimulation
of new root growth and the recovery of
damaged cells.
During the soaking time, you should
place the plant in a cool area, avoiding
direct sunlight to prevent thermal
shock. Next, we need to prepare the new
growing medium before
planting. I use pine bark chips for
planting orchids because pine bark chips
are breathable and retain moisture well,
helping the orchid grow healthily.
And I add a little moss to spread on top
of the orchid pot, helping to retain
moisture better and create a breathable
environment for the plant's
roots. Then pour boiling water over the
pine bark chips and soak the moss.
This helps sterilize and remove harmful
impurities while also making the growing
medium sum softer and better at
retaining moisture for the
[Music]
orchid and let me know which country
you're watching the video from. It's
amazing that we can chat together from
all around the world.
[Music]
If you haven't subscribed to the channel
yet, please hit the subscribe button to
support me and not miss any orchid care
tips. It's wonderful to have you have
you as a companion.
[Music]
If you haven't subscribed to the channel
yet, please hit the subscribe button to
support me and not miss any orchid care
tips. It's wonderful to have you have
you as a companion.
This helps prevent water logging and the
growth of mold while also allowing the
plant to dry out and be ready to
continue growing.
[Music]
Use a soft cloth or cotton pad to gently
wipe, ensuring that you don't damage the
leaves or other parts of the
[Music]
plant. After the growing medium has
completely cooled, we can proceed to
plant the orchid into the new pot.
Uh this ensures that the temperature of
the growing medium won't harm the
plant's
[Music]
roots. Gently place the orchid into the
pot, covering the roots with pine bark
chips and moss to stabilize the plant
and prevent it from being loose.
[Music]
Uh, make sure the roots are evenly
covered but not too tightly allowing
them space to grow.
[Music]
Next, spread a layer of moss on top of
the pot. This layer helps retain
moisture in the growing medium inside
the pot and prevents water from
evaporating too
quickly. Moss also helps create a
breathable environment for the orchid
and adds a natural aesthetic to your
orchid pot.
Then place the orchid pot in a cool,
airy spot for 3 days and avoid watering,
allowing the plant to adapt to the new
environment and recover after being
[Music]
replanted. Then place the orchid pot in
a cool, airy spot for 3 days and avoid
watering, allowing the plant to adapt to
the new environment and recover after
being replanted.
Uh from now on I will care for the
orchid using the aloe vera and vitamin
B1 liquid fertilizer once every 1 to 2
[Music]
weeks. Each time I fertilize, I use a
soft cloth to wipe the leaves, helping
to remove dirt and allowing the leaves
to absorb the nutrients from the
fertilizer more effectively.
[Music]
Gently wiping the leaves also helps the
orchid photosynthesize more effectively
while cleaning off impurities that could
hinder the plant's
[Music]
growth. Uh then water the roots and
growing medium of the orchid with this
mixture.
Make sure that the liquid fertilizer is
evenly distributed around the roots and
throughout the growing medium, helping
the plant absorb nutrients
[Music]
effectively. Water gently to avoid
disturbing the growing medium and help
the orchid develop
[Music]
steadily. After watering, soak the
orchid pot in this mixture for about 20
[Music]
minutes. Afterwards, take the orchid pot
out and place it in a spot with gentle
sunlight to allow the orchid to
photosynthesize and help the plant grow
healthily.
[Music]
Now, let's take a look at the results
after 3 months of reviving the wilted
orchid. You can see that the orchid has
become healthy again with strong root
growth and lush green
leaves. Um, although the bottom leaves
are still wilted and soft, once the
orchid has a healthy root system that
absorbs enough water and nutrients, it
will gradually recover and begin to grow
again.
[Music]
In addition to recovering wilted leaves,
the orchid has also grown two new
leaves. This is a very positive sign
that the plant is developing well and
adapting successfully to its new
environment.
[Music]
And the newly grown roots are very
healthy, bright white and plump,
indicating that the orchid is recovering
well and is capable of effectively
absorbing both water and nutrients.
[Music]
When the orchid roots grow vigorously,
they provide a strong foundation for the
plant to continue producing new leaves
and prepare for the next blooming cycle.
[Music]
I continue to care for the orchid with
the liquid fertilizer mixture made from
aloe vera and vitamin B1 once every 1 to
two weeks so the orchid maintains its
growth momentum with increasingly
stronger roots, lush green leaves, and
readiness for the next blooming phase.
Regular fertilization helps the plant
receive a gentle yet effective supply of
natural
nutrients. After that, I soak the orchid
pot in this mixture for about 20 minutes
to allow the roots to absorb the
nutrients maximally.
[Music]
Um, after that, take the orchid pot out
and place it in a spot with gentle
sunlight to allow the orchid to
[Music]
photosynthesize. Now, let's take a look
at the results after 5 months of
restoring the wilted orchid.
[Music]
Uh you can see that the orchid has fully
recovered with lush green leaves, strong
root growth, and especially new leaves
that have sprouted.
[Music]
The new leaves that have sprouted are
usually vibrant, green, and glossy,
showing that the roots are functioning
well and the plant is receiving all the
nutrients it
[Music]
needs. How do you think about my method
of restoring this small orchid plant?
Don't hesitate to leave a comment and
share your opinions. I'm really looking
forward to hearing your suggestions and
[Music]
experiences. Not only has the wilted
leaves fully recovered, but the orchid
has also produced two new flower spikes
with vibrant blooms, proving that the
care and recovery process has been a
complete success.
These flower spikes are not only
beautiful but also a clear testament to
the patience and love we give to our
orchids. Uh each time you revive a
plant, little by little your garden will
be filled with the vibrant colors of
blooming
orchids. Patience and careful care will
yield wonderful results. Not only
beautifying your living space, but also
bringing joy every day as you watch the
orchids bloom and showcase their beauty.
[Music]
If you find the content interesting and
meaningful, don't forget to like, share
it so more people can know, and
subscribe to support me. Thank you for
always being with
me. Thank you for watching the video. I
always pray that God blesses all of you.
Goodbye.